<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Reaper Class v2.2.2</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="class-reaper.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/spirit-magic/class-reaper.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Reaper" type="Class" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_CLASS_REAPER">
        <description>
            <p>A half-orc grabs the charm around his neck as he charges a chimera. He mutters a word and is transformed into an owlbear just in time to collide with the monstrosity and tackle it to the ground.</p>
            <p class="indent">A gnome grabs a small glowing ball from her belt and chucks it at the pack of goblins chasing her. She laughs with glee as the ball detonates and the goblins cry out in pain and surprise.</p>
            <p class="indent">A human surveys the battlefield and sees the enemies reinforcements closing in. With a gesture and a word she calls forth hazards to hamper the enemy and give her allies more time.</p>
            <p class="indent">As varied as they may seem, these are all Reapers. They use the souls of the dead to fight and destroy monsters. Sometimes the souls make their weapons better. Sometimes the souls are the weapon. And sometimes the soul turns the Reaper into the weapon. But whatever the method the goal is always the same, to take down the foes before them.</p>
            <h4>ANCIENT METHODS</h4>
            <p>Reapers are an order of monster hunters from a bygone age. In the time before wandering mercenaries and adventurers became prevalent it was the Reapers that tracked and hunted monsters and other dangerous creatures. They use Spirit Magic to take the power of the fallen and use it to make themselves stronger.</p>
            <h4>FADED GLORY</h4>
            <p>The training to become a Reaper is long and intensive, often starting at a young age. It is generally considered far more demanding than learning other methods of fighting, and so their numbers have been in steady decline since the advent of adventures and traveling mercenaries. Many of the schools that taught the methods of the Reapers have closed down and what few remain house a small handful of students.</p>
            <h4>CREATING A REAPER</h4>
            <p>When making a Reaper consider why you would choose a life of monster hunting. Did you loose your family to a wild beast and wish to save others the same pain? Were your parents Reapers and you want to follow their footsteps? Were you an orphan of war adopted by a school and simply knew no other life?</p>
            <p class="indent">Traveling and fighting is a hard life. You never have a true home and your life is in constant danger. Why would you accept such a harsh lifestyle? Are you antisocial and prefer life on the road? Do you have wanderlust and fighting monsters servers to finance your travels?</p>
            <h5>QUICK BUILD</h5>
            <p>You can make a Reaper quickly by following these suggestions. First, make Strength or Dexterity your highest ability score, depending on whether you want to focus on melee weapons or on archery (or finesse weapons). Your next-highest score should be Charisma followed by Constitution. Second, choose the Outlander background.</p>
            <h2>CLASS FEATURES</h2>
            <p>As an reaper, you gain the following class features.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">HIT POINTS</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Hit Dice:</strong> 1d10 per reaper level</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at 1st Level:</strong> 10 + your Constitution modifier</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at Higher Levels:</strong> 1d10 (or 6) + your Constitution modifier per reaper level after 1st</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">PROFICIENCIES</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled mb">
                <li><strong>Armor:</strong> Light and medium armor, shields</li>
                <li><strong>Weapons:</strong> Simple weapons, one martial weapon</li>
                <li><strong>Tools:</strong> None</li>
            </ul>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Saving Throws:</strong> Constitution, Charisma</li>
                <li><strong>Skills:</strong> Choose two from Acrobatics, Athletics, History, Insight, Investigation, Nature, Perception, Stealth, and Survival</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">EQUIPMENT</h5>
            <p>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>(a) a martial weapon and a shield or (b) two simple weapons</li>
                <li>(a) scale mail or (b) leather, longbow, and 20 arrows</li>
                <li>(a) a dungeoneer’s pack or (b) an explorer’s pack</li>
            </ul>
            <h4>MULTICLASSING</h4>
            <p>When multiclassing with a Reaper your Charisma and either your Strength or Dexterity must be at least 13. You also gain proficiency in light armor, simple weapons, and shields.</p>
        <!-- class table here -->
            <h5 class="caption">THE REAPER</h5>
            <table class="class-features">
                <thead>
                    <tr><td class="col-5">Level</td><td class="col-10">col1</td><td class="col-60 left">Features</td><td class="col-10">Reliquaries</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td> 1st</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Harvest, Soul Binding</td><td>1</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 2nd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Fighting Style, Soul Rite</td><td>2</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 3rd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Soul Strangle</td><td>3</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 4th</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>4</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 5th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Extra Attack</td><td>5</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 6th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Rite Feature</td><td>6</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 7th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Soul Binding (2)</td><td>7</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 8th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>8</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 9th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Soul Strangle (3 uses)</td><td>9</td></tr>
                <tr><td>10th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Rite Feature</td><td>10</td></tr>
                <tr><td>11th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Short Harvest</td><td>11</td></tr>
                <tr><td>12th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>12</td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Soul Binding (4)</td><td>13</td></tr>
                <tr><td>14th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Rite Feature</td><td>14</td></tr>
                <tr><td>15th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Soul Strangle (4 uses)</td><td>15</td></tr>
                <tr><td>16th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>16</td></tr>
                <tr><td>17th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Soul Capture</td><td>17</td></tr>
                <tr><td>18th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Rite Feature</td><td>18</td></tr>
                <tr><td>19th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>19</td></tr>
                <tr><td>20th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Empty Husk</td><td>20</td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_DZ_SMC_CLASS_FEATURE_REAPER_RELIQUARY" />
            <div element="ID_DZ_SMC_CLASS_FEATURE_REAPER_HARVEST" />
            <div element="ID_DZ_SMC_CLASS_FEATURE_REAPER_SOUL_BINDING" />
            <div element="ID_DZ_SMC_CLASS_FEATURE_REAPER_SOUL_RITE" />
            <div element="ID_DZ_SMC_CLASS_FEATURE_REAPER_FIGHTING_STYLE" />
            <div element="ID_DZ_SMC_CLASS_FEATURE_REAPER_SOUL_STRANGLE" />
            <div element="ID_DZ_SMC_CLASS_FEATURE_REAPER_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" />
            <div element="ID_DZ_SMC_CLASS_FEATURE_REAPER_EXTRA_ATTACK" />
            <div element="ID_DZ_SMC_CLASS_FEATURE_REAPER_SHORT_HARVEST" />
            <div element="ID_DZ_SMC_CLASS_FEATURE_REAPER_SOUL_CAPTURE" />
            <div element="ID_DZ_SMC_CLASS_FEATURE_REAPER_EMPTY_HUSK" />
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="hd">d10</set>
            <set name="short">A class that captures and consumes the powers within souls.</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" requirements="!ID_DZ_SMC_MULTICLASS_REAPER" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_MEDIUM_ARMOR" requirements="!ID_DZ_SMC_MULTICLASS_REAPER" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_SHIELDS" requirements="!ID_DZ_SMC_MULTICLASS_REAPER" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" requirements="!ID_DZ_SMC_MULTICLASS_REAPER" />
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Martial Weapon Proficiency, Reaper" supports="Weapon,Martial" requirements="!ID_DZ_SMC_MULTICLASS_REAPER" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CONSTITUTION" requirements="!ID_DZ_SMC_MULTICLASS_REAPER" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CHARISMA" requirements="!ID_DZ_SMC_MULTICLASS_REAPER" />
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency, Reaper" supports="Skill, Reaper" number="2" requirements="!ID_DZ_SMC_MULTICLASS_REAPER" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_DZ_SMC_CLASS_FEATURE_REAPER_RELIQUARY" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_DZ_SMC_CLASS_FEATURE_REAPER_HARVEST" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_DZ_SMC_CLASS_FEATURE_REAPER_SOUL_BINDING" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_DZ_SMC_CLASS_FEATURE_REAPER_SOUL_RITE" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_DZ_SMC_CLASS_FEATURE_REAPER_FIGHTING_STYLE" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_DZ_SMC_CLASS_FEATURE_REAPER_SOUL_STRANGLE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_DZ_SMC_CLASS_FEATURE_REAPER_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" level="4" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_DZ_SMC_CLASS_FEATURE_REAPER_EXTRA_ATTACK" level="5" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_DZ_SMC_CLASS_FEATURE_REAPER_SHORT_HARVEST" level="11" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_DZ_SMC_CLASS_FEATURE_REAPER_SOUL_CAPTURE" level="17" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_DZ_SMC_CLASS_FEATURE_REAPER_EMPTY_HUSK" level="20" />
        </rules>
        <multiclass id="ID_DZ_SMC_MULTICLASS_REAPER">
            <prerequisite>Charisma 13, Strength or Dexterity 13</prerequisite>
            <requirements>[cha:13],([str:13]||[dex:13])</requirements>
            <setters>
                <set name="multiclass proficiencies">You gain proficiency in light armor, simple weapons, and shields.</set>
            </setters>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_SHIELDS" />
            </rules>
        </multiclass>
    </element>
        <element name="Reliquary" type="Class Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_CLASS_FEATURE_REAPER_RELIQUARY">
            <description>
                <p>Souls are the power that drives a Reaper and Reliquaries are the containers that hold these souls. Each Reliquary can only hold a single soul, and the number of Reliquaries you can have is indicated on the table above. You must be within 5 feet of the Reliquary to access or use the soul within.</p>
                <p class="indent">A Reliquary made by one Reaper will not work for any others. If a Reliquary is ever broken the soul in it is released and you must spend an hour to forge a replacement. At will you can dismantle any Reliquary you made, regardless of distance. Doing this releases the soul within and allows you to make a new Reliquary to replace it.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You have 1 Reliquary, which can hold a single soul. You must be within 5 feet of the Reliquary to access or use the soul within.</description>
                <description level="2">You have {{reliquary:count}} Reliquaries. Each can hold a single soul. You must be within 5 feet of the Reliquary to access or use the soul within.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="reliquary:count" value="level:reaper" level="1" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Harvest" type="Class Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_CLASS_FEATURE_REAPER_HARVEST">
            <description>
                <p>Reapers get the souls to power their abilities from the world around them. As part of a long rest you must spend an hour in meditation to seek out souls in the area. These souls fill your available Reliquaries, one soul in each, and allow you to use your class abilities.</p>
                <h5>SAVES</h5>
                <p>Some Reaper abilities allow for a save. The DC is as follows:</p>
                <p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Ability save DC</strong> = 8 + your Proficiency Bonus + your Charisma modifier</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>As part of a long rest you must spend an hour in meditation to seek out souls in the area. These souls fill your available Reliquaries, one soul in each, and allow you to use your class abilities.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="reaper:save-dc" value="8" />
                <stat name="reaper:save-dc" value="proficiency" />
                <stat name="reaper:save-dc" value="charisma:modifier" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Soul Binding" type="Class Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_CLASS_FEATURE_REAPER_SOUL_BINDING">
            <description>
                <p>At 1st level you learn how to bind a soul to you to aid in your travels. You have two places the soul can be bound, the Mind and the Body, but can only bind a single soul. Binding must be done during a long rest.</p>
                <p class="indent">Binding a soul to the Mind allows you to reroll a single Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma save or ability check and take the higher result. Binding a soul to your Body functions the same way, only for Strength, Dexterity, and Constitution.</p>
                <p class="indent">Using this reroll does not expend the bound soul. Once this ability is used, you must finish a short or long rest to use it again. A bound soul can’t be used for any other feature but still occupies a Reliquary.</p>
                <p class="indent">At 7th level you can have a soul bound to your Mind and another bound to your Body. At 13th level each soul gives 2 rerolls per rest. Both rerolls can’t be used to affect the same initial roll.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="{{soul-binding:uses}}/Short Rest">
                <description>You can bind 1 soul to the Mind or Body. Mind: reroll 1 Int, Wis, or Cha save or ability check and take the higher result. Body: reroll 1 Str, Dex, or Con save or ability check and take the higher result.</description>
                <description level="7">You can bind 1 soul each to the Mind and Body. Mind: reroll 1 Int, Wis, or Cha save or ability check and take the higher result. Body: reroll 1 Str, Dex, or Con save or ability check and take the higher result.</description>
                <description level="13">You can bind 1 soul each to the Mind and Body. Mind: reroll 2 Int, Wis, or Cha saves or ability checks and take the higher result. Body: reroll 2 Str, Dex, or Con saves or ability checks and take the higher result.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="soul-binding:uses" value="1" level="1" />
                <stat name="soul-binding:uses" value="1" level="13" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Soul Rite" type="Class Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_CLASS_FEATURE_REAPER_SOUL_RITE">
            <description>
                <p>Near the end of their training every Reaper undergoes a Rite. The Rites dictate how the Reaper uses the souls they Harvest and are very different from each other. Most Reapers are still learning how their Rite works when they begin their travels but they catch on rather quickly.</p>
                <p class="indent">At 2nd level you choose the Rite that emphasizes how you use souls. Choose from the Rite of the Soul Archer, the Rite of the Soul Binder, the Rite of the Soul Burst, the Rite of the Soul Hunter, the Rite of the Soul Mage, the Rite of the Soul Tamer, or The Grimm. Your choice grants you features at 2nd level and again at 6th, 10th, 14th, and 18th levels.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Archetype" name="Rite" supports="Reaper Rite" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Fighting Style" type="Class Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_CLASS_FEATURE_REAPER_FIGHTING_STYLE">
            <description>
                <p>At 2nd level you adopt a particular style of fighting as your specialty. Choose one of the following options. You can’t take a Fighting Style option more than once, even if you later get to choose again.</p>
                <h5>ARCHERY</h5>
                <p>You gain a +2 bonus to attack rolls you make with ranged weapons.</p>
                <h5>CLOSE QUARTERS SHOOTER</h5>
                <p>You are trained in making ranged attacks at close quarters. When making a ranged attack while you are within 5 feet of a hostile creature, you do not have disadvantage on the attack roll.</p>
                <p class="indent">Your ranged attacks ignore half cover and three quarters cover against targets within 30 feet of you. Finally, you have a +1 bonus to attack rolls on ranged attacks.</p>
                <h5>DEFENSE</h5>
                <p>While you are wearing armor, you gain a +1 bonus to AC.</p>
                <h5>DUELING</h5>
                <p>When you are wielding a melee weapon in one hand and no other weapons, you gain a +2 bonus to damage rolls with that weapon.</p>
                <h5>GREAT WEAPON FIGHTING</h5>
                <p>When you roll a 1 or 2 on a damage die for an attack you make with a melee weapon that you are wielding with two hands, you can reroll the die and must use the new roll, even if the new roll is a 1 or a 2. The weapon must have the twohanded or versatile property for you to gain this benefit.</p>
                <h5>THROWN WEAPON FIGHTING</h5>
                <p>You can draw a weapon that has the thrown property as part of the attack you make with the weapon.</p>
                <p class="indent">In addition, when you hit with a ranged attack using a thrown weapon, you gain a +1 bonus to the damage roll.</p>
                <h5>TWO-WEAPON FIGHTING</h5>
                <p>When you engage in two-weapon fighting, you can add your ability modifier to the damage of the second attack.</p>
                <h5>UNARMED FIGHTING</h5>
                <p>Your unarmed strikes can deal bludgeoning damage equal to 1d6 + your Strength modifier. If you strike with two free hands, the d6 becomes a d8.</p>
                <p class="indent">When you successfully start a grapple, you can deal 1d4 bludgeoning damage to the grappled creature. Until the grapple ends, you can also deal this damage to the creature whenever you hit it with a melee attack.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Fighting Style" supports="Fighting Style, Reaper" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Soul Strangle" type="Class Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_CLASS_FEATURE_REAPER_SOUL_STRANGLE">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 3rd level you can paralyze those around you. As an action you can expend a soul to cast hold person as the spell on a single target. You can use this feature twice before a long rest and an additional time at 9th and 15th level.</p>
                <p class="indent">Also at 9th level you can expend two souls to as an action cast <i>hold monster</i> but you are still limited to 1 target.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="{{soul-strangle:uses}}/Long Rest">
                <description>You can expend 1 soul to cast hold person on a single target.</description>
                <description level="9">You can expend 1 soul to cast hold person on a single target, or you can expend 2 souls to cast hold monster.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="soul-strangle:uses" value="2" level="3" />
                <stat name="soul-strangle:uses" value="1" level="9" />
                <stat name="soul-strangle:uses" value="1" level="15" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HOLD_PERSON" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HOLD_MONSTER" level="9" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Ability Score Improvement" type="Class Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_CLASS_FEATURE_REAPER_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
                <p class="indent">Using the optional feats rule, you can forgo taking this feature to take a feat of your choice instead.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Reaper 4)" supports="Improvement Option,Reaper,4" level="4" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Reaper 8)" supports="Improvement Option,Reaper,8" level="8" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Reaper 12)" supports="Improvement Option,Reaper,12" level="12" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Reaper 16)" supports="Improvement Option,Reaper,16" level="16" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Reaper 19)" supports="Improvement Option,Reaper,19" level="19" />     
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Extra Attack" type="Class Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_CLASS_FEATURE_REAPER_EXTRA_ATTACK">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 5th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="extra attack:count" value="2" level="5" bonus="extra attack" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Short Harvest" type="Class Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_CLASS_FEATURE_REAPER_SHORT_HARVEST">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 11th level when you roll Hit Die on a short rest you Harvest 1 soul per Hit Die rolled. This can not put you past your maximum number of souls.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you roll Hit Die on a short rest you Harvest 1 soul per Hit Die rolled. This can not put you past your maximum number of souls.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Soul Capture" type="Class Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_CLASS_FEATURE_REAPER_SOUL_CAPTURE">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 17th level you can take souls from the living. As an action you can make a ranged attack against a creature within 30 feet of you. You use your Charisma modifier for this attack. If the target has 100 or fewer hit points, it dies. If you have an empty Reliquary you can steal its soul. If the creature has no soul for you to steal you have disadvantage on the attack and can’t fill a Reliquary if the creature dies.</p>
                <p class="indent">This ability can be used once before you need a long rest to regain use of it.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest" action="Action">
                <description>You can make a ranged attack against a creature within 30 feet of you. You use your Charisma modifier for this attack. If the target has 100 or fewer hit points, it dies. If you have an empty Reliquary you can steal its soul. If the creature has no soul for you to steal you have disadvantage on the attack and can’t fill a Reliquary if the creature dies.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Empty Husk" type="Class Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_CLASS_FEATURE_REAPER_EMPTY_HUSK">
            <description>
                <p>At 20th level your body is nothing more than a vehicle for your soul. As an action, you can shunt your soul into the body of another humanoid. The target body does not need to be dead, but it must be empty of a soul. You must succeed a DC 13 Constitution save or the transfer fails and you do not move bodies.</p>
                <p class="indent">If the body has taken significant damage (DM discretion) the check automatically fails. Otherwise the body heals enough to be alive and sustain you in it. Regardless of how much hp it had before when you take the new body it is at 1hp and you have 1 level of exhaustion.</p>
                <p class="indent">You retain your mental Ability scores but gain the physical Ability scores of the body you now inhabit. You do not gain any of the knowledge, languages, proficiencies, abilities, or class features (if any) the previous owner of the body had, nor do you lose any of yours, with one exception.</p>
                <p class="indent">If the new body was of a different race than the old body you loose all racial abilities of your old race and gain the ones of the new race. You lose the Ability score modifications of your old race and gain the ones of the new race. As always, this can not put any Ability score above a 20.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can attempt this transition once per long rest.</p>
                <div ref="sidebar">
                    <h5 class="caption">A TOUCH OF LORE</h5>
                    <p>Changing bodies is a strain on the soul. Many who go through with it have to relearn some or all of their abilities. Although it might be unfair to place penalties on a character using this in a game, it could be used for why a character from a previous game looks a little different and has a different level or even subclass.</p>
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You can shunt your soul into another body that is empty of a soul by making a DC 13 Constitution saving throw.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>

    <element name="Rite of the Soul Archer" type="Archetype" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_RITE_OF_THE_SOUL_ARCHER">
        <supports>Reaper Rite</supports>
        <description>
            <p></p>
            <p class="indent">Those who take the Rite of the Soul Archer focus on keeping away from monsters, and keeping the monsters away from them and their allies as they bring them down. They use their Harvested souls to give them special attacks and traps to use in combat. They are experts in all bows, be they long, short, or cross.</p>
            <div element="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSA_PINNING_SHOT" />
            <div element="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSA_SOUL_TRAPS" />
            <div element="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSA_TRICK_SHOTS" />
            <div element="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSA_COVER_FIRE" />
            <div element="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSA_SOUL_WALL" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSA_PINNING_SHOT" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSA_SOUL_TRAPS" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSA_TRICK_SHOTS" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSA_COVER_FIRE" level="14" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSA_SOUL_WALL" level="18" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_LONGBOW" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SHORTBOW" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_CROSSBOW_LIGHT" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_CROSSBOW_HEAVY" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_CROSSBOW_HAND" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Pinning Shot" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSA_PINNING_SHOT">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 2nd level you gain the ability to keep enemies where you want them. When you hit a creature with a ranged attack you can expend a soul to attempt to pin them in place. The target must succeed a Dexterity save against your Ability DC or their movement becomes 0. The creature can spend an action each turn to attempt this save again.</p>
                <p class="indent">At 10th level a creature affected by this feature becomes restrained. Though a restrained creature has disadvantage on Dexterity saves it does not have disadvantage on the save to break free from being pinned, unless that disadvantage comes from a different source.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you hit a creature with a ranged attack you can expend a soul to reduce the targets speed to 0, if it fails a Dexterity saving throw (DC {{reaper:save-dc}}). The creature can spend an action each turn to attempt this save again.</description>
                <description level="10">When you hit a creature with a ranged attack you can expend a soul restrain the target if it fails a Dexterity saving throw (DC {{reaper:save-dc}}). The creature can spend an action each turn to attempt this save again without disadvantage for this save.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Soul Traps" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSA_SOUL_TRAPS">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level you are able to scatter traps in the battlefield to catch unwary creatures. Each trap takes an action to place and costs a single soul. You can place traps up to 30 feet away from you and they last for 1 minute before dissolving or returning to their normal form. You can end your traps as a free action on your turn.</p>
                <p class="indent">At 10th level the range for your traps extends to 60 feet. You also gain the ability to expend an additional soul when setting the trap to increase the duration to 10 minutes. The traps you can set are detailed below:</p>
                <div element="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSA_SOUL_TRAP_PIT_TRAP" />
                <div element="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSA_SOUL_TRAP_SOFT_EARTH" />
                <div element="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSA_SOUL_TRAP_UNDERBRUSH" />
                <div element="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSA_SOUL_TRAP_WEB" />
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>You can place traps up to {{soul-traps:range}} feet away from you and they last for 1 minute before dissolving or returning to their normal form.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="soul-traps:range" value="30" level="6" />
                <stat name="soul-traps:range" value="30" level="10" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSA_SOUL_TRAP_PIT_TRAP" level="6" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSA_SOUL_TRAP_SOFT_EARTH" level="6" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSA_SOUL_TRAP_UNDERBRUSH" level="6" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSA_SOUL_TRAP_WEB" level="6" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Pit Trap" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSA_SOUL_TRAP_PIT_TRAP">
            <description>
                <p>This trap creates a hollow spot of earth in a circle with a 10-foot radius. The pit is 30-foot deep and the walls are perfectly smooth. The top of the pit is indistinguishable from the ground around it but the next creature of small size or larger that walks across or starts its turn on it will break through the top and fall in. Falling in the pit deals 3d6 bludgeoning damage.</p>
                <p class="indent">When this trap expires the ground of the pit rises back up to the surface, bringing any creatures caught back to ground level without further harm. You always know where any Pit Traps you lay are, but they are indistinguishable to all other creatures.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can expend an additional soul when making a Pit Trap to turn it into a Spike Trap. A Spike Trap functions in all ways like a Pit Trap, but any creature that falls in takes an additional 2d10 piercing damage.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1 soul">
                <description>Hollow spot of earth in a circle with a 10-foot radius, 30 feet deep, with perfectly smooth walls, and the opening is indistinguishable. The next creature that walks across it or starts its turn on it falls for 3d6 bludgeoning damage.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Spike Trap" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSA_SOUL_TRAP_SPIKE_TRAP">
            <description>
                <p>This trap creates a hollow spot of earth in a circle with a 10-foot radius. The pit is 30-foot deep and the walls are perfectly smooth. The top of the pit is indistinguishable from the ground around it but the next creature of small size or larger that walks across or starts its turn on it will break through the top and fall in. Falling in the pit deals 3d6 bludgeoning damage.</p>
                <p class="indent">When this trap expires the ground of the pit rises back up to the surface, bringing any creatures caught back to ground level without further harm. You always know where any Pit Traps you lay are, but they are indistinguishable to all other creatures.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can expend an additional soul when making a Pit Trap to turn it into a Spike Trap. A Spike Trap functions in all ways like a Pit Trap, but any creature that falls in takes an additional 2d10 piercing damage.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="2 souls">
                <description>Hollow spot of earth in a circle with a 10-foot radius, 30 feet deep, with perfectly smooth walls, spikes on the bottom, and the opening is indistinguishable. The next creature that walks across it or starts its turn on it falls for 2d10 piercing damage.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Soft Earth" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSA_SOUL_TRAP_SOFT_EARTH">
            <description>
                <p>This trap is a circle with a diameter of 15 feet. At first glance this area looks normal but with a Perception check against your Ability DC a creature can tell the ground is too soft to support weight.</p>
                <p class="indent">Any creature that steps into or starts its turn in the trap must succeed a Strength save against your Ability DC or be stuck. If the creature succeeds, and was not previously stuck, they can move through the trap at half speed.</p>
                <p class="indent">A stuck creature’s movement becomes 0 and they begin to sink. As an action on their turn a sinking creature can attempt a Strength save to pull themselves free. If they succeed they stop sinking and if they were not sinking on their previous turn they can leave the trap at half speed.</p>
                <p class="indent">A creature that fails this Strength save to stop sinking becomes restrained and sinks to their knees. On the next round they can attempt the saves again to pull their legs up to their ankles. Doing so ends the restrained condition on them but they are unable to leave the trap until they succeed again.</p>
                <p class="indent">If a creature fails to break free a second time they sink to their waist. They are sill restrained, but can no longer make attempts to break free. A creature will not sink further than their waist. When the trap ends any caught creatures are raised back up to the surface without taking any further harm.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1 soul">
                <description>This trap is a circle with a diameter of 15 feet. A Perception check (DC {{reaper:save-dc}} tells a creature the ground is too soft to support weight. Any creature that steps into or starts its turn in the trap must succeed a Strength save or be stuck. If the creature succeeds, and was not previously stuck, they can move through the trap at half speed.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Underbrush" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSA_SOUL_TRAP_UNDERBRUSH">
            <description>
                <p>An area with a radius of 20 feet becomes rough terrain for all creatures. Creatures that can normally ignore any or a specific kind of rough terrain are still affected by this trap.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1 soul">
                <description>An area with a radius of 20 feet becomes rough terrain for all creatures.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Web" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSA_SOUL_TRAP_WEB">
            <description>
                <p>This trap functions like the spell web, except its range and duration are determined by your Soul Trap feature and it is not concentration.</p>
                <div class="reference">
                    <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_WEB" />
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1 soul">
                <description>This trap functions like the spell web, except its range and duration are determined by your Soul Trap feature and it is not concentration.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WEB" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Trick Shots" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSA_TRICK_SHOTS">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 10th level you lean more versatility with your ranged attacks. There are two Trick Shots you learn, Piercing Shot and Spread Shot.</p>
                <div element="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSA_TRICK_SHOT_PIERCING_SHOT" />
                <div element="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSA_TRICK_SHOT_SPREAD_SHOT" />
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSA_TRICK_SHOT_PIERCING_SHOT" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSA_TRICK_SHOT_SPREAD_SHOT" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Piercing Shot" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSA_TRICK_SHOT_PIERCING_SHOT">
                <description>
                    <p>As an action you can expend a soul to make a ranged attack that hits all targets in a 5-foot wide line starting at you and going to the end of the weapon’s range.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Make a single attack roll and apply it to each target’s AC in the line. If the attack roll fails to hit one of the targets the attack stops at them and all targets behind them are not affected.</p>
                    <p class="indent">For example if you have three targets in a line and rolled a 19 to hit which would hit the first target’s AC of 18 but not the second target’s AC of 20, the third target is unaffected, even if their AC was 17 and they would have been hit.</p>
                    <p class="indent">For each target this attack hits it deals an extra 1d6 damage. Roll damage once, the first target takes that much damage. Each subsequent target takes 2 less damage than the one before it.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet action="Action" usage="1 soul">
                    <description>You make a ranged attack that hits all targets in a 5-foot wide line starting at you and going to the end of the weapon’s range. Make a single attack roll and apply it to each target’s AC in the line. If the attack roll fails to hit one of the targets the attack stops at them and all targets behind them are not affected. For each target this attack hits it deals an extra 1d6 damage. Roll damage once, the first target takes that much damage. Each subsequent target takes 2 less damage than the one before it.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Spread Shot" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSA_TRICK_SHOT_SPREAD_SHOT">
                <description>
                    <p>As an action you can expend a soul to fire a barrage of projectiles in a 15-foot cone originating from you. All creatures within the cone must succeed a Dexterity save against your Ability DC or take your normal ranged weapon damage + xd6 radiant damage where x is your Charisma modifier. A successful save takes half damage.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet action="Action" usage="1 soul">
                    <description>You fire a barrage of projectiles in a 15-foot cone originating from you. All creatures within the cone must succeed a Dexterity save (DC {{reaper:save-dc}}) or take your normal ranged weapon damage + xd6 radiant damage where x is your Charisma modifier. A successful save takes half damage.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
        <element name="Cover Fire" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSA_COVER_FIRE">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 14th level you can designate squares on the battlefield to be considered threatened by you. As a bonus action you can expend souls to mark the squares. Each soul you expend allows you to mark two squares. You can not have a number of marked squares more than your level.</p>
                <p class="indent">The squares must be within range of your bow and spaces you could hit with the weapon from where you are when you mark the space. Squares remain marked for 10 minutes even if they are no longer within range of your bow.</p>
                <p class="indent">Any time a creature leaves one of these spaces you can use your reaction to make an attack of opportunity on them with your bow. If the space is no longer in range of the weapon you can not make this opportunity attack.</p>
                <p class="indent">Starting at 18th level, if you already used your reaction and a creature leaves one of your marked spaces you can expend a soul to make a single attack on them. You can only do this once per round.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>You can expend up to {{level:reaper:half:up}} souls to mark 2 squares per soul as threatened by you. The squares must be within range of your bow and spaces you could hit with the weapon from where you are when you mark the space. Squares remain marked for 10 minutes even if they are no longer within range of your bow. Any time a creature leaves one of these spaces you can use your reaction to make an attack of opportunity on them with your bow. If the space is no longer in range of the weapon you can not make this opportunity attack.</description>
                <description level="18">You can expend up to {{level:reaper:half:up}} souls to mark 2 squares per soul as threatened by you. The squares must be within range of your bow and spaces you could hit with the weapon from where you are when you mark the space. Squares remain marked for 10 minutes even if they are no longer within range of your bow. Any time a creature leaves one of these spaces you can use your reaction to make an attack of opportunity on them with your bow. If the space is no longer in range of the weapon you can not make this opportunity attack. If you already used your reaction and a creature leaves one of your marked spaces you can expend a soul to make a single attack on them. You can only do this once per round.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Soul Wall" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSA_SOUL_WALL">
            <description>
                <p>At 18th level you are able to make walls on the battlefield to act as obstacles. Creating a Soul Wall is an action and it costs 1 soul per 10-foot square of wall you wish to make. All the squares from a single use of this feature must connect in some way and Soul Walls must stand vertically. The Soul Wall is 1-foot thick and lasts for 10 minutes.</p>
                <p class="indent">At least part of the Soul Wall must be within 60 feet of you and it has a designated front and back. You can decide which way it faces when you use this future but all connected squares must have the front on the same side and the back on the other.</p>
                <p class="indent">The front of the Soul Wall is completely transparent and a creature can not see it unless they are touching it, at which point they can see the edges of the whole wall provided they have line of sight. The back of the wall is translucent but visible to all creatures. You always know where the entirely of your Soul Wall is.</p>
                <p class="indent">The front of the wall is impenetrable but the back is semi-permeable. A creature can move through the wall, passing through the back to the front, by expending an extra 5 feet of movement to do so. Any attacks that would pass through the wall are stopped entirely from the front side. The attacks have disadvantage, or the save has advantage, if they pass through the wall from the back side.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="1 soul/10-foot square">
                <description>You can create a Soul Wall, which is imprenetrable from the front, but the back is semi-permeable. A creature can move through the wall, passing through the back to the front, by expending an extra 5 feet of movement to do so. Any attacks that would pass through the wall are stopped entirely from the front side. The attacks have disadvantage, or the save has advantage, if they pass through the wall from the back side.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>

    <element name="Rite of the Soul Binder" type="Archetype" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_REAPER_RITE_OF_THE_SOUL_BINDER">
        <supports>Reaper Rite</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Soul Binders don’t look for a new way to use souls. Instead they focus on the basics and delve deeper into Binding. They unlock more areas they can bind souls to, and find new abilities for having souls bound in these places.</p>
            <div element="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSBINDER_MORE_BINDING" />
            <div element="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSBINDER_ADVANCED_BINDING" />
            <div element="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSBINDER_DUAL_BINDING" />
            <div element="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSBINDER_HIGHER_BINDING" />
            <div element="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSBINDER_BLOOD_BINDING" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSBINDER_MORE_BINDING" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSBINDER_ADVANCED_BINDING" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSBINDER_DUAL_BINDING" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSBINDER_HIGHER_BINDING" level="14" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSBINDER_BLOOD_BINDING" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="More Binding" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSBINDER_MORE_BINDING">
            <description>
                <p>At 2nd level you gain access to far more places to Bind souls. Although the name is the same and the method is similar this feature does not merge with the Binding feature granted by the base class.</p>
                <p class="indent">When you get this class feature you have access to the Arms, Brow, Feet, Hands, Head, Heart, Shoulders, Soul, and Waist as places to Bind souls. The maximum number of capabilities you can have Bound is equal to half your level rounded down.</p>
                <p class="indent">Binding can only be done during a long rest. Each location can have a single soul Bound to it and each Bound soul gives a unique capability. Certain capabilities have level requirements before they can be taken. The full list of capabilities is at the end of this Rite’s section.</p>
                <p class="indent">Some capabilities have effects based on damage types. All theses damage types must be the same chosen from the following list; fire, cold, electric, acid, and poison. You can change this damage type on a short rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can bind up to {{level:reaper:half}} capabilities during a long rest. All theses damage types must be the same chosen from the following list; fire, cold, electric, acid, and poison. You can change this damage type on a short rest.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Advanced Binding" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSBINDER_ADVANCED_BINDING">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 6th level you gain access to the Advanced effects of capabilities. To gain the Advanced effects you must Bind two souls to the same place for the same capability.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You gain access to the Advanced effects of capabilities. To gain the Advanced effects you must Bind two souls to the same place for the same capability.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Dual Binding" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSBINDER_DUAL_BINDING">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 10th level you can Bind two capabilities to each location gained by this Rite. You can only gain each capability once.</p>
                <p class="indent">Also, your choice of damage types for your capabilities expands to include radiant, thundering, and necrotic.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can Bind two capabilities to each location gained by this Rite. You can only gain each capability once. Your choice of damage types for your capabilities expands to include radiant, thundering, and necrotic.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Higher Binding" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSBINDER_HIGHER_BINDING">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 14th level you gain access to the Higher effects of capabilities. To gain the Higher effects you must Bind three souls to the same place for the same capability.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You gain access to the Higher effects of capabilities. To gain the Higher effects you must Bind three souls to the same place for the same capability.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Blood Binding" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSBINDER_BLOOD_BINDING">
            <description>
                <p>At 18th level you gain access to a new location for your Binding. Only one capability can be Bound to your Blood, but the souls bound there can grant any capability this Rite offers.</p>
                <p class="indent">Binding to your Blood does not count against your maximum number of capabilities. You are still unable to take any capability more than once.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can bind one capability to your Blood. It does not count against your maximum number of capabilities. The souls bound there can grant any capability this Rite offers.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <!-- Capabilities -->
            <element name="Acrobatic" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSB_MORE_BINDING_ACROBATIC">
                <supports>Reaper More Binding Capability</supports>
                <description>
                    <p><b><i>Feet.</i></b> As a bonus action or reaction you can activate this to gain advantage on acrobatic checks for 1 minute. You have 3 uses of this which recover on a short or long rest.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Advanced.</i></b> This now has 5 uses and lasts for 10 minutes.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Higher.</i></b> This now has 6 uses and lasts for 1 hour.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                    <description></description>
                    <description level="6"></description>
                    <description level="14"></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Athletic" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSB_MORE_BINDING_ATHLETIC">
                <supports>Reaper More Binding Capability</supports>
                <description>
                    <p><b><i>Arms.</i></b> As a bonus action or reaction you can activate this to gain advantage on athletic checks for 1 minute. You have 3 uses of this which recover on a short or long rest.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Advanced.</i></b> This now has 5 uses and lasts for 10 minutes.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Higher.</i></b> This now has 6 uses and lasts for 1 hour.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description></description>
                    <description level="6"></description>
                    <description level="14"></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Concealment" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSB_MORE_BINDING_CONCEALMENT">
                <supports>Reaper More Binding Capability</supports>
                <requirements>[level:reaper:10]</requirements>
                <description>
                    <p><b><i>Soul.</i></b> You must be 10th level or higher to take this capability. You have partial cover from non adjacent enemies.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Higher.</i></b> If an enemy’s attack would have hit you but misses because of this capability you can use your reaction to redirect the attack into a creature that is adjacent to you. The attacker makes a new attack roll against this target and the attack resolves as if it was the intended target.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description></description>
                    <description level="14"></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Cruel" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSB_MORE_BINDING_CRUEL">
                <supports>Reaper More Binding Capability</supports>
                <requirements>[level:reaper:10]</requirements>
                <description>
                    <p><b><i>Waist.</i></b> This capability has no base effect.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Advanced.</i></b> You must be 10th level to take this capability. When attacking a creature that has already taken damage in that round you get a +1 to attack and damage.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Higher.</i></b> You have +1 to attack and damage if the target is not at full health. If the target has taken damage in the round it becomes a +2 to attack and damage.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description></description>
                    <description level="14"></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Deceptive" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSB_MORE_BINDING_DECEPTIVE">
                <supports>Reaper More Binding Capability</supports>
                <description>
                    <p><b><i>Brow.</i></b> As a bonus action or reaction you can activate this to gain advantage on deception checks for 1 minute. You have 3 uses of this which recover on a short or long rest.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Advanced.</i></b> This now has 5 uses and lasts for 10 minutes.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Higher.</i></b> This now has 6 uses and lasts for 1 hour.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description></description>
                    <description level="6"></description>
                    <description level="14"></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Defensive" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSB_MORE_BINDING_DEFENSIVE">
                <supports>Reaper More Binding Capability</supports>
                <description>
                    <p><b><i>Shoulders.</i></b> Gain +1 to your AC.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Disguise Self" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSB_MORE_BINDING_DISGUISE_SELF">
                <supports>Reaper More Binding Capability</supports>
                <description>
                    <p><b><i>Soul.</i></b> You gain the ability to cast disguise self as the spell twice before needing a long rest to regain uses.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Advanced.</i></b> You can use this capability three times before needing a long rest.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Higher.</i></b> This capability now resets on a short or long rest.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description></description>
                    <description level="6"></description>
                    <description level="14"></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Elemental Attack" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSB_MORE_BINDING_ELEMENTAL_ATTACK">
                <supports>Reaper More Binding Capability</supports>
                <description>
                    <p><b><i>Hands.</i></b> Your weapon attacks damage type changes to that of the element you chose.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Advanced.</i></b> You can choose to have your weapons deal their normal damage and deal an additional 1d4 of your chosen element.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Higher.</i></b> If the weapon damage is changed to that of the element it deals an extra 1d4 damage. If the weapon damage is normal and the elemental damage is extra, the elemental damage is 2d4.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description></description>
                    <description level="6"></description>
                    <description level="14"></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Elemental Guard" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSB_MORE_BINDING_ELEMENTAL_GUARD">
                <supports>Reaper More Binding Capability</supports>
                <requirements>[level:reaper:10]</requirements>
                <description>
                    <p><b><i>Shoulders.</i></b> This capability has no base effect.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Advanced.</i></b> You must be 10th level or higher to take this capability. You can activate this capability as a bonus action. When you do all creatures within 5 feet of you immediately take 1d6 damage of your chosen element. Afterwards, at the start of each of your turns all creatures within 5 feet of you take 2d6 damage of that element.</p>
                    <p class="indent">When activated this capability lasts a number of rounds equal to your Proficiency Bonus. You can activate this capability a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum once) before needing a long rest to regain uses.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Higher.</i></b> The initial damage increase to 2d6 and the damage each round increases to 3d6.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description></description>
                    <description level="14"></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Elemental Resistance" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSB_MORE_BINDING_ELEMENTAL_RESISTANCE">
                <supports>Reaper More Binding Capability</supports>
                <requirements>[level:reaper:10]</requirements>
                <description>
                    <p><b><i>Waist.</i></b> You must be 10th level or higher to take this capability. You gain resistance to the element you chose.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Eveready" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSB_MORE_BINDING_EVEREADY">
                <supports>Reaper More Binding Capability</supports>
                <requirements>[level:reaper:7]</requirements>
                <description>
                    <p><b><i>Feet.</i></b> You must be 7th level or higher to take this capability. You gain advantage on initiative rolls.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Good Aim" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSB_MORE_BINDING_GOOD_AIM">
                <supports>Reaper More Binding Capability</supports>
                <description>
                    <p><b><i>Hands.</i></b> As a bonus action you can activate this capability to gain +1 to all your attack rolls for 1 minute. You can activate this capability a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum once) before needing a long rest to regain uses.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Advanced.</i></b> The bonus to hit becomes a +2.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Higher.</i></b> The bonus to hit becomes a +3.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description></description>
                    <description level="6"></description>
                    <description level="14"></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Handy" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSB_MORE_BINDING_HANDY">
                <supports>Reaper More Binding Capability</supports>
                <description>
                    <p><b><i>Hands.</i></b> As a bonus action or reaction you can activate this to gain advantage on checks made with a single tool of your choice, chosen when you take this capability for 1 minute. You have 3 uses of this which recover on a short or long rest.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Advanced.</i></b> This now has 5 uses and lasts for 10 minutes.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Higher.</i></b> This now has 6 uses and lasts for 1 hour.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description></description>
                    <description level="6"></description>
                    <description level="14"></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Hard Hitting" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSB_MORE_BINDING_HARD_HITTING">
                <supports>Reaper More Binding Capability</supports>
                <description>
                    <p><b><i>Hands.</i></b> As a bonus action you can activate this capability to gain +1 to all your weapon damage rolls for 1 minute. You can activate this capability a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum once) before needing a long rest to regain uses.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Advanced.</i></b> The bonus to damage becomes a +2.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Higher.</i></b> The bonus to damage becomes a +3.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description></description>
                    <description level="6"></description>
                    <description level="14"></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Hardy" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSB_MORE_BINDING_HARDY">
                <supports>Reaper More Binding Capability</supports>
                <requirements>[level:reaper:10]</requirements>
                <description>
                    <p><b><i>Shoulders.</i></b> You must be 10th level or higher to take this capability. You gain advantage on checks to resist being stunned or poisoned.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Insightful" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSB_MORE_BINDING_INSIGHTFUL">
                <supports>Reaper More Binding Capability</supports>
                <description>
                    <p><b><i>Brow.</i></b> As a bonus action or reaction you can activate this to gain advantage on insight checks for 1 minute. You have 3 uses of this which recover on a short or long rest.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Advanced.</i></b> This now has 5 uses and lasts for 10 minutes.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Higher.</i></b> This now has 6 uses and lasts for 1 hour.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description></description>
                    <description level="6"></description>
                    <description level="14"></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Lunge" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSB_MORE_BINDING_LUNGE">
                <supports>Reaper More Binding Capability</supports>
                <description>
                    <p><b><i>Arms.</i></b> You must be 7th level or higher to take this capability. You can activate this as a bonus action to give your melee attacks an extra 5 feet of reach for 1 minute. You can use this capability 5 times before needing a long to regain uses.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Advanced.</i></b> This effect resets on a short or long rest.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Higher.</i></b> This effect is constant.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description></description>
                    <description level="6"></description>
                    <description level="14"></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Multiattack" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSB_MORE_BINDING_MULTIATTACK">
                <supports>Reaper More Binding Capability</supports>
                <requirements>[level:reaper:7]</requirements>
                <description>
                    <p><b><i>Arms.</i></b> This capability has no base effect.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Advanced.</i></b> You must be 7th level or higher to take this capability. You gain the ability to make a single melee attack as a bonus action. This attack uses your Strength or Dexterity ability scores as if the attack were made as an action. You do not need to make the attack action to use this capability.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description></description>
                    <description level="7"></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Observant" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSB_MORE_BINDING_OBSERVANT">
                <supports>Reaper More Binding Capability</supports>
                <description>
                    <p><b><i>Brow.</i></b> As a bonus action or reaction you can activate this to gain advantage on investigation checks for 1 minute. You have 3 uses of this which recover on a short or long rest.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Advanced.</i></b> This now has 5 uses and lasts for 10 minutes.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Higher.</i></b> This now has 6 uses and lasts for 1 hour.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description></description>
                    <description level="6"></description>
                    <description level="14"></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Perceptive" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSB_MORE_BINDING_PERCEPTIVE">
                <supports>Reaper More Binding Capability</supports>
                <description>
                    <p><b><i>Brow.</i></b> As a bonus action or reaction you can activate this to gain advantage on perception checks for 1 minute. You have 3 uses of this which recover on a short or long rest.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Advanced.</i></b> This now has 5 uses and lasts for 10 minutes.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Higher.</i></b> This now has 6 uses and lasts for 1 hour.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description></description>
                    <description level="6"></description>
                    <description level="14"></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Persuasive" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSB_MORE_BINDING_PERSUASIVE">
                <supports>Reaper More Binding Capability</supports>
                <description>
                    <p><b><i>Brow.</i></b> As a bonus action or reaction you can activate this to gain advantage on persuasion checks for 1 minute. You have 3 uses of this which recover on a short or long rest.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Advanced.</i></b> This now has 5 uses and lasts for 10 minutes.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Higher.</i></b> This now has 6 uses and lasts for 1 hour.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description></description>
                    <description level="6"></description>
                    <description level="14"></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Resilient" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSB_MORE_BINDING_RESILIENT">
                <supports>Reaper More Binding Capability</supports>
                <requirements>[level:reaper:7]</requirements>
                <description>
                    <p><b><i>Shoulders.</i></b> You must be 7th level or higher to take this capability. When a creature critically hits you this automatically triggers to cancel the critical. The hit still lands but is not critical. This happens once and recovers on a short or long rest.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Higher.</i></b> This capability can trigger twice before needing a short or long rest.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description></description>
                    <description level="14"></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Shrinking Armor" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSB_MORE_BINDING_SHRINKING_ARMOR">
                <supports>Reaper More Binding Capability</supports>
                <description>
                    <p><b><i>Heart.</i></b> When you activate this capability as a reaction your AC goes up by a value equal to your Proficiency Bonus. While you have this extra armor if an attack misses you but it would have hit you normally the amount of extra armor is reduced by 1. If an attack hits or would have missed your normal AC the extra armor is unaffected. This extra armor lasts until it wears away, you fall unconscious, you dispel it as a free action, or you take a short or long rest. You can use this ability once before needing a long rest to regain uses.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Advanced.</i></b> You can use this ability twice before needing a long rest.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Higher.</i></b> You can use this ability three times before needing a long rest.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description></description>
                    <description level="6"></description>
                    <description level="14"></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Skilled" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSB_MORE_BINDING_SKILLED">
                <supports>Reaper More Binding Capability</supports>
                <description>
                    <p><b><i>Head.</i></b> When you take this capability during a long rest pick a skill. You gain proficiency in that skill as long as you have this capability. This has no effect on skills you are already proficient in. In addition to skills you can also choose tools or a language to gain proficiency in. You must have already encountered the language to choose it from this feature.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Advanced.</i></b> If you choose a skill you are proficient in you gain double proficiency in that skill. This has no effect on skills you are already double proficient in.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Higher.</i></b> Choose a second skill for this capability to affect.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description></description>
                    <description level="6"></description>
                    <description level="14"></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Speed" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSB_MORE_BINDING_SPEED">
                <supports>Reaper More Binding Capability</supports>
                <description>
                    <p><b><i>Feet.</i></b> Your movement speed increases by 5 feet.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Advanced.</i></b> The movement speed increase becomes 10 feet.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Higher.</i></b> The movement speed increase becomes 15 feet.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description></description>
                    <description level="6"></description>
                    <description level="14"></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Stealthy" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSB_MORE_BINDING_STEALTHY">
                <supports>Reaper More Binding Capability</supports>
                <description>
                    <p><b><i>Waist.</i></b> As a bonus action or reaction you can activate this to gain advantage on stealth checks for 1 minute. You have 3 uses of this which recover on a short or long rest.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Advanced.</i></b> This now has 5 uses and lasts for 10 minutes.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Higher.</i></b> This now has 6 uses and lasts for 1 hour.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description></description>
                    <description level="6"></description>
                    <description level="14"></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Survivalist" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSB_MORE_BINDING_SURVIVALIST">
                <supports>Reaper More Binding Capability</supports>
                <description>
                    <p><b><i>Waist.</i></b> As a bonus action or reaction you can activate this to gain advantage on survival checks for 1 minute. You have 3 uses of this which recover on a short or long rest.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Advanced.</i></b> This now has 5 uses and lasts for 10 minutes.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Higher.</i></b> This now has 6 uses and lasts for 1 hour.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description></description>
                    <description level="6"></description>
                    <description level="14"></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Water Walking" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSB_MORE_BINDING_WATER_WALKING">
                <supports>Reaper More Binding Capability</supports>
                <requirements>[level:reaper:7]</requirements>
                <description>
                    <p><b><i>Feet.</i></b> You must be 7th level or higher to take this capability. You gain the ability to cast water walk as the spell. This can only affect you and lasts for 10 minutes. This can be used twice before needing a short or long rest.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Higher.</i></b> This capability has no limit on number of uses.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description></description>
                    <description level="14"></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>


    <element name="Rite of the Soul Burst" type="Archetype" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_REAPER_RITE_OF_THE_SOUL_BURST">
        <supports>Reaper Rite</supports>
        <description>
            <p></p>
            <p class="indent">Soul Bursts don’t care so much for making themselves better or stronger. They’re just there to kill monsters. Generally in very violent, messy ways. They destabilize the souls they Harvest and use them as bombs to kill monsters faster.</p>
            <div element="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSBURST_SOUL_BREAK" />
            <div element="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSBURST_DELAY_BURST" />
            <div element="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSBURST_CRATER_MAKER" />
            <div element="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSBURST_SHALLOW_GRAVE" />
            <div element="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSBURST_WALKING_BOMB" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSBURST_SOUL_BREAK" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSBURST_DELAY_BURST" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSBURST_CRATER_MAKER" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSBURST_SHALLOW_GRAVE" level="14" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSBURST_WALKING_BOMB" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Soul Break" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSBURST_SOUL_BREAK">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 2nd level you are able to detonate souls to deal damage on the battlefield. A soul must be Broken during a long rest before it can reliably explode in combat. Broken souls fit in a Reliquary like normal souls and still count against your maximum soul limit.</p>
            <p class="indent">Broken souls can not be used for any class ability not from this Rite, nor can a Broken soul be fixed and returned to normal. There is no limit on the number of Broken souls you can have or souls you can Break during a single rest aside from the maximum limit of souls you can have.</p>
            <p class="indent">Soul bombs are thrown weapons with a range of 30 feet and a blast radius of 20 feet. Each soul bomb is comprised of a single Broken soul and the soul is lost when the bomb goes off. When thrown everything in the radius must succeed a Dexterity save against your Ability DC or take 2d6 + your Proficiency Bonus in force damage. A successful save takes half damage.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Soul bombs: thrown weapons with a range of 30 feet and a blast radius of 20 feet. Each soul bomb is comprised of a single Broken soul and the soul is lost when the bomb goes off. When thrown everything in the radius must succeed a Dexterity save against your Ability DC or take 2d6 + {{proficiency}} in force damage. A successful save takes half damage.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Delay Burst" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSBURST_DELAY_BURST">
        <description>
            <p>Beginning at 6th level you are able to set and detonate your soul bombs as you wish. When you drop or throw a soul bomb you can choose to have it not go off. Dropping a soul bomb in your space is a bonus action.</p>
            <p class="indent">The soul will sit where you threw or dropped it for up to 1 minute, at which point it will detonate. You can detonate it early as bonus action. You must be within 60 feet of the soul bomb to remotely detonate it.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can also pick them back up and return them to their Reliquary, negating the timer. Soul bombs that are loose on the battlefield still count as occupying Reliquaries.</p>
            <p class="indent">Soul bombs on the ground are tiny ethereal blobs. You always know where they are and can find them effortlessly. Anyone else must succeed a Perception check against your Ability DC to find them. No one but you can disarm your own soul bombs but any fire or force damage done in the same space the soul bomb is in will instantly set it off.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you drop or throw a soul bomb you can choose to have it not go off. Dropping a soul bomb in your space is a bonus action. The soul will sit where you threw or dropped it for up to 1 minute, at which point it will detonate. You can detonate it early as bonus action. You must be within 60 feet of the soul bomb to remotely detonate it.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Crater Maker" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSBURST_CRATER_MAKER">
        <description>
            <p>At 10th level you are able to make bigger explosions by pooling your resources. As a bonus action you can add additional Broken souls to the soul bomb before throwing or dropping it. Each additional soul increases the damage by 1d6 and every 2 additional souls increases the blast radius by 10 feet and reduces the delay timer by 6 seconds.</p>
            <p class="indent">For example, a soul bomb with two Broken souls will deal 3d6+ your Proficiency Bonus in force damage and have a blast radius of 20 feet and a delay timer of 1 minute. A soul bomb with three Broken souls will deal 4d6+ your proficiency bonus in force damage and have a blast radius of 30 feet and a delay timer of 54 seconds (9 rounds).</p>
            <p class="indent">The thrown range of the soul bomb is unchanged by how many Broken souls are in it. A soul bomb can only have a number of Broken souls in it equal to half your level rounded down.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Bonus Action">
            <description>You can add additional Broken souls (maximum of {{level:reaper:half}}) to the soul bomb before throwing or dropping it. Each additional soul increases the damage by 1d6 and every 2 additional souls increases the blast radius by 10 feet and reduces the delay timer by 6 seconds.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Shallow Grave" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSBURST_SHALLOW_GRAVE">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 14th level you are able to take the souls of your victims. When a creature dies from one of your soul bombs you can use your reaction to call it into one of your open Reliquaries. A creature unable to fill a Reliquary from the Soul Capture ability is immune to this.</p>
            <p class="indent">The souls you gain through this ability are not Broken, and so can not immediately be used in soul bombs. You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum of once) before needing a long rest to regain uses.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Reaction" usage="{{shallow-grave:uses}}/Long Rest">
            <description>When a creature dies from one of your soul bombs you can call it into one of your open Reliquaries. A creature unable to fill a Reliquary from the Soul Capture ability is immune to this. The souls you gain through this ability are not Broken, and so can not immediately be used in soul bombs.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="shallow-grave:uses" value="1" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="shallow-grave:uses" value="charisma:modifier" bonus="base" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Walking Bomb" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSBURST_WALKING_BOMB">
        <description>
            <p>At 18th level, you are able to detonate a soul still in a living target. As an action you can expend a soul to target a single creature within 60 feet of you that you can see. The creature must succeed a Dexterity save against your Ability DC or take 18d6+40 force damage. They take half damage if they succeed.</p>
            <p class="indent">If the damage reduces the target to 0 or fewer hit points they explode, all non magical items they carry are destroyed and the magical items are scattered 20 feet around them along with what little remains of their body.</p>
            <p class="indent">If the target creature survived the effect all creatures within 20 feet of the target must succeed a Dexterity save or take half of the original damage. They take half again on a successful save.</p>
            <p class="indent">If the target creature died from the attack all creatures within 40 feet of the target must succeed a Dexterity save or take the full original damage. They take half on a successful save. Only the original target of the ability is destroyed if reduced to 0 or fewer hit points by the attack.</p>
            <p class="indent">A creature immune to Shallow Grave can not be the initial target of this ability, though it can still be a secondary target. The initial target of this ability can not be taken as part of Shallow Grave but any secondary creature can be. You can only use this ability once before needing a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>You can expend a soul to target a single creature within 60 feet of you that you can see. The creature must succeed a Dexterity save against your Ability DC or take 18d6+40 force damage. They take half damage if they succeed. If the damage reduces the target to 0 or fewer hit points they explode, all non magical items they carry are destroyed and the magical items are scattered 20 feet around them along with what little remains of their body.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Rite of the Soul Hunter" type="Archetype" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_REAPER_RITE_OF_THE_SOUL_HUNTER">
        <supports>Reaper Rite</supports>
        <description>
            <p></p>
            <p class="indent">Soul Hunters take the souls of their fallen enemies and use them to become stronger. Using the power of these souls they become better able to find and kill certain types of creatures, and so many decide to focus on certain creatures. But this is far from a requirement.</p>
            <div element="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSH_SOUL_TOTEM" />
            <div element="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSH_EMPOWER_TOTEM" />
            <div element="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSH_MULTIPLE_TOTEMS" />
            <div element="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSH_CHANNEL_TOTEM" />
            <div element="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSH_BECOME_TOTEM" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSH_SOUL_TOTEM" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSH_EMPOWER_TOTEM" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSH_MULTIPLE_TOTEMS" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSH_CHANNEL_TOTEM" level="14" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSH_BECOME_TOTEM" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Soul Totem" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSH_SOUL_TOTEM">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 2nd level you gain a specialized Reliquary called a Casket. The Casket can hold a single soul but unlike the Reliquaries it can not be filled as part of a Harvest. The soul that fills a Casket, called a Totem, must be taken at the moment the creature died. Creating a soul Totem is a free action if the creature died on your turn or takes a reaction if it died on someone else’s. The creature must be within 60 feet of you and within your line of sight for you to take its soul.</p>
                <p class="indent">If the target has a level or CR more than three below your level it will fill the Casket but will not become a Totem. Likewise, a creature immune to Soul Capture can not fill a Casket. After having a soul Totem for at least 1 minute it imparts a passive aspect on you and continues to do so until you expend the soul or release it from the Casket as a free action.</p>
                <p class="indent">You must be benefiting from the passive aspect to use any other feature of your soul Totem. The aspect the Totem grants is determined by the type of the creature the soul was taken from. Humanoids can not become Totems. The list of aspects is at the end of this Rite’s section.</p>
                <p class="indent">As an action you can expend a soul to trigger an active aspect of the soul Totem. There are two active aspects, Totem Burst and Totem Beam. They work the same for all aspects, the only difference being the damage type and which save the target is allowed for Totem Burst. You pick which type of active aspect you are using when you expend the soul.</p>
                <p class="indent">If you have no soul to expend you can expend the Totem to trigger the active aspect.</p>
                <div class="sidebar">
                    <h5 class="caption">POWERFUL SOULS</h5>
                    <p>Though there is no limit on how high a creature’s level or CR could be to make a Totem, feel free as a DM to impose restrictions. Remember that creatures immune to Soul Capture can’t become Totems, and you can simply say a particular soul is too strong to be contained.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Alternatively, you could allow the player to take the stronger soul but have it take the place of two Totems instead of one. Or maybe it leaks out of the Casket and influences the character’s thoughts and actions.</p>
                </div>
                <p>In addition to what is listed below every passive aspect grants advantage on survival checks made to track creatures of the type of the Totem as well as Intelligence checks to recall information about them. It also grants +2 damage against creatures of the Totem’s type.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Creating a soul Totem is a free action if the creature died on your turn or takes a reaction if it died on someone else’s. The creature must be CR {{soul-totem:cr}}, within 60 feet of you, and within your line of sight for you to take its soul. After having a soul Totem for at least 1 minute it imparts a passive aspect on you and continues to do so until you expend the soul or release it from the Casket as a free action. You have advantage on Survival checks to track any creature of the same type as the soul. The Soul Totem grants passive and active effects based on the creature type.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="soul-totem:cr" value="1/4" inline="true" level="2" />
                <stat name="soul-totem:cr" value="1/2" inline="true" level="3" />
                <stat name="soul-totem:cr" value="1" inline="true" level="4" />
                <stat name="soul-totem:cr" value="2" inline="true" level="5" />
                <stat name="soul-totem:cr" value="3" inline="true" level="6" />
                <stat name="soul-totem:cr" value="4" inline="true" level="7" />
                <stat name="soul-totem:cr" value="5" inline="true" level="8" />
                <stat name="soul-totem:cr" value="6" inline="true" level="9" />
                <stat name="soul-totem:cr" value="7" inline="true" level="10" />
                <stat name="soul-totem:cr" value="8" inline="true" level="11" />
                <stat name="soul-totem:cr" value="9" inline="true" level="12" />
                <stat name="soul-totem:cr" value="10" inline="true" level="13" />
                <stat name="soul-totem:cr" value="11" inline="true" level="14" />
                <stat name="soul-totem:cr" value="12" inline="true" level="15" />
                <stat name="soul-totem:cr" value="13" inline="true" level="16" />
                <stat name="soul-totem:cr" value="14" inline="true" level="17" />
                <stat name="soul-totem:cr" value="15" inline="true" level="18" />
                <stat name="soul-totem:cr" value="16" inline="true" level="19" />
                <stat name="soul-totem:cr" value="17" inline="true" level="20" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSH_SOUL_TOTEM_TOTEM_BURST" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSH_SOUL_TOTEM_TOTEM_BEAM" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Totem Burst" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSH_SOUL_TOTEM_TOTEM_BURST">
            <description>
                <p>This attack is a circle with a 10-foot radius centered on you. You do not take damage from the Totem Burst. The radius increases by 5 feet at 10th, 14th, and 18th level. All creatures excluding you within the circle must succeed a save against your Ability DC or take xd6 damage where x is twice your Proficiency Bonus. A successful save takes half damage.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>You expend your Soul Totem to create a burst with a {{totem-burst:range}}-foot radius centered on you. All creatures excluding you within the circle must succeed a save against your Ability DC or take {{totem-burst:damage-dice}}d6 force damage. A successful save takes half damage. You gain the active effect of the soul.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="totem-burst:range" value="10" level="2" />
                <stat name="totem-burst:range" value="5" level="10" />
                <stat name="totem-burst:range" value="5" level="14" />
                <stat name="totem-burst:range" value="5" level="18" />
                <stat name="totem-burst:damage-dice" value="proficiency" />
                <stat name="totem-burst:damage-dice" value="proficiency" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Totem Beam" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSH_SOUL_TOTEM_TOTEM_BEAM">
            <description>
                <p>This attack is against a single target within 20 feet. The range increases by 10 feet at 10th, 14th, and 18th level. You have proficiency and use your Charisma modifier for the attack. If it hits the target takes x+2d6 damage where x is twice your Proficiency Bonus.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You target a single creature within {{totem-beam:range}} feet (attack bonus +{{totem-beam:attack-bonus}}). If it hits the target takes 2d6 + {{totem-beam:damage}} force damage. You gain the active effect of the soul.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="totem-beam:range" value="20" level="2" />
                <stat name="totem-beam:range" value="10" level="10" />
                <stat name="totem-beam:range" value="10" level="14" />
                <stat name="totem-beam:range" value="10" level="18" />
                <stat name="totem-beam:damage" value="proficiency" />
                <stat name="totem-beam:damage" value="proficiency" />
                <stat name="totem-beam:attack-bonus" value="proficiency" />
                <stat name="totem-beam:attack-bonus" value="charisma:modifier" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Empower Totem" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSH_EMPOWER_TOTEM">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level you can make your Totem stronger. When triggering the active aspect of your Totem you can expend additional souls to increase the damage by 1d6 per soul.</p>
                <p class="indent">Active aspects can only have a number of souls equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum 1).</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When triggering the active aspect of your Totem you can expend additional souls to increase the damage by 1d6 per soul. Active aspects can only have {{empower-totem:active}} souls.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="empower-totem:active" value="1" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="empower-totem:active" value="charisma:modifier" bonus="base" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Multiple Totems" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSH_MULTIPLE_TOTEMS">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 10th level the capacity of your Casket increases. You can now have two Totems at once but can only benefit from one passive aspect at a time. It’s a bonus action to switch between the two Totems.</p>
                <p class="indent">At 14th you can have three Totems in you Casket at once, and benefit from two of their passive aspects. At 18th you can have a fourth Totem but still only benefit from two passive aspects at once. Swapping between which Totems are passive and which are inactive is still a bonus action, regardless of how many Totems you’re adjusting at once.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can now have two Totems at once but can only benefit from one passive aspect at a time. It’s a bonus action to switch between the two Totems.</description>
                <description level="14">You can have three Totems in your Casket at once, and benefit from two of their passive aspects. It’s a bonus action to switch between the three Totems.</description>
                <description level="18">You can have four Totems in your Casket at once, and benefit from two of their passive aspects. It’s a bonus action to switch between the four Totems.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Channel Totem" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSH_CHANNEL_TOTEM">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 14th level you can gain stronger influences from your Totem. As an action you can expend two souls to gain a single special feature or action of the creature whose soul is in your Totem. This can not be used to gain legendary actions. If the feature you gain requires a part of anatomy you lack, you grow it for the duration you have the future.</p>
                <p class="indent">The Totem can be channeled for 10 minutes and while it is all active aspects from that Totem deal an additional 2d6 damage. If you make the Totem you are channeling inactive the channeling ends immediately.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can only have one Totem channeled at a time, if you use it a second time while the first is still active the first ends immediately. You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum once) before needing a long rest.</p>
                <div class="sidebar">
                    <h5 class="caption">VARIABLE CHANNELS</h5>
                    <p>Some monster abilities can be devastating in the hands of a player, even for a short time. There are a few ways a DM could easily handle this. The first is to simply not allow the player to choose those abilities when channeling a Totem.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Another option is to decide, either on your own or alongside the player, on a single feature a specific Totem will grant every time it is channeled. Although this way removes some choice from the player in the moment, it has the benefit of likely reducing potential slowdown in combat.</p>
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="{{empower-totem:active}}/Long Rest">
                <description>You can expend two souls to gain a single special feature or action of the creature whose soul is in your Totem. This can not be used to gain legendary actions. If the feature you gain requires a part of anatomy you lack, you grow it for the duration you have the future. The Totem can be channeled for 10 minutes and while it is all active aspects from that Totem deal an additional 2d6 damage.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Become Totem" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSH_BECOME_TOTEM">
            <description>
                <p>At 18th level you are able to fully exploit the power of your Totems. As an action you can expend a soul and the Totem to cast the spell <i>true polymorph</i> on yourself. You must take the shape of the creature used to make the Totem and it cannot become permanent. You can use this feature once before needing a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You can expend a soul and the Totem to cast the spell true polymorph on yourself. You must take the shape of the creature used to make the Totem and it can not become permanent.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TRUE_POLYMORPH" />
            </rules>
        </element>

    <!-- Aspects-->
            <element name="Aberration" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSH_SOUL_TOTEM_ASPECT_ABERRATION">
                <supports>Reaper Soul Totem Aspect</supports>
                <description>
                    <p><b><i>Passive.</i></b> You gain proficiency on Intelligence saves.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Active.</i></b> The damage type is psychic and the save is Wisdom.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Beast" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSH_SOUL_TOTEM_ASPECT_BEAST">
                <supports>Reaper Soul Totem Aspect</supports>
                <description>
                    <p><b><i>Passive.</i></b> You gain proficiency on Dexterity saves.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Active.</i></b> The damage type is slashing and the save is Dexterity.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Celestial" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSH_SOUL_TOTEM_ASPECT_CELESTIAL">
                <supports>Reaper Soul Totem Aspect</supports>
                <description>
                    <p><b><i>Passive.</i></b> You gain resistance to radiant damage.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Active.</i></b> The damage type is radiant and the save is Wisdom.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Construct" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSH_SOUL_TOTEM_ASPECT_CONSTRUCT">
                <supports>Reaper Soul Totem Aspect</supports>
                <description>
                    <p><b><i>Passive.</i></b> You gain immunity to magical sleep effects.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Active.</i></b> The damage type is electric and the save is Dexterity.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Dragon" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSH_SOUL_TOTEM_ASPECT_DRAGON">
                <supports>Reaper Soul Totem Aspect</supports>
                <description>
                    <p><b><i>Passive.</i></b> You gain the ability to cast fly at 3rd level on yourself twice per long rest.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Active.</i></b> The damage type is the same as the breath weapon of the dragon the Totem was made from and the save is Dexterity.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Elemental" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSH_SOUL_TOTEM_ASPECT_ELEMENTAL">
                <supports>Reaper Soul Totem Aspect</supports>
                <description>
                    <p><b><i>Passive.</i></b> You gain resistance to the damage type associated with the elemental in the Totem.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Active.</i></b> The damage type is the same this Totem gave resistance to and the save is Dexterity.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Fey" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSH_SOUL_TOTEM_ASPECT_FEY">
                <supports>Reaper Soul Totem Aspect</supports>
                <description>
                    <p><b><i>Passive.</i></b> You gain proficiency on Wisdom saves.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Active.</i></b> The damage type is force and the save is Constitution.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Fiend" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSH_SOUL_TOTEM_ASPECT_FIEND">
                <supports>Reaper Soul Totem Aspect</supports>
                <description>
                    <p><b><i>Passive.</i></b> You gain advantage on saves against charm effects.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Active.</i></b> The damage type is fire and the save is Dexterity.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Giant" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSH_SOUL_TOTEM_ASPECT_GIANT">
                <supports>Reaper Soul Totem Aspect</supports>
                <description>
                    <p><b><i>Passive.</i></b> You gain proficiency on Strength saves.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Active.</i></b> The damage type is thundering and the save is Constitution.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Monstrosity" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSH_SOUL_TOTEM_ASPECT_MONSTROSITY">
                <supports>Reaper Soul Totem Aspect</supports>
                <description>
                    <p><b><i>Passive.</i></b> You gain an extra 5 feet of movement.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Active.</i></b> The damage type is piercing and the save is Dexterity.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Ooze" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSH_SOUL_TOTEM_ASPECT_OOZE">
                <supports>Reaper Soul Totem Aspect</supports>
                <description>
                    <p><b><i>Passive.</i></b> You gain advantage on grapple checks.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Active.</i></b> The damage type is acid and the save is Dexterity.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Plant" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSH_SOUL_TOTEM_ASPECT_PLANT">
                <supports>Reaper Soul Totem Aspect</supports>
                <description>
                    <p><b><i>Passive.</i></b> You gain resistance to poison damage.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Active.</i></b> The damage type is poison and the save is Dexterity.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Undead" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSH_SOUL_TOTEM_ASPECT_UNDEAD">
                <supports>Reaper Soul Totem Aspect</supports>
                <description>
                    <p><b><i>Passive.</i></b> You gain resistance to necrotic damage.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Active.</i></b> The damage type is necrotic and the save is Dexterity.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>


    <element name="Rite of the Soul Mage" type="Archetype" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_REAPER_RITE_OF_THE_SOUL_MAGE">
        <supports>Reaper Rite</supports>
        <description>
            <p></p>
            <p class="indent">The Soul Mage finds that the blend of magic and martial ability leans closer to magic. They generally don’t possess any magical aptitude of their own, and so use the souls they Harvest to fuel the spells they wish to cast. Their limited talent mean they learn less spells than a Wizard might, and as such focus on the schools of necromancy and enchantment.</p>
            <div element="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSM_SOUL_FRAGMENTS" />
            <div element="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSM_VIALS" />
            <div element="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSM_SPELLCASTING" />
            <div element="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSM_SPELLBLADE" />
            <div element="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSM_WAR_MAGIC" />
            <div element="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSM_INTERROGATION" />
            <div element="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSM_SOULBLADE" />
            <div element="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSM_HIGH_CAPACITY_MAGIC" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSM_SOUL_FRAGMENTS" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSM_VIALS" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSM_SPELLCASTING" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSM_SPELLBLADE" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSM_WAR_MAGIC" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSM_INTERROGATION" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSM_SOULBLADE" level="14" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSM_HIGH_CAPACITY_MAGIC" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Soul Fragments" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSM_SOUL_FRAGMENTS">
        <description>
            <p>Souls are too unwieldy to directly use in magic and must be made into Fragments. A single soul can be broken into two Fragments on a long rest.</p>
            <p class="indent">If you break a soul into Fragments but do not have a place to put one of the Fragments it is lost. Souls that were broken into Fragments can not be restored to full souls. Soul Fragments can not be used for any class feature other than casting spells.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>A single soul can be broken into two Fragments on a long rest.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Vials" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSM_VIALS">
        <description>
            <p>Only one Fragment can be in a Reliquary so to optimize space Soul Mages have Vials, which are smaller soul containers. A full soul can not fit into a Vial and each Vial can only hold a single soul Fragment. Aside from capacity, a Vial functions identically to a Reliquary. The number of Vials you can have is indicated on the Rite of the Soul Mage table.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You have {{soul-mage:vials}} soul vials. A full soul can not fit into a Vial and each Vial can only hold a single soul Fragment. Aside from capacity, a Vial functions identically to a Reliquary.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="soul-mage:vials" value="1" level="2" />
            <stat name="soul-mage:vials" value="2" level="7" />
            <stat name="soul-mage:vials" value="2" level="13" />
            <stat name="soul-mage:vials" value="2" level="19" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Spellcasting" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSM_SPELLCASTING">
        <description>
            <p>When you reach 2nd level you gain the ability to cast spells. See chapter 10 of the Players Handbook for the full rules on casting magic. The spells you have access to are from the Wizard spell list.</p>
            <p class="indent">Your Reliquaries function as casting focuses, so as long as you have one in your possession you can cast as if you have a spell focus. Even though you are using soul Fragments to fuel spells, you still must meet material component requirements.</p>
            <h5>CANTRIPS</h5>
            <p>You learn two cantrips of your choice from the Wizard spell list. You learn an additional Wizard cantrip of your choice at 10th level.</p>
            <h5>RITE OF THE SOUL MAGE</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td class="col-5">Level</td><td class="col-5">Cantrips</td><td class="col-10">Spells Known</td><td class="col-10">Max Spell Level</td><td class="col-5">Vials</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>2nd</td><td>2</td><td>3</td><td>1</td><td>1</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3rd</td><td>2</td><td>3</td><td>1</td><td>1</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4th</td><td>2</td><td>4</td><td>1</td><td>1</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5th</td><td>2</td><td>4</td><td>1</td><td>1</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6th</td><td>2</td><td>5</td><td>1</td><td>1</td></tr>
                <tr><td>7th</td><td>2</td><td>5</td><td>2</td><td>3</td></tr>
                <tr><td>8th</td><td>2</td><td>6</td><td>2</td><td>3</td></tr>
                <tr><td>9th</td><td>2</td><td>6</td><td>2</td><td>3</td></tr>
                <tr><td>10th</td><td>3</td><td>7</td><td>2</td><td>3</td></tr>
                <tr><td>11th</td><td>3</td><td>7</td><td>2</td><td>3</td></tr>
                <tr><td>12th</td><td>3</td><td>8</td><td>2</td><td>3</td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td>3</td><td>8</td><td>3</td><td>5</td></tr>
                <tr><td>14th</td><td>3</td><td>9</td><td>3</td><td>5</td></tr>
                <tr><td>15th</td><td>3</td><td>9</td><td>3</td><td>5</td></tr>
                <tr><td>16th</td><td>3</td><td>10</td><td>3</td><td>5</td></tr>
                <tr><td>17th</td><td>3</td><td>10</td><td>3</td><td>5</td></tr>
                <tr><td>18th</td><td>3</td><td>11</td><td>3</td><td>5</td></tr>
                <tr><td>19th</td><td>3</td><td>11</td><td>4</td><td>7</td></tr>
                <tr><td>20th</td><td>3</td><td>12</td><td>4</td><td>7</td></tr>
            </table>
            <h5>SPELLS KNOWN OF 1ST-LEVEL AND HIGHER</h5>
            <p>You know three 1st level Wizard spells of your choice, two of which you must choose from the necromancy or enchantment spells on the Wizard spell list. The spell level column of the Rite of the Soul Mage table shows the maximum spell level you can know or cast per level. To cast a spell you must expend a number of soul Fragments equal to the spells level.</p>
            <p class="indent">The Spells Known column of the Rite of the Soul Mage table shows when you learn more Wizard spells of 1st level or higher. Each of these spells must be a necromancy or enchantment spell of your choice and must not exceed your maximum spell level. For instance, when you reach 7th level in this c1ass, you can learn one new spell of 1st or 2nd level. The spells you learn at 8th, 14th, and 20th level can come from any school of magic.</p>
            <p class="indent">Whenever you gain a level in this c1ass you can replace one of the Wizard spells you know with another spell of your choice from the Wizard spell list. The new spell must not exceed your maximum spell level and it must be a necromancy or enchantment spell, unless you’re replacing the spell you gained at 8th, 14th, or 20th level.</p>
            <h5>SPELLCASTING ABILITY</h5>
            <p>Charisma is your spellcasting ability for your Wizard spells, since you cast them through your command of souls. You use your Charisma whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Charisma modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a Wizard spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.</p>
            <p style="text-align: center"><strong>Spell save DC</strong> = 8 + your Proficiency Bonus + your Charisma modifier</p>
            <p style="text-align: center"><strong>Spell attack modifier</strong> = your Proficiency Bonus + your Charisma modifier</p>
        </description>
        <spellcasting name="Soul Mage" ability="Charisma" prepare="false" allowReplace="true">
            <list>Wizard,(Necromancy||Enchantment)</list>
        </spellcasting>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Soul Mage)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),0" spellcasting="Soul Mage" number="2" level="2" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Soul Mage)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),0" spellcasting="Soul Mage"  level="10" />
            <stat name="soul mage:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="2" />
            <stat name="soul mage:spellcasting:slots:1" value="-1" level="7" />
            <stat name="soul mage:spellcasting:slots:2" value="3" level="7" />
            <stat name="soul mage:spellcasting:slots:2" value="-3" level="13" />
            <stat name="soul mage:spellcasting:slots:3" value="5" level="13" />
            <stat name="soul mage:spellcasting:slots:3" value="-5" level="19" />
            <stat name="soul mage:spellcasting:slots:4" value="7" level="19" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Soul Mage)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" number="2" level="2" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Soul Mage)" supports="Wizard,$(spellcasting:slots)" level="2" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Soul Mage)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="4" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Soul Mage)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="6" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Soul Mage)" supports="Wizard,$(spellcasting:slots)" level="8" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Soul Mage)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="10" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Soul Mage)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="12" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Soul Mage)" supports="Wizard,$(spellcasting:slots)" level="14" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Soul Mage)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="16" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Soul Mage)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="18" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Soul Mage)" supports="Wizard,$(spellcasting:slots)" level="20" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Spellblade" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSM_SPELLBLADE">
        <description>
            <p>At 2nd level you are able to control a weapon with nothing more than magic. As a bonus action you can make a single weapon float and attack at your command. The weapons movement is 30 feet and uses your spell attack modifier to attack and gains your Charisma modifier on damage.</p>
            <p class="indent">It is a bonus action to command the weapon to move and make a single attack against a target within 5 feet of it. Reach weapons must still be within 5 feet of a creature to attack and range weapons can not be controlled by this feature.</p>
            <p class="indent">The Spellblade remains animated for 1 minute after which it immediately tries to return to you. The weapon can only move 60 feet to return to you. If it reaches you and you have a hand open, it flies into your hand. If you don’t have a hand open it falls to your feet. If the weapon files 60 feet and does not reach you it drops to the ground.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Bonus Action">
            <description>You can make a single melee weapon float and attack at your command. The weapons movement is 30 feet and +{{spellcasting:attack}} to attack and +{{charisma:modifier}} damage. It is a bonus action to command the weapon to move and make a single attack against a target within 5 feet of it. The Spellblade remains animated for 1 minute after which it immediately tries to return to you. The weapon can only move 60 feet to return to you. If it reaches you and you have a hand open, it flies into your hand. If you don’t have a hand open it falls to your feet. If the weapon files 60 feet and does not reach you it drops to the ground.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="War Magic" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSM_WAR_MAGIC">
        <description>
            <p>Beginning at 6th level when you use your action to cast a cantrip you can make one weapon attack as a bonus action. This bonus action attack can be made with your Spellblade or Soulblade.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you use your action to cast a cantrip you can make one weapon attack as a bonus action. This bonus action attack can be made with your Spellblade or Soulblade.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Interrogation" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSM_INTERROGATION">
        <description>
            <p>Beginning at 10th level you are able to use your knowledge of necromancy to communicate with souls you have Harvested. Souls used for this are not expended and can not be Fragments. Starting the Interrogation takes 1 minute and allows you to ask 3 questions of your souls.</p>
            <p class="indent">Souls only know about the areas they lived in or rested in before being Harvested. If the soul was intelligent in life (DM discretion) it could provide more information depending on what it once was. You can do this twice before needing a long rest to regain uses.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You are able to communicate with souls you have Harvested. Souls used for this are not expended and can not be Fragments. Starting the Interrogation takes 1 minute and allows you to ask 3 questions of your souls.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Soulblade" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSM_SOULBLADE">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 14th level as a bonus action you can expend a soul to make a second Spellblade. This can be the same bonus action you make the first Spellblade in. You control both the Spellblade and Soulblade as a bonus action and can move both of them as part of the same bonus action, but only one can attack. The Soulblade functions in all ways like the Spellblade.</p>
            <p class="indent">You could if you wish, control the Soulblade as your action and your Spellblade as a bonus action, allowing you to move and attack with each. If you control the Soulblade as an action you cannot move it as part of the bonus action that round.</p>
            <p class="indent">You do not need to have a Spellblade active to make a Soulblade. You can not have two Soulblades at one time.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Bonus Action">
            <description>You can expend a soul to make a second Spellblade. This can be the same bonus action you make the first Spellblade in. You control both the Spellblade and Soulblade as a bonus action and can move both of them as part of the same bonus action, but only one can attack.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="High Capacity Magic" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTSM_HIGH_CAPACITY_MAGIC">
        <description>
            <p>At 18th level you can use full souls in casting your spells. Using a full soul acts like two soul fragments and you take 1d6 psychic damage from the strain.</p>
            <p class="indent">This feature can be used twice before you must take a short or long rest to regain uses of it.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="2/Short Rest">
            <description>You can use full souls in casting your spells. Using a full soul acts like two soul fragments and you take 1d6 psychic damage from the strain.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Rite of the Soul Tamer" type="Archetype" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_REAPER_RITE_OF_THE_SOUL_TAMER">
        <supports>Reaper Rite</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Soul Tamers are never alone. Not really. They’ve learned how to take multiples souls and merge them together into a single entity. These entities are faithful companions of the Soul Tamer and aid them in all things in and out of combat.</p>
            <div element="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTST_SOUL_PUPPET" />
            <div element="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTST_HIGHER_SOULS" />
            <div element="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTST_SECOND_PUPPET" />
            <div element="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTST_ENHANCED_PUPPET" />
            <div element="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTST_SOUL_CORE" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTST_SOUL_PUPPET" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTST_HIGHER_SOULS" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTST_SECOND_PUPPET" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTST_ENHANCED_PUPPET" level="14" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTST_SOUL_CORE" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Soul Puppet" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTST_SOUL_PUPPET">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 2nd level you gain the ability to merge two or more souls together to create a single entity under your control. When you get this feature you can only merge two souls together but you can add more souls at later levels. The stat block below shows what the basic Soul Puppet starts with when it only has two souls. You can only add, remove, or adjust souls in a Soul Puppet during a long rest. You can only have one Soul Puppet at a time.</p>
            <p class="indent">The Soul Puppet does not get stronger as you do but instead you must put more souls into it to give it better traits. Each additional soul adds 1 trait, and the full list of traits is at the end of the Rite’s description. At 3rd level a Soul Puppet can only have 1 trait. Its trait maximum goes up by 1 each time you gain a level in this class. Unless otherwise stated a Soul Puppet can only benefit from a trait once.</p>
            <p class="indent">It takes a bonus action to summon your Soul Puppet and it remains for 1 hour though you can dismiss it early as a free action on your turn. When summoned it appears in an unoccupied space you can see within 10 feet of you. You can summon your Soul Puppet a number of times equal to half your level rounded down. You regain all expended summons during a short or long rest.</p>
            <p class="indent">If the Soul Puppet’s hit points is reduced to 0 or lower it is instantly dismissed and must make a single death saving throw. If it fails the death save it looses one of its souls and traits. Whether or not the Soul Puppet succeeds or fails the save you must wait at least 1 minute to summon it again.</p>
            <p class="indent">The Soul Puppet can be healed through spells but potions have no effect on it. As an action you can expend a soul into the Soul Puppet, healing it by an amount equal to a quarter of its maximum hit points.</p>
            <p class="indent">The Soul Puppet acts on your turn. As your bonus action you can command it, allowing it an action, bonus action, and move. The Soul Puppet does not get any actions in the round it was summoned.</p>
            <p class="indent">If the Soul Puppet ever leaves your sight you loose command of it. If it was recently given a command it will continue to follow the orders until its time expires, you gain sight and control of it again, it is reduced to 0 or fewer hit points, or it is no longer able to complete the task. If the Soul Puppet has no orders when you lose sight of it or it completed the command it will go inert. If it is in the air it will land immediately.</p>
            <p class="indent">A Soul Puppet is an amorphous form that floats a few feet above the ground. The Soul Puppet is unable to equip or use any items and its size is determined by how many souls compromise it. From 2 to 5 souls it is small, from 6 to 15 souls it is medium, and from 16 to 20 souls it is large.</p>
            <p class="indent">The Soul Puppet’s Proficiency Bonus goes to its AC and damage as well as where it normally would. Souls in your Soul Puppet are still considered to occupy Reliquaries.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="level:reaper:half/Short Rest">
            <description>You can summon your Soul Puppet for up to 1 hour. You can combine two souls to make a Soul Puppet during a long rest.</description>
            <description level="3">You can summon your Soul Puppet for up to 1 hour. You can combine two souls to make a Soul Puppet during a long rest. You can add up to {{soul-puppet:extra-souls}} extra souls to your Soul Puppet to add a trait from the list for each additional soul.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="soul-puppet:extra-souls" value="level:reapre" level="3" />
            <stat name="soul-puppet:extra-souls" value="-2" level="3" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Higher Souls" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTST_HIGHER_SOULS">
        <description>
            <p>At 6th level you are able to give your Soul Puppet High traits. High traits cost 1 soul like basic traits. At 6th level the Soul Puppet can only have 1 High trait. At 12th level it can have 2 and at 18th level it can have 3. A Soul Puppet can only benefit from a High trait once.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You are able to give your Soul Puppet up to {{higher-souls:traits}} High traits. High traits cost 1 soul like basic traits.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="higher-souls:traits" value="1" level="6" />
            <stat name="higher-souls:traits" value="1" level="12" />
            <stat name="higher-souls:traits" value="1" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Second Puppet" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTST_SECOND_PUPPET">
        <description>
            <p>At 10th level you can have two Soul Puppets at once. One Puppet becomes your Primary Soul Puppet while the other becomes the Secondary. Treat your level as half of what it is rounded up when determining the soul limit and traits the Secondary Soul Puppet can have. The Secondary Soul Puppet functions like the Primary in all way except those listed here:</p>
            <ol>
                <li>It takes 10 minutes to adjust its traits.</li>
                <li>It can be dismissed as a free action even if it isn’t your turn.</li>
                <li>If it is reduced to 0 or fewer hit points it automatically fails its single death save.</li>
            </ol>
            <p class="indent">You can only have one Secondary Soul Puppet summoned at once. You can have a Secondary and Primary active at once. Both act on your bonus action, but share actions. This means that the Primary and Secondary Soul Puppets only have a single action, bonus action, and move between them. Which Soul Puppet takes which action is up to you when commanding them.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can have two Soul Puppets at once. One Puppet becomes your Primary Soul Puppet while the other becomes the Secondary. Your Secondary Puppet can have {{second-puppet:extra-souls}} extra souls added for traits. </description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="second-puppet:extra-souls" value="level:reaper:half:up" level="10" />
            <stat name="second-puppet:extra-souls" value="-2" level="10" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Enhanced Puppet" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTST_ENHANCED_PUPPET">
        <description>
            <p>At 14th level you can combine your Soul Puppets into a single entity. Doing so requires an action when both a Primary and Secondary Soul Puppet are active. The Soul Puppets need to be within 30 feet of you and each other. The Enhanced Soul Puppet will appear in the space either the Primary or Secondary Soul Puppet previously occupied.</p>
            <p class="indent">The Enhanced Soul Puppet lasts for 1 minute and has the combined traits of both the Primary and Secondary Soul Puppets, even if the resulting number exceeds the normal limit for a certain trait. These traits are placed onto the base stats of the Primary Soul Puppet. When created the Enhanced Soul Puppet is at full hit points, even if the Puppets that made it were not.</p>
            <p class="indent">After the minute ends the Enhanced Soul Puppet reverts to the Primary Soul Puppet while the Secondary Soul Puppet is dismissed. The Primary Soul Puppet’s hit points after the Enhanced form ends returns to it was before the merger.</p>
            <p class="indent">If the Enhanced Soul Puppet is reduced to 0 or fewer hit points it instantly reverts to the Primary Soul Puppet, and the Secondary Soul Puppet is dismissed. No souls are lost, but any damage the Enhanced Soul Puppet took that put it past 0 is taken by the Primary Soul Puppet. For example, if the Enhanced Soul Puppet has 5 hit points and takes 8 damage it reverts to the Primary Soul Puppet, which takes 3 damage.</p>
            <p class="indent">The Enhanced form can’t be dispelled early. You can only form an Enhanced Soul Puppet twice and must take a long rest to regain uses of this feature.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Action" usage="2/Long Rest">
            <description>You can combine your Soul Puppets into a single entity. The Soul Puppets need to be active and within 30 feet of you and each other.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Soul Core" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTST_SOUL_CORE">
        <description>
            <p>At 18th level you can make a Soul Core. This is a specialized Reliquary for your Primary Soul Puppet. The Soul Core allows the Primary Soul Puppet to always be summoned. It also reduced the chance of a soul being lost when the Soul Puppet is reduced to 0 or fewer hit points. When you make the death save, instead of a failure on a 1-10, it is a failure on a 1-5.</p>
            <p class="indent">With a Soul Core you can immediately resummon your Primary Soul Puppet after its defeat but it will return with 1 hit points. If you wait an hour or more it will return at half hit points. If you wait until after a long rest it will be at full health.</p>
            <p class="indent">The Soul Core allows the Primary Soul Puppet to heal on its own when resting. During a short rest, if at less than half its maximum hit points, the Primary Soul Puppet will heal to half its max hit points. During a long rest it will heal to full hit points.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can still dismiss the Primary Soul Puppet as a free action on your turn but it will heal at the same rate while dismissed as when summoned.</p>
            <p class="indent">The Soul Core, as a specialized Reliquary, is able to house souls properly. Specifically, it houses the two souls needed to form the base of a Soul Puppet. Since these souls are in the Soul Core they don’t take up space in the normal Reliquaries and no longer count against your maximum allotment.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>With a Soul Core you can immediately resummon your Primary Soul Puppet after its defeat but it will return with 1 hit points. If you wait an hour or more it will return at half hit points. If you wait until after a long rest it will be at full health.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>

    <!-- Traits -->
    <element name="Ability" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTST_SOUL_PUPPET_TRAIT_ABILITY">
        <description>
            <p><b><i>Higher.</i></b> You can increase any single Ability score by 2, or two Ability scores by one for your Soul Puppet. A single Ability score can not exceed 20.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Attack Type" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTST_SOUL_PUPPET_TRAIT_ATTACK_TYPE">
        <description>
            <p><b><i>Basic.</i></b> Choose bludgeoning or piercing, your Soul Puppet’s attacks now deal damage of this type.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Beast Form" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTST_SOUL_PUPPET_TRAIT_BEAST_FORM">
        <description>
            <p><b><i>Basic.</i></b> Choose a Beast. Your Soul Puppet takes the shape of a member of that species. This only affects its shape, not size or features.</p>
            <p class="indent">The Beast you chose must have all modes of movement your Soul Puppet has. If the Soul Puppet can fly you can not choose a Beast that is incapable of flight.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Elemental" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTST_SOUL_PUPPET_TRAIT_ELEMENTAL">
        <description>
            <p><b><i>Higher.</i></b> Choose a type from fire, cold, acid, lighting, thunder, or poison. All the Soul Puppet’s attacks deal damage of that type. The Soul Puppet also gains resistance to that type of damage.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Grapple" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTST_SOUL_PUPPET_TRAIT_GRAPPLE">
        <description>
            <p><b><i>Basic.</i></b> When the Soul Puppet lands a melee attack it can immediately attempt a grapple as a free action.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Health" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTST_SOUL_PUPPET_TRAIT_HEALTH">
        <description>
            <p><b><i>Basic.</i></b> The Soul Puppet gains an additional Hit Die. There is no limit to how many times a Soul Puppet can have this trait.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Healthy" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTST_SOUL_PUPPET_TRAIT_HEALTHY">
        <description>
            <p><b><i>Higher.</i></b> The Soul Puppet’s Hit Die increases to a d10.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Link" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTST_SOUL_PUPPET_TRAIT_LINK">
        <description>
            <p><b><i>Basic.</i></b> You become passively away of what the Soul Puppet can see and hear. As an action you are able to focus on the Soul Puppet’s senses, seeing and hearing what it does as clearly as you normally see and hear. You can stay in this state as long as you wish, but are blind and deaf to your own surroundings while you are.</p>
            <p class="indent">While in this link you are able to command the Soul Puppet out to a range of 100 feet before loosing control of it. It is a free action on your turn to end the effects of seeing through the Soul Puppet.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Long Arms" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTST_SOUL_PUPPET_TRAIT_LONG_ARMS">
        <description>
            <p><b><i>Basic.</i></b> The range of the Soul Puppet’s melee attacks increases by 5 feet.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Mobility" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTST_SOUL_PUPPET_TRAIT_MOBILITY">
        <description>
            <p><b><i>Higher.</i></b> Choose a type of movement the Soul Puppet doesn’t have, such as flying or swimming. The Soul Puppet gains that movement type at its normal movement speed. A Soul Puppet can have this trait multiple times, each time it grants a different mode of movement.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Movement" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTST_SOUL_PUPPET_TRAIT_MOVEMENT">
        <description>
            <p><b><i>Basic.</i></b> Increase the Soul Puppet’s movement by 10 feet.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Multiattack" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTST_SOUL_PUPPET_TRAIT_MULTIATTACK">
        <description>
            <p><b><i>Higher.</i></b> When the Soul Puppet takes the attack action it can attack twice instead of once.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Proficiency" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTST_SOUL_PUPPET_TRAIT_PROFICIENCY">
        <description>
            <p><b><i>Basic.</i></b> The Soul Puppet’s proficiency bonus goes up by 1. This trait can be taken once for every point your Proficiency Bonus is above 2.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Range" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTST_SOUL_PUPPET_TRAIT_RANGE">
        <description>
            <p><b><i>Basic.</i></b> As an action The Soul Puppet can make a single attack at a range of 30 feet. It needs line of sight and line of effect to do this.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Trip" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTST_SOUL_PUPPET_TRAIT_TRIP">
        <description>
            <p><b><i>Basic.</i></b> When the Soul Puppet lands a melee attack it can immediately attempt to knock the target prone as a bonus action. The Target must succeed a Dexterity save against the Soul Puppet’s ability DC or be knocked prone.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="The Grimm" type="Archetype" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_REAPER_THE_GRIMM">
        <supports>Reaper Rite</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The Grimm are Reapers that have forsaken their hunt of monsters. Perhaps they grew tired of hunting monstrous beasts or maybe they were horrified after learning of the darkness within some humanoids. Whatever the cause, The Grimm have strayed from the path and instead focus their arts on the people they once protected.</p>
            <div element="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_GRIMM_HUMANOID_TOTEM" />
            <div element="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_GRIMM_NECROTIC_BLADE" />
            <div element="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_GRIMM_UNDEAD_MINIONS" />
            <div element="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_GRIMM_DARK_STRIKE" />
            <div element="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_GRIMM_SOUL_PULSE" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_GRIMM_HUMANOID_TOTEM" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_GRIMM_NECROTIC_BLADE" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_GRIMM_UNDEAD_MINIONS" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_GRIMM_DARK_STRIKE" level="14" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_GRIMM_SOUL_PULSE" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Humanoid Totem" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_GRIMM_HUMANOID_TOTEM">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 2nd level you gain a specialized Reliquary called a Casket. The Casket can hold a single soul, but unlike the Reliquaries it can not be filled as part of a Harvest. The soul that fills a Casket, called a Totem, must be from a Humanoid and taken at the moment it died.</p>
            <p class="indent">Creating a soul Totem is a free action if the creature died on your turn or takes a reaction if it died on someone else’s. The Humanoid must be within 60 feet of you and within your line of sight for you to take its soul.</p>
            <p class="indent">If the target has a level or CR more than three below your level it will fill the Casket but will not become a Totem. Likewise, a creature immune to Soul Capture can not fill a Casket. After having a soul Totem for at least 1 minute it imparts a passive aspect on you and continues to do so until you expend the soul or release it from the Casket as a free action.</p>
            <p class="indent">The passive aspect of the Totem gives you advantage on a single attack made each round as long as the target is a Humanoid. As an action you can expend the soul in the Totem to trigger one of its two active aspects; Totem Burst or Totem Beam. You pick which active aspect you are using when you expend the soul.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">TOTEM BURST</h5>
            <p class="indent">This attack is a circle with a 10-foot radius centered on you. You do not take damage from the Totem Burst. The radius increases by 5 feet at 10th, 14th, and 18th level. All creatures excluding you within the circle must succeed a Dexterity save against your Ability DC or take xd6 necrotic damage where x is twice your Proficiency Bonus. A successful save takes half damage.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">TOTEM BEAM</h5>
            <p class="indent">This attack is against a single target within 20 feet. The range increases by 10 feet at 10th, 14th, and 18th level. You have proficiency and use your Charisma modifier for the attack. If it hits the target takes x+2d6 necrotic damage where x is twice your Proficiency Bonus.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Necrotic Blade" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_GRIMM_NECROTIC_BLADE">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 6th level you can defile your weapon to make it more potent against your chosen targets. As a bonus action you can expend a soul to grant a single melee weapon an extra 1d6 necrotic damage against Humanoids. A Necrotic Blade lasts for 1 minute or until it leaves your hand or you fall unconscious.</p>
            <p class="indent">At 10th level the bonus damage increases to 2d6 against Humanoids and 1d6 against all other targets.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Undead Minions" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_GRIMM_UNDEAD_MINIONS">
        <description>
            <p>Beginning at 10th level you can cast animate dead as the spell. You must expend a soul as part of the 1 minute cast. At 13th level you can expend two souls to cast it as a 4th level spell and at 17th level you expend three souls to cast it as a 5th level spell.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Dark Strike" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_GRIMM_DARK_STRIKE">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 14th level when attacking with your Necrotic Blade you can make three attacks as part of the Attack action instead of two.</p>
            <p class="indent">Also, when you hit a creature with your Necrotic Blade you can expend a soul to attempt to poison them. The creature must succeed a Constitution save or be poisoned for 1d6 rounds.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Soul Pulse" type="Archetype Feature" source="Spirit Magic" id="ID_DZ_SMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_GRIMM_SOUL_PULSE">
        <description>
            <p>At 18th level you can create an explosion of necrotic energy. As an action you can expend two souls to set off a Soul Pulse with a radius of 20 feet and a range of 150 feet. All creatures in the area must succeed a Charisma save or take 12d6 necrotic damage. They take half damage on a successful save. Humanoids have disadvantage on the save. This ability can only be used twice before needing a long rest to regain uses of it.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>

  <!-- Reaper Skills -->
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ACROBATICS">
        <supports>Reaper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ATHLETICS">
        <supports>Reaper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_HISTORY">
        <supports>Reaper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT">
        <supports>Reaper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INVESTIGATION">
        <supports>Reaper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_NATURE">
        <supports>Reaper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION">
        <supports>Reaper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_STEALTH">
        <supports>Reaper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SURVIVAL">
        <supports>Reaper</supports>
    </append>

  <!-- Reaper Fighting Styles -->
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_ARCHERY">
        <supports>Reaper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_DEFENSE">
        <supports>Reaper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_DUELING">
        <supports>Reaper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_GREAT_WEAPON_FIGHTING">
        <supports>Reaper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_TWOWEAPON_FIGHTING">
        <supports>Reaper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_MARINER">
        <supports>Reaper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_UA2015_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_CLOSE_QUARTERS_SHOOTER">
        <supports>Reaper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTING_STYLE_BLIND_FIGHTING">
        <supports>Reaper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTING_STYLE_THROWN_WEAPON_FIGHTING">
        <supports>Reaper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTING_STYLE_UNARMED_FIGHTING">
        <supports>Reaper</supports>
    </append>

</elements>