<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Spirit Magic 2.2.2</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="source.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/spirit-magic/source.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Spirit Magic" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_DELZAN_RDDTUA_SOURCE_Spirit Magic">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p>Spirit Magic is not the oldest method of magic in the world but it is an ancient art. It takes little time to learn but decent effort to control properly. And the power it grants is far more than what could otherwise be brought to the battlefield in days long gone by.</p><p class="indent">It is for this reason that people studied and mastered it, not for war against their fellows but to use against monsters. Two humanoids could be an even enough match but a humanoid against a monster was tipped far in the monster’s favor. Spirit Magic was not developed for this purpose but it was quickly adopted by those who would use it for such. These people became known as Reapers because of how they would use the souls of the dead to kill monsters.</p><p class="indent">For years upon decades upon centuries the Reapers used and refined Spirit Magic in their hunt of monsters. In the same time the rest of the world further expanded other ancient magics, developed new ones, and even found different, easier ways to bring a humanoid up to the challenge of a monster.</p><p class="indent">This rise of others able to fight monsters may have led to a decline of Reapers but Spirit Magic still remains in the world. The Reapers are not entirely gone and the ways of Spirit Magic have spread to others.</p><div class="sidebar"><h5 class="caption">Does Everything Have a Soul?</h5><p>Although the term soul is used in this document it is not only souls that Spirit Magic harnesses. It could simply be the life force like in Beasts, or the magic that allows the thing to move like in Constructs.</p><p class="indent">All creatures have something within them unless their soul is under some sort of protection (such as a phylactery) or otherwise specified by the DM.</p></div>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation">SMC</set>
            <set name="url">https://drive.google.com/file/d/1fUj9B2IXvIl-jafCbLc7v0Arq_VFHaw0/view?usp=sharing</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" abbreviation="DZ" url="https://www.reddit.com/user/Delzan/">u/Delzan</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20200728</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
</elements>