<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Eldritch Arcana Warlock</name>
        <update version="0.0.2">
            <file name="class-warlock.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/user/gm-binder-devikyn/eldritch-arcana/class-warlock.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>

<!-- Base Warlock Class-->    
    <element name="Warlock" type="Class" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_WARLOCK">
        <description>
            <p>With a pseudodragon curled on his shoulder, a young elf in golden robes smiles warmly, weaving a magical charm into his honeyed words and bending the palace sentinel to his will.</p>
            <p class="indent">As flames spring to life in her hands, a wizened human whispers the secret name of her demonic patron. infusing her spell with fiendish magic. Shifting his gaze between a battered tome and the odd alignment of the stars overhead, a wild-eyed tiefling chants the mystic ritual that will open a doorway to a distant world.</p>
            <p class="indent">Warlocks are seekers of the knowledge that lies hidden in the fabric of the multiverse. Through pacts made with mysterious beings of supernatural power, warlocks unlock magical effects both subtle and spectacular. Drawing on the ancient knowledge of beings such as fey nobles, demons, devils, hags, and alien entities of the Far Realm, warlocks piece together arcane secrets to bolster their own power.</p>
            <h4>SWORN AND BEHOLDEN</h4>
            <p>A warlock is defined by a pact with an otherworldly being. Sometimes the relationship between warlock and patron is like that of a cleric and a deity, though the beings that serve as patrons for warlocks are not gods. A warlock might lead a cult dedicated to a demon prince, an archdevil, or an utterly alien entity—beings not typically served by clerics. More often, though, the arrangement is similar to that between a master and an apprentice. The warlock learns and grows in power, at the cost of occasional services performed on the patron’s behalf.</p>
            <p class="indent">The magic bestowed on a warlock ranges from minor but lasting alterations to the warlock’s being (such as the ability to see in darkness or to read any language) to access to powerful spells. Unlike bookish wizards, warlocks supplement their magic with some facility at hand-to-hand combat. They are comfortable in light armor and know how to use simple weapons.</p>
            <h4>DELVERS INTO SECRETS</h4>
            <p>Warlocks are driven by an insatiable need for knowledge and power, which compels them into their pacts and shapes their lives. This thirst drives warlocks into their pacts and shapes their later careers as well.</p>
            <p class="indent">Stories of warlocks binding themselves to fiends are widely known. But many warlocks serve patrons that are not fiendish. Sometimes a traveler in the wilds comes to a strangely beautiful tower, meets its fey lord or lady, and stumbles into a pact without being fully aware of it. And sometimes, while poring over tomes of forbidden lore, a brilliant but crazed student’s mind is opened to realities beyond the material world and to the alien beings that dwell in the outer void.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once a pact is made, a warlock’s thirst for knowledge and power can’t be slaked with mere study and research. No one makes a pact with such a mighty patron if he or she doesn’t intend to use the power thus gained. Rather, the vast majority of warlocks spend their days in active pursuit of their goals, which typically means some kind of adventuring. Furthermore, the demands of their patrons drive warlocks toward adventure.</p>
            <h4>CREATING A WARLOCK</h4>
            <p>As you make your warlock character, spend some time thinking about your patron and the obligations that your pact imposes upon you. What led you to make the pact, and how did you make contact with your patron? Were you seduced into summoning a devil, or did you seek out the ritual that would allow you to make contact with an alien elder god? Did you search for your patron, or did your patron find and choose you? Do you chafe under the obligations of your pact or serve joyfully in anticipation of the rewards promised to you?</p>
            <p class="indent">Work with your DM to determine how big a part your pact will play in your character’s adventuring career. Your patron’s demands might drive you into adventures, or they might consist entirely of small favors you can do between adventures.</p>
            <p class="indent">What kind of relationship do you have with your patron? Is it friendly, antagonistic, uneasy, or romantic? How important are you to your patron? What is your part in your patron’s plans? Do you know other servants of your patron?</p>
            <p class="indent">How does your patron communicate with you? If you have a familiar, it might occasionally speak with your patron’s voice. Some warlocks find messages from their patrons etched on trees, mingled among tea leaves, or adrift in the clouds — messages that only the warlock can see. Other warlocks converse with their patrons in dreams or waking visions, or deal only with intermediaries.</p>
            <h5>QUICK BUILD</h5>
            <p>You can make a warlock quickly by following these suggestions. First, Intelligence or Charisma should be your highest ability score, followed by Constitution. Second, choose the charlatan background. Third, choose the <i>chill touch</i> and <i>minor illusion</i> cantrips, along with the 1st-level spells <i>ray of sickness</i> and <i>witch bolt</i>.</p>
            <h2>CLASS FEATURES</h2>
            <p>As a warlock, you gain the following class features.</p>
            <h5>HIT POINTS</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Hit Dice:</strong> 1d8 per class level</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at 1st Level:</strong> 8 + your Constitution modifier</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at Higher Levels:</strong> 1d8 (or 5) + your Constitution modifier per class level after 1st</li>
            </ul>
            <h5>PROFICIENCIES</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Armor:</strong> Light armor</li>
                <li><strong>Weapons:</strong> Simple weapons</li>
                <li><strong>Tools:</strong> None</li>
            </ul>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Saving Throws:</strong> Charisma, Wisdom</li>
                <li><strong>Skills:</strong> Choose two skills from Arcana, Deception, History, Intimidation, Investigation, Nature and Religion</li>
            </ul>
            <h5>EQUIPMENT</h5>
            <p>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>(a) a light crossbow and 20 bolts or (b) any simple weapon</li>
                <li>(a) a component pouch or (b) an arcane focus</li>
                <li>(a) a scholar’s pack or (b) a dungeoneer’s pack</li>
                <li>Any simple weapon, leather armor and two daggers</li>
            </ul>
            <div element="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_OTHERWORLDLY_PATRON" />
            <div element="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_PACT_MAGIC" />
            <div element="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_ELDRITCH_INVOCATIONS" />
            <div element="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_PACT_BOON" />
            <div element="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_AGONIZING_SPELLCASTING" />
            <div element="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" />
            <div element="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_MYSTIC_ARCANUM" />
            <div element="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_ARCANE_FEEDBACK" />
            <div element="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_IMMUTABLE_KNOWLEDGE" />
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="short">A wielder of magic that is derived from a bargain with an extraplanar entity.</set>
            <set name="hd">d8</set>
            <set name="spellcaster">true</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet alt="Warlock" display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" requirements="!ID_EA_MULTICLASS_WARLOCK" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" requirements="!ID_EA_MULTICLASS_WARLOCK" />

            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CHARISMA" requirements="!ID_EA_MULTICLASS_WARLOCK"/>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_WISDOM" requirements="!ID_EA_MULTICLASS_WARLOCK"/>

            <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency (Warlock)" supports="Skill,Warlock" number="2" />

            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_OTHERWORLDLY_PATRON" level="1" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Pact Magic Ability" supports="Warlock Spellcasting Ability" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_ELDRITCH_INVOCATIONS" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_PACT_BOON" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_AGONIZING_SPELLCASTING" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" level="4" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_MYSTIC_ARCANUM" level="11" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_ARCANE_FEEDBACK" level="18" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_IMMUTABLE_KNOWLEDGE" level="20" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Otherworldly Patron" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_OTHERWORLDLY_PATRON">
        <description>
            <p>At 1st level, you have struck a bargain with an otherworldly being of your choice: the Ancient Phoenix, the Archfey, the Celestial, the Chosen of Mystra, the Fiend, the Great Old One, the Shadowforce, or the Undying. Your choice grants you features at 1st level and again at 6th level, 10th level, and 14th level.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Archetype" name="Otherworldly Patron" supports="EA Otherworldly Patron" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Pact Magic" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_PACT_MAGIC">
        <supports>ID_INTERNAL_SUPPORT_SPELLCASTING,Warlock</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Your arcane research and the magic bestowed on you by your patron have given you facility with spells. See the Spells chapter of the Player’s Handbook for the general rules of spellcasting and for the warlock spell list.</p>
            <h5>CANTRIPS</h5>
            <p>You know two cantrips of your choice from the warlock spell list. The Warlock table above shows when you learn additional warlock cantrips of your choice.</p>
            <h5>SPELL SLOTS</h5>
            <p>The Warlock table shows how many spell slots you have. The table also shows what the level of those slots is; your spell slots are all the same level. To cast one of your warlock spells of 1st level or higher, you must expend a spell slot. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            <p class="indent">For example, when you are 5th level, you have two 3rd-level spell slots. To cast the 1st-level spell witch bolt, you must spend one of those slots, and you cast it as a 3rd-level spell.</p>
            <h5>SPELLS KNOWN OF 1ST LEVEL AND HIGHER</h5>
            <p>At 1st level, you know two 1st-level spells of your choice from the warlock spell list.</p>
            <p class="indent">The Spells Known column of the Warlock table shows when you learn more warlock spells of your choice of 1st level and higher. A spell you choose must be of a level no higher than what’s shown in the table’s Slot Level column for your level. When you reach 6th level, for example, you learn a new warlock spell of 3rd level or lower.</p>
            <p class="indent">Also, when you gain a level in this class, you can replace one warlock spell you know with another spell from the warlock spell list. The new spell must also be of a level for which you have spell slots.</p>
            <h5>SPELLCASTING ABILITY</h5>
            <p>Choose either Intelligence or Charisma when you gain this feature. Your choice determines your spellcasting ability for your warlock spells. You use the chosen ability score when setting the saving throw DC and when making attack rolls with warlock spells you cast.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Spell save DC</strong> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your chosen ability modifier</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Spell attack modifier</strong> = your proficiency bonus + your chosen ability modifier</p>
            <h5>SPELLCASTING FOCUS</h5>
            <p>You can use an arcane focus (see the Adventuring Gear section) as a spellcasting focus for your warlock spells.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>

            <stat name="warlock:spellcasting:slots:count" value="1" level="1"/>
            <stat name="warlock:spellcasting:slots:count" value="1" level="2"/>
            <stat name="warlock:spellcasting:slots:count" value="1" level="8"/>
            <stat name="warlock:spellcasting:slots:count" value="1" level="16"/>

            <stat name="warlock:spellcasting:slot" value="1" level="1" />
            <stat name="warlock:spellcasting:slot" value="1" level="3" />
            <stat name="warlock:spellcasting:slot" value="1" level="5" />
            <stat name="warlock:spellcasting:slot" value="1" level="7" />
            <stat name="warlock:spellcasting:slot" value="1" level="9" />
            
            <!-- negative count to remove slots -->
            <stat name="warlock:spellcasting:slots:1" value="warlock:spellcasting:slots:count" level="1" />
            <stat name="warlock:spellcasting:slots:1" value="-warlock:spellcasting:slots:count" level="3" />
            <stat name="warlock:spellcasting:slots:2" value="warlock:spellcasting:slots:count" level="3" />
            <stat name="warlock:spellcasting:slots:2" value="-warlock:spellcasting:slots:count" level="5" />
            <stat name="warlock:spellcasting:slots:3" value="warlock:spellcasting:slots:count" level="5" />
            <stat name="warlock:spellcasting:slots:3" value="-warlock:spellcasting:slots:count" level="7" />
            <stat name="warlock:spellcasting:slots:4" value="warlock:spellcasting:slots:count" level="7" />
            <stat name="warlock:spellcasting:slots:4" value="-warlock:spellcasting:slots:count" level="9" />
            <stat name="warlock:spellcasting:slots:5" value="warlock:spellcasting:slots:count" level="9" />

            <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Warlock)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),0" level="1" number="2" spellcasting="Warlock" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Warlock)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),0" level="4" spellcasting="Warlock" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Warlock)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),0" level="10" spellcasting="Warlock" />
        
            <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Warlock)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="1" number="2" spellcasting="Warlock"/>
            <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Warlock)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="2" spellcasting="Warlock"/>
            <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Warlock)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="3" spellcasting="Warlock"/>
            <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Warlock)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="4" spellcasting="Warlock"/>
            <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Warlock)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="5" spellcasting="Warlock"/>
            <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Warlock)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="6" spellcasting="Warlock"/>
            <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Warlock)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="7" spellcasting="Warlock"/>
            <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Warlock)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="8" spellcasting="Warlock"/>
            <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Warlock)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="9" spellcasting="Warlock"/>
            <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Warlock)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="11" spellcasting="Warlock"/>
            <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Warlock)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="13" spellcasting="Warlock"/>
            <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Warlock)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="15" spellcasting="Warlock"/>
            <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Warlock)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="17" spellcasting="Warlock"/>
            <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Warlock)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="19" spellcasting="Warlock"/>

            <stat name="spell-ability:mod" value="intelligence:modifier" requirements="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_SPELLCASTING_INTELLIGENCE" />
            <stat name="spell-ability:mod" value="charisma:modifier" requirements="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_SPELLCASTING_CHARISMA" />
            <stat name="spell-ability:mod" value="proficiency" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Intelligence" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_SPELLCASTING_INTELLIGENCE">
            <supports>Warlock Spellcasting Ability</supports>
            <description>
                <p></p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <spellcasting name="Warlock" ability="Intelligence" allowReplace="true">
                <list>Warlock</list>
            </spellcasting>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_PACT_MAGIC" level="1" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        claa<element name="Charisma" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_SPELLCASTING_CHARISMA">
            <supports>Warlock Spellcasting Ability</supports>
            <description>
                <p></p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <spellcasting name="Warlock" ability="Charisma" allowReplace="true">
                <list>Warlock</list>
            </spellcasting>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_PACT_MAGIC" level="1" />
            </rules>
        </element>
    <element name="Eldritch Invocations" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_ELDRITCH_INVOCATIONS">
        <description>
            <p>In your study of occult lore, you have unearthed eldritch invocations, fragments of forbidden knowledge that imbue you with an abiding magical ability.</p>
            <p class="indent">At 2nd level, you gain one eldritch invocation of your choice. Your invocation options are listed at the end of the class description and on patron’s page. At certain warlock levels, you gain new invocations of your choice, as shown in the Invocations Known column of the Warlock table.</p>
            <p class="indent">Additionally, when you gain a level in this class, you can choose one of the invocations you know and replace it with another invocation that you could learn at that level.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Eldritch Invocation (Level 2)" supports="EA Eldritch Invocation" level="2" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Eldritch Invocation (Level 3)" supports="EA Eldritch Invocation" level="3" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Eldritch Invocation (Level 5)" supports="EA Eldritch Invocation" level="5" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Eldritch Invocation (Level 7)" supports="EA Eldritch Invocation" level="7" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Eldritch Invocation (Level 9)" supports="EA Eldritch Invocation" level="9" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Eldritch Invocation (Level 11)" supports="EA Eldritch Invocation" level="11" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Eldritch Invocation (Level 14)" supports="EA Eldritch Invocation" level="14" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Eldritch Invocation (Level 17)" supports="EA Eldritch Invocation" level="17" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Eldritch Invocation (Level 20)" supports="EA Eldritch Invocation" level="20" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Pact Boon" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_PACT_BOON">
        <description>
            <p>Also at 2nd level, your otherworldly patron bestows a gift upon you for your loyal service. You gain one of the following features of your choice.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Pact Boon" source="Eldritch Arcana" supports="EA Pact Boon" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Agonizing Spellcasting" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_AGONIZING_SPELLCASTING">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 3rd level, you can add your spellcasting ability modifier to damage rolls you make with any warlock cantrip, except for damage rolls that already add your spellcasting ability modifier.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can add your {{spell-ability:mod}} to damage rolls you make with any warlock cantrip, except for damage rolls that already add your spellcasting ability modifier.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Ability Score Improvement" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT">
        <description>
            <p>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Warlock 4)" supports="Improvement Option,Warlock,4" level="4" />
        <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Warlock 8)" supports="Improvement Option,Warlock,8" level="8" />
        <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Warlock 12)" supports="Improvement Option,Warlock,12" level="12" />
        <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Warlock 16)" supports="Improvement Option,Warlock,16" level="16" />
        <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Warlock 19)" supports="Improvement Option,Warlock,19" level="19" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Mystic Arcanum" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_MYSTIC_ARCANUM">
        <description>
            <p>At 11th level, choose a 6th-level spell from the warlock spell list as an arcanum. You can cast your arcanum spell once without expending a spell slot. You must finish a long rest before you can do so again. At higher levels, you gain more warlock spells of your choice that can be cast in this way: one 7th-level spell at 13th level, one 8th-level spell at 15th level, and one 9th-level spell at 17th level. You regain all uses of your Mystic Arcanum when you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest each">
            <description>You can cast each of your Mystic Arcanum spells once without expending a spell slot.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Spell" name="Mystic Arcanum (Level 11)" supports="Warlock,6" level="11" spellcasting="Warlock" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Mystic Arcanum (Level 13)" supports="Warlock,7" level="13" spellcasting="Warlock" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Mystic Arcanum (Level 15)" supports="Warlock,8" level="15" spellcasting="Warlock" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Mystic Arcanum (Level 17)" supports="Warlock,9" level="17" spellcasting="Warlock" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Arcane Feedback" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_ARCANE_FEEDBACK">
        <description>
            <p>At 18th level, whenever you use your Mystic Arcanum feature, you can regain one expended spell slot from your Pact Magic feature.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Whenever you use your Mystic Arcanum feature, you can regain one expended spell slot from your Pact Magic feature.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Immutable Knowledge" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_IMMUTABLE_KNOWLEDGE">
        <description>
            <p>At 20th level, the knowledge you have obtained leaves an imprint in your mind. Your Intelligence or Charisma score (your choice) increases by 2, and your maximum for the chosen score increases by 2. Also, your Intelligence and Charisma scores can never be reduced.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Your Intelligence and Charisma scores can never be reduced.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="intelligence:max" value="2" />
            <stat name="charisma:max" value="2" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Immutable Knowledge" supports="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_IMMUTABLE_KNOWLEDGE_INT|ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_IMMUTABLE_KNOWLEDGE_CHA" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Intelligence" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_IMMUTABLE_KNOWLEDGE_INT">
        <description>
            <p></p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="intelligence" value="2" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Charisma" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_IMMUTABLE_KNOWLEDGE_CHA">
        <description>
            <p></p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="charisma" value="2" />
        </rules>
    </element>

<!-- Pact Boons -->
    <element name="Pact of the Armory" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_PACT_OF_THE_ARMORY">
        <supports>EA Pact Boon</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You gain proficiency with medium armor and shields. Additionally, you can use your action to create a pact weapon in your empty hand. You can choose the form that this weapon takes each time you create it; it can take the form of any melee weapon, a shortbow, a longbow, a light crossbow or a heavy crossbow (see chapter 5 for weapon options). You are proficient with it while you wield it, and when you attack with it, you can use your spellcasting ability modifier, instead of Strength or Dexterity, for your attack and damage rolls. This weapon counts as magical for the purpose of overcoming resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage.</p>
            <p class="indent">Your pact weapon disappears if it is more than 5 feet away from you for 1 minute or more. It also disappears if you use this feature again, if you dismiss the weapon (no action required), or if you die.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can transform one magic weapon into your pact weapon by performing a special ritual while you hold the weapon. You perform the ritual over the course of 1 hour, which can be done during a short rest. You are proficient with the weapon while it is your pact weapon, and you gain the ability to dismiss the weapon, shunting it into an extradimensional space. You can cause it to reappear whenever you create your pact weapon thereafter. The weapon ceases being your pact weapon if you die, if you perform the 1-hour ritual on a different weapon, or if you use a 1-hour ritual to break your bond to it. The weapon appears at your feet if it is in the extradimensional space when the bond breaks.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Action">
            <description>You can create a pact weapon in your empty hand. You can choose the form that this weapon takes each time you create it. You are proficient with it while you wield it, and when you attack with it, you can use your spellcasting ability modifier, instead of Strength or Dexterity, for your attack and damage rolls. This weapon counts as magical for the purpose of overcoming resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_MEDIUM_ARMOR" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_SHIELDS" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Pact of the Chain" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_PACT_OF_THE_CHAIN">
        <supports>EA Pact Boon</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You learn the <i>find familiar</i> spell and can cast it as a ritual. The spell doesn’t count against your number of spells known. When you cast the spell, you can choose a normal form or one of the following forms: imp, phoenix wisp, pseudodragon, quasit, or sprite. Additionally, you can use your bonus action to allow your familiar to immediately make one attack with its reaction.</p>
            <p class="indent">Finally, you can communicate telepathically with your familiar and perceive through your familiar’s senses as long as you are on the same plane of existence. Additionally, while perceiving through your familiar’s senses, you can also speak through your familiar in your own voice, even if your familiar is normally incapable of speech.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can cast find familiar as a ritual. The spell doesn’t count against your number of spells known. When you cast the spell, you can choose a normal form or one of the following forms: imp, phoenix wisp, pseudodragon, quasit, or sprite. Additionally, you can use your bonus action to allow your familiar to immediately make one attack with its reaction.
            You can communicate telepathically with your familiar and perceive through your familiar’s senses as long as you are on the same plane of existence. Additionally, while perceiving through your familiar’s senses, you can also speak through your familiar in your own voice, even if your familiar is normally incapable of speech.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIND_FAMILIAR" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Pact of the Effigy" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_PACT_OF_THE_EFFIGY">
        <supports>EA Pact Boon</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You have a doll-like effigy whose surface constantly shifts, like water. With it, you can weave your magic into an inexorable bond with other creatures. You can use your action and choose a creature you can see within 60 feet of you to magically steal a sliver of their essence, cursing them and storing the essence in your effigy. Casting <i>remove curse</i> on the cursed creature or on the effigy destroys the essence.</p>
            <p class="indent">While you have the essence of a creature, that creature has disadvantage on Wisdom (Insight) checks against you, as well as saving throws against being charmed by you.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can only have one essence at a time. When you steal a creature’s essence while you already have one, you can choose to replace your existing essence.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Action">
            <description>You can choose a creature you can see within 60 feet of you to magically steal a sliver of their essence, cursing them and storing the essence in your effigy.
            While you have the essence of a creature, that creature has disadvantage on Wisdom (Insight) checks against you, as well as saving throws against being charmed by you.
            You can only have one essence at a time.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Pact of the Gauntlet" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_PACT_OF_THE_GAUNTLET">
        <supports>EA Pact Boon</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Your hands become covered in a thin layer of eerie, unearthly metal. With these gauntlets, you can use your spellcasting ability modifier in place of Strength for ability checks and saving throws. You can also choose to use your spellcasting ability modifier for the attack and damage rolls of your unarmed strikes.</p>
            <p class="indent">Additionally, you learn the <i>eldritch blast</i> cantrip; if you already know it, you instead learn one warlock cantrip of your choice. Once per turn when you cast <i>eldritch blast</i>, you can choose to split part of the beam, targeting another creature within range with a separate attack roll. This beam deals 1d4 force damage on a hit.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can use your spellcasting ability modifier in place of Strength for ability checks and saving throws. You can also choose to use your spellcasting ability modifier for the attack and damage rolls of your unarmed strikes.
            Once per turn when you cast eldritch blast, you can choose to split part of the beam, targeting another creature within range with a separate attack roll. This beam deals 1d4 force damage on a hit.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ELDRITCH_BLAST" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Pact of the Symbol" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_PACT_OF_THE_SYMBOL">
        <supports>EA Pact Boon</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You receive a symbol imbued with the influence of your patron’s power, which takes the shape of an arcane focus. If you ever let go of the focus, or if it is destroyed, you can use your bonus action to cause it to teleport into one of your free hands, fully repaired.</p>
            <p class="indent">Your symbol also gains one influence charge, used to call upon your patron’s power over your fate. While you hold this symbol, when you roll a 1 or a 20 on the d20 for a spell attack, your symbol gains another influence charge. Your symbol can never have more influence charges than your spellcasting ability modifier, and when you finish a short or long rest, its number of charges returns to 1.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once per turn, when you roll a d20 for a spell attack, you can expend a charge from the symbol to replace the d20 roll with a 10. You can do so after the roll, but before determining if the attack hits.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="Max charges: {{pact-of-the-symbol:charges}}">
            <description>While you hold your patron’s symbol, when you roll a 1 or a 20 on the d20 for a spell attack, your symbol gains another influence charge. Once per turn, when you roll a d20 for a spell attack, you can expend a charge from the symbol to replace the d20 roll with a 10. You can do so after the roll, but before determining if the attack hits.
            You can use your bonus action to cause your symbol into one of your free hands, fully repaired.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="pact-of-the-symbol:charges" value="proficiency" />
            <stat name="pact-of-the-symbol:charges" value="intelligence:modifier" requirements="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_SPELLCASTING_INTELLIGENCE" />
            <stat name="pact-of-the-symbol:charges" value="charisma:modifier" requirements="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_SPELLCASTING_CHARISMA" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Pact of the Tome" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_PACT_OF_THE_TOME">
        <supports>EA Pact Boon</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Your patron gives you a grimoire called a Book of Shadows. When you gain this feature, choose three cantrips from any class’s spell list (the three needn’t be from the same list). While the book is on your person, you can cast those cantrips at will. They don’t count against your number of cantrips known. If they don’t appear on the warlock spell list, they are nonetheless warlock spells for you.</p>
            <p class="indent">If you lose your Book of Shadows, you can perform a 1-hour ceremony to receive a replacement from your patron. This ceremony can be performed during a short or long rest, and it destroys the previous book. The book turns to ash when you die.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>While your Book of Shadows is on your person, you can cast your Pact of the Tome cantrips at will.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Pact of the Tome)" number="3" supports="0" spellcasting="Warlock" />
        </rules>
    </element>

<!-- Otherworldly Patrons -->
  <!-- The Celestial -->
    <element name="The Celestial" type="Archetype" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_THE_CELESTIAL">
        <supports>EA Otherworldly Patron</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Your patron is a powerful being of the Upper Planes. You have bound yourself to an ancient empyrean, solar, ki-rin, unicorn, or other entity that resides in the planes of everlasting bliss. Your pact with that being allows you to experience the barest touch of the holy light that illuminates the multiverse.</p>
            <p class="indent">Being connected to such power can cause changes in your behavior and beliefs. You might find yourself driven to annihilate the undead, to defeat fiends, and to protect the innocent. At times, your heart might also be filled with a longing for the celestial realm of your patron, and a desire to wander that paradise for the rest of your days. But you know that your mission is among mortals for now, and that your pact binds you to bring light to the dark places of the world.</p>
            <h5>CELESTIAL FEATURES</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Warlock Level</td><td>Feature</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1st</td><td>Expanded Spell List, Bonus Cantrips, Healing Light</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6th</td><td>Radiant Soul</td></tr>
                <tr><td>10th</td><td>Celestial Reinforcement</td></tr>
                <tr><td>14th</td><td>Searing Vengeance</td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_CELESTIAL_EXPANDED_SPELL_LIST" />
            <div element="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_CELESTIAL_BONUS_CANTRIPS" />
            <div element="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_CELESTIAL_HEALING_LIGHT" />
            <div element="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_CELESTIAL_RADIANT_SOUL" />
            <div element="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_CELESTIAL_CELESTIAL_REINFORCEMENT" />
            <div element="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_CELESTIAL_SEARING_VENGEANCE" />
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_CELESTIAL_EXPANDED_SPELL_LIST" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_CELESTIAL_BONUS_CANTRIPS" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_CELESTIAL_HEALING_LIGHT" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_CELESTIAL_RADIANT_SOUL" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_CELESTIAL_CELESTIAL_REINFORCEMENT" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_CELESTIAL_SEARING_VENGEANCE" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Expanded Spell List" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_CELESTIAL_EXPANDED_SPELL_LIST">
            <description>
                <p>The Celestial lets you choose from an expanded list of spells when you learn a warlock spell. The following spells are added to the warlock spell list for you.</p>
                <h5>CELESTIAL EXPANDED SPELLS</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Spell Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1st</td><td>cure wounds, guiding bolt</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>2nd</td><td>flaming sphere, lesser restoration</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td>daylight, revivify</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>4th</td><td>guadian of faith, wall of fire</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td>flame strike, greater restoration</td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <spellcasting name="Warlock" extend="true">
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_CURE_WOUNDS</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_GUIDING_BOLT</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_FLAMING_SPHERE</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_LESSER_RESTORATION</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_REVIVIFY</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_DAYLIGHT</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_GUARDIAN_OF_FAITH</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_WALL_OF_FIRE</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_FLAME_STRIKE</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_GREATER_RESTORATION</extend>
            </spellcasting>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Bonus Cantrips" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_CELESTIAL_BONUS_CANTRIPS">
            <description>
                <p>When you choose this patron at 1st level, you learn the light and sacred flame cantrips. They count as warlock cantrips for you, but they don’t count against your number of cantrips known.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LIGHT" spellcasting="Warlock" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SACRED_FLAME" spellcasting="Warlock" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Healing Light" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_CELESTIAL_HEALING_LIGHT">
            <description>
                <p>At lst level, you gain the ability to channel celestial energy to heal wounds. You have a pool of d8s that you spend to fuel this healing. The number of dice in the pool equals 1 + half of your warlock level, rounded down (minimum of 0).</p>
                <p class="indent">As a bonus action, you can heal one creature you can see within 60 feet of you, spending dice from the pool. The maximum number of dice you can spend at once equals your spellcasting ability modifier (minimum of one die). Roll the dice you spend, add them together, and restore a number of hit points equal to the total.</p>
                <p class="indent">Your pool regains all expended dice when you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="{{healing-light:dice-pool}} dice/Long Rest">
                <description>You can heal one creature you can see within 60 feet of you, spending dice from the pool. You can spend a maximum of {{spell-ability:mod}} dice from your pool at one time.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="healing-light:dice-pool" value="1" />
                <stat name="healing-light:dice-pool" value="level:warlock:half" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Radiant Soul" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_CELESTIAL_RADIANT_SOUL">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 6th level, your link to the Celestial emblazons your soul with radiant energy, protecting you.</p>
                <p class="indent">You have resistance to radiant damage, and you are immune to poison and disease.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You are immune to poison and disease.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_RADIANT" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Celestial Reinforcement" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_CELESTIAL_CELESTIAL_REINFORCEMENT">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 10th level, the Celestial magic you use gently circulates through you, reinforcing your Celestial abilities.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can add a +2 bonus to each d8 rolled for your Healing Light feature. Additionally, you and up to 5 creatures of your choice that you can see gain temporary hit points equal to half your warlock level + your spellcasting ability modifier whenever you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can add a +2 bonus to each d8 rolled for your Healing Light feature. Additionally, you and up to 5 creatures of your choice that you can see gain {{celestial-reinforcement:temp-hp}} temporary hit points whenever you finish a short or long rest.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="celestial-reinforcement:temp-hp" value="level:warlock:half" />
                <stat name="celestial-reinforcement:temp-hp" value="spell-ability:mod" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Searing Vengeance" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_CELESTIAL_SEARING_VENGEANCE">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 14th level, the radiant energy you channel allows you to resist death. When you have to make a death saving throw at the start of your turn, you can instead spring back to your feet with a burst of radiant energy. You regain hit points equal to half your hit point maximum, and then you stand up if you so choose. Each creature of your choice that is within 30 feet of you takes radiant damage equal to your warlock level + your spellcasting ability modifier, and it is blinded until the end of the current turn.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>When you have to make a death saving throw at the start of your turn, you can instead spring back to your feet with a burst of radiant energy. You regain hit points equal to half your hit point maximum, and then you stand up if you so choose. Each creature of your choice that is within 30 feet of you takes {{searing-vengeance:damage}} radiant damage, and it is blinded until the end of the current turn.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="searing-vengeance:damage" value="spell-ability:mod" />
                <stat name="searing-vengeance:damage" value="level:warlock" />
            </rules>
        </element>

  <!-- The Shadowforce -->
    <element name="The Shadowforce" type="Archetype" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_THE_SHADOWFORCE">
        <supports>EA Otherworldly Patron</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You have made your pact with a mysterious entity — a force that manifests in sentient magic weapons carved from the stuff of shadow. The shadowy force behind these weapons can offer power to warlocks who form pacts with it. These warlocks - sometimes called hexblades - can weave this powerful dark magic into the world.</p>
            <h5>SHADOWFORCE FEATURES</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Warlock Level</td><td>Feature</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1st</td><td>Expanded Spell List, Hexblade’s Curse</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6th</td><td>Shadow Shroud</td></tr>
                <tr><td>10th</td><td>Accursed Specter</td></tr>
                <tr><td>14th</td><td>Master of Hexes</td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_SHADOWFORCE_EXPANDED_SPELL_LIST" />
            <div element="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_SHADOWFORCE_HEXBLADES_CURSE" />
            <div element="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_SHADOWFORCE_SHADOW_SHROUD" />
            <div element="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_SHADOWFORCE_ACCURSED_SPECTER" />
            <div element="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_SHADOWFORCE_MASTER_OF_HEXES" />
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_SHADOWFORCE_EXPANDED_SPELL_LIST" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_SHADOWFORCE_HEXBLADES_CURSE" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_SHADOWFORCE_SHADOW_SHROUD" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_SHADOWFORCE_ACCURSED_SPECTER" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_SHADOWFORCE_MASTER_OF_HEXES" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Expanded Spell List" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_SHADOWFORCE_EXPANDED_SPELL_LIST">
            <description>
                <p>The Shadowforce lets you choose from an expanded list of spells when you learn a warlock spell. The following spells are added to the warlock spell list for you.</p>
                <h5>SHADOWFORCE EXPANDED SPELLS</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Spell Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1st</td><td>ensnaring strike, shield</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>2nd</td><td>blur, branding smite</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td>blink, elemental weapon</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>4th</td><td>faithful hound, phantasmal killer</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td>banishing smite, cone of cold</td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <spellcasting name="Warlock" extend="true">
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_ENSNARING_STRIKE</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_SHIELD</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_BLUR</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_BRANDING_SMITE</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_BLINK</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_ELEMENTAL_WEAPON</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_MORDENKAINENS_FAITHFUL_HOUND</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_PHANTASMAL_KILLER</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_BANISHING_SMITE</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_CONE_OF_COLD</extend>
            </spellcasting>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Hexblade’s Curse" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_SHADOWFORCE_HEXBLADES_CURSE">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 1st level, you can imbue your weapons with a curse that seals victims’ abilities.</p>
                <p class="indent">While you wield a weapon or arcane focus, you can emblazon it with intricate runes that form a wicked, sealing curse, the Hexblade’s Curse. While you have this emblazoned item, you can force a creature you hit with a weapon or spell attack to succeed on a Charisma saving throw against your spell save DC or be cursed with the Hexblade’s Curse for 1 minute. A creature can only be forced to make this saving throw once per turn.</p>
                <p class="indent">As powerful hexes hamper its abilities, the creature cursed by your Hexblade’s Curse can’t add its proficiency bonus to its attacks. The creature must also roll a d4 and subtract it from any ability checks or saving throws it makes.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you have successfully cursed a creature with this feature, you can’t do so again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
                <description>While you wield a weapon or arcane focus, you can emblazon it with intricate runes that form the Hexblade’s Curse. While you have this emblazoned item, you can force a creature you hit with a weapon or spell attack to succeed on a Charisma saving (save DC {{warlock:spellcasting:dc}}) or be cursed with the Hexblade’s Curse for 1 minute. A creature can only be forced to make this saving throw once per turn.
                The creature cursed by your Hexblade’s Curse can’t add its proficiency bonus to its attacks. The creature must also roll a d4 and subtract it from any ability checks or saving throws it makes.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Shadow Shroud" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_SHADOWFORCE_SHADOW_SHROUD">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, you weave shadowy magic around your body, protecting you from attacks.</p>
                <p class="indent">When you are hit with an attack, you can use your reaction to activate your protective shroud, which lasts until the start of your next turn. If you do, roll a d6 whenever an attack hits you, including during the triggering attack; on a 4 or higher, the attack instead misses you.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you have used this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Short Rest" action="Reaction">
                <description>When you are hit with an attack, you can activate your protective shroud, which lasts until the start of your next turn. Roll a d6 whenever an attack hits you, including during the triggering attack; on a 4 or higher, the attack instead misses you.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Accursed Specter" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_SHADOWFORCE_ACCURSED_SPECTER">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 10th level, you can bind the souls of the slain to your service, weaving them into a shadowy form.</p>
                <p class="indent">When you slay a creature, you can cause its spirit to rise from its corpse as a specter, the statistics for which are in the Monster Manual. When the specter appears, it takes the form of a shadowy, panther-like creature, and it gains temporary hit points equal to twice your warlock level plus your spellcasting ability modifier. Roll initiative for the specter, which has its own turns. The specter remains in your service until the end of your next long rest, at which point it vanishes to the afterlife.</p>
                <p class="indent">It obeys your verbal commands (no action required by you), and it gains a special bonus to its AC and saving throws, as well as to its attack and damage rolls. This bonus is equal to your spellcasting ability modifier (minimum of +0).</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you bind a specter with this feature, you can’t use the feature again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
                <description>When you slay a creature, you can cause its spirit to rise from its corpse as a specter, the statistics for which are in the Monster Manual. It takes the form of a shadowy, panther-like creature, and it gains {{accursed-specter:hp}} temporary hit points. Roll initiative for the specter, which has its own turns. The specter remains in your service until the end of your next long rest, at which point it vanishes to the afterlife.
                It obeys your verbal commands (no action required by you), and it gains a +{{spell-ability:mod}} bonus to its AC and saving throws, as well as to its attack and damage rolls.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="accursed-specter:hp" value="level:warlock" />
                <stat name="accursed-specter:hp" value="level:warlock" />
                <stat name="accursed-specter:hp" value="spell-ability:mod" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Master of Hexes" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_SHADOWFORCE_MASTER_OF_HEXES">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 14th level, your curse becomes more persistent and grants you further benefits.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can now curse other creatures with your Hexblade’s Curse while the curse is in effect. If you do, the curse ends on the previous creature, and the curse’s remaining duration carries over.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, you gain the following benefits against creatures afflicted by your Hexblade’s Curse:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Once per turn, you can deal 3d10 additional damage when you hit the cursed target with an attack.</li>
                    <li>Any attack roll you make against the cursed target is a critical hit on a roll of 19 or 20 on the d20.</li>
                    <li>If the cursed target dies, you regain hit points equal to your warlock level + your spellcasting ability modifier.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can now curse other creatures with your Hexblade’s Curse while the curse is in effect. If you do, the curse ends on the previous creature, and the curse’s remaining duration carries over.
                Once per turn, you can deal 3d10 additional damage when you hit the cursed target with an attack.
                Any attack roll you make against the cursed target is a critical hit on a roll of 19 or 20 on the d20.
                If the cursed target dies, you regain {{master-of-hexes:hp}} hit points.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="master-of-hexes:hp" value="level:warlock" />
                <stat name="master-of-hexes:hp" value="spell-ability:mod" />
            </rules>
        </element>

  <!-- The Ancient Phoenix -->
    <element name="The Ancient Phoenix" type="Archetype" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_THE_ANCIENT_PHOENIX">
        <supports>EA Otherworldly Patron</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Your patron is a phoenix which has survived thousands of years of pursuit. This being has settled on the elemental plane of fire, and is so suffused with magical energy that its powerful magic can be siphoned through rituals, even on the innermost planes.</p>
            <p class="indent"></p>
            <h5>ANCIENT PHOENIX FEATURES</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Warlock Level</td><td>Feature</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1st</td><td>Positive Energy Infusion, Expanded Spell List, Mantle of Flame</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6th</td><td>Warding Cyclone</td></tr>
                <tr><td>10th</td><td>Spark of Rebirth</td></tr>
                <tr><td>14th</td><td>Phoenix Pinion</td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_ANCIENT_PHOENIX_POSITIVE_ENERGY_INFUSION" />
            <div element="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_ANCIENT_PHOENIX_EXPANDED_SPELL_LIST" />
            <div element="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_ANCIENT_PHOENIX_MANTLE_OF_FLAME" />
            <div element="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_ANCIENT_PHOENIX_WARDING_CYCLONE" />
            <div element="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_ANCIENT_PHOENIX_SPARK_OF_REBIRTH" />
            <div element="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_ANCIENT_PHOENIX_PHOENIX_PINION" />
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_ANCIENT_PHOENIX_POSITIVE_ENERGY_INFUSION" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_ANCIENT_PHOENIX_EXPANDED_SPELL_LIST" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_ANCIENT_PHOENIX_MANTLE_OF_FLAME" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_ANCIENT_PHOENIX_WARDING_CYCLONE" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_ANCIENT_PHOENIX_SPARK_OF_REBIRTH" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_ANCIENT_PHOENIX_PHOENIX_PINION" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Expanded Spell List" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_ANCIENT_PHOENIX_EXPANDED_SPELL_LIST">
            <description>
                <p>The following spells are added to the warlock spell list for you.</p>
                <h5>ANCIENT PHOENIX EXPANDED SPELLS</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Spell Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1st</td><td>feather fall, guiding bolt</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>2nd</td><td>heat metal, pyrotechnics</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td>beacon of hope, melf’s minute meteors</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>4th</td><td>aura of purity, fire shield</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td>holy weapon, reincarnate</td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <spellcasting name="Warlock" extend="true">
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_FEATHER_FALL</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_GUIDING_BOLT</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_HEAT_METAL</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_PYROTECHNICS</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_BEACON_OF_HOPE</extend>
                <extend>ID_XGTE_SPELL_MELFS_MINUTE_METEORS</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_AURA_OF_PURITY</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_FIRE_SHIELD</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_HOLY_WEAPON</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_REINCARNATE</extend>
            </spellcasting>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Positive Energy Infusion" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_ANCIENT_PHOENIX_POSITIVE_ENERGY_INFUSION">
            <description>
                <p>Would-be Warlocks who make contact with an ancient phoenix are accidentally exposed to the raw life energy infused into a phoenix’s essence. This change to the composition of your soul causes minor incompatibilities with its vessel. You may roll or choose from the following quirks to add manifestations of this change to your character.</p>
                <h5>ANCIENT PHOENIX QUIRKS</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>d8</td><td>Quirk</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1</td><td>You absentmindedly ignite small fires that quickly sputter out.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>2</td><td>You cackle like a fiend when you unleash your fire spells.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3</td><td>You admire fire, even if it burns your friends.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>4</td><td>You are covered in burns that mark the first time your power manifested.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5</td><td>You are brave to the point of recklessness.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>6</td><td>You have a nervous compulsion to keep a bright light in even the barest shadow.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>7</td><td>You have an overwhelming hatred of undead creatures.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>8</td><td>You fidget and are irritable when you can’t see the sun.</td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="List" name="Ancient Phoenix Quirk">
                    <item id="1">You absentmindedly ignite small fires that quickly sputter out.</item>
                    <item id="2">You cackle like a fiend when you unleash your fire spells.</item>
                    <item id="3">You admire fire, even if it burns your friends.</item>
                    <item id="4">You are covered in burns that mark the first time your power manifested.</item>
                    <item id="5">You are brave to the point of recklessness.</item>
                    <item id="6">You have a nervous compulsion to keep a bright light in even the barest shadow.</item>
                    <item id="7">You have an overwhelming hatred of undead creatures.</item>
                    <item id="8">You fidget and are irritable when you can’t see the sun.</item>
                </select>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Mantle of Flame" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_ANCIENT_PHOENIX_MANTLE_OF_FLAME">
            <description>
                <p>Starting when you choose this patron at 1st level, you can unleash the phoenix fire that blazes within you.</p>
                <p class="indent">As an action, you magically wreathe yourself in swirling fire, as your eyes glow like hot coals. For 1 minute, you gain certain benefits:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>You have resistance to fire and radiant damage.</li>
                    <li>You shed bright light in a 30-foot radius and dim light for an additional 30 feet.</li>
                    <li>When a creature hits you with a melee attack, brilliant flames burst from your mantle, enveloping the creature. The creature takes fire or radiant damage equal to your spellcasting ability modifier.</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Short Rest">
                <description>You magically wreathe yourself in swirling fire, as your eyes glow like hot coals. For 1 minute, you gain certain benefits:
                You have resistance to fire and radiant damage.
                You shed bright light in a 30-foot radius and dim light for an additional 30 feet.
                When a creature hits you with a melee attack, the creature takes {{spell-ability:mod}} fire or radiant damage equal.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Warding Cyclone" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_ANCIENT_PHOENIX_WARDING_CYCLONE">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 6th level, you can create a fiery gale around yourself that protects you from damage.</p>
                <p class="indent">When you are hit by an attack or fail a saving throw against an effect that only deals damage, you can use your reaction to move up to 10 feet without provoking opportunity attacks. If your new location is outside of the range or reach of the attack or effect, you take no damage from it and don’t suffer any of its additional effects.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Reaction" usage="1/Short Rest">
                <description>When you are hit by an attack or fail a saving throw against an effect that only deals damage, you can move up to 10 feet without provoking opportunity attacks. If your new location is outside of the range or reach of the attack or effect, you take no damage from it and don’t suffer any of its additional effects.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Spark of Rebirth" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_ANCIENT_PHOENIX_SPARK_OF_REBIRTH">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 10th level, in the face of defeat, your flame knits your wounds and surges outward in a fiery roar.</p>
                <p class="indent">If you are reduced to 0 hit points, you can draw upon the phoenix’s spark. You are instead reduced to 1 hit point, and creatures within 10 feet of you take fire or radiant damage equal to your warlock level + your spellcasting ability modifier.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>If you are reduced to 0 hit points, you can draw upon the phoenix’s spark. You are instead reduced to 1 hit point, and creatures within 10 feet of you take {{spark-of-rebirth:damage}} fire or radiant damage.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="spark-of-rebirth:damage" value="level:warlock" />
                <stat name="spark-of-rebirth:damage" value="spell-ability:mod" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Phoenix Pinion" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_ANCIENT_PHOENIX_PHOENIX_PINION">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 14th level, you can manifest one of your patron’s feathers which sears your foes, heals your allies, and can even restore life.</p>
                <p class="indent">As an action, you conjure a brilliantly glowing feather in your hand. This pinion can be used once before crumbling to ashes, and you can use it in one of the following ways:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>For you, it is a simple melee weapon with the finesse and thrown (range 20/60) properties that deals 5d8 fire and 5d8 radiant damage. When thrown, you can use your spellcasting ability modifier for the attack and damage rolls. When you hit with the pinion, creatures you choose in a 20-foot radius around the target regain a number of hit points equal to 4d8 plus your spellcasting ability modifier.</li>
                    <li>As a bonus action, you stab the heart of a dead creature with the pinion. If creature has died within the last 10 days, the pinion glows with a radiant light for 1 minute. If the pinion is not removed within that time, the creature’s body and the pinion crumble to ash, and in a flash of radiant light, the creature is restored to life as if the resurrection spell had been cast on it. This option can only be used once every 10 days.</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a long rest. If you have a pinion at that time, it crumbles to ash, losing all magical properties.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>As an action, you conjure a brilliantly glowing feather in your hand. This pinion can be used once before crumbling to ashes, and you can use it in one of the following ways:
                It is a simple melee weapon with the finesse and thrown (range 20/60) properties that deals 5d8 fire and 5d8 radiant damage. When thrown, you can use your spellcasting ability modifier for the attack and damage rolls. When you hit with the pinion, creatures you choose in a 20-foot radius around the target regain a number of hit points equal to 4d8 plus your spellcasting ability modifier.
                As a bonus action, you stab the heart of a dead creature with the pinion. If creature has died within the last 10 days, the pinion glows with a radiant light for 1 minute. If the pinion is not removed within that time, the creature’s body and the pinion crumble to ash, and in a flash of radiant light, the creature is restored to life as if the resurrection spell had been cast on it. This option can only be used once every 10 days.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

  <!-- The Chosen of Mystra -->
    <element name="The Chosen of Mystra" type="Archetype" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_CHOSEN_OF_MYSTRA">
        <supports>EA Otherworldly Patron</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Your patron is one of the Chosen of Mystra: mortals of great power who serve Mystra, the mother of all magic. These mortals have been granted a portion of Mystra’s divine essence - called spellfire - which they use to guard the Weave from disruption, preserving the status quo of magic among the realms. These chosen mortals, while extremely powerful, are not infallible themselves; they sometimes contract Warlocks to assist with their goals, granting them a small part of their silver flame in exchange.</p>
            <p class="indent"></p>
            <h5>CHOSEN OF MYSTRA FEATURES</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Warlock Level</td><td>Feature</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1st</td><td>Protect the Weave, Expanded Spell List, Minor Spellfire</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6th</td><td>Chosen’s Absorption</td></tr>
                <tr><td>10th</td><td>Arcane Senses</td></tr>
                <tr><td>14th</td><td>Silver Fire</td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_CHOSEN_OF_MYSTRA_PROTECT_THE_WEAVE" />
            <div element="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_CHOSEN_OF_MYSTRA_EXPANDED_SPELL_LIST" />
            <div element="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_CHOSEN_OF_MYSTRA_MINOR_SPELLFIRE" />
            <div element="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_CHOSEN_OF_MYSTRA_CHOSENS_ABSORPTION" />
            <div element="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_CHOSEN_OF_MYSTRA_ARCANE_SENSES" />
            <div element="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_CHOSEN_OF_MYSTRA_SILVER_FIRE" />
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_CHOSEN_OF_MYSTRA_PROTECT_THE_WEAVE" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_CHOSEN_OF_MYSTRA_EXPANDED_SPELL_LIST" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_CHOSEN_OF_MYSTRA_MINOR_SPELLFIRE" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_CHOSEN_OF_MYSTRA_CHOSENS_ABSORPTION" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_CHOSEN_OF_MYSTRA_ARCANE_SENSES" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_CHOSEN_OF_MYSTRA_SILVER_FIRE" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Expanded Spell List" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_CHOSEN_OF_MYSTRA_EXPANDED_SPELL_LIST">
            <description>
                <p>The following spells are added to the warlock spell list for you.</p>
                <h5>CHOSEN OF MYSTRA EXPANDED SPELLS</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Spell Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1st</td><td>identify, magic missile</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>2nd</td><td>arcanist’s magic aura, dragon’s breath</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td>glyph of warding, nondetection</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>4th</td><td>conjure minor elementals, resilient sphere</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td>arcane hand, far step</td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <spellcasting name="Warlock" extend="true">
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_IDENTIFY</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGIC_MISSILE</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_ARCANISTS_MAGIC_AURA</extend>
                <extend>ID_XGTE_SPELL_DRAGONS_BREATH</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_GLYPH_OF_WARDING</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_NONDETECTION</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_CONJURE_MINOR_ELEMENTALS</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_OTILUKES_RESILIENT_SPHERE</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_ARCANE_HAND</extend>
                <extend>ID_XGTE_SPELL_FAR_STEP</extend>
            </spellcasting>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Protect the Weave" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_CHOSEN_OF_MYSTRA_PROTECT_THE_WEAVE">
            <description>
                <p>Occasionally, warlocks of a Chosen of Mystra will receive missives from their patron, ordering them to investigate an event that might cause damage to the Weave. Such events might range from a ritual all the way to an act of the divine. Often, these events will be orchestrated purposely by an evil entity; however, it is still somewhat likely that a Wizard haphazardly creates a broken summoning circle. Work with your DM to determine such scenarios and explore them with your party.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Minor Spellfire" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_CHOSEN_OF_MYSTRA_MINOR_SPELLFIRE">
            <description>
                <p>When you choose this patron at 1st level, you possess a fragment of Mystra’s spellfire, a flame that protects you from compulsory effects.</p>
                <p class="indent">At the start of each of your turns, or as an action, you can end one effect for yourself that is causing you to be charmed or frightened.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can use this feature twice, and expended uses are replenished when you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="2/Short Rest">
                <description>At the start of each of your turns, or as an action, you can end one effect for yourself that is causing you to be charmed or frightened.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Chosen’s Absorption" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_CHOSEN_OF_MYSTRA_CHOSENS_ABSORPTION">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 6th level, you gain some of the magical resistance of a Chosen, allowing you to convert spell power into your own power. You can cast <i>counterspell</i> once per short or long rest without expending a spell slot. When cast via this feature, you can add your proficiency bonus to the spell’s ability check.</p>
                <p class="indent">Whenever you succeed at countering a spell, for 1 minute, when you roll damage for a spell, you can roll one of the spell’s damage dice and add the result to the damage you deal, and your warlock spell save DC increases by 1. If a spell has multiple damage dice, you choose which die to roll for this feature.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
                <description>You can cast counterspell without expending a spell slot. When cast via this feature, you can add your proficiency bonus to the spell’s ability check.
                Whenever you succeed at countering a spell, for 1 minute, when you roll damage for a spell, you can roll one of the spell’s damage dice and add the result to the damage you deal, and your warlock spell save DC increases by 1. If a spell has multiple damage dice, you choose which die to roll for this feature.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COUNTERSPELL" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Arcane Senses" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_CHOSEN_OF_MYSTRA_ARCANE_SENSES">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 10th level, you can give yourself magical sight, allowing you to project your vision and sense arcane energy.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can cast <i>clairvoyance</i> using a warlock spell slot. When cast via this feature, the spell’s casting time is 1 action, and when you see through the sensor, you can see as if you were under the effects of the detect magic spell.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can cast clairvoyance using a warlock spell slot. When cast via this feature, the spell’s casting time is 1 action, and when you see through the sensor, you can see as if you were under the effects of the detect magic spell.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CLAIRVOYANCE" spellcasting="Warlock" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Silver Fire" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_CHOSEN_OF_MYSTRA_SILVER_FIRE">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 14th level, you gain the ability to project your spellfire outward, blasting your enemies.</p>
                <p class="indent">As an action, you can create a line of silver arcane energy that resembles a spout of fire. Creatures in a line 90 feet long and 5 feet wide originating from you must make a Dexterity saving throw against your warlock spell save DC, taking 8d8 force damage on a failure, or half as much damage on a success. This damage bypasses resistance and immunity.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you’ve used this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Short Rest">
                <description>You can create a line of silver arcane energy that resembles a spout of fire. Creatures in a line 90 feet long and 5 feet wide originating from you must make a Dexterity saving throw (save DC {{warlock:spellcasting:dc}}), taking 8d8 force damage on a failure, or half as much damage on a success. This damage bypasses resistance and immunity.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>


    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_ARCHETYPE_OTHERWORLDLY_PATRON_FIEND">
        <supports>EA Otherworldly Patron</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_ARCHETYPE_OTHERWORLDLY_PATRON_THE_ARCHFEY">
        <supports>EA Otherworldly Patron</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_ARCHETYPE_OTHERWORLDLY_PATRON_THE_GREAT_OLD_ONE">
        <supports>EA Otherworldly Patron</supports>
    </append>


<!-- Eldritch Invocations -->
    <element name="Aberrant Implantation" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_ABERRANT_IMPLANTATION">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>9th level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:warlock:9]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 9th level</p>
            <p>You can cast <i>awaken</i> once without expending a spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>You can cast awaken once without expending a spell slot.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AWAKEN" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Ancient Insight" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_ANCIENT_INSIGHT">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>9th level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:warlock:9]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 9th level</p>
            <p>You can cast <i>legend lore</i> once without expending a spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>You can cast legend lore once without expending a spell slot.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LEGEND_LORE" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Arcane Enigma" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_ARCANE_ENIGMA">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>Pact of the Symbol feature, 5th level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:warlock:5],ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_PACT_OF_THE_SYMBOL</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Pact of the Symbol feature, 5th level</p>
            <p>You can cast <i>Nystul’s magic aura</i> at will, without expending a spell slot or material components.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="At will">
            <description>You can cast Nystul’s magic aura without expending a spell slot or material components.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_NYSTULS_MAGIC_AURA" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Armor of Shadows" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_ARMOR_OF_SHADOWS">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You can cast <i>mage armor</i> on yourself at will, without expending a spell slot or material components.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="At will">
            <description>You can cast mage armor on yourself without expending a spell slot or material components.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGE_ARMOR" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Ascendant Step" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_ASCENDANT_STEP">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>9th level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:warlock:9]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Prerequisite: 9th level</p>
            <p>You can cast <i>levitate</i> on yourself at will, without expending a spell slot or material components.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="At will">
            <description>You can cast levitate on yourself without expending a spell slot or material components.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LEVITATE" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Aspect of the Moon" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_ASPECT_OF_THE_MOON">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>Pact of the Tome feature</prerequisite>
        <requirements>ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_PACT_OF_THE_TOME</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Pact of the Tome feature</p>
            <p>You no longer need to sleep and can’t be forced to sleep. To gain the benefits of a long rest, you can spend all 8 hours doing light activity, such as reading your Book of Shadows and keeping watch.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You no longer need to sleep and can’t be forced to sleep.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Beast Song" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_BEAST_SONG">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You can cast <i>speak with animals</i> at will, without expending a spell slot.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="At will">
            <description>You can cast speak with animals without expending a spell slot.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_ANIMALS" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Beguiling Influence" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_BEGUILING_INFLUENCE">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You gain proficiency in the Deception and Persuasion skills. If you’re already proficient in either skill, your proficiency bonus is doubled for any check you make with that skill.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_OR_DOUBLE_DECEPTION" />
            <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_OR_DOUBLE_PERSUASION" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Bewitching Whispers" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_BEWITCHING_WHISPERS">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>7th level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:warlock:7]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 7th level</p>
            <p>You can cast <i>compulsion</i> once without expending a spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>You can cast compulsion without expending a spell slot.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMPULSION" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Bolstered Familiar" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_BOLSTERED_FAMILIAR">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>5th level, Pact of the Chain feature</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:warlock:5],ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_PACT_OF_THE_CHAIN</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 5th level, Pact of the Chain feature</p>
            <p>Your familiar’s maximum hit points increase by an amount equal to 3 times your warlock level, and it now adds your spellcasting ability modifier to its AC and saving throws, to ability checks using skills with which it is proficient, to its attack and damage rolls, and to the saving throw DCs of its spells and abilities.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Your familiar’s maximum hit points increase {{bolstered-familiar:hp}}, and it now adds {{spell-ability:mod}} to its AC and saving throws, to ability checks using skills with which it is proficient, to its attack and damage rolls, and to the saving throw DCs of its spells and abilities.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="bolstered-familiar:hp" value="level:warlock" />
            <stat name="bolstered-familiar:hp" value="level:warlock" />
            <stat name="bolstered-familiar:hp" value="level:warlock" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Book of Ancient Secrets" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_BOOK_OF_ANCIENT_SECRETS">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>Pact of the Tome feature</prerequisite>
        <requirements></requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Pact of the Tome feature</p>
            <p>You can now inscribe magical rituals in your Book of Shadows. Choose two 1st-level spells that have the ritual tag from any class’s spell list (the two needn’t be from the same list). The spells appear in the book and don’t count against the number of spells you know. With your Book of Shadows in hand, you can cast the chosen spells as rituals. You can’t cast the spells except as rituals, unless you’ve learned them by some other means. You can also cast a warlock spell you know as a ritual if it has the ritual tag.</p>
            <p class="indent">On your adventures, you can add other ritual spells to your Book of Shadows. When you find such a spell, you can add it to the book if the spell’s level is equal to or less than half your warlock level (rounded up) and if you can spare the time to transcribe the spell. For each level of the spell, the transcription process takes 2 hours and costs 50 gp for the rare inks needed to inscribe it.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="Ritual">
            <description>With your Book of Shadows in hand, you can cast the chosen spells as rituals. You can’t cast the spells except as rituals, unless you’ve learned them by some other means. You can also cast a warlock spell you know as a ritual if it has the ritual tag.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Spell" name="Book of Ancient Secrets" supports="Ritual,1" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Breath of the Night" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_BREATH_OF_THE_NIGHT">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>5th level, Pact of the Effigy feature</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:warlock:5],ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_PACT_OF_THE_EFFIGY</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 5th level, Pact of the Effigy feature</p>
            <p>As a bonus action, you create a fog of thick, web-like projections in a 15-foot radius around you, which lasts until the start of your next turn and moves with you. You can automatically steal the essence of any creature who enters the area for the first time on a turn or starts its turn there, as per your Pact of the Effigy feature. This area is difficult terrain, and when a creature attacks while within the area, you can deal necrotic damage equal to your spellcasting ability modifier (minimum of 1) to the creature.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can choose any number of creatures when you use this invocation, causing those creatures to ignore the invocation’s effects.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="" action="Bonus Action">
            <description>You create a fog of thick, web-like projections in a 15-foot radius around you, which lasts until the start of your next turn and moves with you. You can automatically steal the essence of any creature who enters the area for the first time on a turn or starts its turn there, as per your Pact of the Effigy feature. This area is difficult terrain, and when a creature attacks while within the area, you can deal {{spell-ability:mod}} points necrotic damage to the creature.
            You can choose any number of creatures when you use this invocation, causing those creatures to ignore the invocation’s effects.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Call of the Lost" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_CALL_OF_THE_LOST">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>3rd level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:warlock:3]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 3rd level</p>
            <p>You can cast <i>phantasmal force</i> once, without expending a spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>You can cast phantasmal force once, without expending a spell slot.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PHANTASMAL_FORCE" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Chains of Carceri" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_CHAINS_OF_CARCERI">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>14th level, Pact of the Chain feature</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:warlock:14],ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_PACT_OF_THE_CHAIN</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 14th level, Pact of the Chain feature</p>
            <p>You can cast hold monster at will — targeting a celestial, fiend, or elemental — without expending a spell slot or material components. You must finish a long rest before you can use this invocation on the same creature again.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="At will">
            <description>You can cast hold monster at will — targeting a celestial, fiend, or elemental — without expending a spell slot or material components. You must finish a long rest before you can use this invocation on the same creature again.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HOLD_MONSTER" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Cloak of Flies" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_CLOAK_OF_FLIES">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>5th level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:warlock:5]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 5th level</p>
            <p>As a bonus action, you can surround yourself with a magical aura that looks like buzzing flies. The aura extends 5 feet from you in every direction, but not through total cover. It lasts until you’re incapacitated or you dismiss it as a bonus action.</p>
            <p class="indent">The aura grants you advantage on Charisma (Intimidation) checks but disadvantage on all other Charisma checks. Any other creature that starts its turn in the aura takes poison damage equal to your spellcasting ability modifier (minimum of 0 damage).</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you use this invocation, you can’t use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Short Rest" action="Bonus Action">
            <description>You can surround yourself with a magical aura that looks like buzzing flies. The aura extends 5 feet from you in every direction, but not through total cover. It lasts until you’re incapacitated or you dismiss it as a bonus action.
            The aura grants you advantage on Charisma (Intimidation) checks but disadvantage on all other Charisma checks. Any other creature that starts its turn in the aura takes {{spell-ability:mod}} points poison damage.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Devil’s Sight" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_DEVILS_SIGHT">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You can see normally in darkness, both magical and non-magical, to a distance of 120 feet.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="">
            <description>You can see normally in darkness, both magical and non-magical, to a distance of 120 feet.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Dreadful Word" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_DREADFUL_WORD">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>7th level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:warlock:7]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 7th level</p>
            <p>You can cast <i>confusion</i> once without expending a spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>You can cast confusion once without expending a spell slot.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Ejection of Spirit" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_EJECTION_OF_SPIRIT">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>Pact of the Effigy feature</prerequisite>
        <requirements>ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_PACT_OF_THE_EFFIGY</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Pact of the Effigy feature</p>
            <p>While your effigy has a creature’s essence in it, you can use your reaction when you are attacked to eject the essence, attempting to absorb the blow. Roll a d20; on an 11 or above, the essence absorbs the attack instead of you, dealing necrotic damage equal to 1d6 + half your warlock level to the essence’s owner. Regardless of your roll on the d20, the essence is destroyed.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Reaction">
            <description>While your effigy has a creature’s essence in it, you can use your reaction when you are attacked to eject the essence, attempting to absorb the blow. Roll a d20; on an 11 or above, the essence absorbs the attack instead of you, dealing necrotic damage equal to 1d6 + {{level:warlock:half}} to the essence’s owner. Regardless of your roll on the d20, the essence is destroyed.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Eldritch Cone" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_ELDRITCH_CONE">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>11th level, Pact of The Gauntlet feature</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:warlock:11],ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_PACT_OF_THE_GAUNTLET</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 11th level, Pact of The Gauntlet feature</p>
            <p>As an action, you create a cone of crackling energy in a 60-foot cone originating from you. Creatures in the area must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes force damage equal to 4d8 plus your spellcasting ability modifier. You can expend a spell slot to increase the damage by 1d8 for each level of the slot. On a successful save, a creature takes half as much damage. You can’t use this invocation again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Short Rest" action="Action">
            <description>You create a cone of crackling energy in a 60-foot cone originating from you. Creatures in the area must make a Dexterity saving throw (save DC {{spellcasting:dc}}). On a failed save, a creature takes force damage equal to 4d8 plus your spellcasting ability modifier. You can expend a spell slot to increase the damage by 1d8 for each level of the slot. On a successful save, a creature takes half as much damage.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Eldritch Doom" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_ELDRITCH_DOOM">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>17th level, Pact of The Gauntlet feature</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:warlock:17],ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_PACT_OF_THE_GAUNTLET</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 17th level, Pact of The Gauntlet feature</p>
            <p>As an action, choose a point that you can see within 120 feet of you. An explosion of crackling energy erupts from that point, filling a 20-foot radius around it. Creatures in the area must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes force damage equal to 7d6 plus your spellcasting ability modifier. You can expend a spell slot to increase the damage by 1d6 for each level of the slot. On a successful save, a creature takes half as much damage. You can’t use this invocation again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Short Rest" action="Action">
            <description>Choose a point that you can see within 120 feet of you. Creatures within a 20-foot radius the area must make a Dexterity saving throw (save DC {{spellcasting:dc}}). On a failed save, a creature takes force damage equal to 7d6 plus {{spell-ability:mod}}. You can expend a spell slot to increase the damage by 1d6 for each level of the slot. On a successful save, a creature takes half as much damage.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Eldritch Sight" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_ELDRITCH_SIGHT">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You can cast <i>detect magic</i> at will, without expending a spell slot.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="At will">
            <description>You can cast detect magic without expending a spell slot.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Eldritch Spear" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_ELDRITCH_SPEAR">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <description>
            <p>When you cast eldritch blast, its range is doubled.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you cast eldritch blast, its range is doubled.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Eldritch Wave" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_ELDRITCH_WAVE">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>5th level, Pact of The Gauntlet feature</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:warlock:5],ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_PACT_OF_THE_GAUNTLET</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 5th level, Pact of The Gauntlet feature</p>
            <p>As an action, you create a beam of crackling energy 5-feet wide and 30-feet long. Creatures in the area must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes force damage equal to 2d10, plus your spellcasting ability modifier. You can expend a spell slot to increase the damage by 1d10 for each level of the slot. On a successful save, a creature takes half as much damage. You can’t use this invocation again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Short Rest" action="Action">
            <description>You create a beam of crackling energy 5-feet wide and 30-feet long. Creatures in the area must make a Dexterity saving throw (save DC {{spellcasting:dc}}). On a failed save, a creature takes force damage equal to 2d10, plus your spellcasting ability modifier. You can expend a spell slot to increase the damage by 1d10 for each level of the slot. On a successful save, a creature takes half as much damage.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Essence Devourer" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_ESSENCE_DEVOURER">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>17th level, Pact of the Armory feature</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:warlock:17],ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_PACT_OF_THE_ARMORY</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 17th level, Pact of the Armory feature</p>
            <p>Once on each of your turns, when you hit a creature with a weapon attack using your pact weapon, you can regain hit points equal to half the damage dealt (minimum of 0).</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Once on each of your turns, when you hit a creature with a weapon attack using your pact weapon, you can regain hit points equal to half the damage dealt (minimum of 0).</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Eyes of the Rune Keeper" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_EYES_OF_THE_RUNE_KEEPER">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You automatically understand the meaning of any non-magical writing that you read, and you can see writing that is invisible.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="">
            <description>You automatically understand the meaning of any non-magical writing that you read, and you can see writing that is invisible.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Fate’s Vice" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_FATES_VICE">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>17th level, Pact of the Effigy feature</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:warlock:17],ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_PACT_OF_THE_EFFIGY</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 17th level, Pact of the Effigy feature</p>
            <p>When you deal damage with a curse, you can choose to deal psychic damage instead of the curse’s damage type. Also, while a creature is cursed by you, you can deal psychic damage equal to your spellcasting ability modifier to it at the start of each of its turns, as long as the creature is on the same plane of existence as you.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="">
            <description>When you deal damage with a curse, you can choose to deal psychic damage instead of the curse’s damage type. Also, while a creature is cursed by you, you can deal {{spell-ability:mod}} psychic damage to it at the start of each of its turns, as long as the creature is on the same plane of existence as you.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Fiendish Vigor" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_FIENDISH_VIGOR">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You can cast <i>false life</i> on yourself at will at its lowest level, without expending a spell slot or material components.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="At will">
            <description>You can cast false life on yourself at its lowest level, without expending a spell slot or material components.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FALSE_LIFE" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Gaze of Two Minds" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_GAZE_OF_TWO_MINDS">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You can use your action to touch a willing humanoid and perceive through its senses until the end of your next turn. As long as the creature is on the same plane of existence as you, you can use your action on subsequent turns to extend the duration until the end of your next turn. While perceiving through the other creature’s senses, you benefit from any special senses possessed by that creature, and you are blinded and deafened to your own surroundings.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Action">
            <description>You can touch a willing humanoid and perceive through its senses until the end of your next turn. As long as the creature is on the same plane of existence as you, you can use your action on subsequent turns to extend the duration until the end of your next turn. While perceiving through the other creature’s senses, you benefit from any special senses possessed by that creature, and you are blinded and deafened to your own surroundings.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Ghostly Gaze" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_GHOSTLY_GAZE">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>7th level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:warlock:7]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 7th level</p>
            <p>As an action, you gain the ability to see through solid objects to a range of 30 feet. Within that range, you have darkvision if you don’t already have it. This special sight lasts for 1 minute or until your concentration ends (as if you were concentrating on a spell). During that time, you perceive objects as ghostly, transparent images. You can’t use this invocation again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Short Rest" action="Action">
            <description>You gain the ability to see through solid objects to a range of 30 feet. Within that range, you have darkvision if you don’t already have it. This special sight lasts for 1 minute or until your concentration ends (as if you were concentrating on a spell).</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Gift of the Depths" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_GIFT_OF_THE_DEPTHS">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>5th lvel</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:warlock:5]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 5th lvel</p>
            <p>You can breathe underwater, and you gain a swimming speed equal to your walking speed.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can also cast <i>water breathing</i> once without expending a spell slot. You regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="">
            <description>You can breathe underwater, and you gain a swimming speed equal to your walking speed.
            You can also cast water breathing once without expending a spell slot. You regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WATER_BREATHING" />
            <stat name="speed:swim" value="speed" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Gift of the Ever-Living Ones" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_GIFT_OF_THE_EVERLIVING_ONES">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>Pact of The Chain feature</prerequisite>
        <requirements>ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_PACT_OF_THE_CHAIN</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Pact of The Chain feature</p>
            <p>Whenever you regain hit points while your familiar is within 100 feet of you, treat any dice rolled to determine the hit points you regain as having rolled their maximum value for you.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Whenever you regain hit points while your familiar is within 100 feet of you, treat any dice rolled to determine the hit points you regain as having rolled their maximum value for you.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Grasp of Hadar" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_GRASP_OF_HADAR">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with your eldritch blast, you can move the target in a straight line 10 feet closer to you.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with your eldritch blast, you can move the target in a straight line 10 feet closer to you.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Hideous Blow" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_HIDEOUS_BLOW">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>Pact of The Gauntlet feature</prerequisite>
        <requirements>ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_PACT_OF_THE_GAUNTLET</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Pact of The Gauntlet feature</p>
            <p>When you cast eldritch blast, you can replace any number of the beams with an equal number of melee spell attacks. These attacks deal force damage equal to 1d12 + your spellcasting ability modifier.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you cast eldritch blast, you can replace any number of the beams with an equal number of melee spell attacks. These attacks deal force damage equal to 1d12 + {{spell-ability:mod}}.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Hefted Spell" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_HEFTED_SPELL">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>11th level, Pact of The Symbol feature</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:warlock:11],ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_PACT_OF_THE_SYMBOL</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 11th level, Pact of The Symbol feature</p>
            <p>While you hold your patron’s symbol, you can increase the range of any spell you cast with a range of 5 feet or more by 25 feet, and the written size of any area affected by your spells by 10 feet. For example, cloud of daggers affects a 15-foot cube, and darknessaffects a 30-foot radius.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>While you hold your patron’s symbol, the range of any spell you cast with a range of 5 feet or more increases by 25 feet, and the written size of any area affected by your spells by 10 feet.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Horrific Shackles" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_HORRIFIC_SHACKLES">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>7th level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:warlock:7]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 7th level</p>
            <p>You can cast <i>phantasmal killer</i> once without expending a spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>You can cast phantasmal killer once without expending a spell slot.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PHANTASMAL_KILLER" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Improved Pact Weapon" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_IMPROVED_PACT_WEAPON">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>Pact of the Armory feature</prerequisite>
        <requirements>ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_PACT_OF_THE_ARMORY</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Pact of the Armory feature</p>
            <p>You can use any weapon you summon with your Pact of the Armory feature as a spellcasting focus for your warlock spells.</p>
            <p class="indent">Additionally, once per turn when you hit a creature with your pact weapon, you can expend a warlock spell slot to deal an extra 1d8 force damage to the target, plus another 1d8 per level of the spell slot, and you can knock the target prone if it is Huge or smaller.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can use any weapon you summon with your Pact of the Armory feature as a spellcasting focus.
            Once per turn when you hit a creature with your pact weapon, you can expend a warlock spell slot to deal an extra 1d8 force damage to the target, plus another 1d8 per level of the spell slot, and you can knock the target prone if it is Huge or smaller.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Lance of Lethargy" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_LANCE_OF_LETHARGY">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with your eldritch blast, you can reduce that creature’s speed by 10 feet until the end of your next turn.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with your eldritch blast, you can reduce that creature’s speed by 10 feet until the end of your next turn.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Lifedrinker" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_LIFEDRINKER">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>11th level, Pact of the Armory feature</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:warlock:11],ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_PACT_OF_THE_ARMORY</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 11th level, Pact of the Armory feature</p>
            <p>When you hit with your pact weapon, you can deal extra necrotic damage equal to your spellcasting ability modifier (minimum of 1).</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="">
            <description>When you hit with your pact weapon, you can deal {{spell-ability:mod}} points extra necrotic damage.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Liminal Loop" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_LIMINAL_LOOP">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>5th level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:warlock:5]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 5th level</p>
            <p>When you cast a warlock cantrip which deals damage, instead of increasing that damage when you reach certain levels, you can cast the cantrip additional times as part of the same action. To be eligible, the cantrip must make a spell attack or require a saving throw. You can cast it two times at 5th level, three times at 11th level, and four times at 17th level. When you do, the cantrip can deal its damage more than once, but its other effects are not applied again.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you cast a warlock cantrip which deals damage, instead of increasing that damage when you reach certain levels, you can cast the cantrip two times as part of the same action. The cantrip can deal its damage more than once, but its other effects are not applied again.</description>
            <description level="11">When you cast a warlock cantrip which deals damage, instead of increasing that damage when you reach certain levels, you can cast the cantrip three times as part of the same action. The cantrip can deal its damage more than once, but its other effects are not applied again.</description>
            <description level="17">When you cast a warlock cantrip which deals damage, instead of increasing that damage when you reach certain levels, you can cast the cantrip four times as part of the same action. The cantrip can deal its damage more than once, but its other effects are not applied again.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Loremaster’s Bargain" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_LOREMASTERS_BARGAIN">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>17th level, Pact of the Tome feature</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:warlock:17],ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_PACT_OF_THE_TOME</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 17th level, Pact of the Tome feature</p>
            <p>You learn one additional cantrip of your choice from any class’ spell list, which counts as a warlock cantrip for you. Whenever you finish a long rest, you can replace any number of your warlock cantrips with a new choices from the warlock spell list.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Whenever you finish a long rest, you can replace any number of your warlock cantrips with a new choices from the warlock spell list.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Spell" name="Loremaster’s Bargain" supports="0" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Maddening Hex" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_MADDENING_HEX">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>5th level, hex spell or a warlock feature that curses</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:warlock:5],(ID_PHB_SPELL_HEX||ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_SHADOWFORCE_HEXBLADES_CURSE||ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_SIGN_OF_ILL_OMEN)</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 5th level, hex spell or a warlock feature that curses</p>
            <p>As a bonus action, you cause a psychic disturbance around the target cursed by your hex spell or by a warlock feature of yours, such as Sign of Ill Omen. When you do so, you deal psychic damage to the cursed target and each creature of your choice that you can see within 5 feet of it. The psychic damage equals half your warlock level. To use this invocation, you must be able to see the cursed target, and it must be within 30 feet of you.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Bonus Action">
            <description>You can deal {{level:warlock:half}} points psychic damage to a target you have cursed, as long as it’s within 30 feet, and each creature of your choice that you can see within 5 feet of it.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Mask of Many Faces" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_MASK_OF_MANY_FACES">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You can cast <i>disguise self</i> at will, without expending a spell slot.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="At will">
            <description>You can cast disguise self without expending a spell slot.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISGUISE_SELF" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Master’s Bindings" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_MASTERS_BINDINGS">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>17th level, Pact of the Symbol feature</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:warlock:17],ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_PACT_OF_THE_SYMBOL</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 17th level, Pact of the Symbol feature</p>
            <p>While your patron’s symbol is on your person, you have advantage on ability checks and saving throws made against spells or for spells you cast, and the DC of ability checks other creatures make against your warlock spells increases by half your warlock level.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>While your patron’s symbol is on your person, you have advantage on ability checks and saving throws made against spells or for spells you cast, and the DC of ability checks other creatures make against your warlock spells increases by {{level:warlock:half}}.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Master of Myriad Forms" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_MASTER_OF_MYRIAD_FORMS">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>14th level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:warlock:14]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 14th level</p>
            <p>You can cast <i>alter self</i> at will, without expending a spell slot.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="At will">
            <description>You can cast alter self without expending a spell slot.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Materializing Focus" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_MATERIALIZING_FOCUS">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>Pact of the Symbol feature</prerequisite>
        <requirements>ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_PACT_OF_THE_SYMBOL</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Pact of the Symbol feature</p>
            <p>When you cast a warlock spell using your patron’s symbol as a spellcasting focus, you can forego providing a material component if its value is no more than 25gp times your warlock level.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you cast a warlock spell using your patron’s symbol as a spellcasting focus, you can forego providing a material component if its value is no more than {{materializing-focus:cost}}gp.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="materializing-focus:cost" value="25" requirements="[level:warlock:1]" />
            <stat name="materializing-focus:cost" value="25" requirements="[level:warlock:2]" />
            <stat name="materializing-focus:cost" value="25" requirements="[level:warlock:3]" />
            <stat name="materializing-focus:cost" value="25" requirements="[level:warlock:4]" />
            <stat name="materializing-focus:cost" value="25" requirements="[level:warlock:5]" />
            <stat name="materializing-focus:cost" value="25" requirements="[level:warlock:6]" />
            <stat name="materializing-focus:cost" value="25" requirements="[level:warlock:7]" />
            <stat name="materializing-focus:cost" value="25" requirements="[level:warlock:8]" />
            <stat name="materializing-focus:cost" value="25" requirements="[level:warlock:9]" />
            <stat name="materializing-focus:cost" value="25" requirements="[level:warlock:10]" />
            <stat name="materializing-focus:cost" value="25" requirements="[level:warlock:11]" />
            <stat name="materializing-focus:cost" value="25" requirements="[level:warlock:12]" />
            <stat name="materializing-focus:cost" value="25" requirements="[level:warlock:13]" />
            <stat name="materializing-focus:cost" value="25" requirements="[level:warlock:14]" />
            <stat name="materializing-focus:cost" value="25" requirements="[level:warlock:15]" />
            <stat name="materializing-focus:cost" value="25" requirements="[level:warlock:16]" />
            <stat name="materializing-focus:cost" value="25" requirements="[level:warlock:17]" />
            <stat name="materializing-focus:cost" value="25" requirements="[level:warlock:18]" />
            <stat name="materializing-focus:cost" value="25" requirements="[level:warlock:19]" />
            <stat name="materializing-focus:cost" value="25" requirements="[level:warlock:20]" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Minions of Chaos" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_MINIONS_OF_CHAOS">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>9th level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:warlock:9]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 9th level</p>
            <p>You can cast <i>conjure elemental</i> once without expending a spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>You can cast conjure elemental once without expending a spell slot.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONJURE_ELEMENTAL" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Mire the Mind" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_MIRE_THE_MIND">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>5th level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:warlock:5]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 5th level</p>
            <p>You can cast <i>slow</i> once without expending a spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>You can cast slow once without expending a spell slot.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SLOW" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Misty Visions" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_MISTY_VISIONS">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You can cast <i>silent image</i> at will, without expending a spell slot or material components.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="">
            <description>You can cast silent image without expending a spell slot or material components.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SILENT_IMAGE" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="One with Shadows" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_ONE_WITH_SHADOWS">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>5th level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:warlock:5]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 5th level</p>
            <p>When you are in dim light or darkness, you can use your action to become invisible until you move, take an action, or take a reaction.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Action">
            <description>When you are in dim light or darkness, you can become invisible until you move, take an action, or take a reaction.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Otherworldly Leap" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_OTHERWORLDLY_LEAP">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>7th level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:warlock:7]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 7th level</p>
            <p>You can cast <i>jump</i> on yourself at will, without expending a spell slot or material components.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="At will">
            <description>You can cast jump on yourself without expending a spell slot or material components.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_JUMP" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Otherworldly Whispers" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_OTHERWORLDLY_WHISPERS">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You gain proficiency in the Arcana and Religion skills. If you’re already proficient in either skill, your proficiency bonus is doubled for any check you make with that skill.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_OR_DOUBLE_ARCANA" />
            <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_OR_DOUBLE_RELIGION" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Pact-Forged Counsel" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_PACTFORGED_COUNSEL">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>20th level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:warlock:20]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 20th level</p>
            <p>You can cast planar ally once without expending a spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>You can cast planar ally once without expending a spell slot.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Relentless Hex" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_RELENTLESS_HEX">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>7th level, hex spell or a warlock feature that curses</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:warlock:7],(ID_PHB_SPELL_HEX||ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_SHADOWFORCE_HEXBLADES_CURSE||ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_SIGN_OF_ILL_OMEN)</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 7th level, hex spell or a warlock feature that curses</p>
            <p>As a bonus action, you can teleport up to 30 feet to an unoccupied space you can see within 5 feet of the target cursed by your hex spell or by a warlock feature of yours, such as Sign of Ill Omen. To teleport in this way, you must be able to see the cursed target.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Bonus Action">
            <description>You can teleport up to 30 feet to an unoccupied space you can see within 5 feet of the target cursed by your hex spell or by a warlock feature of yours. To teleport in this way, you must be able to see the cursed target.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Repelling Blast" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_REPELLING_BLAST">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <description>
            <p>When you hit a creature with eldritch blast, you can push the creature up to 10 feet away from you in a straight line.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you hit a creature with eldritch blast, you can push the creature up to 10 feet away from you in a straight line.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Scribe of Ancient Knowledge" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_SCRIBE_OF_ANCIENT_KNOWLEDGE">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>5th level, Pact of the Tome feature</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:warlock:5],ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_PACT_OF_THE_TOME</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 5th level, Pact of the Tome feature</p>
            <p>Instead of knowing spells, you now prepare a number of spells equal to the Spells Known column of the warlock table plus your spellcasting ability modifier from the warlock spell list. A spell you choose must be of a level no greater than what’s shown in the Warlock table’s Slot Level column for your level. You can change any number of your prepared spells whenever you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Sculptor of Flesh" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_SCULPTOR_OF_FLESH">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>7th level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:warlock:7]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 7th level</p>
            <p>You can cast <i>polymorph</i> once without expending a spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>You can cast polymorph once without expending a spell slot.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_POLYMORPH" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Two Wise Monkeys" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_TWO_WISE_MONKEYS">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>3rd level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:warlock:3]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 3rd level</p>
            <p>You can cast blindness/deafness once without expending a spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>You can cast blindness/deafness once without expending a spell slot.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLINDNESS_DEAFNESS" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Shepherd of the Occult" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_SHEPHERD_OF_THE_OCCULT">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>11th level, Pact of the Effigy feature</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:warlock:11],ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_PACT_OF_THE_EFFIGY</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 11th level, Pact of the Effigy feature</p>
            <p>You can cast <i>scrying</i> at will - targeting a creature cursed by you - without expending a spell slot or providing material components. Your curse counts as a body part for the purposes of calculating the save DC for the spell.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="At will">
            <description>You can cast scrying at will - targeting a creature cursed by you - without expending a spell slot or providing material components. Your curse counts as a body part for the purposes of calculating the save DC for the spell.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SCRYING" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Shroud of Shadow" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_SHROUD_OF_SHADOW">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>14th level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:warlock:14]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 14th level</p>
            <p>You can cast invisibility at will, without expending a spell slot.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="At will">
            <description>You can cast invisibility without expending a spell slot.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INVISIBILITY" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Sign of Ill Omen" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_SIGN_OF_ILL_OMEN">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>5th level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:warlock:5]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 5th level</p>
            <p>You can cast <i>bestow curse</i> once without expending a spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>You can cast bestow curse once without expending a spell slot.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Sovereign Arcana" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_SOVEREIGN_ARCANA">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>11th level, Pact of the Tome feature</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:warlock:11],ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_PACT_OF_THE_TOME</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 11th level, Pact of the Tome feature</p>
            <p>Whenever you finish a long rest, you may choose new spells from the warlock spell list to replace any of your Mystic Arcanum choices. Each new spell must be of the same spell level as the one it replaces.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Whenever you finish a long rest, you may choose new spells from the warlock spell list to replace any of your Mystic Arcanum choices. Each new spell must be of the same spell level as the one it replaces.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Speech of the Breathless" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_SPEECH_OF_THE_BREATHLESS">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>3rd level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:warlock:3]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 3rd level</p>
            <p>You can cast <i>silence</i> once without expending a spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>You can cast silence once without expending a spell slot.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SILENCE" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Thief of Five Fates" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_THIEF_OF_FIVE_FATES">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You can cast <i>bane</i> once without expending a spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>You can cast bane once without expending a spell slot.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BANE" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Thirsting Blade" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_THIRSTING_BLADE">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>5th level, Pact of the Armory feature</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:warlock:5],ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_PACT_OF_THE_ARMORY</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 5th level, Pact of the Armory feature</p>
            <p>Whenever you take the Attack action on your turn, you can make one additional attack with your pact weapon as part of the same action.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Whenever you take the Attack action on your turn, you can make one additional attack with your pact weapon as part of the same action.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Tomb of Levistus" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_TOMB_OF_LEVISTUS">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>5th level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:warlock:5]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 5th level</p>
            <p>As a reaction when you take damage, you can entomb yourself in ice, which melts away at the end of your next turn. You gain 10 temporary hit points per warlock level, which take as much of the triggering damage as possible. Immediately after you take the damage, you gain vulnerability to fire damage, your speed is reduced to 0, and you are incapacitated. These effects, including any remaining temporary hit points, all end when the ice melts.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you use this invocation, you can’t use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Short Rest" action="Action">
            <description>When you take damage, you can entomb yourself in ice, which melts away at the end of your next turn. You gain {{tomb-of-levistus:temp-hp}} temporary hit points, which take as much of the triggering damage as possible. Immediately after you take the damage, you gain vulnerability to fire damage, your speed is reduced to 0, and you are incapacitated. These effects, including any remaining temporary hit points, all end when the ice melts.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="tomb-of-levistus:temp-hp" value="10" requirements="[level:warlock:1]" />
            <stat name="tomb-of-levistus:temp-hp" value="10" requirements="[level:warlock:2]" />
            <stat name="tomb-of-levistus:temp-hp" value="10" requirements="[level:warlock:3]" />
            <stat name="tomb-of-levistus:temp-hp" value="10" requirements="[level:warlock:4]" />
            <stat name="tomb-of-levistus:temp-hp" value="10" requirements="[level:warlock:5]" />
            <stat name="tomb-of-levistus:temp-hp" value="10" requirements="[level:warlock:6]" />
            <stat name="tomb-of-levistus:temp-hp" value="10" requirements="[level:warlock:7]" />
            <stat name="tomb-of-levistus:temp-hp" value="10" requirements="[level:warlock:8]" />
            <stat name="tomb-of-levistus:temp-hp" value="10" requirements="[level:warlock:9]" />
            <stat name="tomb-of-levistus:temp-hp" value="10" requirements="[level:warlock:10]" />
            <stat name="tomb-of-levistus:temp-hp" value="10" requirements="[level:warlock:11]" />
            <stat name="tomb-of-levistus:temp-hp" value="10" requirements="[level:warlock:12]" />
            <stat name="tomb-of-levistus:temp-hp" value="10" requirements="[level:warlock:13]" />
            <stat name="tomb-of-levistus:temp-hp" value="10" requirements="[level:warlock:14]" />
            <stat name="tomb-of-levistus:temp-hp" value="10" requirements="[level:warlock:15]" />
            <stat name="tomb-of-levistus:temp-hp" value="10" requirements="[level:warlock:16]" />
            <stat name="tomb-of-levistus:temp-hp" value="10" requirements="[level:warlock:17]" />
            <stat name="tomb-of-levistus:temp-hp" value="10" requirements="[level:warlock:18]" />
            <stat name="tomb-of-levistus:temp-hp" value="10" requirements="[level:warlock:19]" />
            <stat name="tomb-of-levistus:temp-hp" value="10" requirements="[level:warlock:20]" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Trickster’s Escape" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_TRICKSTERS_ESCAPE">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>7th level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:warrior:7]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 7th level</p>
            <p>You can cast <i>freedom of movement</i> once without expending a spell slot. You regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>You can cast freedom of movement once without expending a spell slot.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FREEDOM_OF_MOVEMENT" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Usurper in Shadow" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_USURPER_IN_SHADOW">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>11th level, Pact of the Chain feature</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:warrior:11],ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_PACT_OF_THE_CHAIN</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 11th level, Pact of the Chain feature</p>
            <p>You can cast <i>planar binding</i> at will at its lowest level, without expending a spell slot.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="At will">
            <description>You can cast planar binding at its lowest level, without expending a spell slot.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PLANAR_BINDING" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Visions of Distant Realms" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_VISIONS_OF_DISTANT_REALMS">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>14th level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:warrior:14]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 14th level</p>
            <p>You can cast <i>arcane eye</i> at will, without expending a spell slot.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="At will">
            <description>You can cast arcane eye without expending a spell slot.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ARCANE_EYE" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Weaver of Nightmares" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_WEAVER_OF_NIGHTMARES">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>3rd level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:warlock:3]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 3rd level</p>
            <p>You can cast <i>web</i> once without expending a spell slot. You regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>You can cast web once without expending a spell slot.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WEB" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Whispers of the Grave" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_WHISPERS_OF_THE_GRAVE">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>9th level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:warlock:9]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 9th level</p>
            <p>You can cast <i>speak with dead</i> at will, without expending a spell slot.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="At will">
            <description>You can cast speak with dead without expending a spell slot.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Witch Sight" type="Class Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_WITCH_SIGHT">
        <supports>EA Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>14th level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:warlock:14]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 14th level</p>
            <p>You can see the true form of any shapechanger or creature concealed by illusion or transmutation magic while the creature is within 30 feet of you and within line of sight.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="">
            <description>You can see the true form of any shapechanger or creature concealed by illusion or transmutation magic while the creature is within 30 feet of you and within line of sight.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>

</elements>