<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Survivalist Variant Martial Archetype</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="variant-fighter-survivalist.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/subclasses/variant-fighter/variant-fighter-survivalist.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Survivalist" type="Archetype" source="Variant Fighter" id="ID_VDP_VF_ARCHETYPE_VF_SURVIVALIST">
        <supports>Variant Martial Archetype</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Those who model themselves after this archetype have developed the skills to persist and flourish in any environment. They have an innate ability to blend in and use their knowledge of the terrain and its denizens to take every advantage and succeed the day.</p>
            <div element="ID_VDP_VF_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RANGER_OF_THE_WILD" />
            <div element="ID_VDP_VF_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTERS_QUARRY" />
            <div element="ID_VDP_VF_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WILDERNESS_GUIDE" />
            <div element="ID_VDP_VF_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HIDE_IN_PLAIN_SIGHT" />
            <div element="ID_VDP_VF_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STAND_AGAINST_THE_TIDE" />
            <div element="ID_VDP_VF_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SIXTH_SENSE" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_VDP_VF_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RANGER_OF_THE_WILD" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_VDP_VF_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTERS_QUARRY" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_VDP_VF_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WILDERNESS_GUIDE" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_VDP_VF_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HIDE_IN_PLAIN_SIGHT" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_VDP_VF_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STAND_AGAINST_THE_TIDE" level="15" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_VDP_VF_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SIXTH_SENSE" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Ranger of the Wild" type="Archetype Feature" source="Variant Fighter" id="ID_VDP_VF_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RANGER_OF_THE_WILD">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 3rd level, your time spent in the wilderness has honed your survival skills. You gain your choice of three of the following features:</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Forager.</em></strong> When you forage, you find twice as much food as you normally would.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Strider.</em></strong> Moving through nonmagical difficult terrain costs you no extra movement.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Tracker.</em></strong> While tracking other creatures, you also learn their exact number, their sizes, and how long ago they passed through the area.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Trapper.</em></strong> You add your proficiency bonus to the DC for detecting and avoiding the hunting traps that you place.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Trainer.</em></strong> You have advantage on Wisdom (Animal Handling) checks.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Traveler.</em></strong> You learn one language of your choice.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Ranger of the Wild Feature" supports="Ranger of the Wild" number="3" level="3" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Forager" type="Archetype Feature" source="Variant Fighter" id="ID_VDP_VF_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RANGER_OF_THE_WILD_FORAGER">
                <supports>Ranger of the Wild</supports>
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>When you forage, you find twice as much food as you normally would.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>When you forage, you find twice as much food as you normally would.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Strider" type="Archetype Feature" source="Variant Fighter" id="ID_VDP_VF_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RANGER_OF_THE_WILD_STRIDER">
                <supports>Ranger of the Wild</supports>
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>Moving through nonmagical difficult terrain costs you no extra movement.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>Moving through nonmagical difficult terrain costs you no extra movement.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Tracker" type="Archetype Feature" source="Variant Fighter" id="ID_VDP_VF_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RANGER_OF_THE_WILD_TRACKER">
                <supports>Ranger of the Wild</supports>
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>While tracking other creatures, you also learn their exact number, their sizes, and how long ago they passed through the area.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>While tracking other creatures, you also learn their exact number, their sizes, and how long ago they passed through the area.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Trapper" type="Archetype Feature" source="Variant Fighter" id="ID_VDP_VF_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RANGER_OF_THE_WILD_TRAPPER">
                <supports>Ranger of the Wild</supports>
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>You add your proficiency bonus to the DC for detecting and avoiding the hunting traps that you place.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>You add your proficiency bonus to the DC for detecting and avoiding the hunting traps that you place.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Trainer" type="Archetype Feature" source="Variant Fighter" id="ID_VDP_VF_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RANGER_OF_THE_WILD_TRAINER">
                <supports>Ranger of the Wild</supports>
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>You have advantage on Wisdom (Animal Handling) checks.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>You have advantage on Wisdom (Animal Handling) checks.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Traveler" type="Archetype Feature" source="Variant Fighter" id="ID_VDP_VF_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RANGER_OF_THE_WILD_TRAVELER">
                <supports>Ranger of the Wild</supports>
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>You learn one language of your choice.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <select type="Language" name="Language (Ranger of the Wild Traveler)" />
                </rules>
            </element>
        <element name="Hunter’s Quarry" type="Archetype Feature" source="Variant Fighter" id="ID_VDP_VF_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTERS_QUARRY">
            <description>
                <p>Also starting at 3rd level, you’ve learned to hone your sights in on a creature and mark it. As a bonus action, you choose a creature you can see within 100 feet and mark it as your quarry. You must concentrate on this mark as if you were concentrating on a spell, and it lasts up to 1 hour.</p>
                <p class="indent">Until the mark ends, any maneuvers you use that affect this creature also cause it to take damage equal to 1d4 + your Wisdom modifier of a damage type a weapon you’re wielding can deal. In addition, you have advantage on any Wisdom (Perception) or Wisdom (Survival) check you make to find it. If the target drops to 0 hit points before this mark ends, you can use a bonus action on a subsequent turn of yours to mark a new creature.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier (minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you complete a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="{{hunters-quarry:uses}}/Long Rest">
                <description>You choose a creature you can see within 100 feet and mark it as your quarry. You must concentrate on this mark as if you were concentrating on a spell, and it lasts up to 1 hour. Until the mark ends, any maneuvers you use that affect this creature also cause an additional 1d4 + {{wisdom:modifier}} damage. In addition, you have advantage on any Wisdom (Perception) or Wisdom (Survival) check you make to find it. If the target drops to 0 hit points before this mark ends, you can use a bonus action on a subsequent turn of yours to mark a new creature.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="hunters-quarry:uses" value="1" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="hunters-quarry:uses" value="wisdom:modifier" bonus="base" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Wilderness Guide" type="Archetype Feature" source="Variant Fighter" id="ID_VDP_VF_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WILDERNESS_GUIDE">
            <description>
                <p>At 7th level, your adeptness at traveling and surviving in the rough and untamed regions of the world allows you to lead others more easily through any environment. While traveling for an hour or more in the wilderness, you gain the following benefits:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Difficult terrain doesn’t slow your group’s travel.</li>
                    <li>Even when you are engaged in another activity while traveling (such as foraging, navigating, or tracking) you remain alert to danger.</li>
                    <li>You do not suffer the penalty to passive Wisdom (Perception) checks imposed by moving at a fast pace.</li>
                    <li>Your group can move stealthily at a normal pace.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>While traveling for an hour or more in the wilderness, you gain the following benefits: difficult terrain doesn’t slow your group’s travel; even when you are engaged in another activity while traveling (such as foraging, navigating, or tracking) you remain alert to danger; you do not suffer the penalty to passive Wisdom (Perception) checks imposed by moving at a fast pace; and your group can move stealthily at a normal pace.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Hide in Plain Sight" type="Archetype Feature" source="Variant Fighter" id="ID_VDP_VF_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HIDE_IN_PLAIN_SIGHT">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 10th level, you can spend 1 minute creating natural camouflage for yourself. You must have access to fresh mud, dirt, plants, soot, and other naturally occurring materials with which to create your camouflage.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you are camouflaged this way, you gain a +10 bonus to Dexterity (Stealth) checks against creatures while you remain in terrain similar to your natural disguise. Once you move or make an attack, this effect is suppressed until the beginning of your next turn.</p>
                <p class="indent">Your camouflage lasts 1 hour or until physical conditions otherwise ruin it (such as swimming or rain).</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can spend 1 minute creating natural camouflage for yourself. Once you are camouflaged this way, you gain a +10 bonus to Dexterity (Stealth) checks against creatures while you remain in terrain similar to your natural disguise. Once you move or make an attack, this effect is suppressed until the beginning of your next turn. Your camouflage lasts 1 hour or until physical conditions otherwise ruin it (such as swimming or rain).</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Stand Against the Tide" type="Archetype Feature" source="Variant Fighter" id="ID_VDP_VF_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STAND_AGAINST_THE_TIDE">
            <description>
                <p>At 15th level, whenever a creature attacks you and does not have advantage, you can use your reaction to impose disadvantage on the creature’s attack roll against you. You can use this feature before or after the attack roll is made, but it must be used before the outcome of the roll is determined.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Reaction">
                <description>Whenever a creature attacks you and does not have advantage, you can impose disadvantage on the creature’s attack roll against you.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Sixth Sense" type="Archetype Feature" source="Variant Fighter" id="ID_VDP_VF_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SIXTH_SENSE">
            <description>
                <p>At 18th level, you gain preternatural senses that help you fight creatures you can’t see. When you attack a creature you can’t see, your inability to see it doesn’t impose disadvantage on your attack rolls against it.</p>
                <p class="indent">You are also aware of the location of any invisible creature within 30 feet of you, provided that the creature isn’t hidden from you and you aren’t blinded or deafened.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you attack a creature you can’t see, your inability to see it doesn’t impose disadvantage on your attack rolls against it. You are also aware of the location of any invisible creature within 30 feet of you, provided that the creature isn’t hidden from you and you aren’t blinded or deafened.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    <!-- Maneuvers -->
        <element name="Tracer" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_VDP_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_VF_MANEUVER_TRACER">
            <supports>Variant Fighter Maneuver</supports>
            <requirements>ID_VDP_VF_ARCHETYPE_VF_SURVIVALIST</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Survivalist archetype</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Survivalist archetype</p>
                <p>When you first apply your Hunter’s Quarry feature to a creature, your next attack roll against the creature is made with advantage.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Superiority.</em></strong> You can immediately make one weapon attack against a creature you applied Hunter’s Quarry to this turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you first apply your Hunter’s Quarry feature to a creature, your next attack roll against the creature is made with advantage. Superiority: You can immediately make one weapon attack against a creature you applied Hunter’s Quarry to this turn.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Volley" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_VDP_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_VF_MANEUVER_VOLLEY">
            <supports>Variant Fighter Maneuver</supports>
            <requirements>ID_VDP_VF_ARCHETYPE_VF_SURVIVALIST</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Survivalist archetype</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Survivalist archetype</p>
                <p>Choose two creatures within 5 feet of each other that you can see within your weapon’s normal range. You can forgo one of your attacks and make a single volley attack against both creatures. You must have enough ammunition for each target. Make a single attack roll against both creatures. If this attack hits, the targets take your weapon’s normal damage, but you do not add your ability modifier.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Superiority.</em></strong> You can target any number of creatures within 5 feet of a single point that you can see within your weapon’s range. You must have enough ammunition for each target.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can forgo one of your attacks and make a single volley attack against two creatures within 5 feet of each other that you can see within your weapon’s normal range. You must have enough ammunition for each target. Make a single attack roll against both creatures. If this attack hits, the targets take your weapon’s normal damage, but you do not add your ability modifier. Superiority: You can target any number of creatures within 5 feet of a single point that you can see within your weapon’s range. You must have enough ammunition for each target.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Whirlwind" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_VDP_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_VF_MANEUVER_WHIRLWIND">
            <supports>Variant Fighter Maneuver</supports>
            <requirements>ID_VDP_VF_ARCHETYPE_VF_SURVIVALIST</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Survivalist archetype</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Survivalist archetype</p>
                <p>Choose any number of creatures within your reach. You can use your action to make a separate melee attack against each of them. You deal damage equal to your attack modifier to each creature you hit.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Superiority.</em></strong> You deal your normal weapon damage to each creature you hit.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>You can make a separate melee attack against any number of creatures within your reach. You deal damage equal to your attack modifier to each creature you hit. Superiority: You deal your normal weapon damage to each creature you hit.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    
</elements>