<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Blood Knight Maneuvers</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="variant-fighter-blood-knight-maneuvers.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/subclasses/variant-fighter/variant-fighter-blood-knight-maneuvers.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Blood Knight Maneuvers" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_LOBSTERDOG_GMBINDER_SOURCE_Blood Knight Maneuvers">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation">BKM</set>
            <set name="url">https://www.gmbinder.com/share/-LGkyNUbYlkBP9NmI2pK</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" abbreviation="LD" url="">Lobster Dog</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20200904</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
    <append id="ID_JONOMAN3000_DAPC_ARCHETYPE_MARTIAL_ARCHETYPE_BLOOD_KNIGHT">
        <supports>Variant Martial Archetype</supports>
    </append>

    <element name="Bleeding Edge" type="Class Feature" source="Blood Knight Maneuvers" id="ID_LD_BKM_CLASS_FEATURE_VF_MANEUVER_BLEEDING_EDGE">
        <supports>Variant Fighter Maneuver</supports>
        <requirements>ID_JONOMAN3000_DAPC_ARCHETYPE_MARTIAL_ARCHETYPE_BLOOD_KNIGHT</requirements>
        <prerequisite>Blood Knight archetype</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Blood Knight archetype</p>
            <p>After you cast a hemomancy spell of 1st level or higher, the next creature you hit with a weapon attack takes additional necrotic damage at the beginning of its next turn equal to the number of hit points you spent to cast the spell.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Superiority.</em></strong> The damage dealt by this maneuver ignores resistance to necrotic damage. Additionally, you can expend a Blood Die when you trigger this superiority option to add the number rolled to the damage dealt by this maneuver.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>After you cast a hemomancy spell of 1st level or higher, the next creature you hit with a weapon attack takes additional necrotic damage at the beginning of its next turn equal to the number of hit points you spent to cast the spell. Superiority: The damage dealt by this maneuver ignores resistance to necrotic damage. Additionally, you can expend a Blood Die when you trigger this superiority option to add the number rolled to the damage dealt by this maneuver.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Coagulate" type="Class Feature" source="Blood Knight Maneuvers" id="ID_LD_BKM_CLASS_FEATURE_VF_MANEUVER_COAGULATE">
        <supports>Variant Fighter Maneuver</supports>
        <requirements>ID_JONOMAN3000_DAPC_ARCHETYPE_MARTIAL_ARCHETYPE_BLOOD_KNIGHT</requirements>
        <prerequisite>Blood Knight archetype</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Blood Knight archetype</p>
            <p>When you take the attack action on your turn, you can forgo one of your attacks to thicken your foe’s blood. The target must make a Strength saving throw. On a failed save, the target has disadvantage on Strength checks until the end of your next turn.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Superiority.</em></strong> If the target fails its saving throw, its speed is also reduced to 0 until the end of your next turn.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can forgo one of your attacks to thicken your foe’s blood. The target must make a Strength saving throw. On a failed save, the target has disadvantage on Strength checks until the end of your next turn. Superiority: If the target fails its saving throw, its speed is also reduced to 0 until the end of your next turn.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Endure" type="Class Feature" source="Blood Knight Maneuvers" id="ID_LD_BKM_CLASS_FEATURE_VF_MANEUVER_ENDURE">
        <supports>Variant Fighter Maneuver</supports>
        <requirements>ID_JONOMAN3000_DAPC_ARCHETYPE_MARTIAL_ARCHETYPE_BLOOD_KNIGHT</requirements>
        <prerequisite>Blood Knight archetype</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Blood Knight archetype</p>
            <p>When you take damage, you can use your reaction and expend a Blood Die to reduce the damage by a number equal to the number rolled.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Superiority.</em></strong> You gain temporary hit points equal to twice the amount of hit points reduced.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Reaction">
            <description>When you take damage, you can expend a Blood Die to reduce the damage by a number equal to the number rolled. Superiority: You gain temporary hit points equal to twice the amount of hit points reduced.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Stalk the Wounded" type="Class Feature" source="Blood Knight Maneuvers" id="ID_LD_BKM_CLASS_FEATURE_VF_MANEUVER_STALK_THE_WOUNDED">
        <supports>Variant Fighter Maneuver</supports>
        <requirements>ID_JONOMAN3000_DAPC_ARCHETYPE_MARTIAL_ARCHETYPE_BLOOD_KNIGHT</requirements>
        <prerequisite>Blood Knight archetype</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Blood Knight archetype</p>
            <p>When you take the attack action on your turn, you can forgo one of your attacks to approach a suffering foe. Choose one creature that you can see that is below its hit point maximum. You can move 5 feet towards your target and you have advantage on your next attack roll against it.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Superiority.</em></strong> The movement is increased to 15 feet.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can forgo one of your attacks to approach a suffering foe. Choose one creature that you can see that is below its hit point maximum. You can move 5 feet towards your target and you have advantage on your next attack roll against it. Superiority: The movement is increased to 15 feet.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
</elements>