<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Wisdom Artificer Specialist</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="artificer-wisdom.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/a-song-of-ice-and-fire-subclasses/artificer-wisdom.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Wisdom" type="Archetype" source="A Song of Ice and Fire Subclasses" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_ARTIFICER_WISDOM">
        <supports>Artificer Specialist</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Wisdoms are pyromancers of the Alchemist’s Guild. The guild was once very powerful and influential due to its stores of secret knowledge, the most valuable of which is the ability to produce wildfire. Called "the substance" by Wisdoms, wildfire is a murky green, volatile liquid that combusts into a vibrant green, long-burning conflagration. Only dragonflame, or perhaps the summer sun, burns hotter than it. Much care and learning is required to properly create and handle it.</p>
            <div element="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WISDOM_TOOL_PROFICIENCY" />
            <div element="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WISDOM_WISDOM_SPELLS" />
            <div element="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WISDOM_VERDANT_BLAZE" />
            <div element="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WISDOM_PYROMANCER" />
            <div element="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WISDOM_WILDFIRE_COMBUSTION" />
            <div element="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WISDOM_FIRE_IN_YOUR_VEINS" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WISDOM_TOOL_PROFICIENCY" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WISDOM_WISDOM_SPELLS" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WISDOM_VERDANT_BLAZE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WISDOM_PYROMANCER" level="5" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WISDOM_WILDFIRE_COMBUSTION" level="9" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WISDOM_FIRE_IN_YOUR_VEINS" level="15" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Tool Proficiency" type="Archetype Feature" source="A Song of Ice and Fire Subclasses" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WISDOM_TOOL_PROFICIENCY">
            <description>
                <p>When you adopt this specialization at 3rd level, you gain proficiency with alchemist’s supplies. If you already have this proficiency, you gain proficiency with one other type of artisan’s tools of your choice.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Proficiency" name="Tool Proficiency (Wisdom Specialist)" optional="true" default="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_ALCHEMISTS_SUPPLIES" supports="Artisan tool" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Wisdom Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="A Song of Ice and Fire Subclasses" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WISDOM_WISDOM_SPELLS">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 3rd level, you always have certain spells prepared after you reach particular levels in this class, as shown in the Wisdom Spells table. These spells count as artificer spells for you, but they don’t count against the number of artificer spells you prepare.</p>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Artificer Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td><i>burning hands, faerie fire</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><i>flaming sphere, suggestion</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><i>fireball, glyph of warding</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>13th</td><td><i>Mordenkainen’s private sanctum, wall of fire</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>17th</td><td><i>conjure elemental, immolation<sup>EE</sup></i></td></tr>
                </table>
                <div class="sidebar">
                    <h5>Variant: Alternative Spells</h5>
                    <p>For players who do not have access to <em>Elemental Evil Player’s Companion</em>, the Wisdom spell <em>immolation</em> can be replaced with <em>flamestrike</em>.</p>
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BURNING_HANDS" level="3" spellcasting="Artificer" prepared="true" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FAERIE_FIRE" level="3" spellcasting="Artificer" prepared="true" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FLAMING_SPHERE" level="5" spellcasting="Artificer" prepared="true" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SUGGESTION" level="5" spellcasting="Artificer" prepared="true" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIREBALL" level="9" spellcasting="Artificer" prepared="true" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GLYPH_OF_WARDING" level="9" spellcasting="Artificer" prepared="true" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MORDENKAINENS_PRIVATE_SANCTUM" level="13" spellcasting="Artificer" prepared="true" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WALL_OF_FIRE" level="13" spellcasting="Artificer" prepared="true" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONJURE_ELEMENTAL" level="17" spellcasting="Artificer" prepared="true" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_IMMOLATION" level="17" spellcasting="Artificer" prepared="true" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Verdant Blaze" type="Archetype Feature" source="A Song of Ice and Fire Subclasses" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WISDOM_VERDANT_BLAZE">
            <description>
                <p>At 3rd level, you learn the <em>green-flame blade</em> cantrip, and it doesn’t count against your number of cantrips known. The spell’s description can be found in the <em>Sword Coast Adventurer’s Guide</em>. When you cast the spell, it’s range is 120 feet, you can make a ranged attack with a weapon or alchemist’s fire instead of a melee attack with a weapon, and the green fire leaps from the target to a different creature of your choice you can see within 10 feet of it.</p>
                <p class="indent">In addition, when making attacks with alchemist’s fire, you add your proficiency bonus and may use your Intelligence modifier for the attack roll. Also, as an action, you may expend spell slots to create alchemist’s fire without needing raw materials. You create one flask’s worth of alchemist’s fire for each level of spell slot expended, and alchemist’s fire created this way burns green.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you cast green-flame blade, it’s range is 120 feet, you can make a ranged attack with a weapon or alchemist’s fire instead of a melee attack with a weapon, and the green fire leaps from the target to a different creature of your choice you can see within 10 feet of it. In addition, when making attacks with alchemist’s fire, you add your proficiency bonus and may use your Intelligence modifier for the attack roll. Also, as an action, you may expend spell slots to create alchemist’s fire without needing raw materials. You create one flask’s worth of alchemist’s fire for each level of spell slot expended, and alchemist’s fire created this way burns green.</description>
                <description level="5">When you cast green-flame blade, it’s range is 120 feet, you can make a ranged attack with a weapon or alchemist’s fire instead of a melee attack with a weapon, and the green fire leaps from the target to two other creatures of your choice you can see within 15 feet of it. In addition, when making attacks with alchemist’s fire, you add your proficiency bonus and may use your Intelligence modifier for the attack roll. Also, as an action, you may expend spell slots to create alchemist’s fire without needing raw materials. You create one flask’s worth of alchemist’s fire for each level of spell slot expended, and alchemist’s fire created this way burns green.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_SCAG_SPELL_GREEN_FLAME_BLADE" level="3" spellcasting="Artificer" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Pyromancer" type="Archetype Feature" source="A Song of Ice and Fire Subclasses" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WISDOM_PYROMANCER">
            <description>
                <p>At 5th level, you enhance the fire of your green-flame blade to spread further and to more creatures. When you cast the spell, the green fire leaps from the target to two different creatures of your choice you can see within 15 feet of it.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Wildfire Combustion" type="Archetype Feature" source="A Song of Ice and Fire Subclasses" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WISDOM_WILDFIRE_COMBUSTION">
            <description>
                <p>By 9th level, your command of wildfire has become masterful and can enhance the fire you create through your spells. When you cast an artificer spell that deals fire damage, you may use a flask of alchemist’s fire for your spellcasting focus. When you do so, each creature that takes fire damage from the spell is also affected as if it was hit with alchemist’s fire, and the spell ignores resistance to fire. Also, the fire takes on a dark, emerald and jade green hue.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of once), and you regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="{{wildfire-combustion:uses}}/Long Rest">
                <description>When you cast an artificer spell that deals fire damage, you may use a flask of alchemist’s fire for your spellcasting focus. When you do so, each creature that takes fire damage from the spell is also affected as if it was hit with alchemist’s fire, and the spell ignores resistance to fire.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="wildfire-combustion:uses" value="1" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="wildfire-combustion:uses" value="intelligence:modifier" bonus="base" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Fire in Your Veins" type="Archetype Feature" source="A Song of Ice and Fire Subclasses" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WISDOM_FIRE_IN_YOUR_VEINS">
            <description>
                <p>By 15th level, you have mastered fire and unlocked its secrets that it poses no risk to you, and you can use it to revitalize yourself and others:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>You are immune to fire damage.</li>
                    <li>When you are subjected to fire damage, you can choose to regain hit points equal to the fire damage dealt. Alternatively, when you deal fire damage to a creature, you can have the creature be immune to the damage and have it regain hit points equal to the fire damage dealt. Once you use this ability, you can’t use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You are immune to fire damage. When you are subjected to fire damage, you can choose to regain hit points equal to the fire damage dealt. Alternatively, when you deal fire damage to a creature, you can have the creature be immune to the damage and have it regain hit points equal to the fire damage dealt. Once you use this ability, you can’t use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
    
</elements>