<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Druid Circle of the Three-Eyed Crow</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="druid-circle-of-the-three-eyed-crow.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/a-song-of-ice-and-fire-subclasses/druid-circle-of-the-three-eyed-crow.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Circle of the Three-Eyed Crow" type="Archetype" source="A Song of Ice and Fire Subclasses" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_DRUID_CIRCLE_OF_THE_THREEEYED_CROW">
        <supports>Druid Circle</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The Circle of the Three-Eyed Crow (also called the Circle of the Three-Eyed Raven) was formed through the teachings of the children of the forest, fey creatures that live in Westeros and once waged war on the invading humanoids. Some of these druids, often referred to as greenseers, still train with the fey and have close relationships with them. The teachings of the children of the forest involve the ability to harness both the destructive and restorative properties nature, to see visions of the future, to transform into animals as well as to take control of them, and to connect to the deep roots of trees throughout the world to gain and pass on knowledge.</p>
            <div element="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THREEEYED_CROW_GREENSIGHT" />
            <div element="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THREEEYED_CROW_SHAPECHANGER" />
            <div element="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THREEEYED_CROW_ROOTED_IN_THE_PAST" />
            <div element="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THREEEYED_CROW_GODSWOOD" />
            <div element="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THREEEYED_CROW_WEIRWOOD_DENDROCHRONOLOGY" />
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THREEEYED_CROW_GREENSIGHT" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THREEEYED_CROW_SHAPECHANGER" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THREEEYED_CROW_ROOTED_IN_THE_PAST" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THREEEYED_CROW_GODSWOOD" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THREEEYED_CROW_WEIRWOOD_DENDROCHRONOLOGY" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Greensight" type="Archetype Feature" source="A Song of Ice and Fire Subclasses" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THREEEYED_CROW_GREENSIGHT">
            <description>
                <p>When you choose this circle at 2nd level, you gain the ability to cast the <em>augury</em> spell, but only as a ritual, as described in chapter 10 of the <em>Player’s Handbook</em>, and without providing material components.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can cast the augury spell as a ritual, without material components.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AUGURY" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Shapechanger" type="Archetype Feature" source="A Song of Ice and Fire Subclasses" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THREEEYED_CROW_SHAPECHANGER">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 2nd level, your ability to beast shape takes on a unique form. You may expend two uses of Wild Shape to gain control of a beast that you see within 60 feet. Your druid level determines the beasts you can control, as shown in the Beast Shapes table (see pg. 66 in the Player’s Handbook).</p>
                <p class="indent">You take total and precise control of the target. The creature takes only the actions you choose, and doesn’t do anything that you don’t allow it to do. During this time, you can also cause the creature to use a reaction, but this requires you to use your own reaction as well.</p>
                <p class="indent">During this time, you are deaf and blind with regard to your own senses and your own body is incapacitated and cannot move.</p>
                <p class="indent">You remain in control of the beast for a number of hours equal to one-quarter your druid level or when you end the control as an action.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>ou may expend two uses of Wild Shape to gain control of a beast that you see within 60 feet. Your druid level determines the beasts you can control. You take total and precise control of the target. The creature takes only the actions you choose, and doesn’t do anything that you don’t allow it to do. During this time, you can also cause the creature to use a reaction, but this requires you to use your own reaction as well. During this time, you are deaf and blind with regard to your own senses and your own body is incapacitated and cannot move. You remain in control of the beast for a number of hours equal to one-quarter your druid level or when you end the control as an action.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Rooted in the Past" type="Archetype Feature" source="A Song of Ice and Fire Subclasses" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THREEEYED_CROW_ROOTED_IN_THE_PAST">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 6th level, you can draw on the long-living essence of plants for their wisdom. By taking a minute to connect with a plant, you have advantage on any Intelligence (History) checks and you double your proficiency bonus, regardless what the normal bonus applied is.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>By taking a minute to connect with a plant, you have advantage on any Intelligence (History) checks and you double your proficiency bonus, regardless what the normal bonus applied is.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Godswood" type="Archetype Feature" source="A Song of Ice and Fire Subclasses" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THREEEYED_CROW_GODSWOOD">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 10th level, you can see and hear as if through a plant. As an action, pick a plant you have seen or touched at least once before, and is inanimate, connected to the earth, and size Medium or larger. You can see and hear as if you were in its space.</p>
                <p class="indent">During this time, you are deaf and blind with regard to your own senses and your own body is incapacitated and cannot move. You may return to your own senses and regain control of your body as an action.</p>
                <p class="indent">You also always have the <em>commune</em> with nature spell prepared, it doesn’t count against the number of spells you can prepare each day, and you may cast it while channeling a plant to gain knowledge of the territory surrounding the plant.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>Pick a plant you have seen or touched at least once before, and is inanimate, connected to the earth, and size Medium or larger. You can see and hear as if you were in its space. During this time, you are deaf and blind with regard to your own senses and your own body is incapacitated and cannot move. You may return to your own senses and regain control of your body as an action. You may cast commune while channeling a plant to gain knowledge of the territory surrounding the plant.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMMUNE" spellcasting="Druid" prepared="true" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Weirwood Dendrochronology" type="Archetype Feature" source="A Song of Ice and Fire Subclasses" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THREEEYED_CROW_WEIRWOOD_DENDROCHRONOLOGY">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 14th level, you can call up visions of the past that occurred around a tree. You spend at least 1 minute in meditation and reverence, then receive dreamlike, shadowy glimpses of the event. The tree must be within 30 feet of you or one you are currently channeling through your Godswood feature.</p>
                <p class="indent">As you meditate, you see visions of events in the immediate vicinity of the tree (up to a 50-foot cube), going back to when the tree was at least size Medium. You learn about one significant event, beginning with the most recent. Significant events typically involve powerful emotions, such as battles and betrayals, marriages and murders, births and funerals. The one event may be a more mundane event that is nevertheless important in your current situation.</p>
                <p class="indent">Alternatively, you may pick a period of time and view the most significant event of from that period or choose a specific event, significant or mundane, that may have happened in the tree’s vicinity. For example, you might decide to view a battle from around 20 years, to see if anything significant happened from 500 to 600 years ago, or look to see people having a conversation about horse trading from 4 days ago. If nothing of the kind happened by the tree, you instead see the closest event within the closest timeline of your search.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
                <description>You spend at least 1 minute in meditation and reverence, then receive dreamlike, shadowy glimpses of the event. The tree must be within 30 feet of you or one you are currently channeling through your Godswood feature. As you meditate, you see visions of events in the immediate vicinity of the tree (up to a 50-foot cube), going back to when the tree was at least size Medium.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
    
</elements>