<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Unsullied Martial Archetype</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="fighter-unsullied.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/a-song-of-ice-and-fire-subclasses/fighter-unsullied.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Unsullied" type="Archetype" source="A Song of Ice and Fire Subclasses" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FIGHTER_UNSULLIED">
        <supports>Martial Archetype</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You began training as an Unsullied as a young male slave. You were chosen for your size, speed, and strength. You were trained not only how to fight, but how to shed your individuality and emotion to only serve the whims of your master and aid your fellow Unsullied. The training was brutal, grueling, and instructive. Those who could not keep up were killed. You survived, were castrated, and became an elite warrior who can ignore pain and has no concept of personal desire.</p>
            <div element="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNSULLIED_PHALANX" />
            <div element="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNSULLIED_SUPPRESS_PAIN" />
            <div element="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNSULLIED_RESILIENCE" />
            <div element="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNSULLIED_UNRELENTING" />
            <div element="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNSULLIED_DURABLE" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNSULLIED_PHALANX" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNSULLIED_SUPPRESS_PAIN" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNSULLIED_RESILIENCE" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNSULLIED_UNRELENTING" level="15" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNSULLIED_DURABLE" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Phalanx" type="Archetype Feature" source="A Song of Ice and Fire Subclasses" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNSULLIED_PHALANX">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 3rd level, you can form a protective wall with your compatriots. While you are within 5 feet of an ally, you and the ally gain a +1 bonus to AC.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>While you are within 5 feet of an ally, you and the ally gain a +1 bonus to AC.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Suppress Pain" type="Archetype Feature" source="A Song of Ice and Fire Subclasses" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNSULLIED_SUPPRESS_PAIN">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 7th level, you are better equipped endure combat. When you take damage, you can use your reaction to roll a d4. Add your Constitution modifier to the number rolled, and reduce the damage by that total. The damage can’t be reduced to less than 1.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Reaction">
                <description>When you take damage, you can reduce the damage by 1d4 + {{constitution:modifier}}. The damage can’t be reduced to less than 1.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Resilience" type="Archetype Feature" source="A Song of Ice and Fire Subclasses" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNSULLIED_RESILIENCE">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 10th level, your tough training can have you withstand certain effects, such as an air elemental’s whirlwind or the <em>shatter</em> spell. When you are subjected to an effect that allows you to make a Strength or Constitution saving throw to take only half damage, you instead take no damage if you succeed on the saving throw, and only half damage if you fail.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you are subjected to an effect that allows you to make a Strength or Constitution saving throw to take only half damage, you instead take no damage if you succeed on the saving throw, and only half damage if you fail.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Unrelenting" type="Archetype Feature" source="A Song of Ice and Fire Subclasses" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNSULLIED_UNRELENTING">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 15th level, you have lost some the weaknesses of the average warrior. You are immune to the charmed and frightened conditions and have advantage on saving throws to resist the paralyzed and stunned conditions.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You are immune to the charmed and frightened conditions and have advantage on saving throws to resist the paralyzed and stunned conditions.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Durable" type="Archetype Feature" source="A Song of Ice and Fire Subclasses" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNSULLIED_DURABLE">
            <description>
                <p>At 18th level, you gain resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage from nonmagical weapons.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You have resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage from nonmagical weapons.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
    
</elements>