<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Oath of the Faith Militant Sacred Oath</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="paladin-oath-of-the-faith-militant.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/a-song-of-ice-and-fire-subclasses/paladin-oath-of-the-faith-militant.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Oath of the Faith Militant" type="Archetype" source="A Song of Ice and Fire Subclasses" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_PALADIN_OATH_OF_THE_FAITH_MILITANT">
        <supports>Sacred Oath</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The Faith Militant is the military arm of the Faith of the Seven. It is composed of two military orders.</p>
            <p class="indent">The Warrior’s Sons, well-trained, fanatical knights who have renounced all titles, land, gold, and possessions to pledge service to the High Septon. They seek to stamp out heresy and fight all enemies of the Faith.</p>
            <p class="indent">The Poor Fellows are comprised of commoners and women and are armed simply. They are more concerned with escorting pilgrims and travelers on the road and protecting the small folk from men who have gone astray.</p>
            <div element="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FAITH_MILITANT_TENETS_OF_THE_FAITH_MILITANT" />
            <div element="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FAITH_MILITANT_OATH_SPELLS" />
            <div element="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FAITH_MILITANT_CHANNEL_DIVINITY" />
            <div element="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FAITH_MILITANT_AURA_OF_WARDING" />
            <div element="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FAITH_MILITANT_TRIAL_OF_SEVEN" />
            <div element="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FAITH_MILITANT_SEVEN_WHO_ARE_ONE" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FAITH_MILITANT_TENETS_OF_THE_FAITH_MILITANT" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FAITH_MILITANT_OATH_SPELLS" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FAITH_MILITANT_CHANNEL_DIVINITY" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FAITH_MILITANT_AURA_OF_WARDING" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FAITH_MILITANT_TRIAL_OF_SEVEN" level="15" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FAITH_MILITANT_SEVEN_WHO_ARE_ONE" level="20" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Tenets of the Faith Militant" type="Archetype Feature" source="A Song of Ice and Fire Subclasses" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FAITH_MILITANT_TENETS_OF_THE_FAITH_MILITANT">
            <description>
                <p>Many of the Faith Militant are fanatical in their beliefs, but not every member favors all virtues of the Seven equally. The tenets of the Stranger, for example, are oft overlooked.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>The Father.</em></strong> I will embody the Father’s judgment and seek to exact justice where I may.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>The Mother.</em></strong> I will embody the Mother’s mercy and seek to grant clemency to those who deserve it.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>The Warrior.</em></strong> I will embody the Warrior’s courage and seek to fight in battles where I am needed.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>The Maiden.</em></strong> I will embody the Maiden’s innocence and seek to protect young women from harm.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>The Smith.</em></strong> I will embody the Smith’s strength and seek to mend what is broken in the world.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>The Crone.</em></strong> I will embody the Crone’s wisdom and seek to guide people to the righteous path.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>The Stranger.</em></strong> I will embody the Stranger’s ineffability and seek to welcome those who feel like outcasts.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Oath Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="A Song of Ice and Fire Subclasses" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FAITH_MILITANT_OATH_SPELLS">
            <description>
                <p>You gain oath spells at the paladin levels listed in the Oath of the Faith Militant Spells table. See the Sacred Oath class feature for how oath spells work.</p>
                <h5 class="caption">Oath of the Faith Militant Spells</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Paladin Level</td><td>Spell</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td><i>compelled duel, protection from evil and good</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><i>branding smite, silence</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><i>counterspell, crusader’s mantle</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>13th</td><td><i>compulsion, guardian of faith</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>17th</td><td><i>commune, hallow</i></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMPELLED_DUEL" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PROTECTION_FROM_EVIL_AND_GOOD" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BRANDING_SMITE" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SILENCE" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COUNTERSPELL" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CRUSADERS_MANTLE" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMPULSION" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="13" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GUARDIAN_OF_FAITH" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="13" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMMUNE" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="17" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HALLOW" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="17" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Channel Divinity" type="Archetype Feature" source="A Song of Ice and Fire Subclasses" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FAITH_MILITANT_CHANNEL_DIVINITY">
            <description>
                <p>When you take this oath at 3rd level, you gain the following two Channel Divinity options. See the Sacred Oath class feature for how Channel Divinity works.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Trial by Combat.</em></strong> As an action, you can use your Channel Divinity to challenge a creature within 10 feet of you before the Seven. The target must make a Charisma saving throw. On a failure, you gain a bonus to melee weapon attack rolls and melee weapon damage rolls against the target equal to your Charisma modifier. This bonus ends after you make seven melee weapon attacks against the target, you or the target dies, or you attack a creature not under the effects of your Trial by Combat.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Turn the Heretical.</em></strong> You can use your Channel Divinity to utter righteous words that are painful for fey and undead to hear. As an action, you present your holy symbol, and each fey or undead within 30 feet of you that can hear you must make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, the creature is turned for 1 minute or until it takes damage.</p>
                <p class="indent">A turned creature must spend its turns trying to move as far away from you as it can, and it can’t willingly move to a space within 30 feet of you. It also can’t take reactions. For its action, it can use only the Dash action or try to escape from an effect that prevents it from moving. If there’s nowhere to move, the creature can use the Dodge action.</p>
                <p class="indent">If the creature’s true form is concealed by an illusion, shapeshifting, or other effect, that form is revealed while it is turned.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
            <element name="Channel Divinity: Trial by Combat" type="Archetype Feature" source="A Song of Ice and Fire Subclasses" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FAITH_MILITANT_CD_TRIAL_BY_COMBAT">
                <description>
                    <p>As an action, you can use your Channel Divinity to challenge a creature within 10 feet of you before the Seven. The target must make a Charisma saving throw. On a failure, you gain a bonus to melee weapon attack rolls and melee weapon damage rolls against the target equal to your Charisma modifier. This bonus ends after you make seven melee weapon attacks against the target, you or the target dies, or you attack a creature not under the effects of your Trial by Combat.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet alt="Trial by Combat" usage="Channel Divinity" action="Action">
                    <description>You challenge a creature within 10 feet of you before the Seven. The target must make a Charisma saving throw. On a failure, you gain a +{{charisma:modifier}} bonus to melee weapon attack rolls and melee weapon damage rolls against the target. This bonus ends after you make seven melee weapon attacks against the target, you or the target dies, or you attack a creature not under the effects of your Trial by Combat.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Channel Divinity: Turn the Heretical" type="Archetype Feature" source="A Song of Ice and Fire Subclasses" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FAITH_MILITANT_CD_">
                <description>
                    <p>You can use your Channel Divinity to utter righteous words that are painful for fey and undead to hear. As an action, you present your holy symbol, and each fey or undead within 30 feet of you that can hear you must make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, the creature is turned for 1 minute or until it takes damage.</p>
                    <p class="indent">A turned creature must spend its turns trying to move as far away from you as it can, and it can’t willingly move to a space within 30 feet of you. It also can’t take reactions. For its action, it can use only the Dash action or try to escape from an effect that prevents it from moving. If there’s nowhere to move, the creature can use the Dodge action.</p>
                    <p class="indent">If the creature’s true form is concealed by an illusion, shapeshifting, or other effect, that form is revealed while it is turned.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet alt="Turn the Heretical" usage="Channel Divinity" action="Action">
                    <description>You present your holy symbol, and each fey or undead within 30 feet of you that can hear you must make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, the creature is turned for 1 minute or until it takes damage.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
        <element name="Aura of Warding" type="Archetype Feature" source="A Song of Ice and Fire Subclasses" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FAITH_MILITANT_AURA_OF_WARDING">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 7th level, holy conviction lies so heavily upon you that it forms a ward from heathen magic. You and friendly creatures within 10 feet of you have resistance to damage from spells.</p>
                <p class="indent">At 18th level, the range of this aura increases to 30 feet.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You and friendly creatures within {{aura-of-warding:range}} feet of you have resistance to damage from spells.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="aura-of-warding:range" value="10" level="7" />
                <stat name="aura-of-warding:range" value="20" level="18" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Trial of Seven" type="Archetype Feature" source="A Song of Ice and Fire Subclasses" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FAITH_MILITANT_TRIAL_OF_SEVEN">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 15th level, your challenges before the Seven take on a greater, older tradition. If the target of your Trial by Combat does not have at least six allies within 120 feet of it, it automatically fails its saving throw. If it does have have at least six allies within 120 feet of it, it makes a saving throw as normal, and on a failure, you choose six of its allies within 120 feet of it to make a Charisma saving throw against your paladin spell save DC. If a creature fails its saving throw, it is under the effects of your Trial by Combat as well.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>If the target of your Trial by Combat does not have at least six allies within 120 feet of it, it automatically fails its saving throw. If it does have have at least six allies within 120 feet of it, it makes a saving throw as normal, and on a failure, you choose six of its allies within 120 feet of it to make a Charisma saving throw against your paladin spell save DC. If a creature fails its saving throw, it is under the effects of your Trial by Combat as well.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Seven-Who-Are-One" type="Archetype Feature" source="A Song of Ice and Fire Subclasses" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FAITH_MILITANT_SEVEN_WHO_ARE_ONE">
            <description>
                <p>At 20th level, you can assume the mortal form of the Seven and gain seven faces representing its different aspects. Using your action, you undergo a transformation. For 1 minute, you gain the following benefits:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>You gain a +1 bonus to your proficiency bonus and all six ability score modifiers.</li>
                    <li>You gain the benefits of the <em>crown of stars</em> spell being cast on you. The spell’s description can be found in <em>Xanathar’s Guide for Everything</em>.</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You undergo a transformation. For 1 minute, you gain the following benefits: +1 to your proficiency bonus and all ability score modifiers; you gain the benefits of the crown of stars spell being cast on you.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_CROWN_OF_STARS" />
            </rules>
        </element>
    
</elements>