<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Warg Ranger Archetype</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="ranger-warg.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/a-song-of-ice-and-fire-subclasses/ranger-warg.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Warg" type="Archetype" source="A Song of Ice and Fire Subclasses" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_RANGER_WARG">
        <supports>Ranger Archetype</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Also known as skinchangers or beastlings, Wargs have the ability to enter the mind of an animal and control its actions. These talents usually develop in youth with pets or other animals the Warg has a strong bond with. As a Warg’s skills develop, they soon begin to control beasts that are both familiar and strange, friendly and hostile. And the most powerful of skinchangers can take over other creatures besides beasts such as humanoids, monstrosities, dragons, and others.</p>
            <p class="indent">While connected to another creature, it is not merely the Warg exerting complete control, but in fact both minds influencing each other. If the skinchanger is not strong enough, extended time in a beast’s mind may begin to change their own personality having it become more beastly. Other Wargs prefer to live their lives in animal skin as much as they can and will violate taboos such as eating humanoid flesh or mating as a beast.</p>
            <div element="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARG_WARG_MAGIC" />
            <div element="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARG_WARGS_COMPANION" />
            <div element="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARG_WARG_BOND" />
            <div element="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARG_BEASTLING" />
            <div element="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARG_SKINCHANGER" />
            <div element="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARG_LEGENDARY_SKINCHANGER" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARG_WARG_MAGIC" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARG_WARGS_COMPANION" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARG_WARG_BOND" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARG_BEASTLING" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARG_SKINCHANGER" level="11" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARG_LEGENDARY_SKINCHANGER" level="15" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Warg Magic" type="Archetype Feature" source="A Song of Ice and Fire Subclasses" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARG_WARG_MAGIC">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 3rd level, you learn an additional spell when you reach certain levels in this class, as shown in the Warg Spells table. The spell counts as a ranger spell for you, and it doesn’t count against the number of ranger spells you know.</p>
                <h5 class="caption">Warg Spells</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Ranger Level</td><td>Spell</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td><i>command</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><i>detect thoughts</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><i>sending</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>13th</td><td><i>dominate beast</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>17th</td><td><i>dominate person</i></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMMAND" spellcasting="Ranger" known="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_THOUGHTS" spellcasting="Ranger" known="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SENDING" spellcasting="Ranger" known="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DOMINATE_BEAST" spellcasting="Ranger" known="true" level="13" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DOMINATE_PERSON" spellcasting="Ranger" known="true" level="17" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Warg’s Companion" type="Archetype Feature" source="A Song of Ice and Fire Subclasses" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARG_WARGS_COMPANION">
            <description>
                <p>At 3rd level, you have developed a kinship with an animal that accompanies you on your adventures. Choose a beast that is no larger than Medium and that has a challenge rating of 1/4 or lower (appendix D of the <EM>Player’s Handbook</EM> presents statistics for the hawk, mastiff, and panther as examples).</p>
                <p class="indent">The beast obeys your commands as best as it can. It takes its turn on your initiative, though it doesn’t take an action unless you command it to. On your turn, you can verbally command the beast where to move (no action required by you). You can use your action to verbally command it to take the Attack, Dash, Disengage, Dodge, or Help action. Once you have the Extra Attack feature, you can make one weapon attack yourself when you command the beast to take the Attack action.</p>
                <p class="indent">If you are incapacitated or absent, your beast companion acts on its own, focusing on protecting you and itself. It never requires your command to use its reaction, such as when making an opportunity attack.</p>
                <p class="indent">While traveling through your favored terrain with only the beast, you can move stealthily at a normal pace.</p>
                <p class="indent">If the beast dies, you can obtain another one by spending 8 hours magically bonding with another beast that isn’t hostile to you, either the same type of beast as before or a different one.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Companion" name="Warg’s Companion" supports="Beast,(Tiny||Small||Medium),(1/4||1/8||0)" level="3" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Warg Bond" type="Archetype Feature" source="A Song of Ice and Fire Subclasses" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARG_WARG_BOND">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 3rd level, your connection with your companion is enhanced by your warg nature. You have a telepathic link with your companion, through which the beast can understand your telepathic messages to it, and it can telepathically communicate simple emotions and concepts back to you. You also can cast the <em>beast sense</em> spell at will only targeting your companion.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You have a telepathic link with your companion, through which the beast can understand your telepathic messages to it, and it can telepathically communicate simple emotions and concepts back to you. You also can cast the beast sense spell at will only targeting your companion.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BEAST_SENSE" level="3" spellcasting="Ranger" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Beastling" type="Archetype Feature" source="A Song of Ice and Fire Subclasses" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARG_BEASTLING">
            <description>
                <p>At 7th level, you can begin to sense through beasts that aren’t your companion. You can cast the <em>beast sense</em> spell at will. When cast in this way the spell has a range of 60 feet, lasts for 8 hours, and does not require concentration. Also the target does not need to be willing. If the target is unwilling, it must make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failure, the spell takes effect. Once a beast succeeds this saving throw, it is immune to the spell for 24 hours unless it becomes willing.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can cast the beast sense spell at will. When cast in this way the spell has a range of 60 feet, lasts for 8 hours, and does not require concentration. Also the target does not need to be willing. If the target is unwilling, it must make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failure, the spell takes effect. Once a beast succeeds this saving throw, it is immune to the spell for 24 hours unless it becomes willing.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Skinchanger" type="Archetype Feature" source="A Song of Ice and Fire Subclasses" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARG_SKINCHANGER">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 11th level, any beast under the effect’s of your beast sense spell is also under the effects of the dominate beast spell as if you had cast it on them.</p>
                <p class="indent">In addition, if you are reduced to 0 hit points or die, you may immediately target your companion or the nearest beast within 1 mile of you with your beast sense spell. If the spell is successful, it lasts until dispelled or until you choose to end it (no action required), and if you are dead, your soul transfers to the body of the beast.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Any beast under the effect’s of your <em>beast sense</em> spell is also under the effects of the <em>dominate beast</em> spell as if you had cast it on them.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Legendary Skinchanger" type="Archetype Feature" source="A Song of Ice and Fire Subclasses" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARG_LEGENDARY_SKINCHANGER">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 15th level, your warg abilities extend to nonbeasts. When you cast <em>beast sense</em>, you are no longer limited to beasts but may target a creature of any type.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, you may cast the <em>dominate monster</em> spell. Once you do so, you must finish a long rest before doing so again.</p>
                <p class="indent">When you reach 17th level in this class, you cast <em>dominate monster</em> at 9th level when using this feature.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you cast beast sense, you are no longer limited to beasts but may target a creature of any type. Additionally, you may cast the dominate monster spell. Once you do so, you must finish a long rest before doing so again.</description>
                <description level="17">When you cast beast sense, you are no longer limited to beasts but may target a creature of any type. Additionally, you may cast the dominate monster spell at 9th level. Once you do so, you must finish a long rest before doing so again.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
    
</elements>