<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Faceless Man Roguish Archetype</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="rogue-faceless-man.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/a-song-of-ice-and-fire-subclasses/rogue-faceless-man.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Faceless Man" type="Archetype" source="A Song of Ice and Fire Subclasses" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_ROGUE_FACELESS_MAN">
        <supports>Roguish Archetype</supports>
        <description>
            <p><em>Valar morghulis.</em> All men must die. <em>Valar dohaeris.</em> All men must serve.</p>
            <p class="indent">These are the mantras of the Faceless Men, worshipers of the Many-Faced God and hired assassins from the House of Black and White in the Free City of Braavos. They are highly trained in the ways of poison, combat, and deception, but their greatest skill is the ability to instantly transform their appearance to look like a different person. This is done through the collection of faces taken from the dead which are enhanced with arcane glamours and traditional disguise techniques.</p>
            <p class="indent">As a religious order as well as assassins, Faceless Men are very devout and discard any sense of personal identity to become "no one". They are perfect actors maintaining their disguise while remaining steadfast agents of their hired mission. Although, some have learned the ways of the Faceless Man while ultimately rejecting the the tenets of the order.</p>
            <div element="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FACELESS_MAN_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" />
            <div element="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FACELESS_MAN_VALAR_MORGHULIS" />
            <div element="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FACELESS_MAN_NO_ONE" />
            <div element="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FACELESS_MAN_VALAR_DOHAERIS" />
            <div element="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FACELESS_MAN_DEATH_STRIKE" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FACELESS_MAN_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FACELESS_MAN_VALAR_MORGHULIS" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FACELESS_MAN_NO_ONE" level="9" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FACELESS_MAN_VALAR_DOHAERIS" level="13" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FACELESS_MAN_DEATH_STRIKE" level="17" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Bonus Proficiencies" type="Archetype Feature" source="A Song of Ice and Fire Subclasses" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FACELESS_MAN_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES">
            <description>
                <p>When you choose this archetype at 3rd level, you gain proficiency with the disguise kit and the poisoner’s kit.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_DISGUISE_KIT" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_POISONERS_KIT" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Valar Morghulis" type="Archetype Feature" source="A Song of Ice and Fire Subclasses" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FACELESS_MAN_VALAR_MORGHULIS">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 3rd level, you are at your deadliest when you get the drop on your enemies. You have advantage on attack rolls against any creature that hasn’t taken a turn in the combat yet. In addition, any hit you score against a creature that is surprised is a critical hit.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You have advantage on attack rolls against any creature that hasn’t taken a turn in the combat yet. In addition, any hit you score against a creature that is surprised is a critical hit.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="No One" type="Archetype Feature" source="A Song of Ice and Fire Subclasses" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FACELESS_MAN_NO_ONE">
            <description>
                <p>At 9th level, you gain the ability to adopt a humanoid’s persona. When a humanoid dies within 30 feet of you, you can magically capture its face as a mask using your reaction. You retain this mask until you use it or you finish a long rest.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can don the mask as an action. When you do so, it vanishes, magically transforming into a disguise that appears on you. You now look like the dead person, but healthy and alive. This disguise lasts for 1 hour or until you end it as a bonus action.</p>
                <p class="indent">While you’re in the disguise, you gain access to all information that the humanoid would freely share with a casual acquaintance. Such information includes general details on its background and personal life, but doesn’t include secrets. The information is enough that you can pass yourself off as the person by drawing on its memories.</p>
                <p class="indent">Another creature can see through this disguise by succeeding on a Wisdom (Insight) check contested by your Charisma (Deception) check. You gain a +5 bonus to your check.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you capture a mask with this feature, you can’t capture another one with it until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Reaction" usage="1/Short Rest">
                <description>When a humanoid dies within 30 feet of you, you can magically capture its face as a mask. You retain this mask until you use it or you finish a long rest. You can don the mask as an action. When you do so, it vanishes, magically transforming into a disguise that appears on you. You now look like the dead person, but healthy and alive. This disguise lasts for 1 hour or until you end it as a bonus action. Another creature can see through this disguise by succeeding on a Wisdom (Insight) check contested by your Charisma (Deception) check. You gain a +5 bonus to your check.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Valar Dohaeris" type="Archetype Feature" source="A Song of Ice and Fire Subclasses" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FACELESS_MAN_VALAR_DOHAERIS">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 13th level, you may maintain some of your masks indefinitely. You may have a number of permanent masks equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of 1) which you may use at any time. When using a permanent mask, the disguise lasts until you end it.</p>
                <p class="indent">When you choose to make a permanent mask no longer permanent or its magic is rendered inert such as through the dispel magic spell, the mask instantly decays and turns to dust.</p>
                <p class="indent">Also, you gain a thirteen coins identifying yourself as a Faceless Man and gain an additional coin each time you gain a level in this class. If you present one of these coins to someone and say "valar morghulis" and the recipient responds with "valar dohaeris", the recipient has agreed to perform a favor for you. This favor must be fairly simple and reasonable for the recipient to accomplish such as requesting free passage on a ship to its normal destination from a captain, access to a restricted tome from a librarian, or a place to hide from the law from a random citizen. Though they may risk retribution for their favor, they will not risk their lives or livelihoods for you.</p>
                <p class="indent">Upon the recipient of the coin accepting the favor and attempting to complete it in good faith, you can never attack the recipient or any of its compatriots who aided with the favor or target them with a harmful ability or magical effect. This effect ends if they attack you or target you with a harmful ability or magical effect.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You may maintain some of your masks indefinitely. You may have {{valar-dohaeris:masks}} permanent masks which you may use at any time. When using a permanent mask, the disguise lasts until you end it.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="valar-dohaeris:masks" value="1" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="valar-dohaeris:masks" value="intelligence:modifier" bonus="base" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Death Strike" type="Archetype Feature" source="A Song of Ice and Fire Subclasses" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FACELESS_MAN_DEATH_STRIKE">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 17th level, you become a master of instant death. When you attack and hit a creature that is surprised, it must make a Constitution saving throw (DC 8 + your Dexterity modifier + your proficiency bonus). On a failed save, double the damage of your attack against the creature.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you attack and hit a creature that is surprised, it must make a Constitution saving throw (DC {{death-strike:save-dc}}). On a failed save, double the damage of your attack against the creature.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="death-strike:save-dc" value="8" />
                <stat name="death-strike:save-dc" value="dexterity:modifier" />
                <stat name="death-strike:save-dc" value="proficiency" />
            </rules>
        </element>
    
	<element name="Coin of the Faceless Man" type="Item" source="A Song of Ice and Fire Subclasses" id="ID_ASOIAFS_ITEM_FACELESS_MAN_COIN">
		<description>
			<p>If you present one of these coins to someone and say "valar morghulis" and the recipient responds with "valar dohaeris", the recipient has agreed to perform a favor for you. This favor must be fairly simple and reasonable for the recipient to accomplish such as requesting free passage on a ship to its normal destination from a captain, access to a restricted tome from a librarian, or a place to hide from the law from a random citizen. Though they may risk retribution for their favor, they will not risk their lives or livelihoods for you.</p>
            <p class="indent">Upon the recipient of the coin accepting the favor and attempting to complete it in good faith, you can never attack the recipient or any of its compatriots who aided with the favor or target them with a harmful ability or magical effect. This effect ends if they attack you or target you with a harmful ability or magical effect.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Adventuring Gear</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp"></set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0.1">1/10th lb.</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
</elements>