<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Soulknife Roguish Archetype</name>
        <author url="https://www.reddit.com/u/devikyn">u/devikyn</author>
        <update version="0.0.4">
            <file name="rogue-soulknife.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/gm-binder-devikyn/the-renewed-psionic/rogue-soulknife.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Soulknife" type="Archetype" source="The Renewed Psionic" id="ID_GM_BINDER_TRP_ARCHETYPE_ROGUE_SOULKNIFE">
        <supports>Roguish Archetype</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Armed with a mind as sharp as it is deadly, the soulknife is a violent force of psionic lethality. These psionic rogues craft beautiful blades from their mental energy, preferring to hone their natural abilities into a sharp, killing edge, rather than study the inner workings of the universe. A soulknife takes great pride in the design and perfection of their psionic weaponry, often crafting a personal, signature aesthetic into any weapons they create.</p>
            <div element="ID_GM_BINDER_TRP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SOULKIFE_MIND_BLADE" />
            <div element="ID_GM_BINDER_TRP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SOULKIFE_PSIONICS" />
            <div element="ID_GM_BINDER_TRP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SOULKIFE_SPEED_OF_THOUGHT" />
            <div element="ID_GM_BINDER_TRP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SOULKIFE_BLADEWIND" />
            <div element="ID_GM_BINDER_TRP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SOULKIFE_KNIFE_TO_THE_SOULD" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GM_BINDER_TRP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SOULKIFE_MIND_BLADE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GM_BINDER_TRP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SOULKIFE_PSIONICS" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GM_BINDER_TRP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SOULKIFE_SPEED_OF_THOUGHT" level="9" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GM_BINDER_TRP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SOULKIFE_BLADEWIND" level="13" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GM_BINDER_TRP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SOULKIFE_KNIFE_TO_THE_SOULD" level="17" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Mind Blade" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Renewed Psionic" id="ID_GM_BINDER_TRP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SOULKIFE_MIND_BLADE">
        <description>
            <p>At 3rd level, you can create a semisolid blade of psychic energy, distilled from your mind.</p>
            <p class="indent">As a bonus action, you you can create a weapon that flows with mental energy, a mind blade, in one of your free hands. This weapon takes the form of a dagger, a longsword, a rapier or a shortsword (your choice), using the same statistics as the chosen weapon except that it has the finesse and thrown (30/120) properties. You can never be disarmed of your mind blade unless you choose to be, and it functions even in a null psionics field. If you let go of your mind blade, it disappears at the end of the turn.</p>
            <p class="indent">When you Sneak Attack a creature with your mind blade, you can choose to deal psychic damage with the Sneak Attack.</p>
            <p class="indent">Your mind blade gains a +1 bonus to its attack and damage rolls at 9th level in this class, and this bonus becomes a +2 at 17th level.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Bonus Action">
            <description>You you can create a mind blade in one of your free hands. This weapon takes the form of a dagger, a longsword, a rapier or a shortsword (your choice), using the same statistics as the chosen weapon except that it has the finesse and thrown (30/120) properties. You can never be disarmed of your mind blade unless you choose to be, and it functions even in a null psionics field. If you let go of your mind blade, it disappears at the end of the turn. When you Sneak Attack a creature with your mind blade, you can choose to deal psychic damage with the Sneak Attack.</description>
            <description level="9">You you can create a mind blade in one of your free hands. This weapon takes the form of a dagger, a longsword, a rapier or a shortsword (your choice), using the same statistics as the chosen weapon except that it has the finesse and thrown (30/120) properties. You can never be disarmed of your mind blade unless you choose to be, and it functions even in a null psionics field. If you let go of your mind blade, it disappears at the end of the turn. When you Sneak Attack a creature with your mind blade, you can choose to deal psychic damage with the Sneak Attack. Your mind blade gains a +1 bonus to its attack and damage rolls.</description>
            <description level="17">You you can create a mind blade in one of your free hands. This weapon takes the form of a dagger, a longsword, a rapier or a shortsword (your choice), using the same statistics as the chosen weapon except that it has the finesse and thrown (30/120) properties. You can never be disarmed of your mind blade unless you choose to be, and it functions even in a null psionics field. If you let go of your mind blade, it disappears at the end of the turn. When you Sneak Attack a creature with your mind blade, you can choose to deal psychic damage with the Sneak Attack. Your mind blade gains a +2 bonus to its attack and damage rolls.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Psionics" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Renewed Psionic" id="ID_GM_BINDER_TRP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SOULKIFE_PSIONICS">
        <description>
            <p>Also at 3rd level, your psionic power, honed by your focus on perfecting your psionic weaponry, allows you to learn certain psionic spells.</p>
            <h5>PSIONICS</h5>
            <p>You use a method of spellcasting known as psionics, which harnesses your mental energy to warp reality into wondrous effects. Due to the nature of psionics, you ignore the components of any psion spells you have prepared, except material components that are consumed by the spell. Spells cast using psionics are unaffected by effects that negate magic, such as counterspell, dispel magic, and anti-magic field.</p>
            <h5>PSIONIC TALENTS</h5>
            <p>You learn three talents of your choice from the psion spell list. You learn another psion talent of your choice at 10th level in this class.</p>
            <h5>LEARNING SPELLS</h5>
            <p>You know two psion spells of your choice, and one nomad spell of your choice. The Soulknife Innate Spellcasting table shows when you learn more spells of 1st level or higher. Each spell must be chosen from the psion spell list, and must be of a level no greater than the number shown in the Psionic Power Limit column for your rogue level.</p>
            <p class="indent">At 8th, 14th, and 20th levels in this class, the spells you choose can come from the nomad spell list.</p>
            <p class="indent">Whenever you gain a level in this class, you can replace one of the spells you know with another spell of your choice. The new spell must be of a level no greater than the number shown in the Psionic Power Limit column for your rogue level, and it must be a psion spell, unless you’re replacing the spell you gained at 3rd, 8th, 14th, or 20th level from the nomad spell list.</p>
            <h5>PSIONIC POWER</h5>
            <p>The Soulknife Innate Spellcasting table shows how much psionic power you have to cast your spells of 1st level and higher. To cast one of these spells, you must expend psionic power equal to the spell’s level when you cast it. You regain all expended psionic power when you finish a long rest.</p>
            <p class="indent">For example, if you are a level 8 rogue and you know the 1st-level spell <em>magic missile</em>, you can spend 1 psionic power to cast it at 1st level or 2 psionic power to cast it at 2nd level. There is a limit to the amount of psionic power you can sustain at a time; you can’t cast a spell if its psionic power cost is greater than your Psionic Power Limit.</p>
            <h5>SPELLCASTING ABILITY</h5>
            <p>Intelligence is your ability for your psionic spells, since they are created out of psionic energy and shaped by your mind. You use your Intelligence whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Intelligence modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a psionic spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.</p>
            <p class="indent">Spell save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier</p>
            <p class="indent">Spell attack modifier = your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier</p>
			<h5 class="caption">SOULKNIFE PSIONICS</h5>
			<table class="class-features">
				<thead>
					<tr><th class="col-10">Rogue Level</th><th class="col-10">Talents Known</th><th class="col-10">Spells Known</th><th>Psionic Power</th><th>Psionic Power Limit</th></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td> 3rd</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>1</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 4th</td><td>3</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>1</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 5th</td><td>3</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>1</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 6th</td><td>3</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>1</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 7th</td><td>3</td><td>5</td><td>8</td><td>2</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 8th</td><td>3</td><td>6</td><td>8</td><td>2</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 9th</td><td>3</td><td>6</td><td>8</td><td>2</td></tr>
				<tr><td>10th</td><td>4</td><td>7</td><td>10</td><td>2</td></tr>
				<tr><td>11th</td><td>4</td><td>8</td><td>10</td><td>2</td></tr>
				<tr><td>12th</td><td>4</td><td>8</td><td>10</td><td>2</td></tr>
				<tr><td>13th</td><td>4</td><td>9</td><td>16</td><td>3</td></tr>
				<tr><td>14th</td><td>4</td><td>10</td><td>16</td><td>3</td></tr>
				<tr><td>15th</td><td>4</td><td>10</td><td>16</td><td>3</td></tr>
				<tr><td>16th</td><td>4</td><td>11</td><td>19</td><td>3</td></tr>
				<tr><td>17th</td><td>4</td><td>11</td><td>19</td><td>3</td></tr>
				<tr><td>18th</td><td>4</td><td>11</td><td>19</td><td>3</td></tr>
				<tr><td>19th</td><td>4</td><td>12</td><td>23</td><td>4</td></tr>
				<tr><td>20th</td><td>4</td><td>13</td><td>23</td><td>4</td></tr>
			</table>				
        </description>
        <spellcasting name="Soulknife" ability="Intelligence" prepare="false">
            <list known="true">Soulknife</list>
        </spellcasting>
        <sheet usage="{{soulknife:psionic-power}}/Long Rest">
            <description>Psionic Power Limit: {{soulknife:psionic-power-limit}}</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Spell" name="Soulknife Talent (Level 3)" number="3" supports="Psion,0" level="3" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Soulknife Talent (Level 10)" number="1" supports="Psion,0" level="10" />

            <stat name="soulknife:spellcasting:slots:1" value="0" level="3" />
            <stat name="soulknife:spellcasting:slots:2" value="0" level="7" />
            <stat name="soulknife:spellcasting:slots:3" value="0" level="13" />
            <stat name="soulknife:spellcasting:slots:4" value="0" level="19" />

            <stat name="soulknife:psionic-power" value="2" level="3" />
            <stat name="soulknife:psionic-power" value="1" level="4" />
            <stat name="soulknife:psionic-power" value="5" level="7" />
            <stat name="soulknife:psionic-power" value="2" level="10" />
            <stat name="soulknife:psionic-power" value="6" level="13" />
            <stat name="soulknife:psionic-power" value="3" level="16" />
            <stat name="soulknife:psionic-power" value="4" level="19" />

            <stat name="soulknife:psionic-power-limit" value="1" level="3" />
            <stat name="soulknife:psionic-power-limit" value="1" level="7" />
            <stat name="soulknife:psionic-power-limit" value="1" level="13" />
            <stat name="soulknife:psionic-power-limit" value="1" level="19" />
            
            <select type="Spell" name="Soulknife Psionic Spell (Level 3)" number="2" supports="$(spellcasting:slots),Psion" level="3" spellcasting="Soulknife" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Soulknife Psionic Spell (Level 3)" number="1" supports="$(spellcasting:slots),Nomad" level="3" spellcasting="Soulknife" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Soulknife Psionic Spell (Level 4)" number="1" supports="$(spellcasting:slots),Psion" level="4" spellcasting="Soulknife" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Soulknife Psionic Spell (Level 7)" number="1" supports="$(spellcasting:slots),Psion" level="7" spellcasting="Soulknife" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Soulknife Psionic Spell (Level 8)" number="1" supports="$(spellcasting:slots),Nomad" level="8" spellcasting="Soulknife" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Soulknife Psionic Spell (Level 10)" number="1" supports="$(spellcasting:slots),Psion" level="10" spellcasting="Soulknife" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Soulknife Psionic Spell (Level 11)" number="1" supports="$(spellcasting:slots),Psion" level="11" spellcasting="Soulknife" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Soulknife Psionic Spell (Level 13)" number="1" supports="$(spellcasting:slots),Psion" level="13" spellcasting="Soulknife" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Soulknife Psionic Spell (Level 14)" number="1" supports="$(spellcasting:slots),Nomad" level="14" spellcasting="Soulknife" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Soulknife Psionic Spell (Level 16)" number="1" supports="$(spellcasting:slots),Psion" level="16" spellcasting="Soulknife" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Soulknife Psionic Spell (Level 19)" number="1" supports="$(spellcasting:slots),Psion" level="19" spellcasting="Soulknife" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Soulknife Psionic Spell (Level 20)" number="1" supports="$(spellcasting:slots),Nomad" level="20" spellcasting="Soulknife" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Speed of Thought" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Renewed Psionic" id="ID_GM_BINDER_TRP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SOULKIFE_SPEED_OF_THOUGHT">
        <description>
            <p>At 9th level, your sharp focus hastens your body’s responses and heightens your mental acuity. Your speed increases by 10 feet, and you have advantage on ability checks to recall information you’ve learned.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You have advantage on ability checks to recall information you’ve learned.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="speed" value="10" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Bladewind" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Renewed Psionic" id="ID_GM_BINDER_TRP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SOULKIFE_BLADEWIND">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 13th level, you can fragment your mind blade into multiple smaller weapons, each striking at a creature near you.</p>
            <p class="indent">As an action while you’re wielding your mind blade, you can split the blade into multiple weapons, using them to make a melee psionic attack against each creature within 5 feet of you. On a hit, a creature takes 1d6 psychic damage, and you can add an extra number of d6s to the damage; each d6 you add in this way subtracts from your total Sneak Attack damage, and you can distribute these d6s among each of the creatures you hit until you’ve spent the total number of d6s you have for your Sneak Attack.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Action">
            <description>While you’re wielding your mind blade, you can split the blade into multiple weapons, using them to make a melee psionic attack against each creature within 5 feet of you. On a hit, a creature takes 1d6 psychic damage, and you can add an extra number of d6s to the damage; each d6 you add in this way subtracts from your total Sneak Attack damage, and you can distribute these d6s among each of the creatures you hit until you’ve spent the total number of d6s you have for your Sneak Attack.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Knife to the Soul" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Renewed Psionic" id="ID_GM_BINDER_TRP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SOULKIFE_KNIFE_TO_THE_SOULD">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 17th level, when you Sneak Attack a creature with your mind blade, you can choose to forego any number of d6s from your Sneak Attack’s damage in order to deal Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma damage to the creature (your choice). The target must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or have the chosen ability score reduced by 1 for each d6 you forfeited, which lasts until the creature finishes a long rest.</p>
            <p class="indent">This feature can’t reduce a creature’s ability scores by more than the total number of d6s you have for your Sneak Attack.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you Sneak Attack a creature with your mind blade, you can choose to forego any number of d6s from your Sneak Attack’s damage in order to deal Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma damage to the creature (your choice). The target must succeed on a Constitution saving throw (save DC {{spellcasting:dc:int}}) or have the chosen ability score reduced by 1 for each d6 you forfeited, which lasts until the creature finishes a long rest. This feature can’t reduce a creature’s ability scores by more than the total number of d6s you have for your Sneak Attack.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
</elements>