<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Druid Circle: Circle of the Sun ReRedux</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="druid-circle-of-the-sun.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/subclasses/druid/druid-circle-of-the-sun.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Circle of the Sun ReRedux" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_DCOLMENAR_GMBINDER_SOURCE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_SUN_REREDUX">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation">COTSR</set>
            <set name="url">https://www.gmbinder.com/share/-M8XNC5Qw1wD9m8wRV1-</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" abbreviation="DCM" url="https://www.gmbinder.com/profile/dcolmenar">dcolmenar</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20200819</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

	<element name="Circle of the Sun" type="Archetype" source="Circle of the Sun ReRedux" id="ID_DCM_COTSR_ARCHETYPE_DRUID_CIRCLE_OF_THE_SUN">
		<supports>Druid Circle</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Druids of the Circle of the Sun live in adoration of the Green. In forests, gardens, and jungles, these druids both cultivate and venerate the sun’s gift of plant life.</p>
			<p class="indent">Druids of this circle can be as unique and fickle as the myriad of flowers, fruits, and trees they cherish. In brightest day, they can grow tall and confident. In darkest night, they can wilt away and sulk. Despite how they vary, these druids are often found to embody the sincerity and generosity that plants display. But woe to those who desecrate the Green: Roses always bear thorns.</p>
			<div element="ID_DCM_COTSR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COTS_BLOOM" />
			<div element="ID_DCM_COTSR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COTS_THORN_WHIP_FLOURISH" />
			<div element="ID_DCM_COTSR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COTS_FIRMLY_PLANTED" />
			<div element="ID_DCM_COTSR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COTS_BENEVOLENT_TOPIARY" />
			<div element="ID_DCM_COTSR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COTS_WITHERLESS" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DCM_COTSR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COTS_BLOOM" level="2" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DCM_COTSR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COTS_THORN_WHIP_FLOURISH" level="2" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DCM_COTSR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COTS_FIRMLY_PLANTED" level="6" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DCM_COTSR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COTS_BENEVOLENT_TOPIARY" level="10" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DCM_COTSR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COTS_WITHERLESS" level="14" />
		</rules>
	</element>
		<element name="Bloom" type="Archetype Feature" source="Circle of the Sun ReRedux" id="ID_DCM_COTSR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COTS_BLOOM">
			<description>
				<p>Starting at 2nd level, you choose a flower to celebrate for the day and invoke its intrinsic magic. Whenever you finish a long rest, choose one spell from any class, including this one, that’s effects are emblematic to that flower. The spell you choose must require 1 action to cast and be of a level you can cast, as shown on the druid table, or a cantrip.</p>
				<p class="indent">As an action, you can expend a use of your Wild Shape feature to cast your bloom’s spell, rather than assuming a beast form. If the spell isn’t a druid spell, it counts as a druid spell when you cast it. You follow the normal rules for casting the spell, including expending a spell slot.</p>
                <div class="sidebar">
                    <h5 class="caption">CHOOSING A BLOOM SPELL</h5>
                    <p>As a druid of the Circle of the Sun, the flower you choose to celebrate is special and deeply personal. The spell you choose as its manifestation may have meaning in floriography or have cultural or personal significance. For example, you may celebrate the daisy by choosing the spell disguise self. Instead of symbolizing innocence and love, you may focus on the daisy as an expression of dissembling or disguise, like in the play Hamlet. Work with your DM to choose a spell that is appropriate for your game.</p>
                </div>
			</description>
			<sheet usage="Wild Shape" action="Action">
				<description>Whenever you finish a long rest, choose one spell from any class, including this one, that’s effects are emblematic to that flower. The spell you choose must require 1 action to cast and be of a level you can cast, as shown on the druid table, or a cantrip. As an action, you can expend a use of your Wild Shape feature to cast your bloom’s spell, rather than assuming a beast form.</description>
			</sheet>
		</element>
		<element name="Thorn Whip Flourish" type="Archetype Feature" source="Circle of the Sun ReRedux" id="ID_DCM_COTSR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COTS_THORN_WHIP_FLOURISH">
			<description>
				<p>At 2nd level, you learn the <i>thorn whip</i> cantrip if you don’t already know it, and it can perform the following tasks instead of its normal effects:</p>
				<ul>
					<li>You can target and pull a willing creature using the whip without damaging it.</li>
					<li>You can use the whip to manipulate an object, open an unlocked door or container, stow or retrieve an item from an open container, or pour the contents out of a vial. It can’t activate magic items or carry more than 10 pounds.</li>
					<li>If the bloom spell you choose deals damage, you can substitute your thorn whip’s piercing damage with that spell’s damage type.</li>
				</ul>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description>When you cast thorn whip, you can perform the following tasks instead of its normal effects: You can target and pull a willing creature using the whip without damaging it. You can use the whip to manipulate an object, open an unlocked door or container, stow or retrieve an item from an open container, or pour the contents out of a vial. It can’t activate magic items or carry more than 10 pounds. If the bloom spell you choose deals damage, you can substitute your thorn whip’s piercing damage with that spell’s damage type.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_THORN_WHIP" spellcasting="Druid" known="true" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Firmly Planted" type="Archetype Feature" source="Circle of the Sun ReRedux" id="ID_DCM_COTSR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COTS_FIRMLY_PLANTED">
			<description>
				<p>At 6th level, extending roots into the earth fortifies your stance. You gain advantage on Strength and Constitution saving throws if you haven’t moved on the same turn.</p>
				<p class="indent">Additionally, you develop a photosynthetic integument. If you spend at least 1 hour in sunlight and have access to potable water, you do not need to eat to survive.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description>You have advantage on Strength and Constitution saving throws if you haven’t moved on the same turn. If you spend at least 1 hour in sunlight and have access to potable water, you do not need to eat to survive.</description>
			</sheet>
		</element>
		<element name="Benevolent Topiary" type="Archetype Feature" source="Circle of the Sun ReRedux" id="ID_DCM_COTSR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COTS_BENEVOLENT_TOPIARY">
			<description>
				<p>Starting at 10th level, when you cast a spell that creates or manipulates plants, such as the <i>entangle</i> spell, you can protect some creatures from its effects. Choose a number of those creatures up to your Wisdom modifier (minimum of one creature). A chosen creature automatically succeeds on its saving throw against the spell and moving through the spell’s difficult terrain costs it no extra movement.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description>when you cast a spell that creates or manipulates plants, you can protect some creatures from its effects. Choose up to {{enevolent-topiary:creatures}} creatures. A chosen creature automatically succeeds on its saving throw against the spell and moving through the spell’s difficult terrain costs it no extra movement.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <stat name="benevolent-topiary:creatures" value="1" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="benevolent-topiary:creatures" value="wisdom:modifier" bonus="base" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Witherless" type="Archetype Feature" source="Circle of the Sun ReRedux" id="ID_DCM_COTSR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COTS_WITHERLESS">
			<description>
				<p>At 14th level, your blooms help you defy even the most dire situations. When you expend a use of your bloom with fewer than half of your hit points remaining, you can regain a number of hit points equal to your druid level.</p>
				<p class="indent">Additionally, you suffer none of the drawbacks of old age, and you can’t be aged magically.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description>When you expend a use of your bloom with fewer than half of your hit points remaining, you can regain {{level:druid}} hit points. You suffer none of the drawbacks of old age, and you can’t be aged magically.</description>
			</sheet>
		</element>

</elements>