<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Druid Circle of Growth</name>
        <update version="0.0.2">
            <file name="druid-circle-of-growth.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/subclasses/druid/druid-circle-of-growth.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Circle of Growth" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_TT_GMBINDER_SOURCE_CIRCLE_OF_GROWTH">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation">COG</set>
            <set name="url">https://homebrewery.naturalcrit.com/share/BkW_hoTEdS</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" abbreviation="TT" url="https://www.reddit.com/user/TabaxiTaxidermist/">u/TabaxiTaxidermist</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20200609</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Circle of Growth" type="Archetype" source="Circle of Growth" id="ID_TT_COG_ARCHETYPE_DRUID_CIRCLE_OF_GROWTH">
        <supports>Druid Circle</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Purple-black scars stretch across the field like fingers tightening around a throat. A firbolg dressed in earthy greens steps onto the blighted grass, the sun rising behind her. She shakes a rattling gourd and whispers inspiration into the soil. The darkened earth gains color, and the grass lifts its drooped heads. Next, the firbolg scatters seeds into the deepest parts of the blight. They sink into the ground and sprout, growing into mighty trees. By day’s end, the blight has receded, and in its place a grove blooms.</p>
            <div element="ID_TT_COG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COG_SEEDS_OF_THE_EARTH" />
            <div element="ID_TT_COG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COG_VERDANT_DRUIDCRAFT" />
            <div element="ID_TT_COG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COG_HERALD_OF_BLOOMS" />
            <div element="ID_TT_COG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COG_GREATER_FLORA" />
            <div element="ID_TT_COG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COG_MASTER_OF_PLANTS" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TT_COG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COG_SEEDS_OF_THE_EARTH" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TT_COG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COG_VERDANT_DRUIDCRAFT" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TT_COG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COG_HERALD_OF_BLOOMS" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TT_COG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COG_GREATER_FLORA" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TT_COG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COG_MASTER_OF_PLANTS" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Seeds of the Earth" type="Archetype Feature" source="Circle of Growth" id="ID_TT_COG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COG_SEEDS_OF_THE_EARTH">
            <description>
                <p>When you join this circle at 2nd level, you gain the ability to create seeds instilled with the essence of life. When you finish a long rest, you can create a number of seeds equal to your Wisdom modifier (minimum of 1). The seeds last for 24 hours or until you finish another long rest (whichever comes first).</p>
                <p class="indent">As an action, you can throw a seed to an unoccupied space on the ground you can see within 30 feet of you. The ground must be at least partially earth or stone. When you do so, a Medium-sized ferocious flora sprouts from the seed. You choose the color and shape of the flora.</p>
                <p class="indent">As a bonus action on your turn, you can have the ferocious flora lash out at a creature you can see within 15 feet of it. When you do so, you make a melee spell attack roll against the creature. On a hit, the target takes 1d8 bludgeoning damage and is pulled 10 feet toward or pushed 10 feet away from the flora (your choice).</p>
                <p class="indent">When a creature you can see within 15 feet of the ferocious flora makes an attack roll or ability check, you can use your reaction to have the flora harry the creature. The target has disadvantage on that attack roll or ability check.</p>
                <p class="indent">If you have multiple ferocious flora, you can command only one of them at a time. You can command your flora for 1 hour after they sprout. During this time the flora is immune to damage. Afterwards, they remain indefinitely and have game statistics appropriate to their form (DM’s Discretion). </p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you finish a long rest, you can create {{seeds-of-the-earth:seeds}} seeds that last for 24 hours or until you finish another long rest (whichever comes first). As an action, you can throw a seed to an unoccupied space on the ground you can see within 30 feet of you. The ground must be at least partially earth or stone. When you do so, a Medium-sized ferocious flora sprouts from the seed. You choose the color and shape of the flora. As a bonus action on your turn, you can have the ferocious flora lash out at a creature you can see within 15 feet of it. When you do so, you make a melee spell attack roll against the creature. On a hit, the target takes 1d8 bludgeoning damage and is pulled 10 feet toward or pushed 10 feet away from the flora (your choice). When a creature you can see within 15 feet of the ferocious flora makes an attack roll or ability check, you can use your reaction to have the flora harry the creature. The target has disadvantage on that attack roll or ability check.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="seeds-of-the-earth:seeds" value="1" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="seeds-of-the-earth:seeds" value="wisdom:modifier" bonus="base" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Verdant Druidcraft" type="Archetype Feature" source="Circle of Growth" id="ID_TT_COG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COG_VERDANT_DRUIDCRAFT">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 2nd level, you learn the <em>druidcraft</em> cantrip if you didn’t already know it. When you cast <em>druidcraft</em> you can create one of the following effects instead of one of the effects listed in the spell description:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>You create plantlife in a grounded portion of earth or stone that you can see that fits within a 5-foot cube, causing the area to become difficult terrain for 1 minute.</li>
                    <li>You instantly restore a rotten fruit or vegetable to a fresh and edible state.</li>
                    <li>You cause a plant that is not a creature to regain 2d6 hit points.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you cast druidcraft you can create one of the following effects instead of one of the effects listed in the spell description: You create plantlife in a grounded portion of earth or stone that you can see that fits within a 5-foot cube, causing the area to become difficult terrain for 1 minute. You instantly restore a rotten fruit or vegetable to a fresh and edible state. You cause a plant that is not a creature to regain 2d6 hit points.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DRUIDCRAFT" spellcasting="Druid" known="true" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Herald of Blooms" type="Archetype Feature" source="Circle of Growth" id="ID_TT_COG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COG_HERALD_OF_BLOOMS">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 6th level, you always have the <em>plant growth</em> and <em>speak with plants</em> spells prepared, and they don’t count against the number of spells you can prepare each day.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, you can cast either spell once without expending a spell slot. Once you do so, you can’t cast either of them in this way again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You can cast either plant growth or speak with plants once without expending a spell slot.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PLANT_GROWTH" spellcasting="Druid" prepared="true" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_PLANTS" spellcasting="Druid" prepared="true" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Greater Flora" type="Archetype Feature" source="Circle of Growth" id="ID_TT_COG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COG_GREATER_FLORA">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 10th level, you can empower your seeds before they sprout. When you throw a seed from your Seeds of the Earth feature, you can expend a spell slot of 4th level or higher. When you do so, the ferocious flora you create gains the following benefits:</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong>Rapid Growth.</strong> The flora is Large instead of Medium, and it can hit or harry creatures that are within 30 feet of it.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong>Mighty Thorns.</strong> When the flora hits or harries a creature, you can have it pierce the creature with large thorns, dealing 2d6 piercing damage to the target.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong>Restorative Spores.</strong> As an action on your turn, you can have the ferocious flora rain down invigorating spores on your allies. Each creature of your choice within 10 feet of the flora gains 2d6 temporary hit points. You can use a flora’s restorative spores once.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you throw a seed from your Seeds of the Earth feature, you can expend a spell slot of 4th level or higher. When you do so, the ferocious flora you create gains the following benefits: The flora is Large instead of Medium, and it can hit or harry creatures that are within 30 feet of it. When the flora hits or harries a creature, you can have it pierce the creature with large thorns, dealing 2d6 piercing damage to the target. As an action on your turn, you can have the ferocious flora rain down invigorating spores on your allies. Each creature of your choice within 10 feet of the flora gains 2d6 temporary hit points. You can use a flora’s restorative spores once.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Master of Plants" type="Archetype Feature" source="Circle of Growth" id="ID_TT_COG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COG_MASTER_OF_PLANTS">
            <description>
                <p>By 14th level, you learn to instill the growth around you with the same vital essence as you do your seeds. As an action, you can energize the life in all Medium or larger nonmagical plants within 120 feet of you. When you do so, each energized plant becomes a ferocious flora from your Seeds of the Earth feature for 1 minute. Large or larger plants in the area gain the benefits of your Greater Flora feature.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>Each Medium or larger nonmagical plant within 120 feet of you becomes a ferocious flora from your Seeds of the Earth feature for 1 minute. Large or larger plants in the area gain the benefits of your Greater Flora feature.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

</elements>