<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Martial Mastery Feats</name>
        <author url="https://www.reddit.com/u/">u/devikyn</author>
        <update version="0.0.2">
            <file name="feats.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/gm-binder-devikyn/martial-mastery/feats.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Charger" type="Feat" source="Martial Mastery" id="ID_DEVIKYN_GM_BINDER_FEAT_CHARGER">
        <description>
            <p>When you move at least 20 feet in a straight line before stopping in a space with one or more creatures within your reach, you gain the following benefits until the end of the turn or until you move again:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>When you successfully push a creature with a shove attack, you push it an extra 10 feet.</li>
                <li>Your next weapon attack that hits deals extra damage equal to your proficiency bonus.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you move at least 20 feet in a straight line before stopping in a space with one or more creatures within your reach, you gain the following benefits until the end of the turn or until you move again:
            When you successfully push a creature with a shove attack, you push it an extra 10 feet.
            Your next weapon attack that hits deals {{proficiency}} points extra damage equal.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Close-Quarters Shooter" type="Feat" source="Martial Mastery" id="ID_DEVIKYN_GM_BINDER_FEAT_CLOSE_QUARTERS_SHOOTER">
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">(replaces Crossbow Expert)</p>
            <p>Your extensive practice using ranged weapons in close combat grants you the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>You ignore the loading quality of ranged weapons with which you are proficient.</li>
                <li>Being within 5 feet of a hostile creature doesn’t impose disadvantage on your ranged attack rolls.</li>
                <li>When you hit a creature within 30 feet of you with a ranged weapon attack using a one-handed ranged weapon, you can deal 1d6 extra damage to the creature.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You ignore the loading quality of ranged weapons with which you are proficient.
            Being within 5 feet of a hostile creature doesn’t impose disadvantage on your ranged attack rolls.
            When you hit a creature within 30 feet of you with a ranged weapon attack using a one-handed ranged weapon, you can deal 1d6 extra damage to the creature.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Defensive Duelist" type="Feat" source="Martial Mastery" id="ID_DEVIKYN_GM_BINDER_FEAT_DEFENSIVE_DUELIST">
        <description>
            <p>While you are wielding a finesse or versatile weapon and no other weapons, when another creature that you can see hits you with a weapon attack, you can use your reaction to add your proficiency bonus to your AC (potentially causing the attack to miss), which lasts until the start of your next turn or until a weapon attack hits you. You must be proficient with the weapon you are wielding to gain this benefit.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Reaction">
            <description>While you are wielding a finesse or versatile weapon and no other weapons, when another creature that you can see hits you with a weapon attack, you can add {{proficiency}} to your AC (potentially causing the attack to miss), which lasts until the start of your next turn or until a weapon attack hits you. You must be proficient with the weapon you are wielding to gain this benefit.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Great Weapon Master" type="Feat" source="Martial Mastery" id="ID_DEVIKYN_GM_BINDER_FEAT_GREAT_WEAPON_MASTER">
        <description>
            <p>You’ve learned to leverage the weight of a weapon, letting its momentum empower your strikes. You gain the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>On your turn, when you score a critical hit with a melee weapon or reduce a creature to 0 hit points with one, you can make one melee weapon attack as a bonus action.</li>
                <li>Before you make an attack with a heavy weapon that you are proficient with, you can choose to forego adding your proficiency bonus to the attack roll. If the attack hits, you add double your proficiency bonus to to the attack’s damage.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>On your turn, when you score a critical hit with a melee weapon or reduce a creature to 0 hit points with one, you can make one melee weapon attack as a bonus action. Before you make an attack with a heavy weapon that you are proficient with, you can choose to forego adding your proficiency bonus ({{proficiency}}) to the attack roll. If the attack hits, you add {{great-weapon-master:damage-bonus}} to to the attack’s damage.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="great-weapon-master:damage-bonus" value="proficiency" />
            <stat name="great-weapon-master:damage-bonus" value="proficiency" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Inspiring Leader" type="Feat" source="Martial Mastery" id="ID_DEVIKYN_GM_BINDER_FEAT_INSPIRING_LEADER">
        <requirements>[cha:13]</requirements>
        <prerequisite>Charisma 13 or higher</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Charisma 13 or higher </p>
            <p>Your confidence inspires your companions to fight on, granting you the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>Increase your Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</li>
                <li>You can spend 10 minutes inspiring your companions, shoring up their resolve to fight. When you do so, you and up to five friendly creatures within 30 feet of you who can see you, hear you and understand you gain temporary hit points equal to your level + your Charisma modifier. A creature can’t gain temporary hit points from this feat again until it has finished a short or long rest.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
            <description>When you do so, you and up to five friendly creatures within 30 feet of you who can see you, hear you and understand you gain {{inspiring-leader:temp-hp}} temporary hit. A creature can’t gain temporary hit points from this feat again until it has finished a short or long rest.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="charisma" value="1" />
            <stat name="inspiring-leader:temp-hp" value="level" />
            <stat name="inspiring-leader:temp-hp" value="level" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Mage Slayer" type="Feat" source="Martial Mastery" id="ID_DEVIKYN_GM_BINDER_FEAT_MAGE_SLAYER">
        <description>
            <p>You have practiced techniques useful in melee combat against spellcasters, gaining the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>When a creature that’s within your reach casts a spell, you can use your reaction to make a melee weapon attack against that creature.</li>
                <li>When you damage a creature that is concentrating on a spell, that creature has disadvantage on the saving throw it makes to maintain its concentration.</li>
                <li>You have advantage on saving throws against spells cast by creatures within your reach.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When a creature that’s within your reach casts a spell, you can use your reaction to make a melee weapon attack against that creature.
            When you damage a creature that is concentrating on a spell, that creature has disadvantage on the saving throw it makes to maintain its concentration.
            You have advantage on saving throws against spells cast by creatures within your reach.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Polearm Master" type="Feat" source="Martial Mastery" id="ID_DEVIKYN_GM_BINDER_FEAT_POLEARM_MASTER">
        <description>
            <p>You can keep your enemies at bay with reach weapons. You gain the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>When you take the Attack action and attack with only a glaive, halberd, pike, quarterstaff or spear, you can make one additional melee attack with the opposite end of the weapon as part of the same action. The weapon deals 1d4 bludgeoning damage for this attack, and you use the same ability modifier for the attack and damage rolls as a normal attack you make with the weapon.</li>
                <li>While you are wielding a glaive, halberd, pike, quarterstaff or spear, other creatures provoke an opportunity attack from you when they enter the reach you have with that weapon.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you take the Attack action and attack with only a polearm, you can make one additional melee attack with the opposite end of the weapon as part of the same action. The weapon deals 1d4 bludgeoning damage for this attack, and you use the same ability modifier for the attack and damage rolls as a normal attack you make with the weapon.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Savage Attacker" type="Feat" source="Martial Mastery" id="ID_DEVIKYN_GM_BINDER_FEAT_SAVAGE_ATTACKER">
        <description>
            <p>You attack with especially brutal force. You gain the benefits below:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>Increase your Strength or Dexterity score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</li>
                <li>Whenever you roll damage for a melee weapon attack, you can reroll the weapon’s damage dice once and use either total.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Whenever you roll damage for a melee weapon attack, you can reroll the weapon’s damage dice once and use either total.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
			<select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Ability Score Increase (Savage Attacker)" supports="ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_STRENGTH|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_DEXTERITY" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Sharpshooter" type="Feat" source="Martial Mastery" id="ID_DEVIKYN_GM_BINDER_FEAT_SHARPSHOOTER">
        <description>
            <p>You have mastered ranged weapons and can make shots that others find impossible. You gain the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>Attacking at long range doesn’t impose disadvantage on your ranged weapon attack rolls.</li>
                <li>While you are elevated 10 or more feet above a creature, your ranged weapon attacks against it ignore half cover; at 30 feet or higher, your ranged weapon attacks against it ignore three-quarters cover.</li>
                <li>Before you make an attack with a ranged weapon that you are proficient with, you can choose to forego adding your proficiency bonus to the attack roll. If the attack hits, you add double your proficiency bonus to to the attack’s damage.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Attacking at long range doesn’t impose disadvantage on your ranged weapon attack rolls.
            While you are elevated 10 or more feet above a creature, your ranged weapon attacks against it ignore half cover; at 30 feet or higher, your ranged weapon attacks against it ignore three-quarters cover.
            Before you make an attack with a ranged weapon that you are proficient with, you can choose to forego adding your proficiency bonus ({{proficiency}}) to the attack roll. If the attack hits, you add {{sharpshooter:damage-bonus}} to the attack’s damage.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="sharpshooter:damage-bonus" value="proficiency" />
            <stat name="sharpshooter:damage-bonus" value="proficiency" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Shield Master" type="Feat" source="Martial Mastery" id="ID_DEVIKYN_GM_BINDER_FEAT_SHIELD_MASTER">
        <description>
            <p>You use shields not just for protection but also for offense. You gain the following benefits while you are wielding a shield:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>You can use your bonus action to attempt to shove a creature within 5 feet of you and that you can see with your shield.</li>
                <li>If you aren’t incapacitated, you can add your shield’s AC bonus to any Dexterity saving throw you make against a spell or other harmful effect that targets only you.</li>
                <li>When subjected to an effect that allows you to make a Dexterity saving throw to take half damage, you can use your reaction to take no damage if you succeed on the saving throw, interposing your shield between yourself and the source of the effect.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can use your bonus action to attempt to shove a creature within 5 feet of you and that you can see with your shield.
            If you aren’t incapacitated, you can add your shield’s AC bonus to any Dexterity saving throw you make against a spell or other harmful effect that targets only you.
            When subjected to an effect that allows you to make a Dexterity saving throw to take half damage, you can use your reaction to take no damage if you succeed on the saving throw, interposing your shield between yourself and the source of the effect.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Two-Weapon Master" type="Feat" source="Martial Mastery" id="ID_DEVIKYN_GM_BINDER_FEAT_TWO_WEAPON_MASTER">
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">(replaces Dual Wielder)</p>
            <p>You master fighting with two weapons. You gain the benefits below:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>You have a +1 bonus to your AC while you wield at least two one-handed melee weapons in different hands.</li>
                <li>You can add your ability modifier to the damage of additional attacks you make by engaging in two-weapon fighting.</li>
                <li>When you make an attack granted to you by engaging in two-weapon fighting, you can forego adding your proficiency bonus to the attack roll. You can do so after the roll, but before the GM determines if the attack hits or misses. If the attack hits, you deal extra damage equal to double your proficiency bonus plus the damage die of the other weapon that you’re wielding, in addition to the attack’s normal damage.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You have a +1 bonus to your AC while you wield at least two one-handed melee weapons in different hands.
            You can add your ability modifier to the damage of additional attacks you make by engaging in two-weapon fighting.
            When you make an attack granted to you by engaging in two-weapon fighting, you can forego adding your proficiency bonus ({{proficiency}}) to the attack roll. You can do so after the roll, but before the GM determines if the attack hits or misses. If the attack hits, you deal extra  {{two-weapon-master:damage-bonus}} damage plus the damage die of the other weapon that you’re wielding, in addition to the attack’s normal damage.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="two-weapon-master:damage-bonus" value="proficiency" />
            <stat name="two-weapon-master:damage-bonus" value="proficiency" />
        </rules>
    </element>
</elements>