<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Martial Mastery Fighting Styles</name>
        <author url="https://www.reddit.com/u/">u/devikyn</author>
        <update version="0.0.3">
            <file name="fighting-styles.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/gm-binder-devikyn/martial-mastery/fighting-styles.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Two-Weapon Fighting" type="Class Feature" source="Martial Mastery" id="ID_DEVIKYN_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTING_STYLE_TWO_WEAPON_FIGHTING">
        <supports>Fighting Style, Fighter, Ranger, Atavist, Dancer, Disciple, Viking, Focused Ranger, Urban Ranger, Warden</supports>
        <description>
            <p>When you take the Attack action and attack at least once with a light melee weapon that you’re holding in one hand, you can make one attack with a different light melee weapon that you’re holding in another hand as part of the same action. You don’t add your ability modifier to this attack’s damage, unless that modifier is negative.</p>
            <p class="indent">If either weapon has the thrown property, you can throw that weapon instead of making a melee attack with it.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you take the Attack action and attack at least once with a light melee weapon that you’re holding in one hand, you can make one attack with a different light melee weapon that you’re holding in another hand as part of the same action. You don’t add your ability modifier to this attack’s damage, unless that modifier is negative. If either weapon has the thrown property, you can throw that weapon instead of making a melee attack with it.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Dual Wielding" type="Class Feature" source="Martial Mastery" id="ID_DEVIKYN_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTING_STYLE_DUAL_WIELDING">
        <supports>Fighting Style, Fighter, Ranger, Lord, Viking</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You can engage in two-weapon fighting even if the melee weapons you’re wielding aren’t light, and you can draw or stow one additional melee weapon on each of your turns. Additionally, while you are wielding two one-handed melee weapons in different hands, the damage die of both weapons becomes a d8 for you.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can engage in two-weapon fighting even if the melee weapons you’re wielding aren’t light, and you can draw or stow one additional melee weapon on each of your turns. Additionally, while you are wielding two one-handed melee weapons in different hands, the damage die of both weapons becomes a d8 for you.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Pugilism" type="Class Feature" source="Martial Mastery" id="ID_DEVIKYN_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTING_STYLE_PUGILISM">
        <supports>Fighting Style, Fighter, Paladin, Ranger, Viking, Focused Ranger, Urban Ranger, Warden</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Your unarmed strikes use a d4 for damage, and when you take the Attack action and attack only with unarmed strikes, you can make one additional unarmed strike as a bonus action.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Your unarmed strikes use a d4 for damage, and when you take the Attack action and attack only with unarmed strikes, you can make one additional unarmed strike as a bonus action.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Switch Fighting" type="Class Feature" source="Martial Mastery" id="ID_DEVIKYN_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTING_STYLE_SWITCH_FIGHTING">
        <supports>Fighting Style, Fighter, Paladin, Ranger, Atavist, Disciple, Dancer, Dragon Knight, Lord, Viking, Focused Ranger, Urban Ranger, Warden</supports>
        <description>
            <p>While you are wielding a versatile weapon and no other weapons, you can add your Dexterity modifier (maximum of +1 while one-handed, maximum of +2 while two-handed) to your attack and damage rolls with that weapon.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>While you are wielding a versatile weapon and no other weapons, you can add your Dexterity modifier (maximum of +1 while one-handed, maximum of +2 while two-handed) to your attack and damage rolls with that weapon.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Throwing" type="Class Feature" source="Martial Mastery" id="ID_DEVIKYN_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTING_STYLE_THROWING">
        <supports>Fighting Style, Fighter, Paladin, Ranger, Atavist, Dancer, Viking, Focused Ranger, Urban Ranger, Warden</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Your gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls you make with thrown weapons, and each time you attack with such a weapon as part of the Attack action, you can immediately draw another weapon after the attack.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Your gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls you make with thrown weapons, and each time you attack with such a weapon as part of the Attack action, you can immediately draw another weapon after the attack.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Tunnel Fighting" type="Class Feature" source="Martial Mastery" id="ID_DEVIKYN_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTING_STYLE_TUNNEL_FIGHTING">
        <supports>Fighting Style, Fighter, Ranger, Lord, Warden</supports>
        <description>
            <p>While you are within 5 feet of two or more sources of three-quarters or full cover, you have a +2 bonus to your AC, your melee weapon attacks have a +2 bonus to damage, and you make opportunity attacks with advantage.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>While you are within 5 feet of two or more sources of three-quarters or full cover, you have a +2 bonus to your AC, your melee weapon attacks have a +2 bonus to damage, and you make opportunity attacks with advantage.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Slinging" type="Class Feature" source="Martial Mastery" id="ID_DEVIKYN_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTING_STYLE_SLINGING">
        <supports>Fighting Style, Fighter, Ranger, Warden, Atavist, Urban Ranger, Focused Ranger, Dancer</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Being within 5 feet of a hostile creature does not impose disadvantage on your ranged weapon attack rolls. Your ranged weapon attacks ignore half cover and three-quarters cover against targets within 30 feet of you.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Being within 5 feet of a hostile creature does not impose disadvantage on your ranged weapon attack rolls. Your ranged weapon attacks ignore half cover and three-quarters cover against targets within 30 feet of you.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
</elements>