<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Wilder Class</name>
        <update version="0.0.2">
            <file name="class-wilder.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/therin-creative/psionic-rules-set/class-wilder.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Wilder" type="Class" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_CLASS_WILDER">
        <description>
            <p>A human steps into an abandoned mansion. He kneels as he assesses the energies of the edifice. In his mind’s eye he sees the auras of tragic memories from the past, and one pool of energy stands out from the rest. It is the source of the haunting. Plunging his hand into the spiritwell, he dissipates its energies, freeing it from the binds of the Material Plane.</p>
            <p class="indent">Surrounded by the town watch, a tiefling makes one final plea for her innocence. Her harassers unfaltering, she decides that if they believe her to be a monster, she’ll show them what a monster she can be. Suddenly her form shifts into a nightmarish creature and the tiefling sets up her pursuers with fang and claw.</p>
            <p class="indent">A pair of gnomes confronts one another in a magic duel. The wizard is confident in his victory, and he fails to cast any defensive spells. His opponent, however, is all too happy to take advantage of her colleague’s dismissal of her powers. The wizard throws a bolt of lightning which impacts a shield of ectoplasm. Mouth agape in disbelief, the wizard is unprepared when his opponent decides she’ll retaliate with lightning of her own.</p>
            <p class="indent">Often ostracized for their gifts, wilders are psychics with strong manifestation of psionic energies that can be hard to control. What separates the wilder from the misfortunate whose powers consume their minds is that a wilder has mastered reserved control.</p>
            <h4>UNBRIDLED POWER</h4>
            <p>Wilders are not trained, they are born. At times, the psychic fabric of the multiverse touches individuals in such a way that they are changed – awakened to mental powers they never knew existed far beyond their control. As such, wilders are forced to learn to shackle their newfound powers lest it consume them.</p>
            <p class="indent">The nature of power wilders possess is determined by how they were altered by psychic or spiritual powers. In some cases they are affected in their souls, possibly moving them close to the land of the dead. In other cases, their bodies or their minds could be imprinted upon, leading to altered states of being or cognition.</p>
            <h4>SELF RELIANCE</h4>
            <p>Often misunderstood and feared, wilders are driven away from societies and must learn to face the world on their own. It is common that they find strength and companionship in others who travel the lands as they exert growing control over their power. Adventuring provides a natural setting to safely tap the energies within a wilder and to aid its friends and allies.</p>
            <h4>CREATING A WILDER</h4>
            <p>The most important decisions in making your wilder are how your character received its powers and what shape those powers take. Were you touched by spiritual forces that left you able to see the dead? Was your body changed in a way that it’s become malleable to your will? Can you tap into the Weave with your mind and shape it? You need to decide your psionic expression as that determines what powers you can use and the nature of your wilder.</p>
            <p class="indent">Next you want to decide how your wilder became an adventurer. Did you join a group to find safety or to gain camaraderie? How do you approach people you know or don’t know about your powers? Are you afraid of what you are or what you could do if you ever let go? Do you seek to seal away your power or have you decided that you need to bridle and command it?</p>
            <h5>QUICK BUILD</h5>
            <p>You can make a wilder quickly by following these suggestions. First, determine you psionic expression (medium, metamorph, or shaper). Second, your highest ability score should be the manifesting ability for the expression (Charisma for medium, Constitution for metamorph, or Intelligence for shaper), followed by Wisdom. Third choose the hermit background. Lastly, choose the astral construct power and the following power for your expression: precognition (medium), elastic body (metamorph), or ectoplasmic construct (shaper).</p>
            <h2>CLASS FEATURES</h2>
            <p>As a wilder, you gain the following class features.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">HIT POINTS</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Hit Dice:</strong> 1d8 per wilder level</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at 1st Level:</strong> 8 + your Constitution modifier</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at Higher Levels:</strong> 1d8 (or 5) + your Constitution modifier per wilder level after 1st</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">PROFICIENCIES</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled mb">
                <li><strong>Armor:</strong> Light armor</li>
                <li><strong>Weapons:</strong> Simple weapons, rapiers, scimitars, short swords</li>
                <li><strong>Tools:</strong> Fortune telling tools</li>
            </ul>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Saving Throws:</strong> Wisdom, Charisma</li>
                <li><strong>Skills:</strong> Choose two from Deception, Esoteric, History, Insight, Investigation, Medicine, Perception, and Performance</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">EQUIPMENT</h5>
            <p>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>(a) a light crossbow and 20 bolts or (b) any simple weapon</li>
                <li>(a) a scimitar or (b) a simple weapon</li>
                <li>(a) a scholar’s pack or (b) an explorer’s pack</li>
                <li>fortune telling tools</li>
            </ul>
        <!-- class table here -->
            <h5 class="caption">THE WILDER</h5>
            <table class="class-features">
                <thead>
                    <tr><td class="col-5">Level</td><td class="col-10">Proficiency Bonus</td><td class="col-60 left">Features</td><td class="col-10">Powers Known</td><td class="col-10">Power Points</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td> 1st</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Power Manifestation, Psionic Expression</td><td>1</td><td>1</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 2nd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Wild Surge (1 die)</td><td>2</td><td>2</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 3rd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Preternatural Awareness</td><td>2</td><td>4</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 4th</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>2</td><td>6</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 5th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">─</td><td>3</td><td>9</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 6th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Wild Surge (2 dice)</td><td>3</td><td>13</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 7th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Psionic Expression feature</td><td>4</td><td>16</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 8th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>4</td><td>20</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 9th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">─</td><td>5</td><td>24</td></tr>
                <tr><td>10th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Wild Surge (3 dice)</td><td>5</td><td>28</td></tr>
                <tr><td>11th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Psionic Expression feature</td><td>5</td><td>30</td></tr>
                <tr><td>12th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>5</td><td>33</td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Unleashed Id</td><td>5</td><td>36</td></tr>
                <tr><td>14th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Wild Surge (4 dice)</td><td>5</td><td>39</td></tr>
                <tr><td>15th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Volatile Mind</td><td>5</td><td>41</td></tr>
                <tr><td>16th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>6</td><td>43</td></tr>
                <tr><td>17th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Psionic Expression feature</td><td>6</td><td>45</td></tr>
                <tr><td>18th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Wild Surge (5 dice)</td><td>6</td><td>47</td></tr>
                <tr><td>19th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>6</td><td>51</td></tr>
                <tr><td>20th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Power Incarnate</td><td>6</td><td>55</td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDER_POWER_MANIFESTATION" />
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDER_PSIONIC_EXPRESSION" />
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDER_WILD_SURGE" />
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDER_PRETERNATURAL_AWARENESS" />
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDER_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" />
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDER_UNLEASHED_ID" />
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDER_VOLATILE_MIND" />
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDER_POWER_INCARNATE" />
            <h2>MULTICLASSING</h2>
            <p><b>Prerequisites:</b> Constitution 13, Intelligence 13, or Charisma 13</p>
            <p><b>Proficiencies:</b> Fortune telling tool</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="hd">d8</set>
            <set name="short">A psychic with psionic energies that can be hard to control.</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" requirements="!ID_TC_PRS_MULTICLASS_WILDER"/>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" requirements="!ID_TC_PRS_MULTICLASS_WILDER"/>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_RAPIER" requirements="!ID_TC_PRS_MULTICLASS_WILDER"/>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SCIMITAR" requirements="!ID_TC_PRS_MULTICLASS_WILDER"/>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SHORTSWORD" requirements="!ID_TC_PRS_MULTICLASS_WILDER"/>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_TC_PRS_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_FORTUNE_TELLING_TOOLS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_WISDOM" requirements="!ID_TC_PRS_MULTICLASS_WILDER"/>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CHARISMA" requirements="!ID_TC_PRS_MULTICLASS_WILDER"/>
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency, Wilder" supports="Skill, TC Wilder" number="2" requirements="!ID_TC_PRS_MULTICLASS_WILDER"/>
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDER_POWER_MANIFESTATION" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDER_PSIONIC_EXPRESSION" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDER_WILD_SURGE" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDER_PRETERNATURAL_AWARENESS" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDER_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" level="4" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDER_UNLEASHED_ID" level="13" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDER_VOLATILE_MIND" level="15" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDER_POWER_INCARNATE" level="20" />
        </rules>
        <multiclass id="ID_TC_PRS_MULTICLASS_WILDER">
            <prerequisite>Constitution, Charisma, or Intelligence 13</prerequisite>
            <requirements>([con:13]||[int:13]||[cha:13])</requirements>
            <setters>
                <set name="multiclass proficiencies">Fortune telling tool</set>
            </setters>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS" />
            </rules>
        </multiclass>
    </element>
        <element name="Power Manifestation" type="Class Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDER_POWER_MANIFESTATION">
            <description>
                <p>One day the wilder woke up to an expression of psychic energy with no control over it. Often, while trying to cope with the terror of these new found powers a wilder is vilified and forced into a solitary existence. From such solitude, the wilder was free to experiment and ultimately exert control over these powers. With such control, the wilder has limited the strength of their manifestations, but can lift this control and exhibit greater power.</p>
                <h5>POWERS KNOWN</h5>
                <p>You know one power of your choice from the wilder power list. Your expression will grant you additional powers.</p>
                <p class="indent">The Powers Known column of the Wilder table shows when you learn more wilder powers of your choice. Unlike spell casting classes, you may not replace powers when you gain levels in this class.</p>
                <h5>POWER POINTS</h5>
                <p>The Wilder table shows how many power points you have to augment your wilder powers. When you manifest a power, you can expend power points to enhance your power. You can expend a number of power points no greater than your wilder level on a single power. You regain all expended power points when you finish a short or long rest.</p>
                <p class="indent">Psionic powers differ from spells in that powers can have different expressions when augmented by power points. These different expressions have a similar theme, but the scope and scale can change. For example, the suspension power includes expressions that can affect single targets or an area with different measures of control.</p>
                <h5>MANIFESTING ABILITY</h5>
                <p>Your manifesting ability is determined by your expression. Mediums exert their will over others and the world and use Charisma as their manifesting ability. Metamorphs alter the living world and use Constitution as their manifesting ability. Shapers use intense mental acumen and calculation to form psychic energies and use Intelligence as their manifesting ability.</p>
                <p class="indent">You use the appropriate ability whenever a power refers to your manifesting ability. In addition, you use the appropriate ability modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a wilder power you manifest and when making an attack roll.</p>
                <div class="caption" style="text-align: center;">
                    <p><b>Medium</b></p>
                    <p><b>Power save DC</b> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier</p>
                    <p><b>Power attack modifier</b> = your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier</p>
                    <p><b>Metamorph</b></p>
                    <p><b>Power save DC</b> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Constitution modifier</p>
                    <p><b>Power attack modifier</b> = your proficiency bonus + your Constitution modifier</p>
                    <p><b>Shaper</b></p>
                    <p><b>Power save DC</b> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier</p>
                    <p><b>Power attack modifier</b> = your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier</p>
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You have {{psionic-power:points}} power points to expend on psionic powers. You can expend no more than {{level:wilder}} power points on a single power.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="psionic-power:points" value="1" level="1"/>
                <stat name="psionic-power:points" value="1" level="2"/>
                <stat name="psionic-power:points" value="2" level="3"/>
                <stat name="psionic-power:points" value="2" level="4"/>
                <stat name="psionic-power:points" value="3" level="5"/>
                <stat name="psionic-power:points" value="4" level="6"/>
                <stat name="psionic-power:points" value="3" level="7"/>
                <stat name="psionic-power:points" value="4" level="8"/>
                <stat name="psionic-power:points" value="4" level="9"/>
                <stat name="psionic-power:points" value="4" level="10"/>
                <stat name="psionic-power:points" value="2" level="11"/>
                <stat name="psionic-power:points" value="3" level="12"/>
                <stat name="psionic-power:points" value="3" level="13"/>
                <stat name="psionic-power:points" value="3" level="14"/>
                <stat name="psionic-power:points" value="2" level="15"/>
                <stat name="psionic-power:points" value="2" level="16"/>
                <stat name="psionic-power:points" value="2" level="17"/>
                <stat name="psionic-power:points" value="2" level="18"/>
                <stat name="psionic-power:points" value="4" level="19"/>
                <stat name="psionic-power:points" value="4" level="20"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Psionic Power (Wilder)" supports="(TC Wilder||TC Medium)" spellcasting="Wilder" level="1" known="true"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Psionic Power (Wilder)" supports="(TC Wilder||TC Medium)" spellcasting="Wilder" level="2" known="true"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Psionic Power (Wilder)" supports="(TC Wilder||TC Medium)" spellcasting="Wilder" level="5" known="true"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Psionic Power (Wilder)" supports="(TC Wilder||TC Medium)" spellcasting="Wilder" level="7" known="true"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Psionic Power (Wilder)" supports="(TC Wilder||TC Medium)" spellcasting="Wilder" level="9" known="true"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Psionic Power (Wilder)" supports="(TC Wilder||TC Medium)" spellcasting="Wilder" level="16" known="true"/>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Psionic Expression" type="Class Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDER_PSIONIC_EXPRESSION">
            <description>
                <p>When a wilder’s powers awaken they fall under one theme. When you create a wilder, choose a Psionic Expression. Perhaps the wilder feels close to the realm of spirits and to lost souls trapped in the world, taking on the expression of the medium. Another wilder may find its physical form is malleable to their will, becoming a metamorph. The shaper is a wilder who can summon spontaneous energies with but a thought.</p>
                <p class="indent">Your psionic expression determines what powers you may possess and grants additional features at 1st, 7th, 11th, and 17th level.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Archetype" name="Psionic Expression" supports="TC Psionic Expression"/>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Wild Surge" type="Class Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDER_WILD_SURGE">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 2nd level, you can generate psionic energy. You gain one surge die which is a d6.</p>
                <p class="indent">When you manifest a wilder power, you can spend one of your surge dice. You gain a number of temporary power points equal to the result of the die roll. You can use these points to augment your power, and when you do so you can augment the power up to 2 points above your wilder level. For example, if you are 2nd level and manifest energy blast and use one surge die which results in a 3, you can augment the power with up to 4 power points, using all 3 power points from the surge die and one from your power point reserve. If you had rolled a 5, you can still only augment the power by 4 power points, but would have 1 temporary power point remaining.</p>
                <p class="indent">If you have any temporary power points from your surge dice remaining at the start of your next turn, you are afflicted by the synaptic static condition for 1 round per unspent power point from your surge dice. For instance, if you gained 6 temporary power points from your Wild Surge feature, but only spent 4 of them, you will be afflicted with synaptic static for 2 rounds.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can spend as many unspent surge dice as you choose. You don’t have to spend all your temporary power points on the same power. All unspent power points gained from surge dice are lost at the start of your next turn.</p>
                <p class="indent">You gain an additional surge die at 6th, 10th, 14th, and 18th level. You regain all surge dice after completing a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="{{wild-surge:surge-dice}}/Long Rest">
                <description>You have {{wild-surge:surge-dice}} d6 surge dice. When you manifest a wilder power, you can spend one of your surge dice. You gain a number of temporary power points equal to the result of the die roll. You can use these points to augment your power, and when you do so you can augment the power up to {{wild-surge:power-limit}} points.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="wild-surge:surge-dice" value="1" level="2"/>
                <stat name="wild-surge:surge-dice" value="1" level="6"/>
                <stat name="wild-surge:surge-dice" value="1" level="10"/>
                <stat name="wild-surge:surge-dice" value="1" level="14"/>
                <stat name="wild-surge:surge-dice" value="1" level="18"/>
                <stat name="wild-surge:power-limit" value="2" level="2" />
                <stat name="wild-surge:power-limit" value="level:wilder" level="2" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Preternatural Awareness" type="Class Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDER_PRETERNATURAL_AWARENESS">
            <description>
                <p>At 3rd level, your intuition supersedes your intellect, alerting you to close-by danger. When you use your Wild Surge feature you may add the result of your surge die to your AC until the start of your next turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you use your Wild Surge feature you may add the result of your surge die to your AC until the start of your next turn.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Ability Score Improvement" type="Class Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDER_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Wilder 4)" supports="Improvement Option,Wilder,4" level="4" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Wilder 8)" supports="Improvement Option,Wilder,8" level="8" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Wilder 12)" supports="Improvement Option,Wilder,12" level="12" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Wilder 16)" supports="Improvement Option,Wilder,16" level="16" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Wilder 19)" supports="Improvement Option,Wilder,19" level="19" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Unleashed Id" type="Class Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDER_UNLEASHED_ID">
            <description>
                <p>At 13th level, after using your Wild Surge feature, the next power you manifest that is augmented by power points from your surge dice gains double your proficiency bonus on its power save DC or power attack modifier.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, when you have no surge dice remaining you may generate one surge die at the start of your turn, but take 2d8 damage from stress when doing so. You can do this no more than once per manifester ability bonus you have (minimum 1). You regain all uses of this feature after completing a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>After using your Wild Surge feature, the next power you manifest that is augmented by power points from your surge dice gains +{{unleashed-id:bonus}} bonus on its power save DC or power attack modifier. Additionally, when you have no surge dice remaining you may generate one surge die at the start of your turn, but take 2d8 damage from stress when doing so. You can create a surge die {{unleashed-id:uses}} times per long rest.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="unleashed-id:bonus" value="proficiency" />
                <stat name="unleashed-id:bonus" value="proficiency" />
                <stat name="unleashed-id:uses" value="1" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="unleashed-id:uses" value="manifester-ability:modifier" bonus="base" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Volatile Mind" type="Class Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDER_VOLATILE_MIND">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 15th level, you never have disadvantage on saving throws against enchantment spells and telepathic powers. Once per round, when you fail a saving throw vs. an enchantment spell or telepathic power, you may reroll your saving throw. If you had advantage on the save, you make your new roll with advantage. You must keep the new roll.</p>
                <p class="indent">When this feature is triggered you can expend one surge die to force the caster or manifester to immediately lose one spell slot the same level as the spell or power points equal to the power that triggered this feature. If no slots of the spell level remain, then the next highest level slot is lost by the attacker (if a 4th-level spell triggered this feature and no 4th-level slots remain, a 3rd-level or lower slot would be lost instead). If the effect came from a spell-like ability, that creature loses one usage of that power if it has limits, or is unable to use it again for one round per manifesting ability bonus you possess if the spell-like ability is at will. The creature makes a Wisdom saving throw against your power DC. If the save is successful, it doesn’t lose the spell slot or power points. When you use a surge die this way, you don’t gain temporary power points from it.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You never have disadvantage on saving throws against enchantment spells and telepathic powers. Once per round, when you fail a saving throw vs. an enchantment spell or telepathic power, you may reroll your saving throw. If you had advantage on the save, you make your new roll with advantage. You must keep the new roll. When this feature is triggered you can expend one surge die to force the caster or manifester to immediately lose one spell slot the same level as the spell or power points equal to the power that triggered this feature.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Power Incarnate" type="Class Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDER_POWER_INCARNATE">
            <description>
                <p>Upon reaching 20th level, you increase your manifestation ability (Charisma, Constitution, or Intelligence) by 4 (maximum 24).</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="charisma:max" value="4" requirements="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_WILDER_MEDIUM" />
                <stat name="charisma" value="4" requirements="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_WILDER_MEDIUM" />
                <stat name="constitution:max" value="4" requirements="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_WILDER_METAMORPH" />
                <stat name="constitution" value="4" requirements="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_WILDER_METAMORPH" />
                <stat name="intelligence:max" value="4" requirements="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_WILDER_SHAPER" />
                <stat name="intelligence" value="4" requirements="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_WILDER_SHAPER" />
            </rules>
        </element>

    <element name="Medium" type="Archetype" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_WILDER_MEDIUM">
        <supports>TC Psionic Expression</supports>
        <requirements>[cha:13]</requirements>
        <prerequisite>Charisma 13</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p>When you were born, or perhaps as a result of some trauma you experienced, a part of your soul entered the spiritual realm. The lost souls of the dead and free-floating spirits became just more travelers passing by in the world to you.</p>
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MEDIUM_EXPRESSION_OF_SPIRIT" />
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MEDIUM_SPIRIT_TOUCHED" />
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MEDIUM_SPIRIT_VISION" />
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MEDIUM_SPIRITUAL_ATTUNEMENT" />
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MEDIUM_BANISH_SPIRITS" />
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MEDIUM_PERSONA_WARD" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <spellcasting name="Wilder" ability="Charisma" prepare="false" extend="true" allowReplace="false">
            <list>TC Wilder||TC Medium</list>
        </spellcasting>
        <rules>
            <stat name="manifester-ability:modifier" value="charisma:modifier" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MEDIUM_EXPRESSION_OF_SPIRIT" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MEDIUM_SPIRIT_TOUCHED" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MEDIUM_SPIRIT_VISION" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MEDIUM_SPIRITUAL_ATTUNEMENT" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MEDIUM_BANISH_SPIRITS" level="11" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MEDIUM_PERSONA_WARD" level="17" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Expression of Spirit" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MEDIUM_EXPRESSION_OF_SPIRIT">
            <description>
                <p>When you gain a new known power, you may select from any power from the wilder power list and the following powers: <i>apopsi, dimensional disassociation, extrasensory perception, hypercognition, id insinuation, mind probe, mislead, precognition, psychometry, puppetry,</i> and <i>telekinetic grasp</i>.</p>
                <p class="indent">At 1st level, you can select one of the powers above and add it to you powers known. At 12th level, you may add a second power from the list above to your powers known.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Spell" name="Psionic Power (Medium)" supports="TC Medium" spellcasting="Wilder" level="1" known="true"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Psionic Power (Medium)" supports="TC Medium" spellcasting="Wilder" level="12" known="true"/>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Spirit Touched" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MEDIUM_SPIRIT_TOUCHED">
            <description>
                <p>You have awareness of the presence of spirits (celestials, elementals, fey, fiends, and undead) and spiritfonts and immediately know if any such being or feature is within 60 feet of you. You know the type and approximate power (your DM will use challenge rating as a guide). You don’t know the location of such creatures or spiritfonts, only that they are present within range.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You have awareness of the presence of spirits (celestials, elementals, fey, fiends, and undead) and spiritfonts and immediately know if any such being or feature is within 60 feet of you.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Spirit Vision" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MEDIUM_SPIRIT_VISION">
            <description>
                <p>At will, you can concentrate to perceive the Ethereal Plane. You can manifest any telepathic powers against targets in the Ethereal Plane, but can’t maintain them unless you gain ethereal perception through other means as your Spirit Vision feature requires concentration to maintain. While you use your Spirit Vision feature, you have the psionic focus condition.</p>
                <p class="indent">You also gain a +2 bonus on saving throws or Intelligence (Investigation) checks against illusions of any sort.</p>
                <p class="indent">When you reach 7th level, any spirit possessing a creature or object is revealed to you in its natural form when you use your Spirit Vision feature. At 11th level, your Spirit Vision also allows you to see a shape shifted creature in its true form.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>At will, you can concentrate to perceive the Ethereal Plane. You can manifest any telepathic powers against targets in the Ethereal Plane, but can’t maintain them unless you gain ethereal perception through other means as your Spirit Vision feature requires concentration to maintain. While you use your Spirit Vision feature, you have the psionic focus condition. You also have a +2 bonus on saving throws or Investigation checks against illusions of any sort.</description>
                <description level="7">At will, you can concentrate to perceive the Ethereal Plane. You can manifest any telepathic powers against targets in the Ethereal Plane, but can’t maintain them unless you gain ethereal perception through other means as your Spirit Vision feature requires concentration to maintain. While you use your Spirit Vision feature, you have the psionic focus condition. You can see any spirit possessing a creature or object. You also have a +2 bonus on saving throws or Investigation checks against illusions of any sort.</description>
                <description level="11">At will, you can concentrate to perceive the Ethereal Plane. You can manifest any telepathic powers against targets in the Ethereal Plane, but can’t maintain them unless you gain ethereal perception through other means as your Spirit Vision feature requires concentration to maintain. While you use your Spirit Vision feature, you have the psionic focus condition. You can see any spirit possessing a creature or object, or the true form of any shapeshifter. You also have a +2 bonus on saving throws or Investigation checks against illusions of any sort.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Spiritual Attunement" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MEDIUM_SPIRITUAL_ATTUNEMENT">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 7th level, your psionic powers reach beyond the material world, striking a creature’s spirit as well as its body or mind. You can freely have any power you manifest affect creatures and objects on the Ethereal Plane as well as the Material Plane. You must be aware of a creature to target it specifically, but area of effect powers will strike each creature in the Ethereal Plane at the same spot when you use this feature.</p>
                <p class="indent">Psychokinetic and telepathic powers manifest by you can affect celestials, elementals, fey, fiends, and undead even in cases where such creatures would be immune to the effects normally, bypassing psychic and bludgeoning damage immunity and resistance.</p>
                <p class="indent">Becoming closer to spirit in your nature, you can no longer be aged through supernatural means.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can freely have any power you manifest affect creatures and objects on the Ethereal Plane as well as the Material Plane. You must be aware of a creature to target it specifically, but area of effect powers will strike each creature in the Ethereal Plane at the same spot when you use this feature. sychokinetic and telepathic powers manifest by you can affect celestials, elementals, fey, fiends, and undead even in cases where such creatures would be immune to the effects normally, bypassing psychic and bludgeoning damage immunity and resistance. You can no longer be aged through supernatural means.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Banish Spirits" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MEDIUM_BANISH_SPIRITS">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 11th level, as an action you can use your force of will to drive away spirits. You can attempt to do so twice between long rests. At 16th level you can Banish Spirits three times between long rests.</p>
                <p class="indent">The effect of Banish Spirits requires a saving throw. When you use this ability, the DC equals your power save DC.</p>
                <p class="indent">One celestial, elemental, fey, fiend, or undead that you can see within 30 feet of you must make a Wisdom saving throw. If the creature fails the saving throw, it is turned for 1 minute or until it takes any damage.</p>
                <p class="indent">A turned creature must spend its turns trying to move as far from you as it can, and it can’t willingly move to a space within 30 feet of you. It also can’t take reactions. For its actions, it can only use the Dash action or try to escape from an effect that prevents it from moving. If there’s nowhere to move, the creature can use the Dodge action.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can also use this power on a creature, object, or a single location to drive out a creature possessing the target or to suppress a spiritfont.</p>
                <p class="indent">Weaker creatures, at your decision, can be either destroyed (if undead), banished to their home plane (if celestial, elemental, or fiend), or driven away (if fey) if they fail their saving throw. If the challenge rating of the creature is equal or less than the threshold shown on the Banish Spirit table, it suffers the effect. Banished celestials, elementals, and fiends can’t return to the material plane for 24 hours, provided they have the means to do so. Fey that are driven away must flee one mile away from the location and can’t return for one year.</p>
                <h5 class="caption">BANISH SPIRITS</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Medium Level</td><td>Banishes or Destroys Creatures of CR…</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>11th</td><td>1 or lower</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>12th</td><td>2 or lower</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>14th</td><td>3 or lower</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>17th</td><td>4 or lower</td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="{{banish-spirits:uses}}/Long Rest" action="Action">
                <description>One celestial, elemental, fey, fiend, or undead that you can see within 30 feet of you must make a Wisdom saving throw (DC {{spellcasting:dc:cha}}) or be turnd for 1 minute or until it takes damage. Creatures of CR {{banish-spirits:cr}} or lower are destroyed or banished to their home plane.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="banish-spirits:uses" value="2" level="11" />
                <stat name="banish-spirits:uses" value="1" level="16" />
                <stat name="banish-spirits:cr" value="1" level="11" />
                <stat name="banish-spirits:cr" value="1" level="12" />
                <stat name="banish-spirits:cr" value="1" level="14" />
                <stat name="banish-spirits:cr" value="1" level="17" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Persona Ward" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MEDIUM_PERSONA_WARD">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 17th level, you have advantage on Wisdom and Charisma saving throws and you are immune to charm effects and possession. You are immediately aware of the perpetrator of a charm, curse, or possession against you, knowing its exact location and identity. Any creature attempting to possess you is forcibly expelled taking 5d12 force damage and is stunned for 1 round.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You have advantage on Wisdom and Charisma saving throws and you are immune to charm effects and possession. You are immediately aware of the perpetrator of a charm, curse, or possession against you, knowing its exact location and identity. Any creature attempting to possess you is forcibly expelled taking 5d12 force damage and is stunned for 1 round.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    <element name="Metamorph" type="Archetype" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_WILDER_METAMORPH">
        <supports>TC Psionic Expression</supports>
        <requirements>[con:13]</requirements>
        <prerequisite>Constitution 13</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p>Flesh and bone are malleable forms to be sculpted and shaped to your will. You transcend the limits of biology, able to meld objects to your body. You can grow bone or reform your flesh using your Metaform feature.</p>
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_METAMORPH_METAFORM" />
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_METAMORPH_MORPHIC_POWER" />
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_METAMORPH_UNARMORED_DEFENSE" />
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_METAMORPH_BODY_MELD" />
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_METAMORPH_ROBUST_FORM" />
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_METAMORPH_WAR_FORM" />
        </description>
        <spellcasting name="Wilder" ability="Constitution" prepare="false" extend="true" allowReplace="false">
            <list>TC Wilder||TC Metamorph</list>
        </spellcasting>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <stat name="manifester-ability:modifier" value="constitution:modifier" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_METAMORPH_METAFORM" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_METAMORPH_MORPHIC_POWER" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_METAMORPH_UNARMORED_DEFENSE" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_METAMORPH_BODY_MELD" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_METAMORPH_ROBUST_FORM" level="11" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_METAMORPH_WAR_FORM" level="17" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Metaform" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_METAMORPH_METAFORM">
            <description>
                <p>By using your action, you can alter your physical form, adopting a trait from the Metaform Table. You are proficient with attack forms gained from a trait and use your Strength modifier on attack and damage rolls. As you advance in level, you gain access to additional traits. You can remain in your metaform for 10 minutes, and you don’t require concentration to maintain it, nor do you gain psionic focus while in your metaform.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can take on trivial, nonmechanical changes in your metaform as you will, such as growing body hair or scaly skin, red eyes, or nightmarish features, for instance.</p>
                <p class="indent">While maintaining metaform, you can use your action to manifest a second trait. When you reach 7th level, you can maintain a third metaform trait. You gain an additional trait again at 11th level (four traits), and 17th level (five traits). You can spend one surge die to manifest all traits you are capable of at once. You don’t gain temporary power points from the surge die when it’s spent this way.</p>
                <p class="indent">Starting at 7th level, you gain the Multiattack action while in your metaform. You can make two attacks using your metaform attacks, or one attack with a metaform attack and one attack with a weapon. Metaform attacks can only be used once per limb, such that you can only make one bite attack, but could make two claw or tentacle attacks. You gain an additional attack with your metaform attacks at 11th level (three attacks) and one more at 17th level (four attacks).</p>
                <div>
                    <h5 class="caption">OTHER OPTIONS</h5>
                    <p>You aren’t limited to the options below. For instance you could grow a sharp beak instead of fangs and deal the same piercing damage, or you could create a myriad of gaping maws along an arm in place of claws. Metaform is intended to allow the metamorph the ability to create a themed battle form.</p>
                    <p class="indent">The DM can develop and approve additional metaform options that fit within the scope of the framework presented below and that don’t duplicate existing powers.</p>
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" >
                <description>You can adopt a metaform trait for up to 10 minutes. You can use your action to adopt a second trait.</description>
                <description level="7">You can adopt a metaform trait for up to 10 minutes. You can use your action to adopt up to {{metaform:traits}} additional traits. You can make {{metaform:traits}} attacks while in your metaform.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="metaform:traits" value="2" level="7" />
                <stat name="metaform:traits" value="1" level="11" />
                <stat name="metaform:traits" value="1" level="17" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Morphic Power" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_METAMORPH_MORPHIC_POWER">
            <description>
                <p>When you gain a new known power, you may select from any power from the wilder power list and the following powers: <i>accelerated healing, biomorphic skin, chameleon, decay, elastic body, energy shroud, martial insight, molecular agitation, size alteration,</i> and <i>speed of thought</i>.</p>
                <p class="indent">At 1st level, you can select one of the powers above and add it to you powers known. At 12th level, you may add a second power from the list above to your powers known.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Spell" name="Psionic Power (Metamorph)" supports="TC Metamorph" spellcasting="Wilder" level="1" known="true"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Psionic Power (Metamorph)" supports="TC Metamorph" spellcasting="Wilder" level="12" known="true"/>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Unarmored Defense" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_METAMORPH_UNARMORED_DEFENSE">
            <description>
                <p>At 1st level, while you are not wearing armor, your Armor Class equals 10 + your Dexterity modifier + your Constitution modifier.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>While you are wearing no armor and not wielding a shield, your AC equals {{ac:unarmored defense metamorph}}.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="ac:unarmored defense metamorph:base" value="10" />
                <stat name="ac:unarmored defense metamorph:dexterity" value="dexterity:modifier" />
                <stat name="ac:unarmored defense metamorph:constitution" value="constitution:modifier" />
                <stat name="ac:unarmored defense metamorph" value="ac:unarmored defense metamorph:base" />
                <stat name="ac:unarmored defense metamorph" value="ac:unarmored defense metamorph:dexterity" />
                <stat name="ac:unarmored defense metamorph" value="ac:unarmored defense metamorph:constitution" />
                <stat name="ac:calculation" value="ac:unarmored defense metamorph" bonus="calculation" equipped="[armor:none],[shield:none]" alt="Unarmored Defense (Monk)" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Body Meld" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_METAMORPH_BODY_MELD">
            <description>
                <p>At 7th level, you can absorb small objects into your body. You can’t absorb more than one fourth of your mass. Items absorbed by you do not function as a worn item would, so, for example, you can’t benefit from a ring of protection while it is melded into your body. You can absorb any suitable object using a bonus action.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can also use a bonus action to immediately bring any absorbed item to hand, or even don it. For example, you could have boots of elvenkind absorbed, and with your bonus action retrieve and don them. You can absorb one object and retrieve one object as part of the same bonus action.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can also partially absorb weapons or makeshift-implements to act as weapons, grafting them to your limbs. These grafted weapons function as normal weapons of their type, but grafted weapons can’t be disarmed. You are proficient with any grafted weapon. A grafted weapon is considered magical so long as it remains grafted to you.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>You can absorb small objects into your body. You can also use a bonus action to immediately bring any absorbed item to hand, or even don it.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Robust Form" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_METAMORPH_ROBUST_FORM">
            <description>
                <p>Upon reaching 11th level, you gain proficiency with Strength and Constitution saving throws. You can also revert to your normal form if you are polymorphed or petrified during your turn, but can’t take a bonus action during this turn. If you were in your metaform before being afflicted, you revert to your metaform instead.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>You can also revert to your normal form if you are polymorphed or petrified during your turn. If you were in your metaform before being afflicted, you revert to your metaform instead.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_STRENGTH" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CONSTITUTION" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="War Form" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_METAMORPH_WAR_FORM">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 17th level, while in your metaform, you gain a +4 bonus to Strength or Constitution or a +2 bonus to both. You can’t exceed 22 in either Strength or Constitution through this feature.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, the first time you manifest your metaform after a long rest, you gain 40 temporary hit points. These hit points remain until your complete a long rest or are depleted through damage.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>While in your metaform, you gain a +4 bonus to Strength or Constitution or a +2 bonus to both. You can’t exceed 22 in either Strength or Constitution through this feature. Additionally, the first time you manifest your metaform after a long rest, you gain 40 temporary hit points. These hit points remain until your complete a long rest or are depleted through damage.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    <element name="Shaper" type="Archetype" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_WILDER_SHAPER">
        <supports>TC Psionic Expression</supports>
        <requirements>[int:13]</requirements>
        <prerequisite>Intelligence 13</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p>A shaper reaches into the very fabric of reality and bends it to the shaper’s will. A shaper can bring ectoplasm from the Astral Plane and fashion it into a construct or even tap into the Weave and duplicate certain spells. A shaper is direct, focusing on powers that accomplish the shaper’s goals quickly.</p>
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHAPER_SHAPE_REALITY" />
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHAPER_ASTRAL_TRICK" />
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHAPER_MANIFEST_MAGIC" />
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHAPER_ECTOPLASMIC_SHIELD" />
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHAPER_SCULPT_EXPRESSIONS" />
        </description>
        <spellcasting name="Wilder" ability="Intelligence" prepare="false" extend="true" allowReplace="false">
            <list>TC Wilder||TC Shaper</list>
        </spellcasting>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <stat name="manifester-ability:modifier" value="intelligence:modifier" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHAPER_SHAPE_REALITY" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHAPER_ASTRAL_TRICK" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHAPER_MANIFEST_MAGIC" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHAPER_ECTOPLASMIC_SHIELD" level="11" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHAPER_SCULPT_EXPRESSIONS" level="17" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Shape Reality" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHAPER_SHAPE_REALITY">
            <description>
                <p>You gain the ectoplasmic construct power. It doesn’t count against your powers known.</p>
                <p class="indent">When you gain a new known power, you may select from any power from the wilder power list and the following powers: <i>animate electricity, dimensional breach, dimensional disassociation, energy storm, harmonics, hydrokinesis, psionic blast, shadow shape, singularity</i>, and <i>tremor</i>.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_ECTOPLASMIC_CONSTRUCT" spellcasting="Wilder" known="true" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Astral Trick" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHAPER_ASTRAL_TRICK">
            <description>
                <p>You may select any cantrip from the sorcerer list which you manifest it as a psionic power. The cantrip no longer has any components, instead it gains psychic and either glow or beam visual detections. Any duration greater than 1 round requires maintenance with the same timeframe as the spell’s duration. All other details of the cantrip are the same. Cantrips gained through this feature count as wilder powers for you.</p>
                <p class="indent">When you reach 5th level, you may select a second cantrip from the sorcerer list, modified the same way as above. You gain additional converted cantrips at 11th level (third cantrip), and 16th level (fourth cantrip).</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can manifest selected Sorcerer cantrips as psionic powers.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Astral Trick)" supports="Sorcerer,0" spellcasting="Wilder" level="1" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Astral Trick)" supports="Sorcerer,0" spellcasting="Wilder" level="5" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Astral Trick)" supports="Sorcerer,0" spellcasting="Wilder" level="11" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Astral Trick)" supports="Sorcerer,0" spellcasting="Wilder" level="16" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Manifest Magic" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHAPER_MANIFEST_MAGIC">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 7th level, you may use your power points to manifest instantaneous evocation spells from the sorcerer list. You must use a number of power points equal to twice the spell’s level. If a spell allows using a higher level slot, you may expend additional power points to do so. Increasing a spell’s level requires 2 power points per level. For example, if you manifest a fireball spell using 8 power points, you deal 10d6 fire damage. You can’t manifest 9th-level spells, nor can you spend more power points than your wilder level (to a maximum of 16 points).</p>
                <p class="indent">Spells you can manifest include <i>burning hands, chromatic orb, magic missile, thunder wave</i> (1st level), <i>scorching ray, shatter</i> (2nd level), <i>fireball , lightning bolt</i> (3rd level), <i>ice storm</i> (4th level), <i>cone of cold</i> (5th level), <i>chain lightning</i> (6th level), <i>fire storm, prismatic spray</i> (7th level), <i>sunburst</i> (8th level). You don’t require spell components when manifesting evocation spells. Instead, they are manifest with psychic, gesture, and visual detections.</p>
                <p class="indent">You use your power save DC and attack modifier. Manifested spells can’t be maintained, but can be manifested without breaking concentration on psionic powers.</p>
                <p class="indent">Other sorcerer spells from additional sources may be included as approved by your Dungeon Master. Spells must be from the evocation school and have instantaneous duration.</p>
            </description>
            <spellcasting name="Manifest Magic" ability="Intelligence" prepare="false">
                <list known="true">Sorcerer, Evocation, Instantaneous</list>
            </spellcasting>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can manifest sorcerer evocation spells with instantaneous duration using twice the spell’s level of power points. These spells cannot be maintained using concentration. You can’t manifest 9th-level spells, nor can you spend more than {{level:wilder}} power points.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="manifest-magic:limit" value="level:wilder" />
                <stat name="manifest-magic:limit" value="-1" level="17" />
                <stat name="manifest-magic:limit" value="-1" level="18" />
                <stat name="manifest-magic:limit" value="-1" level="19" />
                <stat name="manifest-magic:limit" value="-1" level="20" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Ectoplasmic Shield" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHAPER_ECTOPLASMIC_SHIELD">
            <description>
                <p>At 11th level, when you are hit by a spell or power that deals damage, you can use your reaction to erect a shield of ectoplasm that can absorb damage equal to half your wilder level times your Intelligence modifier. The shield remains in place until the end of your next turn. You may do this a number of times equal to your Intelligence bonus (minimum once). Once you finish a long rest you regain all uses of this feature.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Reaction" usage="{{ecto-shield:uses}}/Long Rest">
                <description>When you are hit by a spell or power that deals damage, you can use your reaction to erect a shield of ectoplasm that can {{ecto-shield:damage}} absorb damage. The shield remains in place until the end of your next turn.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="ecto-shield:uses" value="1" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="ecto-shield:uses" value="intelligence:modifier" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="ecto-shield:damage" value="level:wilder:half" requirements="[intelligence:modifier:1]" />
                <stat name="ecto-shield:damage" value="level:wilder:half" requirements="[intelligence:modifier:2]" />
                <stat name="ecto-shield:damage" value="level:wilder:half" requirements="[intelligence:modifier:3]" />
                <stat name="ecto-shield:damage" value="level:wilder:half" requirements="[intelligence:modifier:4]" />
                <stat name="ecto-shield:damage" value="level:wilder:half" requirements="[intelligence:modifier:5]" />
                <stat name="ecto-shield:damage" value="level:wilder:half" requirements="[intelligence:modifier:6]" />
                <stat name="ecto-shield:damage" value="level:wilder:half" requirements="[intelligence:modifier:7]" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Sculpt Expressions" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHAPER_SCULPT_EXPRESSIONS">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 17th level, whenever you use a power or spell that affects a square, cube, cone, cylinder, or sphere, you can designate a number of creatures you can see equal to 1 + your Intelligence modifier to be somewhat protected of their effects. The chosen creatures automatically succeed their saving throws against the power or spell, and they take no damage if they would normally take half damage on a successful save.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Whenever you use a power or spell that affects a square, cube, cone, cylinder, or sphere, you can designate {{sculpt-expressions:creatures}} creatures to automatically succeed their saving throws against the power or spell, and they take no damage if they would normally take half damage on a successful save.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="sculpt-expressions:creatures" value="1"/>
                <stat name="sculpt-expressions:creatures" value="intelligence:modifier"/>
            </rules>
        </element>

  <!-- Wilder Psionic Powers -->
    <append id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_ADAPTABILITY">
        <supports>TC Wilder</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_ASTRAL_CONSTRUCT">
        <supports>TC Wilder</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_CONTROL_LIGHT">
        <supports>TC Wilder</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_DEFLECTION">
        <supports>TC Wilder</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_DIMENSIONAL_DISASSOCIATION">
        <supports>TC Wilder</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_DISLOCATION">
        <supports>TC Wilder</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_DISSONANT_DESTINY">
        <supports>TC Wilder</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_ECTOPLASMIC_CREATION">
        <supports>TC Wilder</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_EGO_WHIP">
        <supports>TC Wilder</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_ENERGY_BLAST">
        <supports>TC Wilder</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_FORETHOUGHT">
        <supports>TC Wilder</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_INERTIAL_BARRIER">
        <supports>TC Wilder</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_INTELLECT_FORTRESS">
        <supports>TC Wilder</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_MENTAL_BARRIER">
        <supports>TC Wilder</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_MIND_SPIKE">
        <supports>TC Wilder</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_MIND_THRUST">
        <supports>TC Wilder</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_PSYCHIC_CRUSH">
        <supports>TC Wilder</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_PSYCHIC_STATIC">
        <supports>TC Wilder</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_REMOTE_SIGHT">
        <supports>TC Wilder</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_SAP_VITALITY">
        <supports>TC Wilder</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_SUSPENSION">
        <supports>TC Wilder</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_TELEKINETIC_FLIGHT">
        <supports>TC Wilder</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_TELEMPATHIC_PROJECTION">
        <supports>TC Wilder</supports>
    </append>

  <!-- Medium Psionic Powers -->
    <append id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_APOPSI">
        <supports>TC Medium</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_DIMENSIONAL_DISASSOCIATION">
        <supports>TC Medium</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_EXTRASENSORY_PERCEPTION">
        <supports>TC Medium</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_HYPERCOGNITION">
        <supports>TC Medium</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_ID_INSINUATION">
        <supports>TC Medium</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_MIND_PROBE">
        <supports>TC Medium</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_MISLEAD">
        <supports>TC Medium</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_PRECOGNITION">
        <supports>TC Medium</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_PSYCHOMETRY">
        <supports>TC Medium</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_PUPPETRY">
        <supports>TC Medium</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_TELEKINETIC_GRASP">
        <supports>TC Medium</supports>
    </append>

  <!-- Metamorph Psionic Powers -->
    <append id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_ACCELERATED_HEALING">
        <supports>TC Metamorph</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_BIOMORPHIC_SKIN">
        <supports>TC Metamorph</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_CHAMELEON">
        <supports>TC Metamorph</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_DECAY">
        <supports>TC Metamorph</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_ELASTIC_BODY">
        <supports>TC Metamorph</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_ENERGY_SHROUD">
        <supports>TC Metamorph</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_MARTIAL_INSIGHT">
        <supports>TC Metamorph</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_MOLECULAR_AGITATION">
        <supports>TC Metamorph</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_SIZE_ALTERATION">
        <supports>TC Metamorph</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_SPEED_OF_THOUGHT">
        <supports>TC Metamorph</supports>
    </append>

  <!-- Shaper Psionic Powers -->
    <append id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_ANIMATE_ELECTRICITY">
        <supports>TC Shaper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_DIMENSIONAL_BREACH">
        <supports>TC Shaper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_DIMENSIONAL_DISASSOCIATION">
        <supports>TC Shaper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_ENERGY_STORM">
        <supports>TC Shaper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_HARMONICS">
        <supports>TC Shaper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_HYDROKINESIS">
        <supports>TC Shaper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_PSIONIC_BLAST">
        <supports>TC Shaper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_SHADOW_SHAPE">
        <supports>TC Shaper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_SINGULARITY">
        <supports>TC Shaper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_TREMOR">
        <supports>TC Shaper</supports>
    </append>

</elements>