<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Therin Creative’s Psion Class</name>
        <update version="0.0.3">
            <file name="class-psion.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/therin-creative/psionic-rules-set/class-psion.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Psion" type="Class" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_CLASS_PSION">
        <description>
            <p>Negotiations have been going poorly for two sides in a heated debate, when suddenly, one of the heads of states agrees to a settlement. Out of sight, a half-orc sweeps a hand over his brow and breathes a sigh of relief, as his thoughts leave the mind of the negotiator.</p>
            <p class="indent">A human suffers a grievous injury from the axe of a gnoll. He steadies his nerves as he encases his skin in iron, deflecting the gnoll’s next attack. With a quick strike to the gnoll, his injuries heal as they transfer to the gnoll. He smiles as he surveys the field and sees more gnolls arrive. The fight has only now begun.</p>
            <p class="indent">Lurched over a chest, an elf’s eyes widen and she flawlessly dodges an arrow meant for her head. In a moment, she mentally maneuvers the chest before her, shielding her from her attacker’s arrows before slamming the chest through the air to make an attack of her own.</p>
            <p class="indent">Though each expression is different, all psions manifest their will upon the world. Whether they use their powers to gain advantage in trade or to fight in the chaotic fray of battle, all psions bear a measure of confidence that comes from understanding their inner will and the ability to force that will upon others.</p>
            <h4>SHAPER OF WILL</h4>
            <p>Within the multiverse is a universal power of spiritual energies, energies that psions learn to tap and shape through sheer will. For some, tapping the realm of the psychic is simply a way to exert control over one’s self or the surrounding world. Certain psions delve into mysticism to gain a sense of inner peace. Others seek to tap such forces to gain immense power.</p>
            <p class="indent">Psychic energies are complex and require rigorous discipline and understanding to master. Most psions focus on one such discipline, learning to shape these energies in a particular force, whether that force is of the body, external force, the realm of thoughts, or higher consciousness.</p>
            <h4>MASTER OF THE MIND</h4>
            <p>Seeking to master and control psychic energies, psions often form schools to pursue learning and share techniques. While psionic power is shaped by will, understanding of disciplines is a scholarly pursuit. This allows psions to more rapidly learn how to shape psychic energies from other disciplines.</p>
            <p class="indent">In some cases, psions might chase experience in more practical applications, and can readily find a place with other adventurers. Psions bring knowledge along with their ability to manipulate and shape psychic power into a wide range of psionic effects that often proves valuable to adventuring.</p>
            <h4>CREATING A PSION</h4>
            <p>As you craft your psion, you need to determine which psionic discipline your character first studied. This will define what powers you can select and help shape what roles in your adventuring group you can fill or support.</p>
            <p class="indent">You will want to decide what drove your character to leave sheltered study to risk a life of adventure. Were you bored of contemplative study and wanted to try something more practical to enhance your knowledge? Maybe you were tasked with some labor by your school to prove your place among the learned. You also want to decide how your psion treats others. Perhaps you are haughty and feel mundane people are inferior to you, and you need to demonstrate your mental powers. Maybe psionics are misunderstood and hated or feared, so you take on the role of emissary to challenge these beliefs. As a psion, you’ll find you fill roles similar to sorcerers. Your power selection will determine the reach of your abilities.</p>
            <h5>QUICK BUILD</h5>
            <p>You can make a psion quickly by following these suggestions. First, Intelligence should be your highest ability score, followed by Constitution. Second choose the sage background. Third choose the following set of powers: martial insight and extrasensory perception (clairsentience), energy blast and kinetic barrier (psychokinesis), accelerated healing and empathic transference (psychometabolism), or psionic blast and psychic domination (telepathy).</p>
            <h2>CLASS FEATURES</h2>
            <p>As an psion, you gain the following class features.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">HIT POINTS</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Hit Dice:</strong> 1d6 per psion level</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at 1st Level:</strong> 6 + your Constitution modifier</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at Higher Levels:</strong> 1d6 (or 4) + your Constitution modifier per psion level after 1st</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">PROFICIENCIES</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled mb">
                <li><strong>Armor:</strong> None</li>
                <li><strong>Weapons:</strong> Simple weapons</li>
                <li><strong>Tools:</strong> None</li>
            </ul>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Saving Throws:</strong> Intelligence, Wisdom</li>
                <li><strong>Skills:</strong> Choose two from Deception, Esoteric, History, Insight, Investigation, and Perception</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">EQUIPMENT</h5>
            <p>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>(a) a light crossbow and 20 bolts or (b) any simple weapon</li>
                <li>(a) a scholar’s pack or (b) an explorer’s pack</li>
                <li>10 darts</li>
            </ul>
        <!-- class table here -->
            <h5 class="caption">THE PSION</h5>
            <table class="class-features">
                <thead>
                    <tr><td class="col-5">Level</td><td class="col-10">Proficiency Bonus</td><td class="col-60 left">Features</td><td class="col-10">Powers Known</td><td class="col-10">Power Points</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td> 1st</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Power Manifestation, Way of Will</td><td>2</td><td>1</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 2nd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Psionic Fortitude</td><td>3</td><td>2</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 3rd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Psicrystal</td><td>4</td><td>4</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 4th</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>4</td><td>6</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 5th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">─</td><td>4</td><td>9</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 6th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Way of Will feature</td><td>5</td><td>13</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 7th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Expanded Mind (first power)</td><td>5</td><td>16</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 8th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>5</td><td>20</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 9th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">─</td><td>6</td><td>24</td></tr>
                <tr><td>10th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Way of Will feature</td><td>6</td><td>28</td></tr>
                <tr><td>11th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Expanded Mind (second power)</td><td>6</td><td>30</td></tr>
                <tr><td>12th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>6</td><td>33</td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">─</td><td>7</td><td>36</td></tr>
                <tr><td>14th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Way of Will feature</td><td>7</td><td>39</td></tr>
                <tr><td>15th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Expanded Mind (third power)</td><td>7</td><td>41</td></tr>
                <tr><td>16th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>7</td><td>43</td></tr>
                <tr><td>17th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">─</td><td>8</td><td>45</td></tr>
                <tr><td>18th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Psifocus</td><td>8</td><td>47</td></tr>
                <tr><td>19th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>8</td><td>51</td></tr>
                <tr><td>20th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Indomitable Will</td><td>8</td><td>55</td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_POWER_MANIFESTATION" />
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_WAY_OF_WILL" />
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PSIONIC_FORTITUDE" />
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PSICRYSTAL" />
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" />
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_EXPANDED_MIND" />
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PSIFOCUS" />
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_INDOMITABLE_WILL" />
            <h2>MULTICLASSING</h2>
            <p><b>Prerequisites:</b> Intelligence 13</p>
            <p><b>Proficiencies:</b> None</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="hd">d6</set>
            <set name="short">A psychic that can bend the world to their will.</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" requirements="!ID_TC_PRS_MULTICLASS_PSION" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_INTELLIGENCE" requirements="!ID_TC_PRS_MULTICLASS_PSION" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_WISDOM" requirements="!ID_TC_PRS_MULTICLASS_PSION" />
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency, Psion" supports="TC Psion" number="2" requirements="!ID_TC_PRS_MULTICLASS_PSION" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_POWER_MANIFESTATION" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_WAY_OF_WILL" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PSIONIC_FORTITUDE" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PSICRYSTAL" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" level="4" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_EXPANDED_MIND" level="7" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PSIFOCUS" level="18" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_INDOMITABLE_WILL" level="20" />
        </rules>
        <multiclass id="ID_TC_PRS_MULTICLASS_PSION">
            <prerequisite>Intelligence 13</prerequisite>
            <requirements>[int:13]</requirements>
            <setters>
                <set name="multiclass proficiencies"></set>
            </setters>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS" />
            </rules>
        </multiclass>
    </element>
        <element name="Power Manifestation" type="Class Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_POWER_MANIFESTATION">
            <description>
                <p>Whether born with latent psychic talent, through mutation, or by being affected upon by some mysterious source, you have the ability to manifest psionic powers with only a concerted thought.</p>
                <h5>POWERS KNOWN</h5>
                <p>You know two powers of your choice from the psion power list. Both powers must belong to your way of will’s discipline. Future powers known must also come from a discipline you know at least one psion power from. The Expanded Mind feature will allow you to unlock additional disciplines. Once unlocked, you can freely select your known powers from any discipline you know.</p>
                <p class="indent">The Powers Known column of the Psion table shows when you learn more psion powers of your choice. Unlike spell casting classes, you may not replace powers when you gain levels in this class.</p>
                <h5>POWER POINTS</h5>
                <p>The Psion table shows how many power points you have to augment your psion powers. When you manifest a power, you can expend power points to enhance your power. You can expend a number of power points no greater than your psion level on a single power. You regain all expended power points when you finish a short or long rest.</p>
                <p class="indent">Psionic powers differ from spells in that powers can have different expressions when augmented by power points. These different expressions have a similar theme, but the scope and scale can change. For example, the suspension power includes expressions that can affect single targets or an area with different measures of control.</p>
                <h5>MANIFESTING ABILITY</h5>
                <p>Intelligence is your manifesting ability for your powers.</p>
                <p class="indent">You use Intelligence whenever a power refers to your manifesting ability. In addition, you use your Intelligence modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a psion power you manifest and when making an attack roll.</p>
                <p style="align-text: center;"><b>Power save DC</b> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier</p>
                <p style="align-text: center;"><b>Power attack modifier</b> = your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You have {{psionic-power:points}} power points to expend on psionic powers. You can expend no more than {{level:psion}} power points on a single power.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="psionic-power:points" value="1" level="1"/>
                <stat name="psionic-power:points" value="1" level="2"/>
                <stat name="psionic-power:points" value="2" level="3"/>
                <stat name="psionic-power:points" value="2" level="4"/>
                <stat name="psionic-power:points" value="3" level="5"/>
                <stat name="psionic-power:points" value="4" level="6"/>
                <stat name="psionic-power:points" value="3" level="7"/>
                <stat name="psionic-power:points" value="4" level="8"/>
                <stat name="psionic-power:points" value="4" level="9"/>
                <stat name="psionic-power:points" value="4" level="10"/>
                <stat name="psionic-power:points" value="2" level="11"/>
                <stat name="psionic-power:points" value="3" level="12"/>
                <stat name="psionic-power:points" value="3" level="13"/>
                <stat name="psionic-power:points" value="3" level="14"/>
                <stat name="psionic-power:points" value="2" level="15"/>
                <stat name="psionic-power:points" value="2" level="16"/>
                <stat name="psionic-power:points" value="2" level="17"/>
                <stat name="psionic-power:points" value="2" level="18"/>
                <stat name="psionic-power:points" value="4" level="19"/>
                <stat name="psionic-power:points" value="4" level="20"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Psionic Power (Psion)" supports="$(spellcasting:list)" spellcasting="Psion" number="2" level="1" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Psionic Power (Psion)" supports="$(spellcasting:list)" spellcasting="Psion" level="2" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Psionic Power (Psion)" supports="$(spellcasting:list)" spellcasting="Psion" level="3" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Psionic Power (Psion)" supports="$(spellcasting:list)" spellcasting="Psion" level="6" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Psionic Power (Psion)" supports="$(spellcasting:list)" spellcasting="Psion" level="9" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Psionic Power (Psion)" supports="$(spellcasting:list)" spellcasting="Psion" level="13" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Psionic Power (Psion)" supports="$(spellcasting:list)" spellcasting="Psion" level="17" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Way of Will" type="Class Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_WAY_OF_WILL">
            <description>
                <p>Psions manifest their psychic powers under one discipline in which they remain the most skilled. Disciplines encompass powers of similar type including telepathic powers, psychokinetic expressions, clairsentient awareness, and powers of mind over body. When a psion first discovers its power it learns two powers from one of these disciples, using these powers as launching points to further master the psion’s power.</p>
                <p class="indent">Psions must select one way of will from which springs the core of their psionic power. These include the Will of Essence (mind over body), the Will of Force (psychokinetic powers), Will of Foresight (clairsentient powers), and the Will of Thought (telepathic powers). This selection will grant you access to select powers from the psion list within your way of will’s discipline. You gain features at 1st level, and again at 6th, 10th, and 14th level.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Archetype" name="Way of Will" supports="Way of Will" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Psionic Fortitude" type="Class Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PSIONIC_FORTITUDE">
            <description>
                <p>At 2nd level, you are more resilient to managing stress caused from maintaining powers. When you take damage from psychic strain, you reduce the damage caused from stress by an amount equal to your Intelligence bonus. Damage from stress can’t be reduced to less than 1 damage.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you take damage from psychic strain, you reduce the damage caused from stress by {{psion-ability:modifier}}. Damage from stress can’t be reduced to less than 1 damage.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Psicrystal" type="Class Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PSICRYSTAL">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 3rd level, you can imbue a crystal or gem with a psionic power you know. You can then use this gem to manifest that psionic power without consuming power points. Once used, the crystal becomes inert. You can recharge the crystal with the same or a new power by completing a short or long rest and meditating for 30 minutes.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can imbue one or more psicrystals with power points whose total equals half your psion level. A psicrystal must have at least 1 power point. For instance, a 6th-level psion could imbue a psicrystal with 2 power points and a second psicrystal with 1 power point. When using a psicrystal you can choose how to spend its power points at the time of activation.</p>
                <p class="indent">Manifesting a power with a psicrystal is an action equivalent to manifesting the power yourself. A psicrystal can maintain a power a number of rounds equal to your Intelligence bonus or the maximum maintenance time of the power, whichever is lower. The crystal must remain in your possession during the maintenance or the effect is ended. A power maintained by a psicrystal doesn’t use your concentration. Once the power is no longer maintained, the crystal will shatter into dust.</p>
                <p class="indent">To create the psicrystal you must possess a natural, nonmagical gem or crystal worth at least 10 gp per power point it has, and meditate on it for 1 full hour. You can do so only after completing a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can imbue one or more psicrystals with up to {{level:psion:half}} power points. You can then use this gem to manifest that psionic power without consuming power points. Once used, the crystal becomes inert. A psicrystal can maintain a power for {{psion-ability:modifier}} rounds or the maximum maintenance time of the power, whichever is lower. You can recharge the crystal with the same or a new power by completing a short or long rest and meditating for 30 minutes.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Ability Score Improvement" type="Class Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Psion 4)" supports="Improvement Option,Psion,4" level="4" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Psion 8)" supports="Improvement Option,Psion,8" level="8" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Psion 12)" supports="Improvement Option,Psion,12" level="12" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Psion 16)" supports="Improvement Option,Psion,16" level="16" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Psion 19)" supports="Improvement Option,Psion,19" level="19" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Expanded Mind" type="Class Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_EXPANDED_MIND">
            <description>
                <p>At 7th level, and again at 11th and 15th level, you may add one additional power from the psion list to your powers known from any discipline.</p>
                <p class="indent">After acquiring a power through this feature, you can continue to add powers from the same discipline when you gain new powers known, in addition to other disciplines you have learned though this feature.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Psionic Discipline" supports="TC Psionic Discipline" level="7" />
                <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Psionic Discipline" supports="TC Psionic Discipline" level="11" />
                <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Psionic Discipline" supports="TC Psionic Discipline" level="15" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Psionic Power (Expanded Mind)" supports="$(spellcasting:list)" spellcasting="Psion" level="7" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Psionic Power (Expanded Mind)" supports="$(spellcasting:list)" spellcasting="Psion" level="11" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Psionic Power (Expanded Mind)" supports="$(spellcasting:list)" spellcasting="Psion" level="15" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Psifocus" type="Class Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PSIFOCUS">
            <description>
                <p>Upon reaching 18th level, your psicrystals no longer shatter when used to maintain a power.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Your psicrystals no longer shatter when used to maintain a power.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Indomitable Will" type="Class Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_INDOMITABLE_WILL">
            <description>
                <p>At 20th level, once per turn, if a target succeeds its saving throw against one of your powers or one manifested by your psicrystal (but not a psychic item), you can force it to reroll that saving throw. The result of the new save must be used. You can only do this once per Intelligence modifier (minimum 1). You regain all uses after completing a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="{{indomitable-will:uses}}/Long Rest">
                <description>Once per turn, if a target succeeds its saving throw against one of your powers or one manifested by your psicrystal (but not a psychic item), you can force it to reroll that saving throw. The result of the new save must be used.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="indomitable-will:uses" value="1" bonus="base"/>
                <stat name="indomitable-will:uses" value="1" bonus="base"/>
            </rules>
        </element>

  <!-- Ways of Will -->
    <element name="Will of Essence" type="Archetype" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_PSION_WILL_OF_ESSENCE">
        <supports>Way of Will</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Psions of the Will of Essence master the concept of mind over body. Often ascetics, they learn to tap psychic currents to manipulate the bodies of creatures. The discipline of this way of will, psychometabolism, has many personal powers, but psions can augment these powers to affect others.</p>
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ESSENCE_PSYCHOMETABOLISM" />
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ESSENCE_PHYSICAL_RESOLVE" />
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ESSENCE_PSIONIC_REGULATION" />
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ESSENCE_UNCOUSIOUS_CONTROL" />
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ESSENCE_LINGERING_REGULATION" />
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ESSENCE_MASTERY_OF_SELF" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <spellcasting name="Psion" ability="Intelligence" prepare="false" allowReplace="false">
            <list>TC Psion</list>
        </spellcasting>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ESSENCE_PSYCHOMETABOLISM" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ESSENCE_PHYSICAL_RESOLVE" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ESSENCE_PSIONIC_REGULATION" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ESSENCE_UNCOUSIOUS_CONTROL" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ESSENCE_LINGERING_REGULATION" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ESSENCE_MASTERY_OF_SELF" level="14" />
            <stat name="psion-ability:modifier" value="intelligence:modifier" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Psychometabolism" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ESSENCE_PSYCHOMETABOLISM">
            <supports>TC Psionic Discipline</supports>
            <description>
                <p>Psions of the Will of Essence have power over biological bodies. Principally these powers allow them to modify their own bodies, but, often through touch, they can affect the bodies of others. Psychometabolic powers have no affect on creatures that are not organic in nature, such as constructs, elementals, and creatures with no solid form, such as a wraith.</p>
                <p class="indent">You may select powers from the psychometabolic discipline.</p>
            </description>
            <spellcasting name="Psion" extend="true">
                <extend>TC Psionic Power, Psychometabolism</extend>
            </spellcasting>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Physical Resolve" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ESSENCE_PHYSICAL_RESOLVE">
            <description>
                <p>When you take this Way of Will at 1st level, you regain one Hit Dice when you complete a short rest.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can use your action to spend one Hit Dice to regain 1d6 + your Intelligence modifier hit points. When you reach 6th level, you can spend 2 Hit Dice to regain 2d6 + your Intelligence modifier hit points.</p>
                <p class="indent">At 11th level, you can spend Hit Dice by taking a bonus action, but can only spend Hit Dice once per round. At 16th level, you treat any result of 3 or less when you spend Hit Dice as a 4.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description >You regain one Hit Dice when you complete a short rest. You can use your action to spend {{physical-resolve:hd}} Hit Dice to regain {{physical-resolve:hd}}d6 + {{intelligence:modifier}} hit points.</description>
                <description level="11">You regain one Hit Dice when you complete a short rest. You can use your action to spend {{physical-resolve:hd}} Hit Dice to regain {{physical-resolve:hd}}d6 + {{intelligence:modifier}} hit points. You can use your bonus action to spend 1 Hit Dice.</description>
                <description level="16">You regain one Hit Dice when you complete a short rest. You can use your action to spend {{physical-resolve:hd}} Hit Dice to regain {{physical-resolve:hd}}d6 + {{intelligence:modifier}} hit points. You can use your bonus action to spend 1 Hit Dice. You treat any result as 3 or less as a 4.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="physical-resolve:hd" value="1" level="1" />
                <stat name="physical-resolve:hd" value="1" level="6" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Psionic Regulation" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ESSENCE_PSIONIC_REGULATION">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, you gain proficiency with Constitution saving throws.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CONSTITUTION" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Uncousious Control" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ESSENCE_UNCOUSIOUS_CONTROL">
            <description>
                <p>Upon reaching 6th level, you can maintain your psychometabolic powers while incapacitated or unconscious provided they only affect you. Any power that is maintained on yourself and other creatures is no longer in effect on each target except you when you become incapacitated. This functions even if you are dying, stunned, paralyzed, or petrified.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can maintain your psychometabolic powers while incapacitated or unconscious provided they only affect you. Any power that is maintained on yourself and other creatures is no longer in effect on each target except you when you become incapacitated.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Lingering Regulation" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ESSENCE_LINGERING_REGULATION">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 10th level, you can take a bonus action on your turn on to allow a psychometabolic power you manifest to endure for a number of rounds equal to your Intelligence modifier. These powers must have a range of either self or touch. Additionally, only one of your lingering powers can be in effect on a given target at any time, and any new lingering power will replace the earlier effect.</p>
                <p class="indent">A power you are maintaining, as well as a power you first manifest, can benefit from this feature. You may only use this feature three times per rest. Completing a short or long rest will restore all uses of this ability.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="3/Short Rest">
                <description>You can allow a psychometabolic power you manifest to endure for {{intelligence:modifier}} rounds. These powers must have a range of either self or touch. Additionally, only one of your lingering powers can be in effect on a given target at any time, and any new lingering power will replace the earlier effect.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Mastery of Self" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ESSENCE_MASTERY_OF_SELF">
            <description>
                <p>At 14th level, you gain advantage on your saving throw against transmutation spells, psychometabolic powers, and the petrified condition.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You have advantage on your saving throw against transmutation spells, psychometabolic powers, and the petrified condition.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    <element name="Will of Force" type="Archetype" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_PSION_WILL_OF_FORCE">
        <supports>Way of Will</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Practitioners of the Will of Force use telekinetic powers to manipulate the world around them, often through sheer force. They tend to be short tempered and brash, ready to knock opponents away.</p>
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FORCE_PSYCHOKINESIS" />
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FORCE_MANIFEST_WILL" />
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FORCE_DAMPEN_IMPACT" />
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FORCE_KINETIC_EXPRESSION" />
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FORCE_KINETIC_MASTERY" />
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FORCE_IMPROVED_KINETIC_EXPRESSION" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <spellcasting name="Psion" ability="Intelligence" prepare="false" allowReplace="false">
            <list>TC Psion</list>
        </spellcasting>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FORCE_PSYCHOKINESIS" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FORCE_MANIFEST_WILL" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FORCE_DAMPEN_IMPACT" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FORCE_KINETIC_EXPRESSION" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FORCE_KINETIC_MASTERY" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FORCE_IMPROVED_KINETIC_EXPRESSION" level="14" />
            <stat name="psion-ability:modifier" value="intelligence:modifier" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Psychokinesis" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FORCE_PSYCHOKINESIS">
            <supports>TC Psionic Discipline</supports>
            <description>
                <p>Psions of the Will of Force have mastery over telekinetic and related psionic expressions. They can create projections of force and energy that they can move, manipulate, or use to impact their surroundings.</p>
                <p class="indent">You may select powers from the psychokinesis discipline.</p>
            </description>
            <spellcasting name="Psion" extend="true">
                <extend>TC Psionic Power, Psychokinesis</extend>
            </spellcasting>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Manifest Will" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FORCE_MANIFEST_WILL">
            <description>
                <p>At 1st level, having a natural talent for psychokinetic powers, you don’t suffer disadvantage when making a ranged attack with a psionic power when you are within 5 feet of a hostile creature.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You don’t suffer disadvantage when making a ranged attack with a psionic power when you are within 5 feet of a hostile creature.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Dampen Impact" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FORCE_DAMPEN_IMPACT">
            <description>
                <p>When you take this Way of Will at 1st level, you reduce fall damage you take by one die. At 6th level this reduction increases to two dice. It increases to three dice at 10th level, and to four dice at 14th level.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You reduce fall damage you take by {{dampen-impact:dice}} dice.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="dampen-impact:dice" value="1" level="1" />
                <stat name="dampen-impact:dice" value="1" level="6" />
                <stat name="dampen-impact:dice" value="1" level="10" />
                <stat name="dampen-impact:dice" value="1" level="14" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Kinetic Expression" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FORCE_KINETIC_EXPRESSION">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 6th level, you can begin to manifest energy in means beyond raw force. Psychokinetic powers you manifest can take on elemental properties based on your kinetic expression. You may select from pyrokinesis, cryokinesis, electrokinesis, sonokinesis, or greater telekinesis.</p>
                <p class="indent">An energy power can be manifest with the damage type of your Kinetic Expression feature at will when you manifest it. Also, when you augment a non-energy psychokinetic power, you can imbue it with your expression a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum 1). You regain all uses after completing a long rest.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Pyrokinesis.</b> You gain control over fire. Each energy power you manifest can deal fire damage instead of the normal damage type if you choose.</p>
                <p class="indent">Powers you imbue deal 1d8 bonus fire damage to their targets when you first manifest the power, and at the start of each of its turns so long as the power remains in effect on its target. You must spend at least 1 power point to gain this benefit.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Cryokinesis.</b> You can decrease temperatures and create ice from water in the air. Each energy power you manifest can deal cold damage instead of the normal damage type if you choose.</p>
                <p class="indent">Powers you imbue inflict lingering cold, dealing 1d6 bonus cold damage when you first manifest the power. Additionally, any creature that fails the power’s saving throw and takes cold damage suffers a −2 penalty on weapon attack rolls, ability checks, and AC so long as the power remains in effect on the target. If the power allows no saving throw normally, a creature affected is permitted a Constitution saving throw against your power save DC to avoid this penalty. You must spend at least 1 power point to gain this benefit.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Electrokinesis.</b> Electric current can surround your manifestations. Each energy power you manifest can deal lightning damage instead of the normal damage type if you choose.</p>
                <p class="indent">Powers you imbue deal 1d8 bonus lightning damage when you first manifest the power, and at the start of each of its turns so long as the power remains in effect on the target. You must spend at least 1 power point to gain this benefit.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Sonokinesis.</b> You create ultra frequency sounds that rip through matter. Each power you imbue with the sonic expression make a noticeable sound. Creatures made of inorganic material such as stone, crystal, or metal have disadvantage on any saving throw required by your imbued powers and your energy powers that deal thunder damage. Each energy power you manifest can deal thunder damage instead of the normal damage type if you choose.</p>
                <p class="indent">Powers you imbue with sonic expression deal 1d8 bonus thunder damage when you first manifest the power. You must spend at least 1 power point to gain this benefit.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Greater Telekinesis.</b> Your telekinetic manifestations have greater force. Psychokinetic powers that pick up loose objects can rip chucks of earth, stone, and other terrain to use in place of objects.</p>
                <p class="indent">Each energy power you manifest deals the normal damage, but gains one additional die of damage. Powers you imbue deal 1d6 bonus bludgeoning damage whenever the power would deal bludgeoning damage, and if they normally can move a target, move that target up to an additional 10 feet. You must spend at least 1 power point to gain this benefit.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Kinetic Expression" supports="TC Kinetic Expression" />
                <stat rule="kinetic-expression:bonus-dice" value="1" level="6" />
                <stat rule="kinetic-expression:bonus-dice" value="1" level="14" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Pyrokinesis" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FORCE_KINETIC_EXPRESSION_PYROKINESIS">
                <supports>TC Kinetic Expression</supports>
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>You gain control over fire. Each energy power you manifest can deal fire damage instead of the normal damage type if you choose.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Powers you imbue deal 1d8 bonus fire damage to their targets when you first manifest the power, and at the start of each of its turns so long as the power remains in effect on its target. You must spend at least 1 power point to gain this benefit.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>Each energy power you manifest can deal fire damage instead of the normal damage type if you choose. Powers you imbue deal {{kinetic-expression:bonus-dice}}d8 bonus fire damage to their targets when you first manifest the power, and at the start of each of its turns so long as the power remains in effect on its target. You must spend at least 1 power point to gain this benefit.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Cryokinesis" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FORCE_KINETIC_EXPRESSION_CRYOKINESIS">
                <supports>TC Kinetic Expression</supports>
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>You can decrease temperatures and create ice from water in the air. Each energy power you manifest can deal cold damage instead of the normal damage type if you choose.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Powers you imbue inflict lingering cold, dealing 1d6 bonus cold damage when you first manifest the power. Additionally, any creature that fails the power’s saving throw and takes cold damage suffers a −2 penalty on weapon attack rolls, ability checks, and AC so long as the power remains in effect on the target. If the power allows no saving throw normally, a creature affected is permitted a Constitution saving throw against your power save DC to avoid this penalty. You must spend at least 1 power point to gain this benefit.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>Each energy power you manifest can deal cold damage instead of the normal damage type if you choose. Powers you imbue inflict lingering cold, dealing {{kinetic-expression:bonus-dice}}d6 bonus cold damage when you first manifest the power. Additionally, any creature that fails the power’s saving throw(or Constitution saving throw if none) and takes cold damage suffers a −2 penalty on weapon attack rolls, ability checks, and AC so long as the power remains in effect on the target.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Electrokinesis" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FORCE_KINETIC_EXPRESSION_ELECTROKINESIS">
                <supports>TC Kinetic Expression</supports>
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>Electric current can surround your manifestations. Each energy power you manifest can deal lightning damage instead of the normal damage type if you choose.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Powers you imbue deal 1d8 bonus lightning damage when you first manifest the power, and at the start of each of its turns so long as the power remains in effect on the target. You must spend at least 1 power point to gain this benefit.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>Each energy power you manifest can deal lightning damage instead of the normal damage type if you choose. Powers you imbue deal {{kinetic-expression:bonus-dice}}d8 bonus lightning damage when you first manifest the power, and at the start of each of its turns so long as the power remains in effect on the target. You must spend at least 1 power point to gain this benefit.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Sonokinesis" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FORCE_KINETIC_EXPRESSION_SONOKINESIS">
                <supports>TC Kinetic Expression</supports>
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>You create ultra frequency sounds that rip through matter. Each power you imbue with the sonic expression make a noticeable sound. Creatures made of inorganic material such as stone, crystal, or metal have disadvantage on any saving throw required by your imbued powers and your energy powers that deal thunder damage. Each energy power you manifest can deal thunder damage instead of the normal damage type if you choose.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Powers you imbue with sonic expression deal 1d8 bonus thunder damage when you first manifest the power. You must spend at least 1 power point to gain this benefit.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>Each power you imbue with the sonic expression make a noticeable sound. Creatures made of inorganic material such as stone, crystal, or metal have disadvantage on any saving throw required by your imbued powers and your energy powers that deal thunder damage. Each energy power you manifest can deal thunder damage instead of the normal damage type if you choose. Powers you imbue with sonic expression deal {{kinetic-expression:bonus-dice}}d8 bonus thunder damage when you first manifest the power. You must spend at least 1 power point to gain this benefit.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Greater Telekinesis" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FORCE_KINETIC_EXPRESSION_GREATER_TELEKINESIS">
                <supports>TC Kinetic Expression</supports>
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>Your telekinetic manifestations have greater force. Psychokinetic powers that pick up loose objects can rip chucks of earth, stone, and other terrain to use in place of objects.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Each energy power you manifest deals the normal damage, but gains one additional die of damage. Powers you imbue deal 1d6 bonus bludgeoning damage whenever the power would deal bludgeoning damage, and if they normally can move a target, move that target up to an additional 10 feet. You must spend at least 1 power point to gain this benefit.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>Psychokinetic powers that pick up loose objects can rip chucks of earth, stone, and other terrain to use in place of objects. Each energy power you manifest gains one additional die of damage. Powers you imbue deal {{kinetic-expression:bonus-dice}}d6 bonus bludgeoning damage whenever the power would deal bludgeoning damage, and if they normally can move a target, move that target up to an additional {{greater-telekinesis:range}} feet. You must spend at least 1 power point to gain this benefit.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="greater-telekinesis:range" value="10" level="6" />
                    <stat name="greater-telekinesis:range" value="10" level="14" />
                </rules>
            </element>
        <element name="Kinetic Mastery" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FORCE_KINETIC_MASTERY">
            <description>
                <p>Upon reaching 10th level, you gain damage resistance to your kinetic expression element. If you have the greater telekinesis expression, you gain resistance to bludgeoning damage.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_FIRE" requirements="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FORCE_KINETIC_EXPRESSION_PYROKINESIS" />
                <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_COLD" requirements="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FORCE_KINETIC_EXPRESSION_CRYOKINESIS" />
                <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_LIGHTNING" requirements="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FORCE_KINETIC_EXPRESSION_ELECTROKINESIS" />
                <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_THUNDER" requirements="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FORCE_KINETIC_EXPRESSION_SONOKINESIS" />
                <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_BLUDGEONING" requirements="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FORCE_KINETIC_EXPRESSION_GREATER_TELEKINESIS" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Improved Kinetic Expression" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FORCE_IMPROVED_KINETIC_EXPRESSION">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 14th level, your Kinetic Expression feature’s effects improve. Powers you imbue deal an additional bonus die of damage when first manifested, cryokinesis’s penalty lingers for two rounds, and greater telekinesis can move targets 20 feet farther than normal.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    <element name="Will of Foresight" type="Archetype" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_PSION_WILL_OF_FORESIGHT">
        <supports>Way of Will</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Seeing not just the future, but multiple possible futures and the threads that cause each, psions of the Will of Foresight are born seers and prophets. Recognizing patterns in fate and making even the most subtle of changes is how the seer operates.</p>
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FORESIGHT_CLAIRSENTIENCE" />
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FORESIGHT_INTROSPECTIVE_MANIFESTER" />
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FORESIGHT_MINDS_EYE" />
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FORESIGHT_SEERS_GAIT" />
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FORESIGHT_PRESCIENCE" />
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FORESIGHT_HIDDEN_VIEWER" />
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FORESIGHT_CHOICE_OF_FATE" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <spellcasting name="Psion" ability="Wisdom" prepare="false" allowReplace="false">
            <list>TC Psion</list>
        </spellcasting>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FORESIGHT_CLAIRSENTIENCE" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FORESIGHT_INTROSPECTIVE_MANIFESTER" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FORESIGHT_MINDS_EYE" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FORESIGHT_SEERS_GAIT" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FORESIGHT_PRESCIENCE" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FORESIGHT_HIDDEN_VIEWER" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FORESIGHT_CHOICE_OF_FATE" level="14" />
            <stat name="psion-ability:modifier" value="wisdom:modifier" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Clairsentience" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FORESIGHT_CLAIRSENTIENCE">
            <supports>TC Psionic Discipline</supports>
            <description>
                <p>Clairsentient powers allow you to see into the future or the past as well as distant places. They can also reveal the unseen or grant premonitions for both dangerous and fortuitous outcomes.</p>
                <p class="indent">You may select powers from the clairsentience discipline.</p>
            </description>
            <spellcasting name="Psion" extend="true">
                <extend>TC Psionic Power, Clairsentience</extend>
            </spellcasting>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Introspective Manifester" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FORESIGHT_INTROSPECTIVE_MANIFESTER">
            <description>
                <p>Adept in delving into the hidden knowledge of the multiverse, you can substitute your Wisdom for Intelligence as your manifesting ability score and for psion class features.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description>You can substitute your Wisdom for Intelligence as your manifesting ability score and for psion class features.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Mind’s Eye" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FORESIGHT_MINDS_EYE">
            <description>
                <p>When you take this Way of Will at 1st level, whenever you roll for initiative while surprised, you do so with advantage.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Whenever you roll for initiative while surprised, you do so with advantage.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Seer’s Gait" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FORESIGHT_SEERS_GAIT">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, you can see possible outcomes to your movements. You may take the Disengage action using a bonus action.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>You may take the Disengage action.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Prescience" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FORESIGHT_PRESCIENCE">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, you are able to glimpse possible outcomes to situations involving you. You may add your Intelligence bonus to any one attack roll, ability check, or saving throw you make, or you may add your Intelligence bonus to your AC against one attack against you.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can use this feature after the roll is made. This feature doesn’t use an action. You may use Prescience a number of times equal to one fourth of your psion level (rounded down). Completing a long rest restores all uses of this feature</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You may add {{wisdom:modifier}} to any one attack roll, ability check, or saving throw you make, or you may add {{wisdom:modifier}} to your AC against one attack against you.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Hidden Viewer" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FORESIGHT_HIDDEN_VIEWER">
            <description>
                <p>Upon reaching 10th level, your clairsentient powers can no longer be detected through heightened senses, psychic abilities, or magical means. Additionally, each psionic power you use can’t be traced back to you through magical or psionic means.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Your clairsentient powers can no longer be detected through heightened senses, psychic abilities, or magical means. Additionally, each psionic power you use can’t be traced back to you through magical or psionic means.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Choice of Fate" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FORESIGHT_CHOICE_OF_FATE">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 14th level, you can treat one attack roll, ability check, or saving throw made by you as a roll of 20, or you can treat one attack roll, ability check, or saving throw against you as a roll of 1. You can wait until you know the result of the roll before deciding to use this power. You regain use of this feature after completing a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
                <description>You can treat one attack roll, ability check, or saving throw made by you as a roll of 20, or you can treat one attack roll, ability check, or saving throw against you as a roll of 1. You can wait until you know the result of the roll before deciding to use this power.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    <element name="Will of Thought" type="Archetype" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_PSION_WILL_OF_THOUGHT">
        <supports>Way of Will</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Also called telepaths, these psions master powers that directly affect the mind. They can alter thoughts and feelings, and even control the minds of others. Most psions of the Will of Thought are reserved and disciplined, qualities necessary to shut out the cacophony of thoughts abundant in the world of humans.</p>
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THOUGHT_TELEPATHY" />
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THOUGHT_WILLFUL_EXPRESSION" />
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THOUGHT_SENSE_MINDS" />
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THOUGHT_THOUGHT_SHIELD" />
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THOUGHT_MENTAL_CONDUIT" />
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THOUGHT_TOWER_OF_IRON_WILL" />
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THOUGHT_PSYCHIC_CHIRURGERY" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <spellcasting name="Psion" ability="Charisma" prepare="false" allowReplace="false">
            <list>TC Psion</list>
        </spellcasting>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THOUGHT_TELEPATHY" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THOUGHT_WILLFUL_EXPRESSION" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THOUGHT_SENSE_MINDS" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THOUGHT_THOUGHT_SHIELD" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THOUGHT_MENTAL_CONDUIT" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THOUGHT_TOWER_OF_IRON_WILL" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THOUGHT_PSYCHIC_CHIRURGERY" level="14" />
            <stat name="psion-ability:modifier" value="charisma:modifier" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Telepathy" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THOUGHT_TELEPATHY">
            <supports>TC Psionic Discipline</supports>
            <description>
                <p>Psions under the Way of Thought are telepaths, empaths, and mind readers. They can transmit thoughts to other creatures and even mentally assault others.</p>
                <p class="indent">You may select powers from the telepathy discipline.</p>
            </description>
            <spellcasting name="Psion" extend="true">
                <extend>TC Psionic Power, Telepathy</extend>
            </spellcasting>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Willful Expression" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THOUGHT_WILLFUL_EXPRESSION">
            <description>
                <p>Through mastery of influencing the wills and minds of other, you can substitute your Charisma in place of your Intelligence as your manifesting ability score and for psion class features.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Sense Minds" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THOUGHT_SENSE_MINDS">
            <description>
                <p>At 1st level, you have gained an awareness of the thoughts of those around you. You can effectively locate any beast, dragon, fey, giant, humanoid, or monstrosity within 60 feet of you. This allows you to be aware of the location of any hidden or invisible creature, and you can target them with telepathic powers or use their location as the point of origin for other powers, spells, or special abilities.</p>
                <p class="indent">Using this feature requires you to spend 1 minute concentrating, during which time you have psionic focus. Once a creature is sensed, you remain aware of it passively until it moves more than 60 feet from you. When you use this feature, your DM will tell you how many minds you sense and their current state (such as nervous, angered, distracted, etc.).</p>
                <p class="indent">You can choose to focus on one of these creatures, for which you will know its exact location in relation to you. Once you focus on a creature you maintain awareness of its location for up to 10 minutes if it is more than 60 feet away from you, so long as it remains on the same plane of existence. Protected minds, such as through mind blank, are not sensed at all.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can effectively locate any beast, dragon, fey, giant, humanoid, or monstrosity within 60 feet of you. This allows you to be aware of the location of any hidden or invisible creature, and you can target them with telepathic powers or use their location as the point of origin for other powers, spells, or special abilities.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Thought Shield" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THOUGHT_THOUGHT_SHIELD">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, you gain proficiency with Charisma saving throws.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CHARISMA" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Mental Conduit" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THOUGHT_MENTAL_CONDUIT">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, through practice in maintaining telepathic powers, you can channel psionic energy from a manifested power to maintain an existing power. While you are maintaining one telepathic power, if you manifest a second telepathic power and choose to maintain the new power, you can persist the effect of the first power for a number of rounds equal to your Intelligence bonus or until you stop maintaining the second power, whichever comes first.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you choose to use this feature, it is unavailable until you complete a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
                <description>While you are maintaining one telepathic power, if you manifest a second telepathic power and choose to maintain the new power, you can persist the effect of the first power for {{psion-ability:modifier}} rounds or until you stop maintaining the second power, whichever comes first.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Tower of Iron Will" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THOUGHT_TOWER_OF_IRON_WILL">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 10th level, your sense of self becomes so secure that you can’t be charmed or suffer the effects of command, suggestion, mass suggestion, and similar effects. Your mind can’t be read by others unless you allow it. Against all other telepathic powers, mind-affecting special abilities, and enchantment spells you may add twice your proficiency bonus to your saving throws.</p>
                <p class="indent">Your tower also grants you impressive insight. When you are the target of spells, powers, or special abilities that affect the mind, you gain immediate access to your assailant’s identity and can use your reaction to use your Sense Minds feature to focus on it without restriction on range. If the creature is on another plane of existence, you know which plane, but don’t know where on that plane it is.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can’t be charmed or suffer the effects of command, suggestion, mass suggestion, and similar effects. Your mind can’t be read by others unless you allow it. Against all other telepathic powers, mind-affecting special abilities, and enchantment spells you may add twice your proficiency bonus to your saving throws. When you are the target of spells, powers, or special abilities that affect the mind, you gain immediate access to your assailant’s identity and can use your reaction to use your Sense Minds feature to focus on it without restriction on range.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Psychic Chirurgery" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THOUGHT_PSYCHIC_CHIRURGERY">
            <description>
                <p>Upon achieving 14th level, you gain the power to delve deep into a creature’s thoughts and manipulate memories, talents, and personality.</p>
                <p class="indent">Principally, psychic chirurgery is used to repair mental damage, psychological trauma, or remove baleful effects. Offensively it can be used to impart phobias, erase or rewrite memories, or even foster a new persona.</p>
                <div class="sidebar">
                    <h5 class="caption">USING PSYCHIC CHIRURGERY</h5>
                    <p>Through this feature, a psion of the Will of Thought can change PCs and NPCs in ways beyond most powers and features. The implications can be game changing. It is very important to work out details with your DM, and recognize your DM will have final say of the exact ramifications of this feature. </p>
                    <p class="indent">Be extremely cautious about using this feature on player characters, particularly on the more extreme components, such as rewriting a creature’s entire personality.</p>
                </div>
                <p class="indent">In order to operate, you need unrestricted access to the subject for a period no less than one hour. Unwilling subjects must be restrained or incapacitated during the chirurgery, and an unwilling subject must make a Wisdom saving each hour to prevent mental alteration.</p>
                <p class="indent">The results of this feature on a subject can last for months and years or even be permanent. Removing negative effects are permanent (of course the effect could always be reapplied).</p>
                <p class="indent">If you have more than one subject, you can transfer knowledge, memories, and personalities between the subjects instead of creating your own edits to the subject’s mind. Transference applies to all subjects in the same timeframe. For instance, if you are transplanting a memory from one subject to another and removing that transplanted memory from the source, it would only take you one hour to perform both tasks since you are taking from one subject and adding it to the other.</p>
                <p class="indent">In one hour’s time it is possible to:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Add, remove, or alter one section of memory such as the memory of a specific place, person, or event. This effect is permanent, however, any time the subject is confronted with a contradiction of the altered memory, it must make a Charisma saving throw against your power save DC. For each success, the subject regains awareness of the former memory (or that the current memory is false) and will undo some of the memory alteration. Keep track of successes made this way, and when the subject has completed five successful saving throws, the altered memories are restored to the original memory.</li>
                    <li>Remove the effect of the feeblemind spell or similar effect, including those bestowed by a wish or divine intervention.</li>
                    <li>Remove geas or mass suggestion, or undo modify memory or apopsi.</li>
                    <li>Undo the magic jar spell, provided you have access to the subject’s body.</li>
                    <li>Allow a creature that died while under the synaptic static condition to be raised through normal means.</li>
                    <li>Permanently remove knowledge of a single spell or power, including a cantrip. A creature that can choose from a list of spells, such as a cleric, loses knowledge that it can access that spell. A subject can replace the missing spell or power through training or other means requiring at least one week per spell level (one month for a cantrip or psionic power) and spending the equivalent of gold to copy a new spell, if applicable. A unique spell may not be able to be learned again unless the subject meets the criteria to relearn it.</li>
                    <li>Permanently add, remove, or replace a phobia to a specific kind of creature (such as spiders), specific person (such as you), specific event (such as sound of metal clanging on metal), specific kind of object (such as fire), or to a particular phrase, possibly if only uttered by a specific person (such as the subject’s name if spoken by their brother). You can substitute other primal emotions such as rage or sympathy instead of a phobia (such as making a creature sympathetic to the plight of innocent people).</li>
                    <li>Add, remove, or alter a proficiency in a skill or tool or knowledge in a language. You must know the skill, tool, or language in question or have access to another who does and is available to participate (willing or unwilling) in the psychic chirurgery. Proficiency knowledge is lost (or restored) after seven days per level of psion you possess. Subjects who gained a new tool or language skill from the Psychic Chirurgery feature may count the time the feature granted knowledge of the proficiency toward the 250 days required to learn a new tool or language skill. For example, if a 15th-level psion grants the subject skill in using artisan tools for 105 days, and later, after the effects have faded, that subject decides to learn artisan tools, it is considered to have already completed 105 days of training, needing only 145 days to complete training and add artisan tools to its list of skills. If psychic chirurgery would complete such training, the subject must finish at least one additional day at cost to finalize gaining the proficiency.</li>
                    <li>Permanently add, remove, or alter a personality quirk, such as a nervous tick, discomfort from a certain stimulus, or stuttering.</li>
                    <li>Force an astral traveler to return to its body, provided you have access to the body. You can also attempt to reunite a lost astral form to its body if the severance happened within the past 8 hours, but to do so you must succeed a DC 25 Wisdom (Insight) check. If the severance only happened within the last hour when you began the chirurgery, you have a +5 bonus to your roll. A reunited astral form and body is restored to life with 1 hit point.</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">In four hours you can make greater changes in lieu of the changes done in one hour:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Indoctrinate the subject. Indoctrinated subjects are charmed by you, and you can order the creature. If it is able, it will carry out the command. If the command is contrary to the subject’s nature or beliefs, the subject can make a Charisma saving throw at disadvantage to not heed that particular order. Indoctrination lasts for 30 days per psion level.</li>
                    <li>Create a sleeper agent. You set up indoctrination (as described above), but set it to activate when a specific event occurs, including hearing a particular phrase. You can also mentally program a specific instruction that will take place either on trigger or when the opportunity presents itself (such as lowering a drawbridge or speaking a specific line of dialogue to a specific person). Sleeper agents are permanent so long as they haven’t been activated. Once triggered, a sleeper agent will remain indoctrinate for 10 days per psion level you possess.</li>
                    <li>Rewrite a persona. This allows the psion to partially or completely change a creature’s personality. A subject could also be rendered functionally insane (or an insane creature could be restored to normal faculties). A creature’s alignment changes to an appropriate one for the new persona. Like memory alteration, a subject of this effect is permanently altered, but when confronted with a contradiction against the new persona, it makes a Charisma saving throw against your power save DC. If this save succeeds, the creature can act normally a number of minutes equal to its Charisma score. Thereafter, any time the new persona conflicts with the old persona the subject makes a Charisma saving throw to act normally for a number of minutes equal to its Charisma score. For each successful saving throw from contradictions beyond the first, the subject gains a +2 bonus on its Charisma saving throw. After succeeding the contradictory Charisma saving throw five times, the subject is fully restored to its original persona. Creatures of deterministic nature such as fiends and celestials are more resilient against persona alterations and automatically make a Charisma saving throw every 30 days to return to normal, in addition to any granted from contradictions with the new persona.</li>
                    <li>Remove a possessing entity and prevent that entity from ever possessing the subject again.</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">You can only rewrite a subject’s memory or personality to a certain degree; further tinkering will produce no results. A subject’s mind can only be altered by your Psychic Chirurgery a number of hours equal to your Intelligence modifier at any given time. Undoing effects doesn’t count against this limit, thus you can remove a feeblemind effect without consuming an hour’s worth on rewriting the subject’s mind.</p>
                <p class="indent">The effects of psychic chirurgery can be undone by greater restoration or wish. Subjects under the effects of mind blank are immune to Psychic Chirurgery.</p>
                <p class="indent">This ability is exceptionally draining, and you suffer mental exhaustion for one day per hour of psychic chirurgery performed. A day you are unable to take a long rest doesn’t contribute to overcoming this fatigue. While suffering mental exhauston, you can’t maintain powers safely and immediately suffer psychic strain when you maintain a power.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can spend 1 or 4 hours to perform psychic chirurgy.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

</elements>