<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Oath of the Ardent Sacred Oath</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="paladin-oath-of-the-ardent.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/therin-creative/psionic-rules-set/paladin-oath-of-the-ardent.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Oath of the Ardent" type="Archetype" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_PALADIN_OATH_OF_THE_ARDENT">
        <supports>Sacred Oath</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The Oath of the Ardent is taken by paladins possessing an inner fire. Such paladins are stalwart devotees of focus and purpose. They see struggle as inevitable and confront it with calm and reserve. Paladins of this oath serve as leaders or ministers in times of strife and contemplative bastions in periods of calm. When adversity arrives, these paladins change their attitude to one of focus and resolve as easily as someone might don a hat or cloak.</p>
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OATH_OF_THE_ARDENT_TENETS_OF_THE_ARDENT" />
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OATH_OF_THE_ARDENT_POWER_MANIFESTATION" />
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OATH_OF_THE_ARDENT_MANTLE" />
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OATH_OF_THE_ARDENT_CHANNEL_DIVINITY" />
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OATH_OF_THE_ARDENT_AURA_OF_WILL" />
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OATH_OF_THE_ARDENT_SHROUD" />
            <div element="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OATH_OF_THE_ARDENT_INCARNATE" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OATH_OF_THE_ARDENT_TENETS_OF_THE_ARDENT" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OATH_OF_THE_ARDENT_POWER_MANIFESTATION" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OATH_OF_THE_ARDENT_MANTLE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OATH_OF_THE_ARDENT_CHANNEL_DIVINITY" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OATH_OF_THE_ARDENT_AURA_OF_WILL" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OATH_OF_THE_ARDENT_SHROUD" level="15" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OATH_OF_THE_ARDENT_INCARNATE" level="20" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Tenets of the Ardent" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OATH_OF_THE_ARDENT_TENETS_OF_THE_ARDENT">
            <description>
                <p>Those of the Oath of the Ardent don’t typically answer the call of faith or devotion, instead adhering to resolution in deeply held beliefs. However, they are defenders of those who share those beliefs and will take on purpose on their behalf. Paladins of this oath will have resolution matching the mantles they wear.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b><i>Purpose.</i></b> Set a clear goal in a conflict and commit your being toward achieving that goal.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b><i>Resolve.</i></b> With purpose in mind, determine your actions based on the needs of the purpose without losing sight of your values.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b><i>Unwavering.</i></b> When you have been set on your purpose, you mustn’t stray from that purpose.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b><i>Reserve.</i></b> Never allow your emotions to cloud your judgment. Your will is your own to make.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Power Manifestation" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OATH_OF_THE_ARDENT_POWER_MANIFESTATION">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 3rd level, when wearing a mantle, you can manifest psionic powers using your spell slots.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b><i>Powers Known.</i></b> You don’t know any powers, but when you gain a mantle, you gain access to the powers the mantle provides. When you bear a mantle, you always have the powers prepared and they don’t count against how many spells you can prepare.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b><i>Power Points.</i></b> To manifest a power, you must expend a spell slot. You gain 2 power points to augment that power per spell slot level used to manifest the power. Any unused power points are lost. You can’t spend more power points than half your paladin level.</p>
                <p class="indent">If you are a multiclass caster, you can use any of your higher level spell slots to manifest your mantle powers. If you are a multiclass manifester, you can use power points to manifest your mantle powers as normal, but can only spend a number of power points equal to half your paladin level on a single mantle power.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b><i>Manifesting Ability.</i></b> Charisma is your manifesting ability for your powers.</p>
                <p class="indent">You use Charisma whenever a power refers to your manifesting ability. In addition, you use your Charisma modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a psion power you manifest and when making an attack roll.</p>
                <p style="text-align: center;"><b>Power save DC</b> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier</p>
                <p style="text-align: center;"><b>Power attack modifier</b> = your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When wearing a mantle, you can manifest psionic powers using your spell slots. To manifest a power, you must expend a spell slot. You gain 2 power points to augment that power per spell slot level used to manifest the power. Any unused power points are lost. You can’t spend more than {{level:paladin:half}} power points. Charisma is your manifesting ability for your powers.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Mantle" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OATH_OF_THE_ARDENT_MANTLE">
            <description>
                <p>At 3rd level, you are able to attune yourself to a specific creed, granting you access to psionic powers. You may pick two mantles. Each mantle grants you a set of powers known. Your mantle options are detailed at the end of the class description. You can only bear one mantle at a time, and you can change your mantle after completing a long rest when you prepare your spells.</p>
                <p class="indent">When you reach 9th level, you may select an additional mantle, and once again at 17th level.</p>
                <p class="indent">As you gain levels, your active mantle will determine the benefits of your Aura and Shroud features.</p>
                <p class="indent">The Mantle feature replaces the Oath Spells features of the paladin Sacred Oath.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description>You can only bear one mantle at a time, and you can change your mantle after completing a long rest when you prepare your spells.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Ardent Mantle" supports="TC Ardent Mantle" number="2" level="3" />
                <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Ardent Mantle" supports="TC Ardent Mantle" level="9" />
                <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Ardent Mantle" supports="TC Ardent Mantle" level="17" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Channel Divinity" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OATH_OF_THE_ARDENT_CHANNEL_DIVINITY">
            <description>
                <p>When you take this oath at 3rd level, you gain the following two Channel Divinity options.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b><i>Invoke Mantle.</i></b> You can use your Channel Divinity to temporarily wear one of your other mantles. As a bonus action, you gain all the benefits from one mantle you possess for 1 minute. Your powers granted by the mantle are considered prepared during this duration.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b><i>Unleash Psychic Energy.</i></b> You can use your Channel Divinity to release the divine psychic energy of your mantle. Using an action, you strike each creature within a 15-foot cone you choose. Each creature must make a Wisdom saving throw against your power save DC. If the save is failed, the creature is stunned until the end of its next turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OATH_OF_THE_ARDENT_CD_INVOKE_MANTLE" level="3" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OATH_OF_THE_ARDENT_CD_UNLEASH_PSYCHIC_ENERGY" level="3" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Invoke Mantle" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OATH_OF_THE_ARDENT_CD_INVOKE_MANTLE">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>You can use your Channel Divinity to temporarily wear one of your other mantles. As a bonus action, you gain all the benefits from one mantle you possess for 1 minute. Your powers granted by the mantle are considered prepared during this duration.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Channel Divinity" action="Bonus Action">
                    <description>You gain all the benefits from one mantle you possess for 1 minute. Your powers granted by the mantle are considered prepared during this duration.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Unleash Psychic Energy" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OATH_OF_THE_ARDENT_CD_UNLEASH_PSYCHIC_ENERGY">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>You can use your Channel Divinity to release the divine psychic energy of your mantle. Using an action, you strike each creature within a 15-foot cone you choose. Each creature must make a Wisdom saving throw against your power save DC. If the save is failed, the creature is stunned until the end of its next turn.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Channel Divinity" action="Action">
                    <description>You strike each creature within a 15-foot cone you choose. Each creature must make a Wisdom saving throw against your power save DC. If the save is failed, the creature is stunned until the end of its next turn.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
        <element name="Aura of Will" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OATH_OF_THE_ARDENT_AURA_OF_WILL">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 7th level, your active mantle provides an aura affecting you and all friendly creatures within 10 feet of you. You must be conscious to grant the benefits.</p>
                <p class="indent">At 18th level, the range of this aura increases to 30 feet.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Your active mantle now provides an aura effect.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="aura-of-will:range" value="10" level="7"/>
                <stat name="aura-of-will:range" value="20" level="18"/>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Shroud" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OATH_OF_THE_ARDENT_SHROUD">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 15th level, you can use your active mantle to confer upon you some additional benefits. If you have a mount, it also gains the same protections. On your turn, you can activate your shroud which lasts a number of rounds equal to one half your paladin level. After summoning your shroud you can’t summon it again until finishing a short rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
                <description>You can use your active mantle to confer upon you some additional benefits. If you have a mount, it also gains the same protections. On your turn, you can activate your shroud, which lasts {{level:paladin:half}} rounds.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Incarnate" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OATH_OF_THE_ARDENT_INCARNATE">
            <description>
                <p>At 20th level, you can assume all your mantles at once, causing your eyes to shine as bright spots of pure power as energies course around your body as appropriate for your mantles. For instance if you possess the storm mantle, sparks of electricity might cackle around you as supernatural winds blow your hair and clothing.</p>
                <p class="indent">Using your action, you assume your incarnate form for 1 minute, granting you the following benefits:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Your Aura of Will includes all four of your mantle auras at once.</li>
                    <li>You gain the Shroud features of all of your mantles.</li>
                    <li>You can freely use any power you gain from your mantles without preparation and without using a spell slot to manifest it. Such powers gain 4 power points to spend on augmentations. You can use spell slots to increase the power point amount.</li>
                    <li>You are immune to psychic strain, and if you are already suffering from psychic strain, the condition ends.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>you assume your incarnate form for 1 minute, granting you the following benefits: Your Aura of Will includes all four of your mantle auras at once. You gain the Shroud features of all of your mantles. You can freely use any power you gain from your mantles without preparation and without using a spell slot to manifest it. Such powers gain 4 power points to spend on augmentations. You can use spell slots to increase the power point amount. You are immune to psychic strain, and if you are already suffering from psychic strain, the condition ends.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>

  <!-- Oath of the Ardent Mantles -->
    <element name="Communication" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARDENT_OATH_MANTLE_COMMUNICATION">
        <supports>TC Ardent Mantle</supports>
        <description>
            <p><b><i>Aura.</i></b> You and each friendly creature you choose within 10 feet of you can transmit thoughts between one another as if using unaugmented telempathic projection while you are conscious. </p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Shroud.</i></b> You gain immunity to sleep and being charmed, can’t be compelled through magical or psychic means, and any attempt to coerce your mind fails. If you are charmed or otherwise affected mentally, you can activate this shroud during your turn to free yourself.</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Paladin Level</td><td>Power</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>telempathic projection</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>8th</td><td><em>mindlink</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td><em>mind probe</em></td></tr>
            </table>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="Mantle">
            <description></description>
            <description level="7">Aura. You and each friendly creature you choose within {{aura-of-will:range}} feet of you can transmit thoughts between one another as if using unaugmented telempathic projection while you are conscious. </description>
            <description level="15">Aura. You and each friendly creature you choose within {{aura-of-will:range}} feet of you can transmit thoughts between one another as if using unaugmented telempathic projection while you are conscious. Shroud. You gain immunity to sleep and being charmed, can’t be compelled through magical or psychic means, and any attempt to coerce your mind fails. If you are charmed or otherwise affected mentally, you can activate this shroud during your turn to free yourself.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_TELEMPATHIC_PROJECTION" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="3" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_MINDLINK" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="8" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_MIND_PROBE" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="13" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Conflict" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARDENT_OATH_MANTLE_CONFLICT">
        <supports>TC Ardent Mantle</supports>
        <description>
            <p><b><i>Aura.</i></b> You and friendly creatures within 10 feet of you roll one additional die of damage when scoring a critical hit with a weapon attack while you are conscious. </p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Shroud.</i></b> You reduce the damage of each ranged weapon attack directed against you by 2d10 + 10. A foe gains no benefit for having an ally within 5 feet of you unless it has two or more allies within 5 feet of you.</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Paladin Level</td><td>Power</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>speed of thought</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>8th</td><td><em>psychic crush</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td><em>energy shroud</em></td></tr>
            </table>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="Mantle">
            <description></description>
            <description level="7">Aura. You and friendly creatures within {{aura-of-will:range}} feet of you roll one additional die of damage when scoring a critical hit with a weapon attack while you are conscious. </description>
            <description level="15">Aura. You and friendly creatures within {{aura-of-will:range}} feet of you roll one additional die of damage when scoring a critical hit with a weapon attack while you are conscious. Shroud. You reduce the damage of each ranged weapon attack directed against you by 2d10 + 10. A foe gains no benefit for having an ally within 5 feet of you unless it has two or more allies within 5 feet of you.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_SPEED_OF_THOUGHT" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="3" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_PSYCHIC_CRUSH" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="8" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_ENERGY_SHROUD" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="13" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Corruption" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARDENT_OATH_MANTLE_CORRUPTION">
        <supports>TC Ardent Mantle</supports>
        <description>
            <p><b><i>Aura.</i></b> While you aren’t incapacitated, each foe within 10 feet of you suffers disadvantage on saving throws against effects that deal poison damage or inflict the poisoned condition. </p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Shroud.</i></b> You are immune to the poisoned condition and reduce poison damage taken by an amount equal to 1d10 + your Charisma modifier.</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Paladin Level</td><td>Power</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>decay</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>8th</td><td><em>sap vitality</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td><em>shatter psyche</em></td></tr>
            </table>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="Mantle">
            <description></description>
            <description level="7">Aura. While you aren’t incapacitated, each foe within {{aura-of-will:range}} feet of you suffers disadvantage on saving throws against effects that deal poison damage or inflict the poisoned condition. </description>
            <description level="15">Aura. While you aren’t incapacitated, each foe within {{aura-of-will:range}} feet of you suffers disadvantage on saving throws against effects that deal poison damage or inflict the poisoned condition. Shroud. You are immune to the poisoned condition and reduce poison damage taken by an amount equal to 1d10 + your Charisma modifier.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_DECAY" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="3" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_SAP_VITALITY" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="8" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_SHATTER_PSYCHE" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="13" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Creation" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARDENT_OATH_MANTLE_CREATION">
        <supports>TC Ardent Mantle</supports>
        <description>
            <p><b><i>Aura.</i></b> Each construct and object you choose within 10 feet of you regains hit points equal to your Charisma modifier at the start of your turn while you are conscious. Only damage taken within the last hour can be restored through this aura. </p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Shroud.</i></b> You are immune to the petrified condition and can’t be polymorphed against your will. If you are petrified or polymorphed, you can activate this shroud during your turn to free yourself.</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Paladin Level</td><td>Power</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>ectoplasmic creation</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>8th</td><td><em>dimensional breach</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td><em>astral construct</em></td></tr>
            </table>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="Mantle">
            <description></description>
            <description level="7">Aura. Each construct and object you choose within {{aura-of-will:range}} feet of you regains hit points equal to your Charisma modifier at the start of your turn while you are conscious. Only damage taken within the last hour can be restored through this aura. </description>
            <description level="15">Aura. Each construct and object you choose within {{aura-of-will:range}} feet of you regains hit points equal to your Charisma modifier at the start of your turn while you are conscious. Only damage taken within the last hour can be restored through this aura. Shroud. You are immune to the petrified condition and can’t be polymorphed against your will. If you are petrified or polymorphed, you can activate this shroud during your turn to free yourself.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_ECTOPLASMIC_CREATION" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="3" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_DIMENSIONAL_BREACH" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="8" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_ASTRAL_CONSTRUCT" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="13" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Death" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARDENT_OATH_MANTLE_DEATH">
        <supports>TC Ardent Mantle</supports>
        <description>
            <p><b><i>Aura.</i></b> While you aren’t incapacitated, each foe that starts its turn within 10 feet of you must make a Constitution saving throw. If this save is failed, it takes necrotic damage equal to your Charisma bonus (minimum 1). </p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Shroud.</i></b> Weapon attacks you make deal an additional 2d8 necrotic damage. If you have less than half your maximum hit points, you regain a number of hit points equal to half the necrotic damage dealt.</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Paladin Level</td><td>Power</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>dissonant destiny</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>8th</td><td><em>apopsi</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td><em>decay</em></td></tr>
            </table>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="Mantle">
            <description></description>
            <description level="7">Aura. While you aren’t incapacitated, each foe that starts its turn within {{aura-of-will:range}} feet of you must make a Constitution saving throw. If this save is failed, it takes necrotic damage equal to your Charisma bonus (minimum 1). </description>
            <description level="15">Aura. While you aren’t incapacitated, each foe that starts its turn within {{aura-of-will:range}} feet of you must make a Constitution saving throw. If this save is failed, it takes necrotic damage equal to your Charisma bonus (minimum 1). Shroud. Weapon attacks you make deal an additional 2d8 necrotic damage. If you have less than half your maximum hit points, you regain a number of hit points equal to half the necrotic damage dealt.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_DISSONANT_DESTINY" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="3" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_APOPSI" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="8" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_DECAY" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="13" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Deception" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARDENT_OATH_MANTLE_DECEPTION">
        <supports>TC Ardent Mantle</supports>
        <description>
            <p><b><i>Aura.</i></b> You and each friendly creature you choose within 10 feet of you gain advantage on Charisma checks while you are conscious. </p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Shroud.</i></b> You gain the benefit of blur without requiring concentration.</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Paladin Level</td><td>Power</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>mislead</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>8th</td><td><em>chameleon</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td><em>dislocation</em></td></tr>
            </table>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="Mantle">
            <description></description>
            <description level="7">Aura. You and each friendly creature you choose within {{aura-of-will:range}} feet of you gain advantage on Charisma checks while you are conscious. </description>
            <description level="15">Aura. You and each friendly creature you choose within {{aura-of-will:range}} feet of you gain advantage on Charisma checks while you are conscious. Shroud. You gain the benefit of blur without requiring concentration.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_MISLEAD" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="3" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_CHAMELEON" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="8" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_DISLOCATION" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="13" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Destruction" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARDENT_OATH_MANTLE_DESTRUCTION">
        <supports>TC Ardent Mantle</supports>
        <description>
            <p><b><i>Aura.</i></b> When you and friendly creatures within 10 feet of you successfully make an attack roll you gain a +2 bonus on damage rolls while you are conscious. </p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Shroud.</i></b> You have advantage on Constitution saving throws and whenever you succeed a Constitution saving throw to take reduced damage, you instead take no damage.</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Paladin Level</td><td>Power</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>molecular agitation</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>8th</td><td><em>singularity</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td><em>energy blast</em></td></tr>
            </table>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="Mantle">
            <description></description>
            <description level="7">Aura. When you and friendly creatures within {{aura-of-will:range}} feet of you successfully make an attack roll you gain a +2 bonus on damage rolls while you are conscious. </description>
            <description level="15">Aura. When you and friendly creatures within {{aura-of-will:range}} feet of you successfully make an attack roll you gain a +2 bonus on damage rolls while you are conscious. Shroud. You have advantage on Constitution saving throws and whenever you succeed a Constitution saving throw to take reduced damage, you instead take no damage.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_MOLECULAR_AGITATION" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="3" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_SINGULARITY" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="8" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_ENERGY_BLAST" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="13" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Fate" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARDENT_OATH_MANTLE_FATE">
        <supports>TC Ardent Mantle</supports>
        <description>
            <p><b><i>Aura.</i></b> Once per round, you and friendly creatures within 10 feet of you can increase one attack roll, ability check, or saving throw by 1d4 while you are conscious. You must choose to use this effect before the result of the roll is known.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Shroud.</i></b> Whenever you make a saving throw, treat any roll below 12 as a 12. You may use your reaction to reroll a failed saving throw.</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Paladin Level</td><td>Power</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>dissonant destiny</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>8th</td><td><em>probability manipulation</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td><em>trauma infusion</em></td></tr>
            </table>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="Mantle">
            <description></description>
            <description level="7">Aura. Once per round, you and friendly creatures within {{aura-of-will:range}} feet of you can increase one attack roll, ability check, or saving throw by 1d4 while you are conscious. You must choose to use this effect before the result of the roll is known.</description>
            <description level="15">Aura. Once per round, you and friendly creatures within {{aura-of-will:range}} feet of you can increase one attack roll, ability check, or saving throw by 1d4 while you are conscious. You must choose to use this effect before the result of the roll is known. Shroud. Whenever you make a saving throw, treat any roll below 12 as a 12. You may use your reaction to reroll a failed saving throw.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_DISSONANT_DESTINY" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="3" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_PROBABILITY_MANIPULATION" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="8" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_TRAUMA_INFUSION" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="13" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Flame" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARDENT_OATH_MANTLE_FLAME">
        <supports>TC Ardent Mantle</supports>
        <description>
            <p><b><i>Aura.</i></b> You and friendly creatures within 10 feet of you are encircled by orbiting bands of flames while you are conscious. Each creature within 5 feet of you that makes a melee attack against you takes fire damage equal to your Charisma bonus (minimum 1). A creature only takes this damage once per round regardless of how many attacks it makes against you. </p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Shroud.</i></b> You gain a shield that absorbs fire damage for you and grants you damage resistance to fire. Your shield can absorb 20 points of fire damage, refreshing at the start of each of your turns.</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Paladin Level</td><td>Power</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>flame manipulation</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>8th</td><td><em>energy blast (fire)</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td><em>energy shroud (fire)</em></td></tr>
            </table>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="Mantle">
            <description></description>
            <description level="7">Aura. You and friendly creatures within {{aura-of-will:range}} feet of you are encircled by orbiting bands of flames while you are conscious. Each creature within 5 feet of you that makes a melee attack against you takes fire damage equal to your Charisma bonus (minimum 1). A creature only takes this damage once per round regardless of how many attacks it makes against you. </description>
            <description level="15">Aura. You and friendly creatures within {{aura-of-will:range}} feet of you are encircled by orbiting bands of flames while you are conscious. Each creature within 5 feet of you that makes a melee attack against you takes fire damage equal to your Charisma bonus (minimum 1). A creature only takes this damage once per round regardless of how many attacks it makes against you. Shroud. You gain a shield that absorbs fire damage for you and grants you damage resistance to fire. Your shield can absorb 20 points of fire damage, refreshing at the start of each of your turns.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_FLAME_MANIPULATION" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="3" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_ENERGY_BLAST" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="8" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_ENERGY_SHROUD" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="13" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Force" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARDENT_OATH_MANTLE_FORCE">
        <supports>TC Ardent Mantle</supports>
        <description>
            <p><b><i>Aura.</i></b> You and friendly creatures within 10 feet of you may take a bonus action when you hit with a melee weapon attack to knock the target back 10 feet while you are conscious. A creature hit must make a DC 12 Strength saving throw. If failed, the creature is knocked back 10 feet. If the creature hits a creature or object larger in size than it or a wall, it is knocked prone. </p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Shroud.</i></b> You can’t be pushed or knocked prone. When you fall, you take half damage and aren’t knocked prone. You may activate this shroud using a reaction when you are falling.</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Paladin Level</td><td>Power</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>energy blast</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>8th</td><td><em>kinetic barrier</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td><em>telekinetic grasp</em></td></tr>
            </table>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="Mantle">
            <description></description>
            <description level="7">Aura. You and friendly creatures within {{aura-of-will:range}} feet of you may take a bonus action when you hit with a melee weapon attack to knock the target back 10 feet while you are conscious. A creature hit must make a DC 12 Strength saving throw. If failed, the creature is knocked back 10 feet. If the creature hits a creature or object larger in size than it or a wall, it is knocked prone. </description>
            <description level="15">Aura. You and friendly creatures within {{aura-of-will:range}} feet of you may take a bonus action when you hit with a melee weapon attack to knock the target back 10 feet while you are conscious. A creature hit must make a DC 12 Strength saving throw. If failed, the creature is knocked back 10 feet. If the creature hits a creature or object larger in size than it or a wall, it is knocked prone. Shroud. You can’t be pushed or knocked prone. When you fall, you take half damage and aren’t knocked prone. You may activate this shroud using a reaction when you are falling.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_ENERGY_BLAST" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="3" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_KINETIC_BARRIER" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="8" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_TELEKINETIC_GRASP" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="13" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Frost" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARDENT_OATH_MANTLE_FROST">
        <supports>TC Ardent Mantle</supports>
        <description>
            <p><b><i>Aura.</i></b> You and friendly creatures within 10 feet of you reduce cold and fire damage taken by an amount equal to your Charisma bonus (minimum 1) while you are conscious. </p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Shroud.</i></b> You gain resistance to cold damage. Each creature you choose that starts its turn within range of your paladin aura takes cold damage equal to 2d6 + your Charisma bonus.</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Paladin Level</td><td>Power</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>energy storm (cold)</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>8th</td><td><em>energy shroud (cold)</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td><em>hydrokinesis</em></td></tr>
            </table>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="Mantle">
            <description></description>
            <description level="7">Aura. You and friendly creatures within {{aura-of-will:range}} feet of you reduce cold and fire damage taken by an amount equal to your Charisma bonus (minimum 1) while you are conscious. </description>
            <description level="15">Aura. You and friendly creatures within {{aura-of-will:range}} feet of you reduce cold and fire damage taken by an amount equal to your Charisma bonus (minimum 1) while you are conscious. Shroud. You gain resistance to cold damage. Each creature you choose that starts its turn within range of your paladin aura takes cold damage equal to 2d6 + your Charisma bonus.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_ENERGY_STORM" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="3" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_ENERGY_SHROUD" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="8" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_HYDROKINESIS" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="13" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Guardian" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARDENT_OATH_MANTLE_GUARDIAN">
        <supports>TC Ardent Mantle</supports>
        <description>
            <p><b><i>Aura.</i></b> You and friendly creatures within 10 feet of you gain a +1 bonus to AC while you are conscious. </p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Shroud.</i></b> You don’t trigger reactions from moving. When you hit a foe with a melee weapon attack, that foe has disadvantage on each attack roll it makes against a creature other than you until the end of its next turn. You only take half damage from that creature.</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Paladin Level</td><td>Power</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>biomorphic skin</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>8th</td><td><em>dislocation</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td><em>mental barrier</em></td></tr>
            </table>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="Mantle">
            <description></description>
            <description level="7">Aura. You and friendly creatures within {{aura-of-will:range}} feet of you gain a +1 bonus to AC while you are conscious. </description>
            <description level="15">Aura. You and friendly creatures within {{aura-of-will:range}} feet of you gain a +1 bonus to AC while you are conscious. Shroud. You don’t trigger reactions from moving. When you hit a foe with a melee weapon attack, that foe has disadvantage on each attack roll it makes against a creature other than you until the end of its next turn. You only take half damage from that creature.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_BIOMORPHIC_SKIN" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="3" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_DISLOCATION" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="8" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_MENTAL_BARRIER" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="13" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Justice" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARDENT_OATH_MANTLE_JUSTICE">
        <supports>TC Ardent Mantle</supports>
        <description>
            <p><b><i>Aura.</i></b> You and friendly creatures within 10 feet of you gain a +1 bonus on attack rolls against a foe that has attacked you or a friendly creature within the last round while you are conscious. </p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Shroud.</i></b> Whenever you take damage from a melee attack, you may use your reaction to reverse the attack. You reduce the damage of the attack by 2d12 + your Charisma modifier. If you prevent all of the damage, you instead deal the damage prevented to your attacker.</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Paladin Level</td><td>Power</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>ego whip</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>8th</td><td><em>mind probe</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td><em>living weapon</em></td></tr>
            </table>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="Mantle">
            <description></description>
            <description level="7">Aura. You and friendly creatures within {{aura-of-will:range}} feet of you gain a +1 bonus on attack rolls against a foe that has attacked you or a friendly creature within the last round while you are conscious. </description>
            <description level="15">Aura. You and friendly creatures within {{aura-of-will:range}} feet of you gain a +1 bonus on attack rolls against a foe that has attacked you or a friendly creature within the last round while you are conscious. Shroud. Whenever you take damage from a melee attack, you may use your reaction to reverse the attack. You reduce the damage of the attack by 2d12 + your Charisma modifier. If you prevent all of the damage, you instead deal the damage prevented to your attacker.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_EGO_WHIP" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="3" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_MIND_PROBE" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="8" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_LIVING_WEAPON" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="13" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Knowledge" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARDENT_OATH_MANTLE_KNOWLEDGE">
        <supports>TC Ardent Mantle</supports>
        <description>
            <p><b><i>Aura.</i></b> You and each friendly creature you choose within 10 feet of you gain advantage on Intelligence checks while you are conscious. </p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Shroud.</i></b> You are immune to confusion and never fail Intelligence saving throws.</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Paladin Level</td><td>Power</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>hypercognition</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>8th</td><td><em>precognition</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td><em>psychometry</em></td></tr>
            </table>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="Mantle">
            <description></description>
            <description level="7">Aura. You and each friendly creature you choose within {{aura-of-will:range}} feet of you gain advantage on Intelligence checks while you are conscious. </description>
            <description level="15">Aura. You and each friendly creature you choose within {{aura-of-will:range}} feet of you gain advantage on Intelligence checks while you are conscious. Shroud. You are immune to confusion and never fail Intelligence saving throws.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_HYPERCOGNITION" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="3" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_PRECOGNITION" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="8" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_PSYCHOMETRY" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="13" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Life" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARDENT_OATH_MANTLE_LIFE">
        <supports>TC Ardent Mantle</supports>
        <description>
            <p><b><i>Aura.</i></b> You and friendly creatures within 10 feet of you may take a bonus action to regain 1d10 hit points while you are conscious. Only damage taken within the last turn can be regained through this aura. </p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Shroud.</i></b> At the start of each of your turns, you regain twice your Charisma bonus hit points (minimum 1) and have resistance to necrotic damage.</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Paladin Level</td><td>Power</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>accelerated healing</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>8th</td><td><em>empathic transference</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td><em>adaptability</em></td></tr>
            </table>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="Mantle">
            <description></description>
            <description level="7">Aura. You and friendly creatures within {{aura-of-will:range}} feet of you may take a bonus action to regain 1d10 hit points while you are conscious. Only damage taken within the last turn can be regained through this aura. </description>
            <description level="15">Aura. You and friendly creatures within {{aura-of-will:range}} feet of you may take a bonus action to regain 1d10 hit points while you are conscious. Only damage taken within the last turn can be regained through this aura. Shroud. At the start of each of your turns, you regain twice your Charisma bonus hit points (minimum 1) and have resistance to necrotic damage.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_ACCELERATED_HEALING" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="3" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_EMPATHIC_TRANSFERENCE" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="8" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_ADAPTABILITY" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="13" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Magic" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARDENT_OATH_MANTLE_MAGIC">
        <supports>TC Ardent Mantle</supports>
        <description>
            <p><b><i>Aura.</i></b> You and friendly creatures within 10 feet of you are treated as using magical weapons for the purpose of overcoming damage resistance and immunity while you are conscious. </p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Shroud.</i></b> You have resistance to damage from spells and make saving throws against spells with a +2 bonus.</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Paladin Level</td><td>Power</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>mental barrier</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>8th</td><td><em>mind spike</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td><em>dimensional breach</em></td></tr>
            </table>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="Mantle">
            <description></description>
            <description level="7">Aura. You and friendly creatures within {{aura-of-will:range}} feet of you are treated as using magical weapons for the purpose of overcoming damage resistance and immunity while you are conscious. </description>
            <description level="15">Aura. You and friendly creatures within {{aura-of-will:range}} feet of you are treated as using magical weapons for the purpose of overcoming damage resistance and immunity while you are conscious. Shroud. You have resistance to damage from spells and make saving throws against spells with a +2 bonus.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_MENTAL_BARRIER" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="3" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_MIND_SPIKE" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="8" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_DIMENSIONAL_BREACH" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="13" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Mental" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARDENT_OATH_MANTLE_MENTAL">
        <supports>TC Ardent Mantle</supports>
        <description>
            <p><b><i>Aura.</i></b> You and friendly creatures within 10 feet of you gain advantage on saving throws against telepathic spells, powers, and effects, such as mind blast while you are conscious. </p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Shroud.</i></b> You have resistance to psychic damage and can’t be mentally dominated or charmed.</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Paladin Level</td><td>Power</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>id insinuation</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>8th</td><td><em>intellect fortress</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td><em>psychic crush</em></td></tr>
            </table>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="Mantle">
            <description></description>
            <description level="7">Aura. You and friendly creatures within {{aura-of-will:range}} feet of you gain advantage on saving throws against telepathic spells, powers, and effects, such as mind blast while you are conscious. </description>
            <description level="15">Aura. You and friendly creatures within {{aura-of-will:range}} feet of you gain advantage on saving throws against telepathic spells, powers, and effects, such as mind blast while you are conscious. Shroud. You have resistance to psychic damage and can’t be mentally dominated or charmed.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_ID_INSINUATION" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="3" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_INTELLECT_FORTRESS" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="8" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_PSYCHIC_CRUSH" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="13" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Prowess" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARDENT_OATH_MANTLE_PROWESS">
        <supports>TC Ardent Mantle</supports>
        <description>
            <p><b><i>Aura.</i></b> You and each friendly creature you choose within 10 feet of you make Strength and Dexterity checks with advantage while you are conscious. </p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Shroud.</i></b> You add your proficiency bonus to Strength and Dexterity saving throws and checks.</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Paladin Level</td><td>Power</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>martial insight</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>8th</td><td><em>energy shroud</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td><em>kinetic barrier</em></td></tr>
            </table>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="Mantle">
            <description></description>
            <description level="7">Aura. You and each friendly creature you choose within {{aura-of-will:range}} feet of you make Strength and Dexterity checks with advantage while you are conscious. </description>
            <description level="15">Aura. You and each friendly creature you choose within {{aura-of-will:range}} feet of you make Strength and Dexterity checks with advantage while you are conscious. Shroud. You add your proficiency bonus to Strength and Dexterity saving throws and checks.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_MARTIAL_INSIGHT" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="3" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_ENERGY_SHROUD" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="8" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_KINETIC_BARRIER" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="13" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Resolve" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARDENT_OATH_MANTLE_RESOLVE">
        <supports>TC Ardent Mantle</supports>
        <description>
            <p><b><i>Aura.</i></b> You and friendly creatures within 10 feet of you may reroll a failed Wisdom or Charisma saving throw while you are conscious. If the roll was made with disadvantage, the reroll is made without disadvantage. A creature may only benefit from this effect once per minute. </p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Shroud.</i></b> You reduce damage you take by an amount equal to your Charisma bonus, but an attack can’t be reduced to less than 1 damage through this feature. If you are below half your maximum hit points, double this amount. At the start of each of your turns, you remove the following conditions: charmed, frightened, paralyzed, and stunned.</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Paladin Level</td><td>Power</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>adaptability</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>8th</td><td><em>kinetic barrier</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td><em>intellect fortress</em></td></tr>
            </table>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="Mantle">
            <description></description>
            <description level="7">Aura. You and friendly creatures within {{aura-of-will:range}} feet of you may reroll a failed Wisdom or Charisma saving throw while you are conscious. If the roll was made with disadvantage, the reroll is made without disadvantage. A creature may only benefit from this effect once per minute. </description>
            <description level="15">Aura. You and friendly creatures within {{aura-of-will:range}} feet of you may reroll a failed Wisdom or Charisma saving throw while you are conscious. If the roll was made with disadvantage, the reroll is made without disadvantage. A creature may only benefit from this effect once per minute. Shroud. You reduce damage you take by an amount equal to your Charisma bonus, but an attack can’t be reduced to less than 1 damage through this feature. If you are below half your maximum hit points, double this amount. At the start of each of your turns, you remove the following conditions: charmed, frightened, paralyzed, and stunned.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_ADAPTABILITY" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="3" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_KINETIC_BARRIER" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="8" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_INTELLECT_FORTRESS" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="13" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Shadow" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARDENT_OATH_MANTLE_SHADOW">
        <supports>TC Ardent Mantle</supports>
        <description>
            <p><b><i>Aura.</i></b> You and friendly creatures within 10 feet of you gain darkvision out to 60 feet (or an additional 30 feet if you already have darkvision) and have advantage on saving throws against blindness while you are conscious. </p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Shroud.</i></b> You can see in darkness and dim light as if it were bright light up to 60 feet. You can take a bonus action to turn invisible until the end of your next turn or until you make an attack.</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Paladin Level</td><td>Power</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>control light</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>8th</td><td><em>shadow shape</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td><em>chameleon</em></td></tr>
            </table>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="Mantle">
            <description></description>
            <description level="7">Aura. You and friendly creatures within {{aura-of-will:range}} feet of you gain darkvision out to 60 feet (or an additional 30 feet if you already have darkvision) and have advantage on saving throws against blindness while you are conscious. </description>
            <description level="15">Aura. You and friendly creatures within {{aura-of-will:range}} feet of you gain darkvision out to 60 feet (or an additional 30 feet if you already have darkvision) and have advantage on saving throws against blindness while you are conscious. Shroud. You can see in darkness and dim light as if it were bright light up to 60 feet. You can take a bonus action to turn invisible until the end of your next turn or until you make an attack.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_CONTROL_LIGHT" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="3" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_SHADOW_SHAPE" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="8" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_CHAMELEON" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="13" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Sight" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARDENT_OATH_MANTLE_SIGHT">
        <supports>TC Ardent Mantle</supports>
        <description>
            <p><b><i>Aura.</i></b> You and friendly creatures within 10 feet of you gain advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks to see while you are conscious. </p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Shroud.</i></b> You gain blindsense and truesight out to 60 feet. You see a shapechanger in its true form and can detect spiritfonts.</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Paladin Level</td><td>Power</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>remote sight</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>8th</td><td><em>glimmer</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td><em>extrasensory perception</em></td></tr>
            </table>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="Mantle">
            <description></description>
            <description level="7">Aura. You and friendly creatures within {{aura-of-will:range}} feet of you gain advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks to see while you are conscious. </description>
            <description level="15">Aura. You and friendly creatures within {{aura-of-will:range}} feet of you gain advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks to see while you are conscious. Shroud. You gain blindsense and truesight out to 60 feet. You see a shapechanger in its true form and can detect spiritfonts.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_REMOTE_SIGHT" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="3" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_GLIMMER" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="8" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_EXTRASENSORY_PERCEPTION" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="13" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Storm" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARDENT_OATH_MANTLE_STORM">
        <supports>TC Ardent Mantle</supports>
        <description>
            <p><b><i>Aura.</i></b> Once per round, when you and friendly creatures within 10 feet of you hit with a melee weapon attack, you deal an additional 1d6 lightning damage while you are conscious. </p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Shroud.</i></b> You can move unhindered by high winds (including those made from spells or psionic powers) and gain immunity to lightning damage.</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Paladin Level</td><td>Power</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>energy storm (lightning)</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>8th</td><td><em>animate electricity</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td><em>weather manipulation</em></td></tr>
            </table>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="Mantle">
            <description></description>
            <description level="7">Aura. Once per round, when you and friendly creatures within {{aura-of-will:range}} feet of you hit with a melee weapon attack, you deal an additional 1d6 lightning damage while you are conscious. </description>
            <description level="15">Aura. Once per round, when you and friendly creatures within {{aura-of-will:range}} feet of you hit with a melee weapon attack, you deal an additional 1d6 lightning damage while you are conscious. Shroud. You can move unhindered by high winds (including those made from spells or psionic powers) and gain immunity to lightning damage.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_ENERGY_STORM" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="3" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_ANIMATE_ELECTRICITY" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="8" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_WEATHER_MANIPULATION" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="13" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Tremors" type="Archetype Feature" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARDENT_OATH_MANTLE_TREMORS">
        <supports>TC Ardent Mantle</supports>
        <description>
            <p><b><i>Aura.</i></b> You and friendly creatures within 10 feet of you gain advantage on saving throws against being knocked prone or pushed while you are conscious. When pushing a target you have advantage on your ability check. </p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Shroud.</i></b> Once each round, when you hit with a weapon attack, you deal an additional 5d6 thunder damage and a creature your size or smaller hit must make a Strength saving throw against your spellcasting DC or be knocked prone.</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Paladin Level</td><td>Power</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>tremor</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>8th</td><td><em>energy blast</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td><em>inertial barrier</em></td></tr>
            </table>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="Mantle">
            <description></description>
            <description level="7">Aura. You and friendly creatures within {{aura-of-will:range}} feet of you gain advantage on saving throws against being knocked prone or pushed while you are conscious. When pushing a target you have advantage on your ability check. </description>
            <description level="15">Aura. You and friendly creatures within {{aura-of-will:range}} feet of you gain advantage on saving throws against being knocked prone or pushed while you are conscious. When pushing a target you have advantage on your ability check. Shroud. Once each round, when you hit with a weapon attack, you deal an additional 5d6 thunder damage and a creature your size or smaller hit must make a Strength saving throw against your spellcasting DC or be knocked prone.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_TREMOR" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="3" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_ENERGY_BLAST" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="8" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_INERTIAL_BARRIER" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="13" />
        </rules>
    </element>

</elements>