<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Dromite Race</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="race-dromite.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/therin-creative/psionic-rules-set/race-dromite.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Dromite" type="Race" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_RACE_DROMITE">
        <description>
            <p>Beneath the land are hives of a proud people sharing a common family bond. The dromites are a curious race of humanoid with insect features, living in city hives.</p>
            <h4>INSECT BUT HUMANOID</h4>
            <p>Dromites, crassly called bugfolk by those who know no better, are a humanoid race with statures similar to halflings and gnomes. The average dromite stands about 3 feet tall and weighs around 35 pounds. Unlike most other humanoids, dromites are androgynous, with only two members of their hive possessing female or male traits – the Grand Queen and Elected Consort.</p>
            <p class="indent">Dromites have chitin-encrusted skin, compound eyes, and two small antennae protruding from their brows. They have the silhouette of a thin humanoid, but have no body hair. Where a humanoid might possess a head of hair, a dromite has a thin ridge of intricate chitin that smoothly rises from its skin and extends down the base of its head, neck and the rest of its body.</p>
            <p class="indent">A dromite’s eyes sparkle like pale yellow or white luminescent orbs divided into hundreds of tiny cells. Dromite skin ranges from gray to brown to yellow, with chitin having a deeper hue.</p>
            <h4>BONDED FOR LIFE</h4>
            <p>Dromites belong to an ordered society where each dromite is dedicated not only to its hive, but also to others with which it establishes a bond. Dromites are loyal to those they form such emotional bonds with, and will undertake great efforts to protect their people. While dromites have a caste society, there is no barrier between the castes, each working alongside the others to create a functioning, harmonious collective.</p>
            <p class="indent">Dromites will establish special, self-selected groups called life bonds. These relationships are similar to what other races refer to as families, and members of a life bond may have a closeness resembling marriage among its members. Life bonds generally consist of members from all castes.</p>
            <h4>WORKING TOGETHER SEAMLESSLY</h4>
            <p>When a dromite is born to the Grand Queen, it is preselected to a particular caste depending on what traits the hive will need. Each caste focuses on different aspects of dromite society, using the talents of its members to best fulfill its role.</p>
            <p class="indent">Despite being a hive society, dromites are independent individuals with their own dreams and fancies. Unlike other societies, however, dromites are most apt to assist one another in pursuit of such interests, especially in the case of life bonds.</p>
            <h4>CURIOSITY BEYOND THE HIVE</h4>
            <p>Dromites possessed with desire to explore the world outside are fostered and supported by their hive. Dromites are often encouraged to expand their knowledge and talents through interaction with other races, even by life bond members, wishing their loved one to fulfill its heart and to return one day to share the tales of distant people and places.</p>
            <p class="indent">At times, a hive may become too large to remain within its borders. In these cases, many dromites will leave the city-hive to establish a new home. It is common during these times for some dromites to drift away, seizing the opportunity to adventure, until such a time they are ready to return home.</p>
            <h4>DROMITE NAMES</h4>
            <p>Dromites, when born, are chosen from the nurseries by adult dromites who have entered life bonds. The adopted dromite is named by its new “parents" according to the traditions of the life bond. Dromites are proud of their life bond names, but mostly use them among their own kind, using their first name when dealing with other races.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b>First Names:</b> Demisse, Elimu, Fela, Gebre, Idi, Idrissa, Kato, Matunda, Obi, Sefu, Vita, Xolu</p>
            <p class="indent"><b>Life Bond Family Names:</b> Adanech, Dedanech, Fanech, Gyalech, Marimech, Massawech, Nikech, Ulech</p>
            <h4>DROMITE TRAITS</h4>
            <p>Your dromite is born with a number of natural abilities from its insectoid heritage and hive upbringing.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong> Your Charisma score increases by 2.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Age.</em></strong> Dromites mature relatively quickly, becoming full-fledged adults by 15. Typically, they will live well into their 80s.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Alignment.</em></strong> Dromites naturally organize within a hive hierarchy in service of the Grand Queen. Those who are most concerned with service to the hive skew toward an orderly manner. Other dromites, especially those that travel far from the hive, are more open to experiences and are adaptable to new ways of thinking.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Size.</em></strong> Dromites average around 3 feet tall without much variance, weighing about 35 pounds. Your size is Small.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Speed.</em></strong> Your base walking speed is 25 feet.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Chitin.</em></strong> Your skin is hardened like an exoskeleton. Your AC is never less than 13.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Hivemind.</em></strong> You can use <i>telempathic projection</i> at will with members of your hive. Additionally, once per turn, you have advantage on an attack roll against a creature if at least one of your hive members is within 5 feet of the creature and isn’t incapacitated.</p>
            <p class="indent"> You can use this trait with an ally that isn’t a hive member if you are both under the effects of mindlink or a similar effect.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Scent.</em></strong> Your antennae can detect creatures through scent. You have blindsight up to 30 feet, but can only sense creatures or objects that have a distinct scent. When tracking, you gain a +1 bonus on your ability check if your quarry leaves scent traces.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Compound Eyes.</em></strong> You have a +2 bonus on Wisdom (Perception) checks made to spot something.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Languages.</em></strong> You can speak, read, and write Common and are conversant in Terran. Dromites don’t have a language, communicating through their Hivemind trait with members of their own hive.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Subrace.</em></strong> Dromites belong to a caste based on the needs of the hive and the role they are intended to serve. Hives consist of all castes.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <setters>
            <set name="names" type="name">Demisse, Elimu, Fela, Gebre, Idi, Idrissa, Kato, Matunda, Obi, Sefu, Vita, Xolu</set>
            <set name="names" type="clan">Adanech, Dedanech, Fanech, Gyalech, Marimech, Massawech, Nikech, Ulech</set>
            <set name="names-format">{{name}} {{clan}}</set>
            <set name="height" modifier="1d4">3'</set>
            <set name="weight" modifier="1d4">35 lb.</set>
        </setters>
        <rules>
            <stat name="charisma" value="2" />
            <grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_SMALL" />
            <stat name="innate speed" value="25" bonus="base"/>
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_TC_PRS_RACIAL_TRAIT_DROMITE_CHITIN" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_TC_PRS_RACIAL_TRAIT_DROMITE_HIVEMIND" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_TC_PRS_RACIAL_TRAIT_DROMITE_SCENT" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_TC_PRS_RACIAL_TRAIT_DROMITE_COMPOUND_EYES" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_TC_PRS_RACIAL_TRAIT_DROMITE_SUBRACE" />
            <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON" />
            <grant type="Language" id="ID_MM_LANGUAGE_TERRAN" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Chitin" type="Racial Trait" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_RACIAL_TRAIT_DROMITE_CHITIN">
            <description>
                <p>Your skin is hardened like an exoskeleton. Your AC is never less than 13.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Your AC is never less than 13.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Hivemind" type="Racial Trait" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_RACIAL_TRAIT_DROMITE_HIVEMIND">
            <description>
                <p>You can use <i>telempathic projection</i> at will with members of your hive. Additionally, once per turn, you have advantage on an attack roll against a creature if at least one of your hive members is within 5 feet of the creature and isn’t incapacitated.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can use this trait with an ally that isn’t a hive member if you are both under the effects of mindlink or a similar effect.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can use telempathic projection at will with members of your hive. Additionally, once per turn, you have advantage on an attack roll against a creature if at least one of your hive members is within 5 feet of the creature and isn’t incapacitated. You can use this trait with an ally that isn’t a hive member if you are both under the effects of mindlink or a similar effect.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_TELEMPATHIC_PROJECTION" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Scent" type="Racial Trait" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_RACIAL_TRAIT_DROMITE_SCENT">
            <description>
                <p>Your antennae can detect creatures through scent. You have blindsight up to 30 feet, but can only sense creatures or objects that have a distinct scent. When tracking, you gain a +1 bonus on your ability check if your quarry leaves scent traces.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You have blindsight up to 30 feet, but can only sense creatures or objects that have a distinct scent. When tracking, you gain a +1 bonus on your ability check if your quarry leaves scent traces.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Compound Eyes" type="Racial Trait" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_RACIAL_TRAIT_DROMITE_COMPOUND_EYES">
            <description>
                <p>You have a +2 bonus on Wisdom (Perception) checks made to spot something.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You have a +2 bonus on Perception checks made to spot something.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Subrace" type="Racial Trait" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_RACIAL_TRAIT_DROMITE_SUBRACE">
            <description>
                <p>Dromites belong to a caste based on the needs of the hive and the role they are intended to serve. Hives consist of all castes.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Sub Race" name="Dromite Caste" supports="Dromite" />
            </rules>
        </element>

        <element name="Artisan Caste" type="Sub Race" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_SUBRACE_ARTISAN_CASTE">
            <supports>Dromite</supports>
            <description>
                <p>As a member of the artisan caste, you’re analytical and reflective. Often you arrive at decisions slowly, but often these decisions are right.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong> Your Intelligence score increases by 1.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Mind’s Eye.</em></strong> You mind can create a vivid mental picture when you are using tools, simulating how each articulation you make will contribute to a give task. By spending a minute focusing on a task requiring any tool, you gain proficiency with that tool on ability checks toward that task you make within the next 10 minutes. If you already have proficiency with that tool, you gain a +2 bonus on the ability check.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Insightful.</em></strong> You can manifest <i>glimmer</i> 1/day with up to 1 power point in augmentations. Charisma is your manifesting ability.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Practiced Merchant.</em></strong> When bartering, you are a master of the deal. You gain advantage on the first Charisma check you make in negotiating prices with a creature.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false" />
            <rules>
                <stat name="intelligence" value="1" />
                <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_TC_PRS_RACIAL_TRAIT_DROMITE_ARTISAN_MINDS_EYE" />
                <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_TC_PRS_RACIAL_TRAIT_DROMITE_ARTISAN_INSIGHTFUL" />
                <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_TC_PRS_RACIAL_TRAIT_DROMITE_ARTISAN_PRACTICED_MERCHANT" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Mind’s Eye" type="Racial Trait" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_RACIAL_TRAIT_DROMITE_ARTISAN_MINDS_EYE">
                <description>
                    <p>You mind can create a vivid mental picture when you are using tools, simulating how each articulation you make will contribute to a give task. By spending a minute focusing on a task requiring any tool, you gain proficiency with that tool on ability checks toward that task you make within the next 10 minutes. If you already have proficiency with that tool, you gain a +2 bonus on the ability check.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>By spending a minute focusing on a task requiring any tool, you gain proficiency with that tool on ability checks toward that task you make within the next 10 minutes. If you already have proficiency with that tool, you gain a +2 bonus on the ability check.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Insightful" type="Racial Trait" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_RACIAL_TRAIT_DROMITE_ARTISAN_INSIGHTFUL">
                <description>
                    <p>You can manifest <i>glimmer</i> 1/day with up to 1 power point in augmentations. Charisma is your manifesting ability.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="1/day">
                    <description>You can manifest glimmer with up to 1 power point in augmentations. (Charisma)</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_GLIMMER" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Practiced Merchant" type="Racial Trait" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_RACIAL_TRAIT_DROMITE_ARTISAN_PRACTICED_MERCHANT">
                <description>
                    <p>When bartering, you are a master of the deal. You gain advantage on the first Charisma check you make in negotiating prices with a creature.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>You gain advantage on the first Charisma check you make in negotiating prices with a creature.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>

        <element name="Herald Caste" type="Sub Race" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_SUBRACE_HERALD_CASTE">
            <supports>Dromite</supports>
            <description>
                <p>As a member of the herald caste, you are drawn to the arts and performances, often possessing a love of song and dance. You prefer to seek out and establish relationships with other people, indulging in the culture of others.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong> Your Wisdom score increases by 1.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Cooperation.</em></strong> When you and an ally are within 5 feet of the same foe, you can take a bonus action to give that ally advantage on its next attack roll or ability check made against that foe provided you are within 5 feet of that foe when your ally makes its roll.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Dampen Hue.</em></strong> You can manifest <i>chameleon</i> 1/day with 1 power point in augmentations. Charisma is your manifesting ability.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Extra Language.</em></strong> You can speak, read, and write one extra language of your choice.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false" />
            <rules>
                <stat name="wisdom" value="1" />
                <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_TC_PRS_RACIAL_TRAIT_DROMITE_HERALD_COOPERATION" />
                <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_TC_PRS_RACIAL_TRAIT_DROMITE_HERALD_DAMPEN_HUE" />
                <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_TC_PRS_RACIAL_TRAIT_DROMITE_HERALD_EXTRA_LANGUAGE" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Cooperation" type="Racial Trait" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_RACIAL_TRAIT_DROMITE_HERALD_COOPERATION">
                <description>
                    <p>When you and an ally are within 5 feet of the same foe, you can take a bonus action to give that ally advantage on its next attack roll or ability check made against that foe provided you are within 5 feet of that foe when your ally makes its roll.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>When you and an ally are within 5 feet of the same foe, you can take a bonus action to give that ally advantage on its next attack roll or ability check made against that foe provided you are within 5 feet of that foe when your ally makes its roll.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Dampen Hue" type="Racial Trait" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_RACIAL_TRAIT_DROMITE_HERALD_DAMPEN_HUE">
                <description>
                    <p>You can manifest <i>chameleon</i> 1/day with 1 power point in augmentations. Charisma is your manifesting ability.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="1/day">
                    <description>You can manifest chameleon with up to 1 power point in augmentations. (Charisma)</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_CHAMELEON" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Extra Language" type="Racial Trait" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_RACIAL_TRAIT_DROMITE_HERALD_EXTRA_LANGUAGE">
                <description>
                    <p>You can speak, read, and write one extra language of your choice.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <select type="Language" name="Herald Extra Language" />
                </rules>
            </element>

        <element name="Runner Caste" type="Sub Race" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_SUBRACE_RUNNER_CASTE">
            <supports>Dromite</supports>
            <description>
                <p>As a member of the runner caste, you rarely sit still. You tend to move at high speed in pursuit of life’s tasks.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong> Your Dexterity score increases by 1.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Continuous Motion.</em></strong> Once per round, when you hit with a melee attack, you increase your movement speed by 5 feet until the end of your next turn.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Burst of Speed.</em></strong> You can manifest <i>speed of thought</i> 1/day with 1 power point in augmentation. Charisma is your manifesting ability.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Duck and Bob.</em></strong> Once during your turn, you don’t draw an opportunity attack while moving.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false" />
            <rules>
                <stat name="dexterity" value="1" />
                <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_TC_PRS_RACIAL_TRAIT_DROMITE_RUNNER_CONTINUOUS_MOTION" />
                <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_TC_PRS_RACIAL_TRAIT_DROMITE_RUNNER_BURST_OF_SPEED" />
                <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_TC_PRS_RACIAL_TRAIT_DROMITE_RUNNER_DUCK_AND_BOB" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Continuous Motion" type="Racial Trait" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_RACIAL_TRAIT_DROMITE_RUNNER_CONTINUOUS_MOTION">
                <description>
                    <p>Once per round, when you hit with a melee attack, you increase your movement speed by 5 feet until the end of your next turn.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>Once per round, when you hit with a melee attack, you increase your movement speed by 5 feet until the end of your next turn.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Burst of Speed" type="Racial Trait" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_RACIAL_TRAIT_DROMITE_RUNNER_BURST_OF_SPEED">
                <description>
                    <p>You can manifest <i>speed of thought</i> 1/day with 1 power point in augmentation. Charisma is your manifesting ability.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>You can manifest speed of thought with up to 1 power point in augmentations. (Charisma)</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_SPEED_OF_THOUGHT" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Duck and Bob" type="Racial Trait" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_RACIAL_TRAIT_DROMITE_RUNNER_DUCK_AND_BOB">
                <description>
                    <p>Once during your turn, you don’t draw an opportunity attack while moving.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>Once during your turn, you don’t draw an opportunity attack while moving.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>

        <element name="Surveyor Caste" type="Sub Race" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_SUBRACE_SURVEYOR_CASTE">
            <supports>Dromite</supports>
            <description>
                <p>As a member of the surveyor caste, you’re often quick to anger and tend to be suspicious of things you don’t fully know or understand. You also tend to be quick to laugh and forgive.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong> Your Constitution score increases by 1.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Focus on the Target.</em></strong> Whenever you hit a foe with disadvantage on your attack roll, each attack you make against that foe until the end of your turn no longer has disadvantage. Whenever a foe you hit within 5 feet of you moves away from you, you are aware of its position so long as it remains within 30 feet of you.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Fervent Pitch.</em></strong> You can fire a beam of psychokinetic force, manifesting <i>energy blast</i> 1/day with 1 power point in augmentation. Charisma is your manifesting ability.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Dromite Weapon Training.</em></strong> You have proficiency with hand crossbows, javelins, scimitars, and spears.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false" />
            <rules>
                <stat name="constitution" value="1" />
                <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_TC_PRS_RACIAL_TRAIT_DROMITE_SURVEYOR_FOCUS_ON_THE_TARGET" />
                <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_TC_PRS_RACIAL_TRAIT_DROMITE_SURVEYOR_FERVENT_PITCH" />
                <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_TC_PRS_RACIAL_TRAIT_DROMITE_SURVEYOR_DROMITE_WEAPON_TRAINING" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Focus on the Target" type="Racial Trait" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_RACIAL_TRAIT_DROMITE_SURVEYOR_FOCUS_ON_THE_TARGET">
                <description>
                    <p>Whenever you hit a foe with disadvantage on your attack roll, each attack you make against that foe until the end of your turn no longer has disadvantage. Whenever a foe you hit within 5 feet of you moves away from you, you are aware of its position so long as it remains within 30 feet of you.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>Whenever you hit a foe with disadvantage on your attack roll, each attack you make against that foe until the end of your turn no longer has disadvantage. Whenever a foe you hit within 5 feet of you moves away from you, you are aware of its position so long as it remains within 30 feet of you.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Fervent Pitch" type="Racial Trait" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_RACIAL_TRAIT_DROMITE_SURVEYOR_FERVENT_PITCH">
                <description>
                    <p>You can fire a beam of psychokinetic force, manifesting <i>energy blast</i> 1/day with 1 power point in augmentation. Charisma is your manifesting ability.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>You can manifest energy blast with up to 1 power point in augmentations. (Charisma)</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TC_PRS_PSIONIC_POWER_ENERGY_BLAST" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Dromite Weapon Training" type="Racial Trait" source="Therin Creative’s Psionic Rules Set" id="ID_TC_PRS_RACIAL_TRAIT_DROMITE_SURVEYOR_DROMITE_WEAPON_TRAINING">
                <description>
                    <p>You have proficiency with hand crossbows, javelins, scimitars, and spears.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_CROSSBOW_HAND" />
                    <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_JAVELIN" />
                    <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SCIMITAR" />
                    <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SPEAR" />
                </rules>
            </element>
    
</elements>