<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Spellblocker Monastic Tradition</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="monk-spellblocker.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/silent-edict/monk-spellblocker.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Spellblocker" type="Archetype" source="Silent Edict" id="ID_RG_SE_ARCHETYPE_MONK_SPELLBLOCKER">
        <supports>Monastic Tradition</supports>
        <description>
            <div element="ID_RG_SE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPELLBLOCKER_DEFLECT_MAGIC" />
            <div element="ID_RG_SE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPELLBLOCKER_BONUS_PROFICIENCY" />
            <div element="ID_RG_SE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPELLBLOCKER_DELAYED_STRIKES" />
            <div element="ID_RG_SE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPELLBLOCKER_PATIENT_RETURN" />
            <div element="ID_RG_SE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPELLBLOCKER_QUICK_SHELTER" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RG_SE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPELLBLOCKER_DEFLECT_MAGIC" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RG_SE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPELLBLOCKER_BONUS_PROFICIENCY" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RG_SE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPELLBLOCKER_DELAYED_STRIKES" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RG_SE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPELLBLOCKER_PATIENT_RETURN" level="11" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RG_SE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPELLBLOCKER_QUICK_SHELTER" level="17" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Deflect Magic" type="Archetype Feature" source="Silent Edict" id="ID_RG_SE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPELLBLOCKER_DEFLECT_MAGIC">
            <description>
                <p>At 3rd level, you can use your Deflect Missiles ability to reduce the damage of spell and magical effects that would damage you. In addition, you may instead use Deflect missiles without a reaction a number of times equal to your Wisdom Modifier. If the damage is reduced to 0 you spend a ki point and make a ranged attack as normal doing the spell’s or magical effect’s damage.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can use your Deflect Missiles ability to reduce the damage of spell and magical effects that would damage you. You may use Deflect missiles without a reaction a {{wisdom:modifier}} times. If the damage is reduced to 0 you spend a ki point and make a ranged attack as normal doing the spell’s or magical effect’s damage.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Bonus Proficiency" type="Archetype Feature" source="Silent Edict" id="ID_RG_SE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPELLBLOCKER_BONUS_PROFICIENCY">
            <description>
                <p>When you choose this tradition at 3rd level, you gain proficiency in the Arcana skill.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ARCANA" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Delayed Strikes" type="Archetype Feature" source="Silent Edict" id="ID_RG_SE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPELLBLOCKER_DELAYED_STRIKES">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, whenever you successfully hit a creature with consecutive melee weapon attacks, you can delay the damage choosing to deliver it all at once on a later hit in your turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Whenever you successfully hit a creature with consecutive melee weapon attacks, you can delay the damage choosing to deliver it all at once on a later hit in your turn.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Patient Return" type="Archetype Feature" source="Silent Edict" id="ID_RG_SE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPELLBLOCKER_PATIENT_RETURN">
            <description>
                <p>At 11th level, when you reduce damage from a spell or magical effect you can spend 2 ki points to store the damage for later use. Your next unarmed attack is infused with this magic and deals force damage equal to the amount reduced. This damage can crit and you can only store one instance of damage at a time and it lasts until your next short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you reduce damage from a spell or magical effect you can spend 2 ki points to store the damage for later use. Your next unarmed attack is infused with this magic and deals force damage equal to the amount reduced. This damage can crit and you can only store one instance of damage at a time and it lasts until your next short or long rest.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Quick Shelter" type="Archetype Feature" source="Silent Edict" id="ID_RG_SE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPELLBLOCKER_QUICK_SHELTER">
            <description>
                <p>At 17th level, when you would use your Deflect Missiles ability to reduce the damage of an attack, spell or magical effect you also reduce the damage of allies within 5 feet of you. Only a single instance of damage which you choose may be returned or stored for later use.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you would use your Deflect Missiles ability to reduce the damage of an attack, spell or magical effect you also reduce the damage of allies within 5 feet of you. Only a single instance of damage which you choose may be returned or stored for later use.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
    
</elements>