<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Oath of the Mage Hunter Sacred Oath</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="paladin-oath-of-the-mage-hunter.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/silent-edict/paladin-oath-of-the-mage-hunter.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Oath of the Mage Hunter" type="Archetype" source="Silent Edict" id="ID_RG_SE_ARCHETYPE_PALADIN_OATH_OF_THE_MAGE_HUNTER">
        <supports>Sacred Oath</supports>
        <description>
            <div element="ID_RG_SE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OOTMH_TENETS_OF_THE_MAGE_HUNTER" />
            <div element="ID_RG_SE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OOTMH_OATH_SPELLS" />
            <div element="ID_RG_SE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OOTMH_CHANNEL_DIVINITY" />
            <div element="ID_RG_SE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OOTMH_MAGE_HUNTERS_SMITE" />
            <div element="ID_RG_SE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OOTMH_ARCANE_BARRIER" />
            <div element="ID_RG_SE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OOTMH_DIVINE_CONVERSION" />
            <div element="ID_RG_SE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OOTMH_BANE_OF_MAGIC" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RG_SE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OOTMH_TENETS_OF_THE_MAGE_HUNTER" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RG_SE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OOTMH_OATH_SPELLS" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RG_SE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OOTMH_CHANNEL_DIVINITY" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RG_SE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OOTMH_MAGE_HUNTERS_SMITE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RG_SE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OOTMH_ARCANE_BARRIER" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RG_SE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OOTMH_DIVINE_CONVERSION" level="15" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RG_SE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OOTMH_BANE_OF_MAGIC" level="20" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Tenets of the Mage Hunter" type="Archetype Feature" source="Silent Edict" id="ID_RG_SE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OOTMH_TENETS_OF_THE_MAGE_HUNTER">
            <description>
                <p class="indent">A paladin who takes this oath has the tenets of the Silent Edict</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>The Arcane is blashphemous.</em></strong> The use of arcane magic is too dangerous for mortals.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Inspired by the Divine.</em></strong> I will only use my divine magic in the goal of defeating the Arcane.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Knowledge is Power.</em></strong> I will find and collect arcane knowledge so that my order might better overcome magic.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Oath Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="Silent Edict" id="ID_RG_SE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OOTMH_OATH_SPELLS">
            <description>
                <p>You gain oath spells at the paladin levels listed.</p>
                <h5 class="caption">OATH OF THE MAGE HUNTER SPELLS</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Paladin Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>detect magic, shield</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>detect thoughts, silence</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><em>dispel magic, counterspell</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>13th</td><td><em>banishment, divination</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>17th</td><td><em>mislead, commune</em></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_MAGIC" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHIELD" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_THOUGHTS" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SILENCE" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISPEL_MAGIC" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COUNTERSPELL" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BANISHMENT" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="13" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DIVINATION" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="13" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MISLEAD" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="17" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMMUNE" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="17" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Channel Divinity" type="Archetype Feature" source="Silent Edict" id="ID_RG_SE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OOTMH_CHANNEL_DIVINITY">
            <description>
                <p>When you take this oath at 3rd level, you gain the following two Channel Divinity options.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Speak No Evil.</em></strong> As an action, you present your holy symbol and speak a prayer of silence, using your Channel Divinity. Target creature must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or become deafened and unable to make sounds for 1 minute. At the end of each of its turns, the target can make another Constitution saving throw. On a success, the effect ends on the target.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Arcane Chains.</em></strong> You can use your Channel Divinity to manifest a pair of Clarified Lead braclets on an enemy. As an action, choose a creature that you can see within 90 feet of you. The creature must make a Strength saving throw. On a failed save, the creature is grappled for one minute. When grappled in this way they are unable to cast spells that require a somatic component and any weapons they are holding(including natural) become nonmagical for the duration. The creature repeats the saving throw at the end of each of its turns. On a success, it frees itself and the braclets vanish.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RG_SE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OOTMH_CD_SPEAK_NO_EVIL" level="3" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RG_SE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OOTMH_CD_ARCANE_CHAINS" level="3" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Channel Divinity: Speak No Evil" type="Archetype Feature" source="Silent Edict" id="ID_RG_SE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OOTMH_CD_SPEAK_NO_EVIL">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>As an action, you present your holy symbol and speak a prayer of silence, using your Channel Divinity. Target creature must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or become deafened and unable to make sounds for 1 minute. At the end of each of its turns, the target can make another Constitution saving throw. On a success, the effect ends on the target.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Channel Divinity" alt="Speak No Evil" action="Action">
                    <description>Target creature must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or become deafened and unable to make sounds for 1 minute. At the end of each of its turns, the target can make another Constitution saving throw. On a success, the effect ends on the target.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Channel Divinity: Arcane Chains" type="Archetype Feature" source="Silent Edict" id="ID_RG_SE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OOTMH_CD_ARCANE_CHAINS">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>You can use your Channel Divinity to manifest a pair of Clarified Lead braclets on an enemy. As an action, choose a creature that you can see within 90 feet of you. The creature must make a Strength saving throw. On a failed save, the creature is grappled for one minute. When grappled in this way they are unable to cast spells that require a somatic component and any weapons they are holding (including natural) become nonmagical for the duration. The creature repeats the saving throw at the end of each of its turns. On a success, it frees itself and the braclets vanish.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Channel Divinity" alt="Arcane Chains" action="Action">
                    <description>Choose a creature that you can see within 90 feet of you. The creature must make a Strength saving throw. On a failed save, the creature is grappled for one minute. When grappled in this way they are unable to cast spells that require a somatic component and any weapons they are holding (including natural) become nonmagical for the duration.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
        <element name="Mage Hunter’s Smite" type="Archetype Feature" source="Silent Edict" id="ID_RG_SE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OOTMH_MAGE_HUNTERS_SMITE">
            <description>
                <p>Also when you take this oath at 3rd level, your Divine Smite features impose disadvantage on creatures holding concentration.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Your Divine Smite features impose disadvantage on creatures holding concentration.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Arcane Barrier" type="Archetype Feature" source="Silent Edict" id="ID_RG_SE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OOTMH_ARCANE_BARRIER">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 7th level, your knowledge of arcane energies has allowed you form a barrier with a 10 foot radius around you that can absorb energy. This barrier has an amount of hit points equal to twice your Paladin level + your Charisma modifier. Whenever a magical effect would deal damage to a creature within the barrier, the barrier takes damage instead. If damage would reduce the barrier to 0 hit points, any remaining damage is transferred to you, and the barrier dissipates.</p>
                <p class="indent">Whenever you use a spell slot, the barrier gains a number of hit points equal to twice the level of the spell slot.</p>
                <p class="indent">After a long rest, the barrier regains its full hit points.</p>
                <p class="indent">At 18th level, the range of the barrier increases to 30 feet.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You project an arcane barrier with a {{arcane-barrier:radius}}-foot radius and {{arcane-barrier:hp}}. Whenever a magical effect would deal damage to a creature within the barrier, the barrier takes damage instead. If damage would reduce the barrier to 0 hit points, any remaining damage is transferred to you, and the barrier dissipates. Whenever you use a spell slot, the barrier gains a number of hit points equal to twice the level of the spell slot. After a long rest, the barrier regains its full hit points.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="arcane-barrier:hp" value="level:paladin" />
                <stat name="arcane-barrier:hp" value="level:paladin" />
                <stat name="arcane-barrier:hp" value="charisma:modifier" />
                <stat name="arcane-barrier:radius" value="10" level="7" />
                <stat name="arcane-barrier:radius" value="20" level="18" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Divine Conversion" type="Archetype Feature" source="Silent Edict" id="ID_RG_SE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OOTMH_DIVINE_CONVERSION">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 15th level, when you or a creature within your arcane barrier is the target of a spell you can absorb some of the magic to restore a spell slot equal to half the spell level to a maximum of 5th level. You can’t use it again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>When you or a creature within your arcane barrier is the target of a spell you can absorb some of the magic to restore a spell slot equal to half the spell level to a maximum of 5th level.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Bane of Magic" type="Archetype Feature" source="Silent Edict" id="ID_RG_SE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OOTMH_BANE_OF_MAGIC">
            <description>
                <p>At 20th level, you become the ultimate holy mage killer. For one minute you have the following improvements to your abilities.</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>You gain an additional use of your Channel divinity. When this effect ends you lose any additional uses above your maximum.</li>
                    <li>Your Channel divinity: Arcane Chains can target creatures up to your Charisma modifier and restrain the targets.</li>
                    <li>You are sourrounded by an Antimagic Field per the Antimagic Field spell requiring no concentration.</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest" action="Bonus Action">
                <description>For one minute you have the following improvements to your abilities. You gain an additional use of your Channel divinity. You can target up to {{charisma:modifier}} creatures with your Arcane Chains feature. You are sourrounded by an Antimagic Field per the Antimagic Field spell requiring no concentration.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
    
</elements>