<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Spell Sniper Roguish Archetype</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="rogue-spell-sniper.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/silent-edict/rogue-spell-sniper.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Spell Sniper" type="Archetype" source="Silent Edict" id="ID_RG_SE_ARCHETYPE_ROGUE_SPELL_SNIPER">
        <supports>Roguish Archetype</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Through training and underhanded tactics you have learned to fight those who use the Arcane.</p>
            <div element="ID_RG_SE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPELL_SNIPER_ARCANE_INQUIRY" />
            <div element="ID_RG_SE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPELL_SNIPER_EAGLE_EYE" />
            <div element="ID_RG_SE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPELL_SNIPER_ARCANE_EVASION" />
            <div element="ID_RG_SE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPELL_SNIPER_QUICK_SHOT" />
            <div element="ID_RG_SE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPELL_SNIPER_BULLSEYE" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RG_SE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPELL_SNIPER_ARCANE_INQUIRY" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RG_SE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPELL_SNIPER_EAGLE_EYE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RG_SE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPELL_SNIPER_ARCANE_EVASION" level="9" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RG_SE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPELL_SNIPER_QUICK_SHOT" level="13" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RG_SE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPELL_SNIPER_BULLSEYE" level="17" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Arcane Inquiry" type="Archetype Feature" source="Silent Edict" id="ID_RG_SE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPELL_SNIPER_ARCANE_INQUIRY">
            <description>
                <p>You are proficent in Arcana and can add double your proficiency modifier to skill checks with it.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ARCANA" />
                <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_EXPERTISE_SKILL_ARCANA" level="3" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Eagle Eye" type="Archetype Feature" source="Silent Edict" id="ID_RG_SE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPELL_SNIPER_EAGLE_EYE">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 3rd level, you don’t need advantage on the attack roll to use your Sneak Attack against a creature if you are at least 60 feet from it. All the other rules for Sneak Attack still apply to you.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You don’t need advantage on the attack roll to use your Sneak Attack against a creature if you are at least 60 feet from it. All the other rules for Sneak Attack still apply to you.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Arcane Evasion" type="Archetype Feature" source="Silent Edict" id="ID_RG_SE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPELL_SNIPER_ARCANE_EVASION">
            <description>
                <p>At 9th level, your evasion skills improve. Whenever you would be forced to make a saving throw for any magical area effect to take only half damage, you instead take no damage if you succeed on the saving throw, and only half damage if you fail.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Whenever you would be forced to make a saving throw for any magical area effect to take only half damage, you instead take no damage if you succeed on the saving throw, and only half damage if you fail.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Quick Shot" type="Archetype Feature" source="Silent Edict" id="ID_RG_SE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPELL_SNIPER_QUICK_SHOT">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 13th level you become adept at stopping spellcasters. As a reaction to seeing a spell cast by an enemy you can make an attack at disadvantage towards that creature. If it hits the target must make a concentration check equal to 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Dexterity modifier. On failure the spellcast is interrupted and fails to cast.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Reaction">
                <description>As a reaction to seeing a spell cast by an enemy you can make an attack at disadvantage towards that creature. If it hits the target must make a concentration check (DC {{quick-shot:dc}}). On failure the spellcast is interrupted and fails to cast.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="quick-shot:dc" value="8" />
                <stat name="quick-shot:dc" value="proficiency" />
                <stat name="quick-shot:dc" value="dexterity:modifier" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Bullseye" type="Archetype Feature" source="Silent Edict" id="ID_RG_SE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPELL_SNIPER_BULLSEYE">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 17th level, once per round, whenever you hit a creature with an attack and they have a magical effect or spell active on itself or are concentrating on a spell, your sneak attack damage is maximized. When maximized in this way your sneak attack cannot crit.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Once per round, whenever you hit a creature with an attack and they have a magical effect or spell active on itself or are concentrating on a spell, your sneak attack damage is maximized. When maximized in this way your sneak attack cannot crit.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
    
</elements>