<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>GrimmDark Backgrounds</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="backgrounds.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/grimmdark/backgrounds.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Storytouched" type="Background" source="GrimmDark" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_BACKGROUND_STORYTOUCHED">
        <description>
            <p>From the day you were born, your life was trapped inside of a fairy tale. It’s likely that the events of the story are why you were born and how you were treated as some pawn in the cosmic narrative. Perhaps your family was driven crazy by the event, or maybe you were somehow enchanted when the final line was written.</p>
            <p class="indent">Regardless of what happened, when the story ended, you were forever marked. Your reasons for journeying are your own, but they likely include; the desire to find new fairy tales, to undo the effects of what happened to those you loved, or to somehow find an answer or reason to what happened. It seems lucky (or unfortunate) that everywhere you go, fairy tales seem to follow. As the stories stitch themselves together, it’s starting to seem like your entire life is one neverending fable.</p>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Skill Proficiencies:</strong> Insight, Performance</li>
                <li><strong>Tool Proficiencies:</strong> One type of gaming set of your choice, one type of kit of your choice</li>
                <li><strong>Languages:</strong> None</li>
                <li><strong>Equipment:</strong> A set of common clothes, a kit of your choice, a magical trinket from your fairy tale (see table below), a belt pouch containing 10 gp</li>
            </ul>
            <h5>FAIRY TALE TRINKETS</h5>
            <p>When the story that changed you came to an end, you were likely left with some kind of relic from the event. This magical item has come to define you, and it may very well be the thing that keeps attracting fairy tales to you. Below is a list of 10 possible trinkets, but we encourage you to come up with your own.</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d10</td><td>Fairy Tale Trinkets</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>A golden egg that cannot be cracked.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>A magical bean that produces a towering beanstalk and then back to its normal size.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>A pair of red slippers that sparkle when you click the heels together.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>A fruit that makes you drowsy whenever you take a bite, and that always regenerates.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>A small, hand-held mirror that answers mundane, pointless questions.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>A pipe that, when smoked, produces odd phantasms in the rising stack.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>7</td><td>The ring of a powerful leader you have never heard of. Sometimes it laughs at your jokes.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>8</td><td>A toy soldier that has a tendency for leaving your pocket to find and crack nuts.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>9</td><td>An odd snowglobe that shows you inside of a feywild version ofthe location you’re at.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>10</td><td>A black hat that, at night, massages your scalp.</td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_TALE_FINDER" />
            <h5>SUGGESTED CHARACTERISTICS</h5>
            <p>Storytouched are often colorful or robust characters that always seem to be interested in the narratives around them. They enjoy talking to people, hearing their stories, and telling them to others they meet on their adventures. Many, however, are left broken by the fairy tales that birthed them. These storytouched listen to the tales of others only to find a way out of their own endless narrative.</p>
        </description>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_TALE_FINDER" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_OPTIONAL_BACKGROUND_FEATURE"/>
            <select type="Background Feature" name="Variant Feature" supports="Optional Background Feature" optional="true" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERFORMANCE" />
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Kit Proficiency (Storytouched)" supports="Artisan tools" />
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Gaming Set Proficiency (Storytouched)" supports="Gaming Set" />
            <select type="List" name="Fairy Tale Trinked">
                <item id="1">A golden egg that cannot be cracked.</item>
                <item id="2">A magical bean that produces a towering beanstalk and then back to its normal size.</item>
                <item id="3">A pair of red slippers that sparkle when you click the heels together.</item>
                <item id="4">A fruit that makes you drowsy whenever you take a bite, and that always regenerates.</item>
                <item id="5">A small, hand-held mirror that answers mundane, pointless questions.</item>
                <item id="6">A pipe that, when smoked, produces odd phantasms in the rising stack.</item>
                <item id="7">The ring of a powerful leader you have never heard of. Sometimes it laughs at your jokes.</item>
                <item id="8">A toy soldier that has a tendency for leaving your pocket to find and crack nuts.</item>
                <item id="9">An odd snowglobe that shows you inside of a feywild version ofthe location you’re at.</item>
                <item id="10">A black hat that, at night, massages your scalp.</item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="Personality Trait" number="2">
                <item id="1">The first thing I do when meeting a person is to ask them what their story is.</item>
                <item id="2">When I‘m bored, or even when I’m not, I like to come up with new riddles and tongue twisters.</item>
                <item id="3">If there‘s a local superstition. I’m always quick to investigate it.</item>
                <item id="4">I keep a journal of everything that I see. Most of it is highly embellished.</item>
                <item id="5">I believe that the entire world is one grand fairy tale. and I want to see it through till the end.</item>
                <item id="6">It isn’t hard for me to tell exaggerations from reality.</item>
                <item id="7">My life is controlled by patterns and everything I do has to follow this outline.</item>
                <item id="8">When I hear a story and I think it’s incomplete. I have to do my best to join in.</item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="Ideal">
                <item id="1">Adventure. Every story is another adventure to be had. (Any)</item>
                <item id="2">Symbolism. Even the smallest details represent something grander. (Neutral)</item>
                <item id="3">Heroism. There must always be a hero to someone or something’s story. (Good)</item>
                <item id="4">Change. There is always an end and there is always a new beginning. (Neutral)</item>
                <item id="5">Antagonist. There is always an obstacle to someone or something’s story. (Chaotic)</item>
                <item id="6">Creativity. A .ot can change if you give a fresh look to an old idea. (Good)</item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="Bond">
                <item id="1">I once saved a very important person from a very tall tower. </item>
                <item id="2">A child asked me ifI knew what happened to their parents. I am forever trying to finish that story. </item>
                <item id="3">A comrade of mine and I were sucked into a fairy tale and only I made it out. </item>
                <item id="4">The talking animal following me around was apparently a king or queen of a faroff land. </item>
                <item id="5">I know of a powerful evil tale that creates disasters where it goes and I seek to put an end to that story. </item>
                <item id="6">I’ve forgotten the story that created me and I want to find who or what was involved with it.</item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="Flaw">
                <item id="1">No matter the story, I always have to involve my comrades for better or worse.</item>
                <item id="2">I’m afraid to admit it to myself, but I would do anything to finish a fairy tale–even kill an innocent.</item>
                <item id="3">I think everything is a fairy tale in disguise and can trust no one, not even myself.</item>
                <item id="4">I could save you... but if I let the dragon kidnap you, it’ll make for a better talke in the end.</item>
                <item id="5">I don’t think I can tell reality from fiction anymore.</item>
                <item id="6">I’m addicted to drugs that trap me in my fantastic dreams.</item>
            </select>
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Feature: Tale Finder" type="Background Feature" source="GrimmDark" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_TALE_FINDER">
            <description>
                <p>Aspects of the world related to the fey call to you. You always know when there is a fey around, and you have a sixth sense for picking up small details that would otherwise implicate a fey’s involvement.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet alt="Tale Finder">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
    
    <element name="Wild Born" type="Background" source="GrimmDark" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_BACKGROUND_WILD_BORN">
        <description>
            <p>As a child, you found yourself lost in the wilds of fairyland. The feywild, as it is more commonly called, consumed you at birth. Another likely tale is that your parents, for some reason or another, chose or were forced to raise you there. Your entire life has been a neverending adventure, where the alien nature of the fey as seeped into your very pores. When you returned to the world, you were no longer the same.</p>
            <p class="indent">As an adventurer, you operate off of the same princples that the fey do. Your emotions are extreme and your morality is blue or orange, not black or white. It is often hard for you to fit in with those that you meet, but your natural attitude always has a way of finding someon strange for you to quest with.</p>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Skill Proficiencies:</strong> Animal Handling, Sleight of Hand</li>
                <li><strong>Tool Proficiencies:</strong> One set of artisan’s tools of your choice, one musical instrument of your choice</li>
                <li><strong>Languages:</strong> None</li>
                <li><strong>Equipment:</strong> A pouch of strangeness containing something from the feywild (such as pixie dust or color-changing leaves), a set of common clothes, a pouch containing 5 gp</li>
            </ul>
            <h5>WILDE TRAITS</h5>
            <!-- feyborn traits go here -->
            <div element="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_FEY_BEAUTY" />
            <h5>SUGGESTED CHARACTERISTICS</h5>
            <p>As a wild born character, you are likely a fair shake different than everyone else you meet. You may sometimes do the right or wrong thing, but you never do it for the predicted reasons. Controlled by your whims and emotions, you can be a playful as a pixie or as terrible as a hag at a moment’s notice.</p>
        </description>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_FEY_BEAUTY" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_OPTIONAL_BACKGROUND_FEATURE"/>
            <select type="Background Feature" name="Variant Feature" supports="Optional Background Feature" optional="true" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ANIMALHANDLING" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SLEIGHTOFHAND" />
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Artisan Tools (Wild Born)" supports="Artisan Tools" />
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Musical Instrument (Wild Born)" supports="Musical Instrument" />
            <select type="List" name="Personality Trait" number="2">
                <item id="1">I find that talking to animals and trees provides more stimulating conversation then with people.</item>
                <item id="2">I wonder what beautiful things this world has to hide from me.</item>
                <item id="3">It’s only natural for me to want to kill things that I don‘t like.</item>
                <item id="4">An unnatural world is one that deserves to be destroyed.</item>
                <item id="5">I wonder why no one else can see the pixies and sprites dancing around us.</item>
                <item id="6">I understand the world to such a degree that everyone else seems to think I‘ve gone mad.</item>
                <item id="7">Nothing is more fun than playing a horrific prank on someone who doesn’t expect it!</item>
                <item id="8">Much like a storm, I can go from being quiet as a breeze to as terrifying as a tornado in but a second!</item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="Ideal">
                <item id="1">My Way or No Way. Getting what I want, how I want it, is the most important thing. (Chaotic)</item>
                <item id="2">Do Not Disturb. If you interfere in my business, you forfeit your right to live. (Evil)</item>
                <item id="3">Whimsy. The world is one great game and we are all a part of it. (Chaotic)</item>
                <item id="4">Supremacy. The feywild is the better of all things. (Neutral)</item>
                <item id="5">The Fittest. Life is about survival of the fittest, and I am the greatest hunter. (Neutral)</item>
                <item id="6">Uncaring. There are greter problems in the world than those of most mortals. (Good)</item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="Bond">
                <item id="1">I am searching for old family that knew me when I entered the feywild.</item>
                <item id="2">I came back to find a person of interest for my archfey lord.</item>
                <item id="3">Someone I met on my journey brings out my inner humanity, and I wish to know why.</item>
                <item id="4">I played a cruel prank on a powerful person and now they want my head.</item>
                <item id="5">A fool entered into my wood and took something precious to me. I seek to do the same to them.</item>
                <item id="6">Beauty is all this world has to offer, and I seek the most beautiful soul of them all.</item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="Flaw">
                <item id="1">For some reason, people seem to think that what they want is more important than what I want.</item>
                <item id="2">Oddly enough, most think me evil when I flay a pup out of boredom.</item>
                <item id="3">I’m not sure if the lives of others has any value to me, especially if they don’t provide any entertainment.</item>
                <item id="4">The sight of cold iron or worked stone makes me sick to stomach, and sometimes it enrages me.</item>
                <item id="5">People have limits to what they can handle, mentally and physically. I’m never sure of what those are.</item>
                <item id="6">Sometimes when I get too excited I can only speak in rhymes. People love to shun what I find fun.</item>
            </select>
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Feature: Fey Beauty" type="Background Feature" source="GrimmDark" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_FEY_BEAUTY">
            <description>
                <p>Though you are alien in nature and maybe even appearance, your beauty is without match. People are naturally attracted to you, and they are often enthralled by your weird behaviors and strange mannerisms. No one can fully understand you either; this makes it child’s play to persueade some, and impossible to convince the more stalwart or religious.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet alt="Fey Beauty">
                <description>Though you are alien in nature and maybe even appearance, your beauty is without match. People are naturally attracted to you, and they are often enthralled by your weird behaviors and strange mannerisms. No one can fully understand you either; this makes it child’s play to persueade some, and impossible to convince the more stalwart or religious.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
</elements>