<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Order of the Huntsman Blood Hunter Order</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="blood-hunter-order-of-the-huntsman.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/grimmdark/blood-hunter-order-of-the-huntsman.xml" />
        </update>
        <!-- https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B4Y9pHMOZQFjY05zRmRUYWVUVms/view -->
    </info>
    
    <element name="Order of the Huntsman" type="Archetype" source="GrimmDark" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_ARCHETYPE_BLOOD_HUNTER_ORDER_OF_THE_HUNTSMAN">
        <supports>Blood Hunter Order</supports>
        <description>
            <p>By order of a Queen a Huntsman is made, not born. You have taken a sworn oath that commands your body and soul to follow their will. This Queen may be an existing one within the world, or one of your own imagination and creation. And under this Queen’s orders, you hunt the monsters of the world, be them witches or fey, dragons or abominations. As long as you do so, her cursed magic is yours to wield.</p>
            <div element="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTSMAN_THE_OATH_TO_HUNT" />
            <div element="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTSMAN_THE_OATH_TO_KILL" />
            <div element="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTSMAN_THE_OATH_TO_CONTINUE" />
            <div element="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTSMAN_THE_OATH_TO_WIN" />
            <div element="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTSMAN_THE_FlNAL_OATH" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTSMAN_THE_OATH_TO_HUNT" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTSMAN_THE_OATH_TO_KILL" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTSMAN_THE_OATH_TO_CONTINUE" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTSMAN_THE_OATH_TO_WIN" level="15" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTSMAN_THE_FlNAL_OATH" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="The Oath to Hunt" type="Archetype Feature" source="GrimmDark" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTSMAN_THE_OATH_TO_HUNT">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at the 3rd level when you take this archetype, you make a cursed oath with your queen that allows you to manifest her power to assist you on your hunts. As a bonus action, you summon a levitating arrow or crossbow bolt of your design. This counts as your main hand weapon and you add your Wisdom modifier to attack and damage rolls instead of your Dexterity modifier. The bolt or arrow deals 1d8 damage. You can use this weapon to attack any creature of your choice within 30 feet of you. If the bolt or arrow is broken, or if it is brought more than 30 feet away from you. it disappears.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>You summon a levitating arrow or crossbow bolt of your design. This counts as your main hand weapon and you add your Wisdom modifier to attack and damage rolls instead of your Dexterity modifier. The bolt or arrow deals 1d8 damage. You can use this weapon to attack any creature of your choice within 30 feet of you. If the bolt or arrow is broken, or if it is brought more than 30 feet away from you. it disappears.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="The Oath to Kill" type="Archetype Feature" source="GrimmDark" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTSMAN_THE_OATH_TO_KILL">
            <description>
                <p>At the 7th level, in order to fulfil your oath to your queen you have begun to invoke the cursed nature of your summoned weapon. As a bonus action, you can spend 3 hit dice to curse your summoned bolt or arrow. The next attack you make with your bolt or arrow, should it hit, is considered a critical hit. In exchange, you lose the amount of hit points rolled on the hit dice, and you regain 3 less hit dice on your next long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>You can spend 3 hit dice to curse your summoned bolt or arrow. The next attack you make with your bolt or arrow, should it hit, is considered a critical hit. In exchange, you lose the amount of hit points rolled on the hit dice, and you regain 3 less hit dice on your next long rest.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="The Oath to Continue" type="Archetype Feature" source="GrimmDark" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTSMAN_THE_OATH_TO_CONTINUE">
            <description>
                <p>Upon reaching the 10th level. the oath you have with your queen pushes you ever onwards. As an action, you can summon a piece of jewelry that is cursed by your oath. If you are at 0 hit points, after making your first death saving throw you can roll all remaining hit dice that you have and regain that number of hit points. You cannot regain more than your maximum number of hit points using this feature. In exchange, you do not regain these hit dice after your next long rest. Additionally. you have disadvantage on all saving throws and skills checks until you take a long rest. The amulet disappears after 1 minute or after it has been used once.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you have used this feature. you cannot use it again until you complete a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest" action="Action">
                <description>You can summon a piece of jewelry that is cursed by your oath. If you are at 0 hit points, after making your first death saving throw you can roll all remaining hit dice that you have and regain that number of hit points. In exchange, you do not regain these hit dice after your next long rest. Additionally. you have disadvantage on all saving throws and skills checks until you take a long rest.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="The Oath to Win" type="Archetype Feature" source="GrimmDark" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTSMAN_THE_OATH_TO_WIN">
            <description>
                <p>At the 15th level, the oath with your queen has become powerful, compelling you to victory against her foes. When you summon your bolt or arrow via your Oath to Hunt feature, you can summon an identical bolt or arrow. Whenever you attack with the original bolt or arrow. you may take the Attack action for free with the secondary bolt or arrow. At the beginning of your next turn, the bolt or arrow fades away. In exchange. you suffer the amount of damage the copy of the bolt or arrow does.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you summon your bolt or arrow via your Oath to Hunt feature, you can summon an identical bolt or arrow. Whenever you attack with the original bolt or arrow. you may take the Attack action for free with the secondary bolt or arrow. At the beginning of your next turn, the bolt or arrow fades away. In exchange. you suffer the amount of damage the copy of the bolt or arrow does.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="The Flnal Oath" type="Archetype Feature" source="GrimmDark" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTSMAN_THE_FlNAL_OATH">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at the 18th level, your oath follows you even into death. Upon suffering 3 death saving throw failures, a levitating bolt or arrow is summoned above your corpse. On initiative order 20 (losing ties) of the next round, the bolt or arrow strikes the creature that reduced you to 0 hit points. Additionally, a creature of the queen’s choice, should she see your death, can be targeted instead. The targeted creature must make a Constitution saving throw versus your total Blood Hunter levels + your Wisdom ability modifier. On a failure, they are dropped to 0 hit points and die.</p>
                <p class="indent">Should the arrow have no creature to strike, the queen that you made the oath with can choose to use the arrow at her leisure. After the arrow has been used, it disappears.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Upon suffering 3 death saving throw failures, a levitating bolt or arrow is summoned above your corpse. On initiative order 20 (losing ties) of the next round, the bolt or arrow strikes the creature that reduced you to 0 hit points. Additionally, a creature of the queen’s choice, should she see your death, can be targeted instead. The targeted creature must make a Constitution saving throw (save DC {{final-oath:save-dc}}). On a failure, they are dropped to 0 hit points and die.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="final-oath:save-dc" value="level:blood hunter" />
                <stat name="final-oath:save-dc" value="wisdom:modifier" />
            </rules>
        </element>
    
</elements>