<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>GrimmDark Feats</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="feats.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/grimmdark/feats.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Fey Hunter" type="Feat" source="GrimmDark" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_FEAT_FEY_HUNTER">
        <description>
            <p>You are seasoned when it comes to hunting fey and dealing with fairy tales. Your years of experience and training gives you the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>When a fey creature attempts to charm or frighten you, you gain advantage on the saving throw.</li>
                <li>You can naturally sense when a fey creature is within 30 feet of your persons at all times.</li>
                <li>When fighting a fey creature, you can choose to take a -5 penalty to your attack roll to gain +10 to the total damage rolled.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When a fey creature attempts to charm or frighten you, you gain advantage on the saving throw. You can naturally sense when a fey creature is within 30 feet of your persons at all times. When fighting a fey creature, you can choose to take a -5 penalty to your attack roll to gain +10 to the total damage rolled.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Mad As A Hare" type="Feat" source="GrimmDark" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_FEAT_MAD_AS_A_HARE">
        <description>
            <p>You have long since been driven insane by fairy tales you’ve suffered granting you the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>Increase your Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</li>
                <li>When you make a Performance (Charisma) check to try and distract someone, your insanity makes your attempts unpredictable, granting you advantage on the roll.</li>
                <li>When a creature you can see within 120 feet attempts to make a Concentration check, you can interfere with their check through some insane method. You subtract your Charisma modifier from their Concentration roll.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you make a Performance (Charisma) check to try and distract someone, your insanity makes your attempts unpredictable, granting you advantage on the roll. When a creature you can see within 120 feet attempts to make a Concentration check, you can interfere with their check through some insane method. You subtract {{charisma:modifier}} from their Concentration roll.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="charisma" value="1" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Wild Tongued" type="Feat" source="GrimmDark" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_FEAT_WILD_TONGUED">
        <prerequisite>The Storytouched or Wild Born background</prerequisite>
        <requirements>ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_BACKGROUND_STORYTOUCHED||ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_BACKGROUND_WILD_BORN</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisites: The Storytouched or Wild Born background</p>
            <p>Your natural fey personality has blessed you with the guile and Cunning of trueborn fey. When Speaking with another creature with an Intelligence of 6 or higher and that understands your language, you can make contested a Charisma roll versus the creature’s Charisma ability score. If you succeed, you are able to trick the creature into answering any one question of your choice, no matter how secret or private it is.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When Speaking with another creature with an Intelligence of 6 or higher and that understands your language, you can make contested a Charisma roll versus the creature’s Charisma ability score. If you succeed, you are able to trick the creature into answering any one question of your choice, no matter how secret or private it is.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    
</elements>