<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>GrimmDark Items</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="items.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/grimmdark/items.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
	<element name="Axe of True Striking" type="Magic Item" source="GrimmDark" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_MAGIC_ITEM_AXE_OF_TRUE_STRIKING">
		<description>
			<p>A magical axe designed for striking down trees in the feywilde and cleaving through fairy underbrush. The Axe of of True Striking is a +1 axe. Additionally, when used against a magical or sentient plant or tree creature, it deals 2d6 bonus slashing damage.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">handaxe</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any axe">Weapon</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="attunement">false</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_WOTC_PHB_WEAPON_HANDAXE</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

    <element name="Cursed and Poisonous Comb" type="Magic Item" source="GrimmDark" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_MAGIC_ITEM_CURSED_AND_POISONOUS_COMB">
        <description>
            <p>This beautiful comb once belonged to a cursed queen, gifted to her by a particularly cruel hag that was wronged. The teeth of the comb are covered in a magical poison. Those who wear it must make a DC 10 + their Charisma modifier Constitution check or suffer the poisoned condition until their next long rest. This curse can only be removed by a remove curse spell. Additionally, when a creature looks at the comb, they must succeed on a DC 15 Charisma saving throw. On a failure, they have an extreme desire to wear the comb. Once a creature succeeds on this check, they cannot be affected by the comb.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
            <set name="cursed">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Enchanted Storybook" type="Magic Item" source="GrimmDark" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_MAGIC_ITEM_ENCHANTED_STORYBOOK">
        <description>
            <p>A gorgeous, but old, leather bound story book, it is said to have been created by a powerful archfey and used to incite their slaves to madness. A creature who opens the story book will see their life drawn and written within. The pages turn blank and white about half way through. Just before they do, however, they show a scene where the reader is about to suffer some horrible peril. The story book can only be read once per long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Golden Egg" type="Magic Item" source="GrimmDark" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_MAGIC_ITEM_GOLDEN_EGG">
        <description>
            <p>This golden egg is said to have been laid by a golden goose of immense power and divinity. The egg itself is worth roughly 5000 pp, enough money to buy one their own kingdom. If the egg is consumed, it grants the eater the benefits of a long rest instantaneously. Additionally, the consumer gains temporary magical abilities. Until their next short rest, they can cast a spell from the Archfey’s patron spell list found in the Warlock section of the <em></em>. They can only cast the spell once, and it does not require any components.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

	<element name="Huntsman’s Crossbow" type="Magic Item" source="GrimmDark" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_MAGIC_ITEM_HUNSTMANS_CROSSBOW">
		<description>
			<p>Crafted by a famous huntsmen and cursed by his queenly oath, this crossbow has served as a powerful weapon in many, many fairy tales. When a bolt is fired from the crossbow, it ignores range penalties and any cover the target has as long as the huntsmen knows that the creature is in the direction that he is shooting. In addition, the bolt fired has a maximum range of 6 miles before it loses momentum.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">light crossbow</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any axe">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">false</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_WOTC_PHB_WEAPON_CROSSBOW_LIGHT</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

    <element name="Iron Slippers" type="Magic Item" source="GrimmDark" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_MAGIC_ITEM_IRON_SLIPPERS">
        <description>
            <p>Created by the cursed queen Arcadia, these iron slippers serve as torture devices for those that wrong her. When the slippers are worn, they cannot be removed until remove curse is cast on them. They are eternally hot as coals and forever burn their victims. After a long rest is finished, the creature wearing these slippers takes 1d4 fire damage. Their hit point maximum is reduced by the amount rolled. A creature whose maximum hit points is reduced to O dies. If remove curse is cast on the creature instead of the slippers, their maximum hit points increases to its original value.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="cursed">true</set>
            <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Magical Wilting Rose" type="Magic Item" source="GrimmDark" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_MAGIC_ITEM_MAGICAL_WILTING_ROSE">
        <description>
            <p>This cursed rose was raised from a seedling by a powerful fey creature, or a worker of dark magics. When a creature is offered the rose as a gift but declines the rose, they are cursed by its power. Their fate is linked to that of the rose’s own. The rose has an equal amount of hit points to the creature that declined it, as well as an Armor Class of 5. Damage that the rose suffers and vice versa is dealt to the creature that declined it. This effect ends once the rose hits 0 hit points, or when remove curse is cast on the creature or the rose.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="cursed">true</set>
            <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Ring of the Spider" type="Magic Item" source="GrimmDark" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_MAGIC_ITEM_RING_OF_THE_SPIDER">
        <description>
            <p>A ring created from the webs, venom, and exoskeleton of an ancient spider, it has a powerful aura of fear around it. Any who look at the ring other than the wearer must make a DC 13 Wisdom saving throw or be overcome by fear and horror, becoming frightened for 1 minute. A creature affected by this ring can make the saving throw again at the start of every turn until they break the spell or the effect ends. A creature that succeeds on a saving throw against this ring is immune to its power.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Still Beating Heart of the Queen" type="Magic Item" source="GrimmDark" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_MAGIC_ITEM_STILL_BEATING_HEART_OF_THE_QUEEN">
        <description>
            <p>The heart of a cursed queen, it is kept beating by the powerful dark magic that courses through it. The heart can be used as an arcane focus for any class. Additionally, when a creature is killed within at least 10 feet of the heart or by a spell cast by the holder of the heart, the holder of the heart regains their lowest expended spell slot.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Vial of Pixie Dust" type="Magic Item" source="GrimmDark" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_MAGIC_ITEM_VIAL_OF_PIXIE_DUST">
        <description>
            <p>A vile of multi—colored pixie dust, when a little is poured on top of a creature’s head and the creature thinks happy thoughts, they gain a fly speed equal to their movement for up to 4 hours. This duration includes times when the character is not flying as well. Every vial contains 10 uses of pixie dust.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Vial of Sleeping Death" type="Magic Item" source="GrimmDark" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_MAGIC_ITEM_Vial of Sleeping Death">
        <description>
            <p>A liquid black as tar, with a stench of decay and death rests within a vial of glass and gold. Poured into drink or food, it becomes perfectly undetectable, even by magical means. This poisons causes a sleeping death, reducing a creature to 0 hit points instantly and stabilizing them afterwards. The only way to wake a character that has consumed the sleeping death is for their true love to kiss them on their lips.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
</elements>