<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Siren Race from GrimmDark</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="race-siren.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/grimmdark/race-siren.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Siren" type="Race" source="GrimmDark" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_RACE_SIREN">
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">“I sat beached on the Isle ofForgotten Souls, sure that no creature would come this way to find me. My boat had capsized in the storm the night prior and the waves had carried me in. The high sun was threatening to end me. Not a drop of fresh water was to be found on this god forsaken island when a voice called to me like a cooling breeze. I was sure it was just the sun playing tricks on me, but as Ineared the source toward the center of the island, a large sprawling lake spilled out before me. On its’ edge a woman sat with her back to me, running her fingers through long tendrils of ashen blonde hair. It wasn’t until I stepped for ward and a twig snapped beneath my feet that her gaze snapped in my direction. Quick as lightning she slipped into the water: and it was only then I saw her long tail, tipped with fins, splash against the water as she swam away. Realizing it or not, that creature saved my life by leading me to these fresh waters; it wasn’t but a day later a merchant ship spotted me and whisked me away to safety I’ve tried many times since to return to the Isle where that Siren sang so sweetly, but I’ve never been able to find that strange lake, or the enchanting creature within it again."</p>
            <p>Sirens are a rare and mystical race descended from a cursed group of fae banished to the oceans. It wasn’t for many generations that the Sirens broke their curse and populated the world. By this time, they were long separated from their fae ancestry. Most choose to stay in seclusion or secret in fear of the black market trading for their fins, which most believe to hold magical properties.</p>
            <h4>ESSENCE OF BEAUTY</h4>
            <p>Sirens are the epitome of grace and beauty. making even Elven or Fae women seem homely. Like humans, their hair, skin color, and complexion vary from Siren to Siren, with features that charm and seduce even the most stalwart of men. However, sometimes Sirens with elven blood can be hues of gold.copper. or even bronze. having a metallic and glistening reflection to their skin. They range on the petite side of height and build averaging 5 and a half feet tall, and weighing about 135 pounds.</p>
            <p class="indent">Sirens, having usually came from their sea or lake dwelling, are usually sparsely dressed but sport magnificent jewels, or organic clothing the is usually hand made but beautiful beyond compare. They usually wear these in their aquatic forms as well, along with their legs fusing together seamlessly becoming a beautiful tail much like a dolphin’s but with colorful scales of a vast variety of tones.</p>
            <h4>SIREN NAMES</h4>
            <p>Sirens are named for their beauty, voice, and grace, often a reflection of the race as a whole. with touches of the individual’s traits.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Female Names:</strong> Aglaope. Calypso, Delena. Lamia, Leucoisa. Ligeia. Molpe. Myst. Pisinoe, Raidne, Teles</p>
            <h4>SIREN TRAITS</h4>
            <p>Your siren character has a number of traits in common with all other siren.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong> Your Charisma score increases by 2.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Age.</em></strong> A siren reaches adulthood at the age of 20 and could live anywhere from 60 to 700 years.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Alignment.</em></strong> Most sirens are Chaotic evil. However they can be good or neutral as well, but normally always falling into the chaotic sphere.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Size.</em></strong> Siren average about 5 and half feet tall and weigh about 135 pounds. Your size is medium.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Speed.</em></strong> Your base walking speed is 30 feet. Your base swimming speed is 45.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Creation.</em></strong> Sirens are only born as females due to a magical curse placed upon them.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Shape Changer.</em></strong> A siren can use it’s action to shapeshift between the form of a medium humanoid female and its aquatic form. It’s statistics remain the same in either form.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Siren’s Call.</em></strong> A siren’s voice carries a charming power that few other creatures can replicate. At the first level, you have access to the <em>friends</em> cantrip. At the third level, you gain access to the <em>command</em> spell once per day. At the fifth level, you can cast <em>enthrall</em> once per day. Your spellcasting ability for these spells is Charisma.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Seabound.</em></strong> While in your aquatic form, you can breath underwater.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Languages.</em></strong> Sylvan, Common</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="names" type="male"></set>
            <set name="names" type="female">Aglaope. Calypso, Delena. Lamia, Leucoisa. Ligeia. Molpe. Myst. Pisinoe, Raidne, Teles</set>
            <set name="names-format">{{name}}</set>
            <set name="height" modifier="2d10">4’8"</set>
            <set name="weight" modifier="2d4">110 lb.</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <stat name="charisma" value="2" />
            <stat name="innate speed" value="30" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="innate speed:swim" value="45" bonus="base" />
            <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON" />
            <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_SYLVAN" />
            <grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_MEDIUM"/>
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_RACIAL_TRAIT_SIREN_SHAPE_CHANGER" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_RACIAL_TRAIT_SIREN_SIRENS_CALL" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_RACIAL_TRAIT_SIREN_SEABOUND" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Shape Changer" type="Racial Trait" source="GrimmDark" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_RACIAL_TRAIT_SIREN_SHAPE_CHANGER">
            <description>
                <p>A siren can use it’s action to shapeshift between the form of a medium humanoid female and its aquatic form. It’s statistics remain the same in either form.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>A siren can shapeshift between the form of a medium humanoid female and its aquatic form. It’s statistics remain the same in either form.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Siren’s Call" type="Racial Trait" source="GrimmDark" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_RACIAL_TRAIT_SIREN_SIRENS_CALL">
            <description>
                <p>A siren’s voice carries a charming power that few other creatures can replicate. At the first level, you have access to the <em>friends</em> cantrip. At the third level, you gain access to the <em>command</em> spell once per day. At the fifth level, you can cast <em>enthrall</em> once per day. Your spellcasting ability for these spells is Charisma.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can cast friends at will. Charisma is your spellcasting ability.</description>
                <description level="3">You can cast friends at will. You can cast command once per day. Charisma is your spellcasting ability.</description>
                <description level="5">You can cast friends at will. You can cast command and enthrall once each per day. Charisma is your spellcasting ability.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FRIENDS" level="1" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMMAND" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENTHRALL" level="5" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Seabound" type="Racial Trait" source="GrimmDark" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_RACIAL_TRAIT_SIREN_SEABOUND">
            <description>
                <p>While in your aquatic form, you can breath underwater.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>While in your aquatic form, you can breath underwater.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
</elements>