<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Fairy Tale Sorcerous Origin</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="sorcerer-fairy-tale.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/grimmdark/sorcerer-fairy-tale.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Fairy Tale" type="Archetype" source="GrimmDark" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_ARCHETYPE_SORCERER_FAIRY_TALE">
        <supports>Sorcerous Origin</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The magic of the feywild and its many denizens often bleeds out into a world Violently. When this happens, fairy tales are born: events Where feyborn creatures interact. torture, kill, or bless those that they drag into their theater. When a child is born from these dark events. or when a person is caught in the whirlwind of insanity that is the fairy tale. they are often completely and utterly changed.</p>
            <p class="indent">Those who become sorcerers through this origin are no longer themselves. They are often mad or somehow mentally addled. and their physical features often take on fey or animalistic traits. Many speak in rhymes, riddles, or tongue twisters, while others seek only to replicate the tale that created them with others they find.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">FAIRY TALE QUIRKS</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d6</td><td>Flaw</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>You can only ask questions in riddles or rhymes.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>Sometimes you cook with non-food ingredients. Like flowers. Or bone.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>You like to tie flowers around things. Especially necks.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>You are very pretty during the day and very ugly during night.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>You like making games. Only you understand the rules.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>Ponds ripple when you walk past them, and leaves begin to fall.</td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FAIRY_TALE_TONGUETWISTED_MAGIC" />
            <div element="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FAIRY_TALE_FAIRY_CHARM" />
            <div element="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FAIRY_TALE_GRIMM_STORY" />
            <div element="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FAIRY_TALE_MAD_AND_CHESHIRE" />
            <div element="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FAIRY_TALE_A_NEW_STORY" />
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FAIRY_TALE_TONGUETWISTED_MAGIC" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FAIRY_TALE_FAIRY_CHARM" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FAIRY_TALE_GRIMM_STORY" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FAIRY_TALE_MAD_AND_CHESHIRE" level="14" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FAIRY_TALE_A_NEW_STORY" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Tongue-Twisted Magic" type="Archetype Feature" source="GrimmDark" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FAIRY_TALE_TONGUETWISTED_MAGIC">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at the 1st level when you take this sorcerous origin, you know how to compose spells through different methods. As an action, you make make a Concentration check versus your spell save DC. On a success, you can cast a concentration spell as a normal spell.</p>
                <p class="indent">You may use this feature a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier per short rest. You may not apply a metamagic feat to a spell cast with this feature.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="{{tonguetwisted-magic:uses}}/Short Rest">
                <description>You make make a Concentration check versus your spell save DC. On a success, you can cast a concentration spell as a normal spell. You may not apply a metamagic feat to a spell cast with this feature.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="tonguetwisted-magic:uses" value="1" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="tonguetwisted-magic:uses" value="charisma:modifier" bonus="base" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Fairy Charm" type="Archetype Feature" source="GrimmDark" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FAIRY_TALE_FAIRY_CHARM">
            <description>
                <p>At the lst level, you may invoke your natural fey-like abilities when dealing with others. Upon failing a Charisma check when attempting to intimidate, persuade, or wow another creature, you may spend 1 sorcery point to cast <em>charm person</em> on that creature without expending a spell slot.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Upon failing a Charisma check when attempting to intimidate, persuade, or wow another creature, you may spend 1 sorcery point to cast charm person on that creature without expending a spell slot.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CHARM_PERSON" level="1"/>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Grimm Story" type="Archetype Feature" source="GrimmDark" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FAIRY_TALE_GRIMM_STORY">
            <description>
                <p>Upon reaching the 6th level, you have learned to make others experience the magic of the fairy tale that granted you your power. Using an action, you may spend 3 sorcery points to summon a modified fey creature that targets a single creature of your choice. The fey creature summoned cannot have a CR higher than half your sorcerer level. The fey creature has the following changes:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>A successful Charisma save versus your spell save DC made by a creature targeted by the fey generated using this feature has resistance against damage from the fey. This save can be made at the end of the target’s turn.</li>
                    <li>At the start of its turn, the fey automatically knows its target’s location. If the target was hidden. it is no longer hidden from the fey.</li>
                    <li>If the fey casts a spell. it uses one of your spell slots of equal level. The fey has no spell slots of its own, though it retains its spells.</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">The fey appears within an unoccupied space within 30 feet of your target. Roll initiative for the fey. On its turn. it can only talk too. move towards, or use actions against the target. The fey has resistance against damage from creatures not targeted by it. The fey disappears when it is killed, its target is killed. when 1 hour passes. or you spend an action to end the fairy tale. Only one fey can be summoned at a time, and only one creature can be targeted at a time.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>You may spend 3 sorcery points to summon a modified fey creature that targets a single creature of your choice. The fey creature summoned cannot have a CR higher than {{level:sorcerer:half}}.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Mad And Cheshire" type="Archetype Feature" source="GrimmDark" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FAIRY_TALE_MAD_AND_CHESHIRE">
            <description>
                <p>At the 14th level, you can draw additional power from within yourself at the cost of your own sanity. As an action, you may roll on the Short—Term Madness table found on page 259 of the Dungeon Master’s Guide. For 1 minute you suffer the madness you rolled, and you regain a number of spell slots equal to half your sorcerer levels, or half your expended sorcery points.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once this feature is used. you cannot use it again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You may roll on the Short—Term Madness table found on page 259 of the Dungeon Master’s Guide. For 1 minute you suffer the madness you rolled, and you regain {{level:sorcerer:half}} spell slots , or half your expended sorcery points.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="A New Story" type="Archetype Feature" source="GrimmDark" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FAIRY_TALE_A_NEW_STORY">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at the 18th level, you can allow your fey magic to take control, allowing you to create your own fairy tale. As an action, you may spend half your maximum sorcery points to create a 120 foot sphere around you. While within this sphere you can cast the spell <em>hallucinatory terrain</em> as a bonus action without spending spell slots or material components. Additionally. you may spend 1 sorcery point to cast <em>phantasmal killer</em> without spending a spell slot as a bonus action while within the sphere.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>You may spend half your maximum sorcery points to create a 120 foot sphere around you. While within this sphere you can cast the spell hallucinatory terrain as a bonus action without spending spell slots or material components. Additionally. you may spend 1 sorcery point to cast phantasmal killer without spending a spell slot as a bonus action while within the sphere.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HALLUCINATORY_TERRAIN" level="18" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PHANTASMAL_KILLER" level="18" />
            </rules>
        </element>

    <element name="Confusing Spell" type="Class Feature" source="GrimmDark" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_CLASS_FEATURE_METAMAGIC_CONFUSING_SPELL">
        <supports>Metamagic</supports>
        <description>
            <p>When you cast a spell, you may spend a number of Sorcery points equal to the spell‘s level. If the creature is hit by the spell attack roll or fails the spell save DC, they have disadvantage on all non-damage rolls until the end of their next turn.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you cast a spell, you may spend a number of Sorcery points equal to the spell‘s level. If the creature is hit by the spell attack roll or fails the spell save DC, they have disadvantage on all non-damage rolls until the end of their next turn.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Illusory Spell" type="Class Feature" source="GrimmDark" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_CLASS_FEATURE_METAMAGIC_ILLUSORY_SPELL">
        <supports>Metamagic</supports>
        <description>
            <p>When you cast a spell that requires a saving throw, you can spend 2 sorcery points to turn it into an illusion. The target(s) of the spell must make an Intelligence saving throw instead of the normal saving throw or else they suffer the effects of the spell.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you cast a spell that requires a saving throw, you can spend 2 sorcery points to turn it into an illusion. The target(s) of the spell must make an Intelligence saving throw instead of the normal saving throw or else they suffer the effects of the spell.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Playful Spell" type="Class Feature" source="GrimmDark" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_CLASS_FEATURE_METAMAGIC_PLAYFUL_SPELL">
        <supports>Metamagic</supports>
        <description>
            <p>When you cast a spell thats duration is instantaneous and that deals damage, you can spend 1 sorcery point to deal half damage. At the start of the target’s next turn they take half damage again.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you cast a spell thats duration is instantaneous and that deals damage, you can spend 1 sorcery point to deal half damage. At the start of the target’s next turn they take half damage again.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Trick Spell" type="Class Feature" source="GrimmDark" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_CLASS_FEATURE_METAMAGIC_TRICK_SPELL">
        <supports>Metamagic</supports>
        <description>
            <p>When you cast a spell that requires a spell attack roll, you may spend 2 sorcery point to change a random aspect of the spell, such as the direction it is coming from or what it looks like. This grants you advantage on your spell attack roll.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you cast a spell that requires a spell attack roll, you may spend 2 sorcery point to change a random aspect of the spell, such as the direction it is coming from or what it looks like. This grants you advantage on your spell attack roll.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>


</elements>