<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Dark Imagination Otherworldly Patron</name>
        <update version="0.0.2">
            <file name="warlock-dark-imagination.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/grimmdark/warlock-dark-imagination.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Dark Imagination" type="Archetype" source="GrimmDark" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_ARCHETYPE_WARLOCK_DARK_IMAGINATION">
        <supports>Otherworldly Patron</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Your patron bears no physical body or ties to the mortal plane but is rather an idea. an essence of childish abandon. You have touched the darkest parts of humanity and somehow held onto that power of innocence. the power of believing.</p>
            <p class="indent">As such. your personality and views on the world have vastly been altered. You are now prone to always look for hope in the darkest of places. seeking the brighter side of bad news. You seek out creative and alternative paths to solve problems, and often crave adventure and entertain ideas of grandeur.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">FAIRY TALE QUIRKS</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d6</td><td>Flaw</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>If you see a woodland creature you are drawn to go to it.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>You often find yourself singing or humming even when it’s dangerous.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>You would put yourself in danger to protect anyone else.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>You are prone to become lost, even with a trail to follow.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>You have a short memory span, and often forget important details.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>You are drawn to touch pointy objects.</td></tr>
            </table>
            <h5 class="caption">EXPANDED SPELL LIST</h5>
            <p>The Strange lets you choose from an expanded list of spells when you learn a warlock spell. The following spells are added to the warlock spell list for you.</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Spell Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>lst</td><td><i>color spray, faerie fire</i></td></tr>
                <tr><td>2nd</td><td><i>blur, nystul’s magic aura</i></td></tr>
                <tr><td>3rd</td><td><i>fear, plant growth</i></td></tr>
                <tr><td>4th</td><td><i>conjure woodland beings, fabricate</i></td></tr>
                <tr><td>5th</td><td><i>creation, tree stride</i></td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DARK_IMAGINATION_A_LITTLE_MAD" />
            <div element="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DARK_IMAGINATION_MIRROR_MIRROR" />
            <div element="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DARK_IMAGINATION_A_SHEEP_IN_WOLFS_CLOTHING" />
            <div element="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DARK_IMAGINATION_TWISTED_DREAMS" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DARK_IMAGINATION_A_LITTLE_MAD" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DARK_IMAGINATION_MIRROR_MIRROR" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DARK_IMAGINATION_A_SHEEP_IN_WOLFS_CLOTHING" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DARK_IMAGINATION_TWISTED_DREAMS" level="14" />
        </rules>
        <spellcasting name="Warlock" extend="true">
            <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_COLOR_SPRAY</extend>
            <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_FAERIE_FIRE</extend>
            <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_BLUR</extend>
            <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_NYSTULS_MAGIC_AURA</extend>
            <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_FEAR</extend>
            <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_PLANT_GROWTH</extend>
            <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_CONJURE_WOODLAND_BEINGS</extend>
            <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_FABRICATE</extend>
            <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_CREATION</extend>
            <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_TREE_STRIDE</extend>
        </spellcasting>
    </element>
        <element name="All A Little Mad" type="Archetype Feature" source="GrimmDark" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DARK_IMAGINATION_A_LITTLE_MAD">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at the lst level, you are able to force others to see the world through the lense of your own imagination. When you critically hit a creature with a spell attack, or when a creature fails a saving throw versus one of your spells by more than 10, the creature must roll on the Short—Term Madness table found on page 259 of the <em>Dungeon Master’s Guide</em>. They suffer this madness until the end of their next turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you critically hit a creature with a spell attack, or when a creature fails a saving throw versus one of your spells by more than 10, the creature must roll on the Short—Term Madness table found on page 259 of the Dungeon Master’s Guide. They suffer this madness until the end of their next turn.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Mirror Mirror" type="Archetype Feature" source="GrimmDark" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DARK_IMAGINATION_MIRROR_MIRROR">
            <description>
                <p>Upon reaching the 6th level, you are able to reflect spell—like effects back upon their users. On your turn, you may ready an action to use this feature. If a spell is cast on you before the beginning of your next turn, the spell is negated as if you had cast <em>counterspell</em>. Additionally, the casting creature must make a Constitution saving throw versus your spell save DC or suffer the effects of the countered spell.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once this feature has been used, it cannot be used again until you complete a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>On your turn, you may ready an action to use this feature. If a spell is cast on you before the beginning of your next turn, the spell is negated as if you had cast counterspell. Additionally, the casting creature must make a Constitution saving throw versus your spell save DC or suffer the effects of the countered spell.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COUNTERSPELL" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="A Sheep In Wolf’s Clothing" type="Archetype Feature" source="GrimmDark" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DARK_IMAGINATION_A_SHEEP_IN_WOLFS_CLOTHING">
            <description>
                <p>At 10th level, your mind is capable of extraordinary acts of pretend. You can feign a creature of your choice. You feign that creature’s appearance and Armor Class. However, a successful Intelligence check versus your spell save DC reveals the illusion.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once this feature has been used. it cannot be used again until you complete a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
                <description>You can feign a creature of your choice. You feign that creature’s appearance and Armor Class. However, a successful Intelligence check versus your spell save DC reveals the illusion.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Twisted Dreams" type="Archetype Feature" source="GrimmDark" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DARK_IMAGINATION_TWISTED_DREAMS">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at the 14th level, you have learned to bring the fantasy of your patron’s power into reality. As an action, you can roll Charisma check. If you roll at or under your total Warlock levels. you summon your twisted imagination into reality. While you describe the nonsensical nature of this creation. the DM determines the actual effect: the effect of any warlock spell or the summoning of a twisted creature are but two of the appropriate ways this can be used.</p>
                <p class="indent">If you succeeded on your roll, your body reels from the efforts of the summons. Until your next long rest, short rests only restore 1 spell slot. Additionally, once this feature has been used, it cannot be used again until you complete a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest" action="Action">
                <description>You can roll Charisma check. If you roll {{level:warlock}} or less, you summon your twisted imagination into reality. While you describe the nonsensical nature of this creation, the DM determines the actual effect: the effect of any warlock spell or the summoning of a twisted creature are but two of the appropriate ways this can be used. If you succeeded on your roll, short rests only restore 1 spell slot until your next long rest.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
    
	<element name="Fey Sight" type="Class Feature" source="GrimmDark" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_CLASS_FEATURE_INVOCATION_FEY_SIGHT">
		<supports>Eldritch Invocation</supports>
		<prerequisite></prerequisite>
		<requirements></requirements>
		<description>
			<p>Your eyes see the true nature of all things. You can see a ghostly outline of a creature’s true form if they are polymorphed or shapeshifted.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can see a ghostly outline of a creature’s true form if they are polymorphed or shapeshifted.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Nature’s Lover" type="Class Feature" source="GrimmDark" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_CLASS_FEATURE_INVOCATION_NATURES_LOVER">
		<supports>Eldritch Invocation</supports>
		<prerequisite></prerequisite>
		<requirements></requirements>
		<description>
			<p>You can cast <em>pass without trace</em> on yourself at will, without expending a spell slot or material components.</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_PASS_WITHOUT_TRACE" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can cast pass without trace on yourself at will, without expending a spell slot or material components.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PASS_WITHOUT_TRACE" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Phantasmal Psychedelia" type="Class Feature" source="GrimmDark" id="ID_STRIDERT_GRIMMDARK_CLASS_FEATURE_INVOCATION_PHANTASMAL_PSYCHEDELIA">
		<supports>Eldritch Invocation</supports>
		<prerequisite>7th level</prerequisite>
		<requirements>[level:7]</requirements>
		<description>
			<p><em>Prerequisite: 7th level</em></p>
			<p>You can cast the spell <em>phantasmal killer</em> once per day using a warlock spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_PHANTASMAL_KILLER" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
			<description>You can cast the spell phantasmal killer once per day using a warlock spell slot.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PHANTASMAL_KILLER" />
		</rules>
	</element>
</elements>