<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>HZ Marksman 2.0</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="class-marksman.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/dmforeva/class-marksman.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="HZ Marksman" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_DMFOREVA_MARKSMAN_SOURCE_HZ Marksman">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation">DMFMC</set>
            <set name="url">https://drive.google.com/file/d/1qt3BPKvEAGeyRXf1iabZiISqQ5aUPR0B/view</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" abbreviation="DMF" url="https://www.reddit.com/user/dmforeva/">u/dmforeva</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20200913</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Marksman" type="Class" source="HZ Marksman" id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_CLASS_MARKSMAN">
        <description>
            <p>The dark lord strides smugly across the battlefield, his glowing gem of power shining at his neck, commanding his undead legions. On a high cliff far away, the world pins its hopes on a single white ash arrow, flung off an elven bow, streaking through the air to shatter the dark villain’s power.</p>
            <p class="indent">A goblin and a dwarf meet at high noon, under a scorching desert sun. The goblin grins, flips a golden coin, and before it can hit the ground her opponent topples, a rusty dagger sprouting from between his eyes.</p>
            <p class="indent">A haphazard human militia trembles in their ranks as an orcish horde unleashes a wave of javelins, preparing to charge. At the top of their arc, in the blink of an eye, each javelin bursts into harmless splinters that patter down over the battlefield. The orcs hesitate as the village elder twirls his sling, preparing for another volley.</p>
            <p class="indent">No matter their chosen weapon or the manner in which they wield it, all Marksmen are united by a common goal. Hit the target; don’t miss. Don’t ever miss. It’s a simple creed, yet it calls for a lifetime of devotion. Marksmen know that one failed shot could mean a rampaging beast goes unchecked, a spy makes off with crucial information, a general lives to see another battlefield. A child starves, an empire falls. Don’t ever miss.</p>
            <h4>THE PERFECT SHOT</h4>
            <p>Marksmen are not unique in being especially skilled with ranged weaponry. A fighter or a ranger might overcome their foes with a volley of arrows or a barrage of flying steel. Marksmen set themselves apart by their pursuit of one singular, utterly flawless shot. Perfection in motion. Not just striking the target, but striking it precisely the right way, with the right force, at the right time. The fighter sees his crossbow as a weapon. A ranger looks at a brace of axes and sees the tools of survival. The marksman looks at a strung bow and sees an instrument, waiting to make art.</p>
            <h4>A STUDIOUS PROFESSION</h4>
            <p>Marksmanship is an exacting path, which calls to obsessive, detail-oriented people. True mastery of the art demands both constant training and constant study. Gravity, wind, air resistance, statics and kinetics, mathematics, meteorology, optics, anatomy… an endless list of theories and formulae fill a marksman’s mind. The perfect shot is crafted as much in the library as on the range, and a devoted marksman may go to great lengths in search of obscure teachings or lost secrets pertaining to their passion.</p>
            <h4>CREATING A MARKSMAN</h4>
            <p>As you build your Marksman, consider two questions which may be particularly relevant to your character. How did you come by your weapon of choice, and how did you become trained in its use?</p>
            <p class="indent">Perhaps you took your father’s hunting bow off the mantle as a child, and he schooled you in its use throughout your life. Maybe the day raiders came to your village, a sling and stone were all you could find, and you had to learn to survive. Did you follow in your tribe’s ancient hunting tradition, carving your own blowpipe from the tree planted at your birth? Or maybe you simply showed a knack in basic training, and the army introduced you to all manner of assorted weaponry.</p>
            <p class="indent">A marksman is also defined by the unceasing repetition of practice and rehearsal. How do you train? Do you have any associated rituals, or routines that you always follow? Some marksmen can’t sleep without scoring a dozen bullseyes before bed. A stretching routine might be needed to keep your shooting arm in good condition. Maybe you eat an apple a day, and you always skin it from ten paces away.</p>
            <h5>QUICK BUILD</h5>
            <p>You can make a Marksman quickly by following these suggestions. First, Dexterity should be your highest ability score (or Strength if you plan to use throwing weapons), followed by Intelligence. Second, choose the soldier background.</p>
            <h2>CLASS FEATURES</h2>
            <p>As a marksman, you gain the following class features.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">HIT POINTS</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Hit Dice:</strong> 1d6 per marksman level</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at 1st Level:</strong> 6 + your Constitution modifier</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at Higher Levels:</strong> 1d6 (or 4) + your Constitution modifier per marksman level after 1st</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">PROFICIENCIES</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled mb">
                <li><strong>Armor:</strong> Light armor, shields</li>
                <li><strong>Weapons:</strong> Simple weapons, martial weapons</li>
                <li><strong>Tools:</strong> None</li>
            </ul>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Saving Throws:</strong> Dexterity, Intelligence</li>
                <li><strong>Skills:</strong> Choose two from Acrobatics, History, Insight, Investigation, Perception, Sleight of Hand, and Stealth.</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">EQUIPMENT</h5>
            <p>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>(a) a longbow and a quiver of 20 arrows or (b) five javelins and a belt of five handaxes</li>
                <li>(a) an explorer’s pack or (b) a dungeoneer’s pack</li>
                <li>ten throwing darts, a shortsword, a shield, leather armor, and one ranged or thrown weapon of your choice.</li>
            </ul>
        <!-- class table here -->
            <h5 class="caption">THE MARKSMAN</h5>
            <table class="class-features">
                <thead>
                    <tr><td class="col-5">Level</td><td class="col-10">Proficiency Bonus</td><td class="col-60 left">Features</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td> 1st</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Marksman’s Shot, Proper Positioning</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 2nd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Trained Spotter, Calculated Cover</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 3rd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Marksman’s Archetype</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 4th</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 5th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Marksman’s Shot Improvement (2 dice), Muscle Memory (3d20)</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 6th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Marksman’s Archetype Feature</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 7th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Excessive Precision</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 8th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 9th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Astonishing Skill</td></tr>
                <tr><td>10th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Marksman’s Archetype Feature</td></tr>
                <tr><td>11th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Marksman’s Shot Improvement (3 dice), Muscle Memory improvement (4d20)</td></tr>
                <tr><td>12th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Counterfire</td></tr>
                <tr><td>14th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Marksman’s Archetype Feature</td></tr>
                <tr><td>15th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Refined Targeting</td></tr>
                <tr><td>16th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td></tr>
                <tr><td>17th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Marksman’s Shot Improvement (4 dice), Muscle Memory Improvement (5d20)</td></tr>
                <tr><td>18th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Multiple Impact Mastery</td></tr>
                <tr><td>19th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td></tr>
                <tr><td>20th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Marksman’s Archetype Feature</td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_DMF_DMFMC_CLASS_FEATURE_MARKSMAN_MARKSMANS_SHOT" />
            <div element="ID_DMF_DMFMC_CLASS_FEATURE_MARKSMAN_PROPER_POSITIONING" />
            <div element="ID_DMF_DMFMC_CLASS_FEATURE_MARKSMAN_TRAINED_SPOTTER" />
            <div element="ID_DMF_DMFMC_CLASS_FEATURE_MARKSMAN_CALCULATED_COVER" />
            <div element="ID_DMF_DMFMC_CLASS_FEATURE_MARKSMAN_MARKSMANS_ARCHETYPE" />
            <div element="ID_DMF_DMFMC_CLASS_FEATURE_MARKSMAN_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" />
            <div element="ID_DMF_DMFMC_CLASS_FEATURE_MARKSMAN_MUSCLE_MEMORY" />
            <div element="ID_DMF_DMFMC_CLASS_FEATURE_MARKSMAN_EXCESSIVE_PRECISION" />
            <div element="ID_DMF_DMFMC_CLASS_FEATURE_MARKSMAN_ASTONISHING_SKILL" />
            <div element="ID_DMF_DMFMC_CLASS_FEATURE_MARKSMAN_COUNTERFIRE" />
            <div element="ID_DMF_DMFMC_CLASS_FEATURE_MARKSMAN_REFINED_TARGETING" />
            <div element="ID_DMF_DMFMC_CLASS_FEATURE_MARKSMAN_MULTIPLE_IMPACT_MASTERY" />
            <h2>MULTICLASSING RULES</h2>
            <p>In a game following the multi-classing rules (PHB pg.163), these additional rules apply to the marksman.</p>
            <p><b>Multiclassing Prerequisites:</b> To qualify for a level in this class, you must have Dexterity and Intelligence scores of 13 or higher.</p>
            <p><b>Multiclassing Proficiencies:</b> When you gain your first level in this class, if it wasn’t your initial class, you gain proficiency with simple weapons, martial weapons, light armor, and shields.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="hd">d6</set>
            <set name="short">A master of the ranged weapon attack.</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_SHIELDS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_MARTIAL_WEAPONS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_DEXTERITY" requirements="!ID_DMF_DMFMC_MULTICLASS_MARKSMAN" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_INTELLIGENCE" requirements="!ID_DMF_DMFMC_MULTICLASS_MARKSMAN" />
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency, Marksman" supports="Marksman" number="2" requirements="!ID_DMF_DMFMC_MULTICLASS_MARKSMAN" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_CLASS_FEATURE_MARKSMAN_MARKSMANS_SHOT" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_CLASS_FEATURE_MARKSMAN_PROPER_POSITIONING" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_CLASS_FEATURE_MARKSMAN_TRAINED_SPOTTER" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_CLASS_FEATURE_MARKSMAN_CALCULATED_COVER" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_CLASS_FEATURE_MARKSMAN_MARKSMANS_ARCHETYPE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_CLASS_FEATURE_MARKSMAN_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" level="4" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_CLASS_FEATURE_MARKSMAN_MUSCLE_MEMORY" level="5" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_CLASS_FEATURE_MARKSMAN_EXCESSIVE_PRECISION" level="7" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_CLASS_FEATURE_MARKSMAN_ASTONISHING_SKILL" level="9" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_CLASS_FEATURE_MARKSMAN_COUNTERFIRE" level="13" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_CLASS_FEATURE_MARKSMAN_REFINED_TARGETING" level="15" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_CLASS_FEATURE_MARKSMAN_MULTIPLE_IMPACT_MASTERY" level="18" />
        </rules>
        <multiclass id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_MULTICLASS_MARKSMAN">
            <prerequisite>Intelligence and Dexterity 13</prerequisite>
            <requirements>[int:13],[dex:13]</requirements>
            <setters>
                <set name="multiclass proficiencies">When you gain your first level in this class, if it wasn’t your initial class, you gain proficiency with simple weapons, martial weapons, light armor, and shields.</set>
            </setters>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS" />
            </rules>
        </multiclass>
    </element>
        <element name="Marksman’s Shot" type="Class Feature" source="HZ Marksman" id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_CLASS_FEATURE_MARKSMAN_MARKSMANS_SHOT">
            <description>
                <p>A Marksman’s pride and joy, the product of countless hours of training and study. Beginning at 1st level, you may take an action to make an especially damaging ranged weapon attack using a ranged or thrown weapon. If you use that weapon with two hands, you may treat its weapon damage die as 1d10 for the purpose of this attack. If you use it with one hand, you may treat its weapon damage die as 1d8. You may add your Intelligence modifier as an extra bonus to the attack roll and the damage of this shot. You may not make any other attacks on the same turn you take this action, neither before nor after, unless those attacks are specifically granted as <i>Marksman’s Shots</i>.</p>
                <p class="indent">When you reach your 5th, 11th, and 17th levels in this class, the damage of this attack is increased by one additional weapon damage die.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>You may make a ranged weapon attack using a ranged or thrown weapon. Two-handed damage die is {{marksmans-shot:damage-dice}}d10; one-handed damage die is {{marksmans-shot:damage-dice}}d8. You add {{intelligence:modifier}} to the attack and damage rolls. You may not make any other attacks on the same turn you take this action, neither before nor after, unless those attacks are specifically granted as<i> Marksman’s</i> Shots.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="marksmans-shot:damage-dice" value="1" level="1" />
                <stat name="marksmans-shot:damage-dice" value="1" level="5" />
                <stat name="marksmans-shot:damage-dice" value="1" level="11" />
                <stat name="marksmans-shot:damage-dice" value="1" level="17" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Proper Positioning" type="Class Feature" source="HZ Marksman" id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_CLASS_FEATURE_MARKSMAN_PROPER_POSITIONING">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 1st level, you’ve learned many ways to put yourself in a good tactical position, and many ways to capitalize on one. When you take the Dash action, the amount of extra movement you gain is increased by a number of feet equal to 5 times your Dexterity modifier. You also gain a climbing speed and long jump distance equal to the same amount, which last until the end of your turn.</p>
                <p class="indent">Whenever you make a ranged attack, if you are at a higher elevation than or have the benefit of cover with respect to the target, you gain advantage on that attack.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you take the Dash action, you can move an extra {{proper-positioning:range}} feet. You also gain a {{proper-positioning:range}}-foot climbing speed and long jump distance, which last until the end of your turn.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="proper-positioning:range" value="5" requirements="[dexterity:modifier:1]" />
                <stat name="proper-positioning:range" value="5" requirements="[dexterity:modifier:2]" />
                <stat name="proper-positioning:range" value="5" requirements="[dexterity:modifier:3]" />
                <stat name="proper-positioning:range" value="5" requirements="[dexterity:modifier:4]" />
                <stat name="proper-positioning:range" value="5" requirements="[dexterity:modifier:5]" />
                <stat name="proper-positioning:range" value="5" requirements="[dexterity:modifier:6]" />
                <stat name="proper-positioning:range" value="5" requirements="[dexterity:modifier:7]" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Trained Spotter" type="Class Feature" source="HZ Marksman" id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_CLASS_FEATURE_MARKSMAN_TRAINED_SPOTTER">
            <description>
                <p>You’ve studied the techniques used to recognize fine details and gained experience discerning subtle cues where others see only blurry shapes. At 2nd level, only if your sight is applicable, you gain an extra bonus to your active and passive Wisdom (Perception) and Intelligence (Investigation) checks equal to your Intelligence modifier.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You gain an extra +{{intelligence:modifier}} bonus to your active and passive Perception and Investigation checks using sight.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Calculated Cover" type="Class Feature" source="HZ Marksman" id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_CLASS_FEATURE_MARKSMAN_CALCULATED_COVER">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 2nd level, your intensive study of trajectories and angles has improved your ability to use cover. The bonuses you receive from ½ and ¾ cover are increased by +1. When a melee attack is made against you, if a plausible impediment such as a barrel, goblin, or ally is both adjacent to you and within the attack’s reach, you may take a reaction to briefly twist aside and gain the benefit of ½ cover against that attack. You don’t move out of your space when doing so.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>The bonuses you receive from ½ and ¾ cover are increased by +1. When a melee attack is made against you, if a plausible impediment such as a barrel, goblin, or ally is both adjacent to you and within the attack’s reach, you may take a reaction to briefly twist aside and gain the benefit of ½ cover against that attack. You don’t move out of your space when doing so.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Marksman’s Archetype" type="Class Feature" source="HZ Marksman" id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_CLASS_FEATURE_MARKSMAN_MARKSMANS_ARCHETYPE">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 3rd level, you choose an archetype to represent your unique motivations, habits, and techniques of marksmanship: Guardian, Gambler, or Executioner. They are detailed following this class description. The style you choose grants you unique features when you choose it at 3rd level, and again at 6th, 10th, 14th, and 20th levels.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Archetype" name="Marksman’s Archetype" supports="Marksman Archetype" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Ability Score Improvement" type="Class Feature" source="HZ Marksman" id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_CLASS_FEATURE_MARKSMAN_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 4th, 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th levels, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Marksman 4)" supports="Improvement Option,Marksman,4" level="4" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Marksman 8)" supports="Improvement Option,Marksman,8" level="8" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Marksman 12)" supports="Improvement Option,Marksman,12" level="12" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Marksman 16)" supports="Improvement Option,Marksman,16" level="16" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Marksman 19)" supports="Improvement Option,Marksman,19" level="19" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Muscle Memory" type="Class Feature" source="HZ Marksman" id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_CLASS_FEATURE_MARKSMAN_MUSCLE_MEMORY">
            <description>
                <p>By 5th level, your long hours of practice have instilled you with the routine actions of the perfect shot. When you take a <i>Marksman’s Shot</i> with advantage, your muscle memory kicks in. Instead of making the attack roll twice, you may roll 3d20 and take the highest result for your attack roll.</p>
                <p class="indent">When you reach your 11th and 17th levels in this class your muscle memory improves, and you may roll an additional d20 for this effect.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you take a <i>Marksman’s Shot</i> with advantage, you may roll {{muscle-memory:attack-dice}}d20 (instead of 2) and take the highest result for your attack roll.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="muscle-memory:attack-dice" value="3" level="5" />
                <stat name="muscle-memory:attack-dice" value="1" level="11" />
                <stat name="muscle-memory:attack-dice" value="1" level="17" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Excessive Precision" type="Class Feature" source="HZ Marksman" id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_CLASS_FEATURE_MARKSMAN_EXCESSIVE_PRECISION">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 7th level, just hitting the target isn’t good enough anymore. You can always find a weaker link in a chain shirt; slice open a millimeter more of throbbing artery. When you take a <i>Marksman’s Shot</i> with advantage and score a hit using the highest attack roll, you may further determine whether any of the other attack rolls you made would have resulted in a hit. For each one that would, you may add one additional weapon damage die to the damage of that attack.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you take a <i>Marksman’s Shot</i> with advantage and score a hit using the highest attack roll, you may further determine whether any of the other attack rolls you made would have resulted in a hit. For each one that would, you may add one additional weapon damage die to the damage of that attack.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Astonishing Skill" type="Class Feature" source="HZ Marksman" id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_CLASS_FEATURE_MARKSMAN_ASTONISHING_SKILL">
            <description>
                <p>At 9th level, you’ve developed skills that seem wondrous and incredible to others. When you make a ranged attack, you may attempt to perform an especially impressive trick of mastery with that shot by taking a -10 penalty to the attack roll. If it hits, describe your accomplishment. Creatures that witness a successful attempt are astounded, and you have advantage on any attempt to persuade or intimidate them for the next hour. Creatures that witness an unsuccessful attempt become immune to this effect for the next 24 hours.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you make a ranged attack, you can make a trick shot by taking a -10 penalty to the attack roll. If it hits, you have advantage on any attempt to persuade or intimidate creatures that witness a successful attempt for the next hour. Creatures that witness an unsuccessful attempt become immune to this effect for the next 24 hours.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Counterfire" type="Class Feature" source="HZ Marksman" id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_CLASS_FEATURE_MARKSMAN_COUNTERFIRE">
            <description>
                <p>Upon reaching 13th level, your aim has become so quick and true that you can shoot incoming projectiles right out of the air. When you see a creature make a ranged weapon attack against you, you may take a reaction to make a <i>Marksman’s Shot</i> against the incoming projectile. Contest the incoming attack roll with your own. If your attack meets or exceeds your opponent’s attack, your shot knocks the incoming attack off-target and it automatically misses.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you see a creature make a ranged weapon attack against you, you may take a reaction to make a Marksman’s Shot against the incoming projectile. Contest the incoming attack roll with your own. If your attack meets or exceeds your opponent’s attack, your shot knocks the incoming attack off-target and it automatically misses.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Refined Targeting" type="Class Feature" source="HZ Marksman" id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_CLASS_FEATURE_MARKSMAN_REFINED_TARGETING">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 15th level, your accuracy extends even to a target’s accessories and items. Your<i> Marksman’s</i> Shot can target an object even if it is being worn or held, such as a pendant around a creature’s neck or a satchel tied to their belt. You choose whether the target object takes damage or flies off, carried away on the tip of your projectile. Your shot can’t carry off tightly grasped objects such as wielded weapons, or tightly bound garments such as pieces of armor.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Your <i>Marksman’s Shot</i> can target an object even if it is being worn or held. You choose whether the target object takes damage or flies off, carried away on the tip of your projectile.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Multiple Impact Mastery" type="Class Feature" source="HZ Marksman" id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_CLASS_FEATURE_MARKSMAN_MULTIPLE_IMPACT_MASTERY">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 18th level, your mastery over projectile dynamics enables you to plot complex trajectories involving multiple ricochets. When you take a <i>Marksman’s Shot</i>, you can bounce the shot off of any hard, stable surface. You select up to 3 points on suitable surfaces, and the shot’s trajectory follows straight paths between those points, flying off the last bounce in any direction you choose.</p>
                <p class="indent">For example, if you are aware of an enemy waiting to ambush you around a corner, you may bounce your shot around the corner and target that creature even though it would otherwise be protected by total cover. You do not suffer any penalty to your accuracy or damage for doing so, beyond the usual effects of attacking an unseen target.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you take a <i>Marksman’s Shot</i>, you can bounce the shot off of any hard, stable surface. You select up to 3 points on suitable surfaces, and the shot’s trajectory follows straight paths between those points, flying off the last bounce in any direction you choose.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    <element name="Guardian" type="Archetype" source="HZ Marksman" id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_ARCHETYPE_MARKSMAN_GUARDIAN">
        <supports>Marksman Archetype</supports>
        <description>
            <p>A guardian is devoted to marksmanship for the sake of others. They leverage their talents towards neutralizing hostilities and protecting the vulnerable. In times of peace they work to keep it, and when violence is unavoidable, they seek a swift and decisive resolution.</p>
            <div element="ID_DMF_DMFMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GUARDIAN_SUPPRESSION" />
            <div element="ID_DMF_DMFMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GUARDIAN_ASSISTED_REPOSITIONING" />
            <div element="ID_DMF_DMFMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GUARDIAN_DISABLING_SHOT" />
            <div element="ID_DMF_DMFMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GUARDIAN_AREA_OF_DENIAL" />
            <div element="ID_DMF_DMFMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GUARDIAN_TOTAL_DENIAL" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GUARDIAN_SUPPRESSION" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GUARDIAN_ASSISTED_REPOSITIONING" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GUARDIAN_DISABLING_SHOT" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GUARDIAN_AREA_OF_DENIAL" level="14" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GUARDIAN_TOTAL_DENIAL" level="20" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Suppression" type="Archetype Feature" source="HZ Marksman" id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GUARDIAN_SUPPRESSION">
            <description>
                <p>When you take on this style at 3rd level, you aim to weaken your targets and destroy their means of aggression. When you hit a creature with a <i>Marksman’s Shot</i>, it suffers a -1d4 penalty on attack rolls until the end of its next turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you hit a creature with a <i>Marksman’s Shot</i>, it suffers a -1d4 penalty on attack rolls until the end of its next turn.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Assisted Repositioning" type="Archetype Feature" source="HZ Marksman" id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GUARDIAN_ASSISTED_REPOSITIONING">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 6th level, you can help your allies escape bad situations. When you take the Dash action on your turn, you also gain the ability to grapple one willing creature as a bonus action until the end of that turn. A willing creature grappled this way does not contest your grapple check and becomes automatically released at the end of your turn. When you pull a willingly grappled creature along with your movement, they do not provoke opportunity attacks and they do not impede your movement or reduce your speed.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you take the Dash action on your turn, you also gain the ability to grapple one willing creature as a bonus action until the end of that turn.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Disabling Shot" type="Archetype Feature" source="HZ Marksman" id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GUARDIAN_DISABLING_SHOT">
            <description>
                <p>At 10th level, you learn how to precisely cripple your foes. When you hit a creature with a<i> Marksman’s</i> Shot, you may choose to reduce that target’s speed by 20 feet until the end of its next turn, or blind or deafen it for the same duration.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you hit a creature with a <i>Marksman’s Shot</i>, you may choose to reduce that target’s speed by 20 feet until the end of its next turn, or blind or deafen it for the same duration.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Area of Denial" type="Archetype Feature" source="HZ Marksman" id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GUARDIAN_AREA_OF_DENIAL">
            <description>
                <p>Upon reaching 14th level, you’ve learned to extend the reach of your projectile protection. You may use Counterfire in response to ranged weapon attacks made against any creature within the maximum range of your weapon.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You may use Counterfire in response to ranged weapon attacks made against any creature within the maximum range of your weapon.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Total Denial" type="Archetype Feature" source="HZ Marksman" id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GUARDIAN_TOTAL_DENIAL">
            <description>
                <p>At 20th level, your protection is uncompromising. Nothing is beyond your ability to deny. You gain a special reaction that you can take once on every creature’s turn, except your turn. You can use this special reaction only to use Counterfire, and you can’t use it on the same turn that you take your normal reaction. You may also use Counterfire in response to a creature you can see casting a spell, to disrupt the spell’s magic with your shot. When you attempt this, the target number you must hit to successfully counter a spell is 20 + (2 * the spell’s level). Countering a spell this way causes it to fail with no effect but does not damage to the caster.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You gain a special reaction that you can take once on every creature’s turn, except your turn. You can use this special reaction only to use Counterfire, and you can’t use it on the same turn that you take your normal reaction.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    <element name="Gambler" type="Archetype" source="HZ Marksman" id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_ARCHETYPE_MARKSMAN_GAMBLER">
        <supports>Marksman Archetype</supports>
        <description>
            <p>A gambler’s first love is Lady Luck. They relish the chance to show off their skill, but they also understand that fortune trumps all. They tend to be more easygoing than other marksmen, meeting good times and bad with equal cheer.</p>
            <div element="ID_DMF_DMFMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GAMBLER_JACKPOT" />
            <div element="ID_DMF_DMFMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GAMBLER_LOADED_DICE" />
            <div element="ID_DMF_DMFMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GAMBLER_CHEATERS_ESCAPE" />
            <div element="ID_DMF_DMFMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GAMBLER_LUCKY_SEVEN" />
            <div element="ID_DMF_DMFMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GAMBLER_COMPLETELY_UNFAIR" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GAMBLER_JACKPOT" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GAMBLER_LOADED_DICE" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GAMBLER_CHEATERS_ESCAPE" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GAMBLER_LUCKY_SEVEN" level="14" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GAMBLER_COMPLETELY_UNFAIR" level="20" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Jackpot!" type="Archetype Feature" source="HZ Marksman" id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GAMBLER_JACKPOT">
            <description>
                <p>At 3rd level, you’ve learned that luck can be just as good as skill. Whenever you roll the maximum value on one of your weapon damage dice for a <i>Marksman’s Shot</i>, you may roll one more weapon damage die for that shot. This effect may apply to any bonus weapon damage dice, including those granted by a critical hit or this effect itself, but the number of dice granted by this effect is not doubled by a critical hit.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Whenever you roll the maximum value on one of your weapon damage dice for a <i>Marksman’s Shot</i>, you may roll 1 more weapon damage die for that shot.</description>
                <description level="14">Whenever you roll the maximum value or a 7 on one of your weapon damage dice for a<i> Marksman’s</i> Shot, you may roll 1 more weapon damage die for that shot.</description>
                <description level="20">Whenever you roll the maximum value or a 7 on one of your weapon damage dice for a<i> Marksman’s</i> Shot, you may roll 3 more weapon damage die for that shot.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Loaded Dice" type="Archetype Feature" source="HZ Marksman" id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GAMBLER_LOADED_DICE">
            <description>
                <p>By 6th level, you’ve learned to make your own luck. Once per turn, when you roll a weapon damage die for a <i>Marksman’s Shot</i>, you may change the result to the maximum value. You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="{{intelligence:modifier}}/Long Rest">
                <description>Once per turn, when you roll a weapon damage die for a <i>Marksman’s Shot</i>, you may change the result to the maximum value.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Cheater’s Escape" type="Archetype Feature" source="HZ Marksman" id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GAMBLER_CHEATERS_ESCAPE">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 10th level, you learn to get out while the getting’s good. When you use your Loaded Dice feature, you gain the benefits of the Disengage and Dash actions until the end of that turn, including your Proper Positioning feature.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you use your Loaded Dice feature, you gain the benefits of the Disengage and Dash actions until the end of that turn, including your Proper Positioning feature.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Lucky Seven" type="Archetype Feature" source="HZ Marksman" id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GAMBLER_LUCKY_SEVEN">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 14th level, you may also use your “Jackpot!” feature when you roll a 7.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description>You may also use your “Jackpot!” feature when you roll a 7.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Completely Unfair" type="Archetype Feature" source="HZ Marksman" id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GAMBLER_COMPLETELY_UNFAIR">
            <description>
                <p>At 20th level, you’re not even pretending to play a fair game anymore. When you use your “Jackpot!” feature, you may roll three additional weapon damage dice instead of just one.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description>When you use your “Jackpot!” feature, you may roll 3 additional weapon damage dice instead of just one.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    <element name="Executioner" type="Archetype" source="HZ Marksman" id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_ARCHETYPE_MARKSMAN_EXECUTIONER">
        <supports>Marksman Archetype</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Executioners see themselves as the plainest practitioners of marksmanship. To them, a weapon is a tool of deadly violence, and a marksman’s purpose is to do such work. Some executioners are cruel sadists, drawn to it by a taste for blood. Some are solemn and stoic, heralds of a silent end. All are exceptional, superlative, consummate killers.</p>
            <div element="ID_DMF_DMFMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_EXECUTIONER_CRUEL_EYE" />
            <div element="ID_DMF_DMFMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_EXECUTIONER_BLOODRUSH" />
            <div element="ID_DMF_DMFMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_EXECUTIONER_OVERPENETRATION" />
            <div element="ID_DMF_DMFMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_EXECUTIONER_PIERCING_GAZE" />
            <div element="ID_DMF_DMFMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_EXECUTIONER_STOPPING_POWER" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_EXECUTIONER_CRUEL_EYE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_EXECUTIONER_BLOODRUSH" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_EXECUTIONER_OVERPENETRATION" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_EXECUTIONER_PIERCING_GAZE" level="14" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_EXECUTIONER_STOPPING_POWER" level="20" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="A Cruel Eye" type="Archetype Feature" source="HZ Marksman" id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_EXECUTIONER_CRUEL_EYE">
            <description>
                <p>An executioner’s gaze is merciless and unyielding. Starting at 3rd level, you have advantage on any attempt to discern whether a creature you can see is lying. As a bonus action, you may choose one creature you can see and make an Intelligence (Investigation) check contested by the target’s Charisma (Deception) to discover whether it is intimidated, frightened, or unsettled, and what its vulnerabilities are.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>You may choose one creature you can see and make an Investigation check contested by the target’s Deception to discover whether it is intimidated, frightened, or unsettled, and what its vulnerabilities are.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Bloodrush" type="Archetype Feature" source="HZ Marksman" id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_EXECUTIONER_BLOODRUSH">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 6th level, the act of taking a life fills your veins with a rush of vigor. Whenever you reduce a target to 0 hit points using a <i>Marksman’s Shot</i>, you gain the ability to take a <i>Marksman’s Shot</i> as a bonus action until the end of that turn. You may also trigger this feature of your own will once, at any time on your turn without needing to meet the usual trigger condition, and you regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Whenever you reduce a target to 0 hit points using a <i>Marksman’s Shot</i>, you gain the ability to take a <i>Marksman’s Shot</i> as a bonus action until the end of that turn. You may also trigger this feature of your own will once, at any time on your turn without needing to meet the usual trigger condition, and you regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Overpenetration" type="Archetype Feature" source="HZ Marksman" id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_EXECUTIONER_OVERPENETRATION">
            <description>
                <p>At 10th level, you’ve learned to deliver your <i>Marksman’s Shot</i> in such a way that it pierces through your target entirely. When you hit a creature with your <i>Marksman’s Shot</i>, your shot passes through the target and continues onwards along its path. You may roll a <i>Marksman’s Shot</i> attack against the next creature in the way of that trajectory, if there is one. Your projectile stops in that second target if you hit it, or glances harmlessly to the ground if you miss or decline to make this attack. If a<i> Marksman’s</i> Shot you took reduces a target to 0 hit points, it always passes through that target no matter how many targets it pierced previously.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you hit a creature with your <i>Marksman’s Shot</i>, your shot passes through the target and continues onwards along its path. You may roll a <i>Marksman’s Shot</i> attack against the next creature in the way of that trajectory, if there is one. If a <i>Marksman’s Shot</i> you took reduces a target to 0 hit points, it always passes through that target no matter how many targets it pierced previously.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Piercing Gaze" type="Archetype Feature" source="HZ Marksman" id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_EXECUTIONER_PIERCING_GAZE">
            <description>
                <p>When you achieve 14th level, you learn how to spot the weakest points on a target with your Cruel Eye. When you successfully investigate a target with A Cruel Eye, your <i>Marksman’s Shots</i> against that target gain a damage bonus of one additional weapon damage die. This bonus lasts for up to one minute, ending early if you lose sight of the target.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you successfully investigate a target with A Cruel Eye, your <i>Marksman’s Shots</i> against that target gain a damage bonus of one additional weapon damage die. This bonus lasts for up to one minute, ending early if you lose sight of the target.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Stopping Power" type="Archetype Feature" source="HZ Marksman" id="ID_DMF_DMFMC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_EXECUTIONER_STOPPING_POWER">
            <description>
                <p>At 20th level, you’ve learned to lay your targets low with dreadful certainty. When you deal damage with a <i>Marksman’s Shot</i>, if that damage reduces the target’s hit points to 50 or less, the target dies. Causing a target to die this way activates your Bloodrush feature and allows your shot to pass through that target with Overpenetration.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you deal damage with a <i>Marksman’s Shot</i>, if that damage reduces the target’s hit points to 50 or less, the target dies. Causing a target to die this way activates your Bloodrush feature and allows your shot to pass through that target with Overpenetration.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

  <!-- Marksman Skills -->
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ACROBATICS">
        <supports>Marksman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_HISTORY">
        <supports>Marksman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT">
        <supports>Marksman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INVESTIGATION">
        <supports>Marksman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION">
        <supports>Marksman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SLEIGHTOFHAND">
        <supports>Marksman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_STEALTH">
        <supports>Marksman</supports>
    </append>

</elements>