<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>The Spider Queen Otherworldly Patron</name>
        <update version="0.0.2">
            <file name="warlock-the-spider-queen.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/subclasses/warlock/warlock-the-spider-queen.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Arachnids" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_FLIPIWIPY_HOMEBREWERY_SOURCE_ARACHNIDS">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation"></set>
            <set name="url">https://homebrewery.naturalcrit.com/share/Uk7ERUpk</set>
            <set name="image">http://conceptartworld.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/Daniel_Ljunggren_07a.jpg</set>
            <set name="author" url="https://www.reddit.com/user/Flipiwipy/">u/Flipiwipy</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20200318</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="The Spider Queen" type="Archetype" source="Arachnids" id="ID_FLIPIWIPY_ARACHNIDS_ARCHETYPE_WARLOCK_THE_SPIDER_QUEEN">
        <supports>Otherworldly Patron</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Your patron is an inmense beast that dwells in darkness and has an inclination for schemes, deception, and cruelty.</p>
            <p class="indent">The Spider Queens are ancient and spiteful, making pacts with mortals to fulfill their revenge plans agains those who hurt or disrespected them.</p>
            <p class="indent">Their inclination for ancient, dense forests may put them in conflict with some archfey or an elven civilization, or cause a problem with humans destroying their home.</p>
            <div class="sidebar">
                <h5 class="caption">Unearthed Arcana - Class Variant Features</h5>
                <p>This class option assumes the use of the Class Variant features published on Unearthed Arcana (Spell versatility and the expanded Warlock spell list).</p>
                <p class="indent">In case this list isn’t being used, the Expanded Spell least for this patron will include Mislead at level 5, instead of Seeming.</p>
            </div>
            <div element="ID_FLIPIWIPY_ARACHNIDS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIDER_QUEEN_EXPANDED_SPELL_LIST" />
            <div element="ID_FLIPIWIPY_ARACHNIDS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIDER_QUEEN_BONUS_CANTRIPS" />
            <div element="ID_FLIPIWIPY_ARACHNIDS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIDER_QUEEN_BLESSING_OF_THE_SPIDER" />
            <div element="ID_FLIPIWIPY_ARACHNIDS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIDER_QUEEN_WEB_WEAVER" />
            <div element="ID_FLIPIWIPY_ARACHNIDS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIDER_QUEEN_ARACHNID_BODY" />
            <div element="ID_FLIPIWIPY_ARACHNIDS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIDER_QUEEN_MARK_OF_THE_SPIDER_QUEEN" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FLIPIWIPY_ARACHNIDS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIDER_QUEEN_EXPANDED_SPELL_LIST" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FLIPIWIPY_ARACHNIDS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIDER_QUEEN_BONUS_CANTRIPS" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FLIPIWIPY_ARACHNIDS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIDER_QUEEN_BLESSING_OF_THE_SPIDER" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FLIPIWIPY_ARACHNIDS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIDER_QUEEN_WEB_WEAVER" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FLIPIWIPY_ARACHNIDS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIDER_QUEEN_ARACHNID_BODY" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FLIPIWIPY_ARACHNIDS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIDER_QUEEN_MARK_OF_THE_SPIDER_QUEEN" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Expanded Spell List" type="Archetype Feature" source="Arachnids" id="ID_FLIPIWIPY_ARACHNIDS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIDER_QUEEN_EXPANDED_SPELL_LIST">
            <description>
                <p>The Spider Queen allows you to choose from a expanded list of spells when you learn a warlock spell. The following spells are added to the warlock spell list for you.</p>
                <h5 class="caption">SPIDER QUEEN PATRON EXPANDED SPELLS</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Spell Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1</td><td><em>snare, hunter’s mark</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>2</td><td><em>pass without trace, web</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3</td><td><em>conjure animals, nondetection</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>4</td><td><em>giant insect, freedom of movement</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5</td><td><em>insect plague, seeming</em></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <spellcasting name="Warlock" extend="true">
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_SNARE</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_HUNTERS_MARK</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_PASS_WITHOUT_TRACE</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_WEB</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_CONJURE_ANIMALS</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_NONDETECTION</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_GIANT_INSECT</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_FREEDOM_OF_MOVEMENT</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_INSECT_PLAGUE</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_SEEMING</extend>
            </spellcasting>
        </element>
        <element name="Bonus Cantrips" type="Archetype Feature" source="Arachnids" id="ID_FLIPIWIPY_ARACHNIDS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIDER_QUEEN_BONUS_CANTRIPS">
            <description>
                <p>You learn the <em>poison spray</em> cantrip. It counts as a warlock cantrip for you, but it doesn’t count against your number of cantrips known.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_POISON_SPRAY" spellcasting="Warlock" known="true" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Blessing of the Spider" type="Archetype Feature" source="Arachnids" id="ID_FLIPIWIPY_ARACHNIDS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIDER_QUEEN_BLESSING_OF_THE_SPIDER">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 1st level, you may spend your bonus action inbuing a weapon with Spider Queen poison. The next succesful attack made with that weapon will deal an additional 1d4 poison damage.</p>
                <p class="indent">The size of the damage die increases at levels 5 (1d6), 7 (1d8) and 13 (1d10).</p>
                <p class="indent">When you reach level 5, a successful imbued weapon attack will force the target to make a Constitution saving throw against your spell save DC, or be poisoned for one minute. The target may spend their action to repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns.</p>
                <p class="indent">At level 7, if the target fails the saving throw, it will take 1d6 additional poision damage at the beginning of each of its turns.</p>
                <p class="indent">Finally, on your 13th level every imbued weapon attack you make counts as magical for the purposes of overcoming resistance and immunity to non-magical attacks.</p>
                <p class="indent">In addition to this, the Spider Queen gives you insight into her predatorial talents. You acquire proficiency on Deception and Stealth, as well as proficiency with nets.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>You imbue a weapon with Spider Queen poison. The next succesful attack made with that weapon will deal an additional 1d{{blessing-spider:die-type}} poison damage.</description>
                <description level="5">You imbue a weapon with Spider Queen poison. The next succesful attack made with that weapon will deal an additional 1d{{blessing-spider:die-type}} poison damage and the target must make a Constitution saving throw against your spell save DC, or be poisoned for one minute. The target may spend their action to repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns.</description>
                <description level="7">You imbue a weapon with Spider Queen poison. The next succesful attack made with that weapon will deal an additional 1d{{blessing-spider:die-type}} poison damage and the target must make a Constitution saving throw against your spell save DC, or be poisoned for one minute, and take 1d6 additional poision damage at the beginning of each of its turns. The target may spend their action to repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns.</description>
                <description level="13">You imbue a weapon with Spider Queen poison and it counts as magical for the purposes of overcoming resistance and immunity to non-magical attacks. The next succesful attack made with that weapon will deal an additional 1d{{blessing-spider:die-type}} poison damage and the target must make a Constitution saving throw against your spell save DC, or be poisoned for one minute, and take 1d6 additional poision damage at the beginning of each of its turns. The target may spend their action to repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="blessing-spider:die-type" value="4" bonus="base" level="1" />
                <stat name="blessing-spider:die-type" value="6" bonus="base" level="5" />
                <stat name="blessing-spider:die-type" value="8" bonus="base" level="7" />
                <stat name="blessing-spider:die-type" value="10" bonus="base" level="13" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_DECEPTION" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_STEALTH" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Web Weaver" type="Archetype Feature" source="Arachnids" id="ID_FLIPIWIPY_ARACHNIDS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIDER_QUEEN_WEB_WEAVER">
            <description>
                <p>The influence of your patron over your body is changing it in some supernatural ways, allowing you to produce spider silk and developping affinity for arachnid creatures.</p>
                <p class="indent">Starting at 6th level, you’ll learn the <em>web</em> spell and will be able to cast it without spending a spell slot a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier. This spell doesn’t count against your number of spells known.</p>
                <p class="indent">You recover all uses of this spell after a long rest.</p>
                <p class="indent">If you already knew the web spell, you may learn another spell from the warlock spell list.</p>
                <p class="indent">You also acquire the Web Sense and Web Walker traits, and can use your web producing capabilities to perform the following actions:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li><div element="ID_FLIPIWIPY_ARACHNIDS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIDER_QUEEN_WEB_WEAVER_WEB_ROPE" /></li>
                    <li><div element="ID_FLIPIWIPY_ARACHNIDS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIDER_QUEEN_WEB_WEAVER_WEB_SHOT" /></li>
                    <li><div element="ID_FLIPIWIPY_ARACHNIDS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIDER_QUEEN_WEB_WEAVER_WEB_TRAP" /></li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">Your patron’s influence over your mind also gives you the capacity to communicate telepathically with arachnids, and gives you advantage on Charisma (Persuasion, Intimidation, Deception) checks against arachnids.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You communicate telepathically with arachnids, and gives you advantage on Deception, Intimidation, and Persuasion checks against arachnids.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FLIPIWIPY_ARACHNIDS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIDER_QUEEN_WEB_WEAVER_WEB" level="6" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FLIPIWIPY_ARACHNIDS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIDER_QUEEN_WEB_WEAVER_WEB_WALKER" level="6" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FLIPIWIPY_ARACHNIDS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIDER_QUEEN_WEB_WEAVER_WEB_ROPE" level="6" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FLIPIWIPY_ARACHNIDS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIDER_QUEEN_WEB_WEAVER_WEB_SHOT" level="6" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FLIPIWIPY_ARACHNIDS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIDER_QUEEN_WEB_WEAVER_WEB_TRAP" level="6" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Web Weaver: Web" type="Archetype Feature" source="Arachnids" id="ID_FLIPIWIPY_ARACHNIDS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIDER_QUEEN_WEB_WEAVER_WEB">
                <description>
                    <p>Starting at 6th level, you’ll learn the <em>web</em> spell and will be able to cast it without spending a spell slot a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier. This spell doesn’t count against your number of spells known.</p>
                    <p class="indent">You recover all uses of this spell after a long rest.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="{{charisma:modifier}}/Long Rest" alt="Web">
                    <description>You can cast web without expending a spell slot.</description>
                    <description level="10">You can cast the web spell without expending a spell slot or using any verbal or material components, and any creature restrained by it has disadvantage on Strength checks to escape. If you are within 5 feet of a restrained creature, you may cast the web spell again in order to trap said creature within a web cocoon (AC 13; hp 14; vulnerability to fire damage; immunity to bludgeoning, poison, and psychic damage), leaving it paralyzed if the spell is succesful.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WEB" spellcasting="Warlock" known="true" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Web Weaver: Web Sense" type="Archetype Feature" source="Arachnids" id="ID_FLIPIWIPY_ARACHNIDS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIDER_QUEEN_WEB_WEAVER_WEB_SENSE">
                <description>
        			<p>While in contact with a web, the spider knows the exact location of any other creature in contact with the same web.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet alt="Web Sense">
        			<description>While in contact with a web, the spider knows the exact location of any other creature in contact with the same web.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Web Weaver: Web Walker" type="Archetype Feature" source="Arachnids" id="ID_FLIPIWIPY_ARACHNIDS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIDER_QUEEN_WEB_WEAVER_WEB_WALKER">
                <description>
        			<p>The spider ignores movement restrictions caused by webbing.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet alt="Web Walker">
        			<description>The spider ignores movement restrictions caused by webbing.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Web Weaver: Web Rope" type="Archetype Feature" source="Arachnids" id="ID_FLIPIWIPY_ARACHNIDS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIDER_QUEEN_WEB_WEAVER_WEB_ROPE">
                <description>
                    <p>A number of times equal to your Charisma modifier, you can spend an action to create 20 feet of rope or 60 feet of thread. These items wil decompose within 1 hour.</p>
                    <p class="indent">You regain all expended uses of this ability after either a long or short rest.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet alt="Web Rope" usage="{{charisma:modifier}}/Short Rest" action="Action">
                    <description>You can create 20 feet of web rope or 60 feet of web thread. These items wil decompose within 1 hour.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Web Weaver: Web Shot" type="Archetype Feature" source="Arachnids" id="ID_FLIPIWIPY_ARACHNIDS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIDER_QUEEN_WEB_WEAVER_WEB_SHOT">
                <description>
                    <p>A number of times equal to your Charisma modifier, you may use your bonus action to perform a ranged weapon attack with your spider silk, with which you are considered proficient, and uses Dexterity as its attack characteristic. If the attack is successful and your target is Large or smaller, you can pull that target up to 10 feet towards you. You regain all expended uses of this ability after either a long or short rest.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet alt="Web Shot" usage="{{charisma:modifier}}/Short Rest" action="Bonus Action">
                    <description>You may perform a ranged weapon attack with your spider silk, with which you are considered proficient, and uses Dexterity as its attack characteristic. If the attack is successful and your target is Large or smaller, you can pull that target up to 10 feet towards you.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Web Weaver: Web Trap" type="Archetype Feature" source="Arachnids" id="ID_FLIPIWIPY_ARACHNIDS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIDER_QUEEN_WEB_WEAVER_WEB_TRAP">
                <description>
                    <p>You may spend 10 minutes weaving a nearly invisibly web taking up a 20 feet cube (or up to 64 5ft. cubes, as long as they’re adjacent to each other).</p>
                    <p class="indent">Detecting this web requires a Wisdom (Percepction) ability check, and moving through it without touching it requires a Dexterity (Acrobatics) ability check. Both checks will be made against your spell save DC.</p>
                    <p class="indent">As long as you are within a mile of this web and in the same plane of existence, the moment a creature touches it you will be aware of it, as if you were in contact with it, using your Web Sense.</p>
                    <p class="indent">You won’t be able to use thise feature again until you finish either a short or long rest.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet alt="Web Trap" usage="1/Short Rest">
                    <description>You may spend 10 minutes weaving a nearly invisibly web taking up a 20 feet cube (or up to 64 5ft. cubes, as long as they’re adjacent to each other). Detecting this web requires a Percepction ability check, and moving through it without touching it requires a Acrobatics ability check. Both checks will be made against your spell save DC. As long as you are within a mile of this web and in the same plane of existence, the moment a creature touches it you will be aware of it, as if you were in contact with it, using your Web Sense.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
        <element name="Arachnid Body" type="Archetype Feature" source="Arachnids" id="ID_FLIPIWIPY_ARACHNIDS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIDER_QUEEN_ARACHNID_BODY">
            <description>
                <p>Your connection with the dark powers of your patron becomes deeper, fundamentally changing your body, as if you were becoming a different creature.</p>
                <p class="indent">When you reach level 10, you gain resistance against poison damage and advantage on all saving throws against poison.</p>
                <p class="indent">You also acquire the Spider Climb trait and a climbing speed equal to your walking speed.</p>
                <p class="indent">In addition to this, you may cast the Web spell without any verbal or material components, and any creature restrained by it has disadvantage on Strength checks to escape. If you are within 5 feet of a restrained creature, you may cast the Web spell again in order to trap said creature within a web cocoon (AC 13; hp 14; vulnerability to fire damage; immunity to bludgeoning, poison, and psychic damage), leaving it paralyzed if the spell is succesful.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You advantage on all saving throws against poison. You can also climb difficult surfaces, including upside down on ceilings, without needing to make an ability check.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_POISON" />
                <stat name="speed:climb" value="speed" bonus="base" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Mark of the Spider Queen" type="Archetype Feature" source="Arachnids" id="ID_FLIPIWIPY_ARACHNIDS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIDER_QUEEN_MARK_OF_THE_SPIDER_QUEEN">
            <description>
                <p>The dark powers of your patron have taken hold of every fiber of your being, conecting you with the very essence of her nature, which you can tap into to empower yourself.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Spider Form.</em></strong> You may spend 1 action to transform yourself into a spider hybrid for an hour. Your lower half will become like that of a spider, and you will grow extra arms on your still humanoid torso.</p>
                <p class="indent">Any equipment you were carrying on the lower half of your body will meld into your new form, and you will lose any benefit you gained from them.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you won’t be able to use it again until you finish a long rest. When you transform, you experience the following changes:</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong>Hit points.</strong> When you reach level 14, besides rolling your warlock hit die, roll 1d10 for each level you have in this class, adding your constitution modifier to each roll. Adding the result of those d10 will give you the Hit point total you’ll have under this form.<br />Every time you gain a warlock level, roll an additional d10 hit die + your constitution modifier and add it to the hit point total of your Spider Form.<br />If you become unconscious, die, or are reduced to 0 hit points, you will revert to your normal form. When you revert to your normal form, you return to the number of Hit Points you had before transforming. with the same amount of hit points you had before transforming. If you revert as a result of dropping to 0 Hit points, any excess damage carries over to its normal form.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong>Armour Class.</strong> You receive a +2 bonus to your AC.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong>Senses.</strong> Darkvision 60 feet, blindsight 20 feet. If you already had Darkvision, you gain an additional 60 feet.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong>Skills.</strong> Your proficiency modificer on Dexterity (Stealth) checks is doubled.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong>Immunities.</strong> You are immune to poison.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong>Resistances.</strong> You are resistant to non-magical bludgeoning, piercing and slashing damage.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong>Additional Arms.</strong> Two additional arms grow on your torso, allowing you to hold more items (a weapon or arcane focus, but not more than one shield), and gaining an additionl free item interaction, as long as you have at least 1 free hand.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong>Innate Spellcasting.</strong> You may cast the Web spell at will, with all the changes granted by your patron.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong>Natural Poison.</strong> Every one of your weapon attacks will be considered imbued with poison, without spending your bonus action.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong>Web Mummy.</strong> You may spend 10 minutes to wrap the corpse of a creature in a web cocoon and reanimate it as a Web Mummy (see the template on page 3 of this document) under your control. The mummy acts immediately after your turn. You may spend a bonus action to give the mummy a specific order, but it will otherwise protect you and attack hostile creatures. This mummy will remain reanimated for an hour, after which it will collapse and won’t be possible to reanimate this way again. Once you’ve used this feature, you won’t be able to use it again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You can transform into your Spider Form.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
</elements>