<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Pactbreaker Otherworldly Patron</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="warlock-pactbreaker.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/subclasses/warlock/warlock-pactbreaker.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="The Pactbreaker" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_FLASHPOINTBREWS_GMBINDER_SOURCE_THE_PACTBREAKER">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation">TPBOP</set>
            <set name="url">https://www.gmbinder.com/share/-M7tBaWOT0YPdhFp-wgG</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" abbreviation="FPB" url="https://www.gmbinder.com/profile/flashpointbrews">flashpointbrews</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20201001</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="The Pactbreaker" type="Archetype" source="The Pactbreaker" id="ID_FPB_TPBOP_ARCHETYPE_WARLOCK_PACTBREAKER">
        <supports>Otherworldly Patron</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You made a pact with a powerful being, perhaps one that was beyond your understanding. The pact set terms for the exchange of powers, conditions that had to be met. Whether by your choice or your patron's, the terms were broken and the pact is no more. Your patron no longer actively issues you power. In fact, your patron may even be spiteful and actively trying to hinder your efforts.</p>
            <p class="indent">Regardless, the issuing of a pact is an eldritch contract beyond comprehension, and its formation leaves the humanoid vessel changed. Despite the destruction of your pact, you find yourself imbued with a new and different set of power.</p>
            <div element="ID_FPB_TPBOP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTBREAKER_EXPANDED_SPELL_LIST" />
            <div element="ID_FPB_TPBOP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTBREAKER_PACT_SURVIVOR" />
            <div element="ID_FPB_TPBOP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTBREAKER_CORRUPT_INFLUENCE" />
            <div element="ID_FPB_TPBOP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTBREAKER_ENTREAT_FOLLOWING" />
            <div element="ID_FPB_TPBOP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTBREAKER_INDEPENDENT_MIND" />
            <div element="ID_FPB_TPBOP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTBREAKER_ELDRITCH_INTELLECT" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FPB_TPBOP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTBREAKER_EXPANDED_SPELL_LIST" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FPB_TPBOP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTBREAKER_PACT_SURVIVOR" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FPB_TPBOP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTBREAKER_CORRUPT_INFLUENCE" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FPB_TPBOP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTBREAKER_ENTREAT_FOLLOWING" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FPB_TPBOP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTBREAKER_INDEPENDENT_MIND" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FPB_TPBOP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTBREAKER_ELDRITCH_INTELLECT" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Expanded Spell List" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Pactbreaker" id="ID_FPB_TPBOP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTBREAKER_EXPANDED_SPELL_LIST">
            <description>
                <p>The Pactbreaker loses previously learned patron spells. However, in order to protect yourself from your former patron and the influence of others, you can choose to learn spells from an expanded list of spells. The following spells are added to the warlock spell list for you and you may choose them to replace any spells lost when your pact was broken or when you gain a level in this class.</p>
                <h5 class="caption">PACTBREAKER EXPANDED SPELLS</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Spell Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1st</td><td><em>detect evil and good, magic missile</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>2nd</td><td><em>arcanist's magic aura, pass without trace</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>haste, nondetection</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>4th</td><td><em>confusion, freedom of movement</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>dispel evil and good, modify memory</em></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <spellcasting name="Warlock" extend="true">
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_EVIL_AND_GOOD</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGIC_MISSILE</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_ARCANISTS_MAGIC_AURA</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_PASS_WITHOUT_TRACE</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_HASTE</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_NONDETECTION</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_CONFUSION</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_FREEDOM_OF_MOVEMENT</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_DISPEL_EVIL_AND_GOOD</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_MODIFY_MEMORY</extend>
            </spellcasting>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Pact Survivor" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Pactbreaker" id="ID_FPB_TPBOP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTBREAKER_PACT_SURVIVOR">
            <description>
                <p>At 1st level, your body has survived losing your power. Your hit point maximum increases by 1, and it increases by 1 every time you gain a level in this class.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="hp" value="level:warlock" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Corrupt Influence" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Pactbreaker" id="ID_FPB_TPBOP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTBREAKER_CORRUPT_INFLUENCE">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 1st level, you have learned the harsh truths of subordination and know how to corrupt such relationships. As an action, you can force a creature you can see within 30 feet to make a Wisdom saving throw if its CR is less than that of one of its allies within 120 feet. On a failure, the creature becomes frightened of the higher CR ally and cannot willingly use its turn to aid the ally toward its obvious goals, like protecting itself or defeating its enemies. If there are multiple creatures with higher challenge ratings within range, you may choose the creature to be frightened of. If the creature is allied with no creatures of higher CR, this feature automatically fails and you regain your use of this feature.</p>
                <p class="indent">The frightened creature remains so until it takes damage, it uses its action to succeed on the saving throw, or the higher CR creature is incapacitated.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Short Rest" action="Action">
                <description>You can force a creature you can see within 30 feet to make a Wisdom saving throw if its CR is less than that of one of its allies within 120 feet. On a failure, the creature becomes frightened of the higher CR ally and cannot willingly use its turn to aid the ally toward its obvious goals, like protecting itself or defeating its enemies. The frightened creature remains so until it takes damage, it uses its action to succeed on the saving throw, or the higher CR creature is incapacitated.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Entreat Following" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Pactbreaker" id="ID_FPB_TPBOP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTBREAKER_ENTREAT_FOLLOWING">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 6th level, you can become a guiding light to those who've broken their bonds but fear the repercussions of doing so. As an action, you can cause a frightened creature of CR 1 or lower to make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failure, the creature joins you as an ally and gains temporary hit points equal to half your warlock level. In combat, the creature rolls its own initiative, but it obeys your verbal commands (no action required), and it gains a special bonus to its attack rolls equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum of +0). On a success, the creature is immune to this feature for 24 hours.</p>
                <p class="indent">You may have one such creature in your service at a time. It remains in your service until it is reduced to 0 hit points, until this effect is ended by a greater restoration or other similar magic, or until the end of your next long rest, at which point it sets out on a new life. If this effect ends before you take a long rest, the creature makes a new Wisdom saving throw. On a success, it may choose to become hostile. On a failure, it sets out on a new life peacefully.</p>
                <p class="indent">The CR creatures you can affect increases as you gain levels in this class to CR 2 at 10th level, CR 3 at 14th level, and CR 4 at 18th level.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>You can cause a frightened creature of CR {{entreat-following:cr}} or lower to make a Wisdom saving throw (DC {{spellcasting:dc:cha}}). On a failure, the creature joins you as an ally and gains {{level:warlock:half}} temporary hit points. the creature rolls its own initiative, but it obeys your verbal commands (no action required), and it gains a +{{charisma:modifier}} bonus to its attack rolls.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="entreat-following:cr" value="1" level="6" />
                <stat name="entreat-following:cr" value="1" level="10" />
                <stat name="entreat-following:cr" value="1" level="14" />
                <stat name="entreat-following:cr" value="1" level="18" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Independent Mind" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Pactbreaker" id="ID_FPB_TPBOP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTBREAKER_INDEPENDENT_MIND">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 10th level, your separation from your patron has led to increased self-discovery and mental fortitude. You are resistant to psychic damage.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, as an action on your turn, you can end one effect that is causing you to be charmed or frightened.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>You can end one effect that is causing you to be charmed or frightened.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_PSYCHIC" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Eldritch Intellect" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Pactbreaker" id="ID_FPB_TPBOP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTBREAKER_ELDRITCH_INTELLECT">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 14th level, the magic that has sustained the breaking of your pact suffices your body and allows you to discover your own arcanums. At the end of long rest, you can exchange one Mystic Arcanum spell for another spell available at the same spell level from any class's spell list.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>At the end of long rest, you can exchange one Mystic Arcanum spell for another spell available at the same spell level from any class's spell list.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

</elements>