<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>The Forest Guadian Patron</name>
        <author url="https://www.gmbinder.com/share/-Ldh11KaW31PVZ54-5NY">sinon</author>
        <update version="0.0.2">
            <file name="warlock-forest-guardian.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/subclasses/warlock/warlock-forest-guardian.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="The Forest Guardian" type="Archetype" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FOREST_GUARDIAN_PATRON">
        <supports>Otherworldly Patron</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You have made a pact with a powerful being that serves nature itself. Such creatures seek to grow and protect the natural beauty of the forest. Protecting nature from the encroachment of civilization and industrious cities is in the forefront of their thoughts, and is often the reason for offering power to others. Many see them as terrible creatures, ruthlessly bringing vengeance to those who would intrude on the spread of nature. Others find harmony with them, spreading the vines of nature throughout the planes. Entities capable of this power include ancient treants, dryads, or coalitions of awakened plants.</p>
            <div element="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FOREST_GUARDIAN_EXPANDED_SPELL_LIST"/>
            <div element="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FOREST_GUARDIAN_EMISSARY_OF_NATURE" />
            <div element="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FOREST_GUARDIAN_VINE_GROWTH" />
            <div element="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FOREST_GUARDIAN_BLOOM" />
            <div element="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FOREST_GUARDIAN_HEART_OF_THE_WILD" />
            <div element="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FOREST_GUARDIAN_CONSTRICTING_FOREST" />
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You have made a pact with a powerful being that serves nature itself. Such creatures seek to grow and protect the natural beauty of the forest.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FOREST_GUARDIAN_EXPANDED_SPELL_LIST" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FOREST_GUARDIAN_EMISSARY_OF_NATURE" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FOREST_GUARDIAN_VINE_GROWTH" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FOREST_GUARDIAN_BLOOM" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FOREST_GUARDIAN_HEART_OF_THE_WILD" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FOREST_GUARDIAN_CONSTRICTING_FOREST" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Expanded Spell List" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FOREST_GUARDIAN_EXPANDED_SPELL_LIST">
        <description>
            <p>The Forest Guardian lets you choose from an expanded list of spells when you learn a warlock spell. The following are added to the warlock spell list for you.</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Spell Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1st</td><td><i>animal friendship, earth tremor</i></td></tr>
                <tr><td>2nd</td><td><i>Maximilian’s earthen grasp, spike growth</i></td></tr>
                <tr><td>3rd</td><td><i>erupting earth, speak with plants</i></td></tr>
                <tr><td>4th</td><td><i>control water, guardian of nature</i></td></tr>
                <tr><td>5th</td><td><i>commune with nature, wrath of nature</i></td></tr>
            </table>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description>The Forest Guardian lets you choose from an expanded list of spells when you learn a warlock spell.</description>
        </sheet>
        <spellcasting name="Warlock" extend="true">
            <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_ANIMAL_FRIENDSHIP</extend>
            <extend>ID_XGTE_SPELL_EARTH_TREMOR</extend>
            <extend>ID_XGTE_SPELL_MAXIMILIANS_EARTHEN_GRASP</extend>
            <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_SPIKE_GROWTH</extend>
            <extend>ID_XGTE_SPELL_ERUPTING_EARTH</extend>
            <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_PLANTS</extend>
            <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_CONTROL_WATER</extend>
            <extend>ID_XGTE_SPELL_GUARDIAN_OF_NATURE</extend>
            <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_COMMUNE_WITH_NATURE</extend>
            <extend>ID_XGTE_SPELL_WRATH_OF_NATURE</extend>
        </spellcasting>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Emissary of Nature" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FOREST_GUARDIAN_EMISSARY_OF_NATURE">
        <description>
            <p>You spread the forest wherever you go. At 1st level, you learn the <i>druidcraft</i> cantrip. It doesn’t count against your number of cantrips known, but is nonetheless a warlock cantrip for you. While traveling outside, you don’t leave tracks unless you choose to.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>While traveling outside, you don’t leave tracks unless you choose to.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DRUIDCRAFT" spellcasting="Warlock" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Vine Growth" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FOREST_GUARDIAN_VINE_GROWTH">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 1st level, you can call nature to your aid. As an action, you can grow a magical spectral vine on a flat surface you can see within 30 feet of you.</p>
            <p class="indent">When you grow a vine, and as an action on subsequent turns, you can have it make a melee spell attack against a creature within 10 feet of it. On a hit, you choose to either have the vine deal 1d8 + your Charisma modifier piercing damage to the creature, or, if it is size Large or smaller, have the vine grapple it. A creature can use its action to make a Strength saving throw against your spell save DC to break this grapple. A vine can’t attack while it is grappling a creature.</p>
            <p class="indent">A vine withers and dies after one minute, or if you are more than 500 feet away from it. You can never have more vines active than your Charisma modifier (minimum of 1). You can dismiss one of your vines at any time (no action required).</p>
            <p class="indent">The number of vines you summon or have attack increases to 2 at 5th level, 3 at 11th level, and 4 at 17th level.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Action">
            <description level="1">You can grow a magical spectral vine on a flat surface you can see within 30 feet of you. As an action on subsequent turns, you can have it make a melee spell attack against a creature within 10 feet of it. You can choose to have the vine deal 1d8 + {{charisma:modifier}} piercing damage or, if it is size Large or smaller, to grapple it.</description>
            <description level="5">You can grow {{vine growth:count}} magical spectral vines on a flat surface you can see within 30 feet of you. As an action on subsequent turns, you can have them each make melee spell attacks against a creature within 10 feet of them. You can choose to have each of the vines deal 1d8 + {{charisma:modifier}} piercing damage or, if it is size Large or smaller, to grapple it.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="vine growth:count" value="2" level="5" />
            <stat name="vine growth:count" value="3" level="11" />
            <stat name="vine growth:count" value="4" level="17" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Bloom" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FOREST_GUARDIAN_BLOOM">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 6th level, as a reaction to an attack being made against you, you can grow large flower petals around yourself, which bloom at the start of your next turn. Until they bloom, you have three quarters cover and your movement speed is 0. When the petals bloom, they cover you in magical pollen, granting you advantage on saving throws against being frightened for the next minute.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t do so again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Short Rest" action="Reaction">
            <description>You can grow large flower petals around yourself, which bloom at the start of your next turn. Until they bloom, you have three quarters cover and your movement speed is 0. When the petals bloom, they cover you in magical pollen, granting you advantage on saving throws against being frightened for the next minute.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Heart of the Wild" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FOREST_GUARDIAN_HEART_OF_THE_WILD">
        <description>
            <p>Beginning at 10th level, your affinity with nature alters your life force. You gain resistance to poison damage and immunity to the poisoned condition. Whenever a creature you can see attempts to poison you, you can use your reaction to shoot poison back at it. The creature must succeed on a Constitution saving throw against your spell save DC or be poisoned until the end of its next turn.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Reaction">
            <description>When a creature attempts to poison you, you can shoot poison back at it. The creature must succeed on a Constitution saving throw (save DC {{spellcasting:dc}}) or be poisoned until the end of its next turn. You are also immune to the poisoned condition.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_POISON" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Constricting Forest" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FOREST_GUARDIAN_CONSTRICTING_FOREST">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 14th level, you can channel the forest itself. As an action, you can grow magical plants from beneath you, which last until the end of your next turn. These plants grow out 100 feet from you in all directions, spreading around corners. Creatures of your choice within this range take 4d10 poison damage and must succeed a Strength saving throw against your spell save DC or become restrained by the plants while they remain. The plants are difficult terrain for these creatures, but double your speed while you are within their range. Any creature reduced to 0 hit points while restrained by the plants is instantly killed and flowers begin to grow from their body.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest" action="Action">
            <description>You can grow magical plants from beneath you, which last until the end of your next turn. These plants grow out 100 feet from you in all directions, spreading around corners. Creatures of your choice within this range take 4d10 poison damage and must succeed a Strength saving throw (save DC {{spellcasting:dc}}) or become restrained by the plants while they remain. The plants are difficult terrain for these creatures, but double your speed while you are within their range. Any creature reduced to 0 hit points while restrained by the plants is instantly killed and flowers begin to grow from their body.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    
    <!-- Eldritch Invocations -->
    <element name="Living Flora" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_LIVING_FLORA">
        <supports>Eldritch Invocation, Pact of the Chain</supports>
        <prerequisite>The Forest Guadian patron, Pact of the Chain feature</prerequisite>
        <requirements>ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_PACT_BOON_PACT_OF_THE_CHAIN, ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FOREST_GUARDIAN_PATRON</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">The Forest Guadian patron, Pact of the Chain feature</p>
            <p>As an action, you can teleport to the nearest unoccupied space within 5 feet of one vine of your choice created by your Vine Growth feature. If your familiar is within 5 feet of you, it can teleport to an unoccupied space within 5 feet of you as well.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="Action">
            <description>Yyou can teleport to the nearest unoccupied space within 5 feet of one vine of your choice created by your <i>Vine Growth</i> feature. If your familiar is within 5 feet of you, it can teleport to an unoccupied space within 5 feet of you as well.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="Nature’s Shield" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_NATURES_SHIELD">
        <supports>Eldritch Invocation, Pact of the Blade</supports>
        <prerequisite>The Forest Guardian patron, Pact of the Blade feature</prerequisite>
        <requirements>ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FOREST_GUARDIAN_PATRON, ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_PACT_BOON_PACT_OF_THE_BLADE</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">The Forest Guardian patron, Pact of the Blade feature</p>
            <p>As a bonus action, if you are not wearing medium armor, heavy armor, or wielding a shield, you can grow a +1 magical shield made of vines and vegetation around your arm. You are proficient with this shield and you do not need a free hand to hold it as it wraps itself around your arm with vines. The shield lasts until you are incapacitated or until you dismiss it as a bonus action. It ends early if you done medium armor, heavy armor, or wield another shield. Whenever a creature misses you with a melee attack while you are wielding this shield, it takes poison damage equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum of 1).</p>
            <p class="indent">You can’t use this invocation to create more than one shield at a time.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Bonus Action">
            <description>If you are not wearing medium armor, heavy armor, or wielding a shield, you can grow a +1 magical shield made of vines and vegetation around your arm. Whenever a creature misses you with a melee attack while you are wielding this shield, it takes {{charisma:modifier}} hit points poison damage (minimum of 1). You may only create one shield at a time.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Primal Force" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_PRIMAL_FORCE">
        <supports>Eldritch Invocation, Pact of the Tome</supports>
        <prerequisite>The Forest Guardian patron, Pact of the Tome feature</prerequisite>
        <requirements>ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FOREST_GUARDIAN_PATRON, ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_PACT_BOON_PACT_OF_THE_TOME</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">The Forest Guardian patron, Pact of the Tome feature</p>
            <p>You gain proficiency in the Nature skill. While you are outside, you always know the distance and direction to the closest natural food and water sources.</p>
            <p class="indent">In addition, as an action, you can open your senses to the natural world and what invades it. For the next 10 minutes, you know the location of any magical plants and any constructs within 1 mile of you. Once you use feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Short Rest">
            <description>While you are outside, you always know the distance and direction to the closest natural food and water sources. As an action, you can open your senses to the natural world and for the next 10 minutes, you know the location of any magical plants and any constructs within 1 mile of you.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_NATURE" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Sending Tree" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_SENDING_TREE">
        <supports>Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>The Forest Guardian patron, 12th level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:12],ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FOREST_GUARDIAN_PATRON</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">The Forest Guardian patron, 12th level</p>
            <p>You can cast <i>transport via plants</i> once using a spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            <p class="indent">In addition, over the course of 10 minutes, you can grow a tree from a 10 foot square of fertile soil you are touching. The tree immediately grows to size Large, begins growing at a normal pace, and can’t be destroyed or moved except by magical means. When you can cast <i>transport via plants</i> using this invocation, you can do so without using a spell slot, as long as this tree is one of the plants linked. You regain the ability to do so again after you complete a long rest.</p>
            <p class="indent">If you grow another tree this way while one is already grown, the first tree loses all of the above benefits and becomes a normal nonmagical tree, and the new tree gains these benefits instead.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>You can cast <i>transport via plants</i> once using a spell slot. In addition, over the course of 10 minutes, you can grow a tree from a 10 foot square of fertile soil you are touching. The tree immediately grows to size Large, begins growing at a normal pace, and can’t be destroyed or moved except by magical means. When you can cast <i>transport via plants</i> using this invocation, you can do so without using a spell slot, as long as this tree is one of the plants linked.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    
</elements>