<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Dearly Departed Otherworldly Patron</name>
        <update version="0.0.2">
            <file name="warlock-dearly-departed.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/subclasses/warlock/warlock-dearly-departed.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Warlock: The Dearly Departed" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_FRENCHTECH16_GMBINDER_SOURCE_Warlock: The Dearly Departed">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation">TDDOP</set>
            <set name="url">https://www.gmbinder.com/share/-MB6wIWZsHsk8PUrUYui/-MBGNwIh_jCqpFbC3w8b</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" abbreviation="FT16" url="https://www.gmbinder.com/profile/frenchtech16">FrenchTech16</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20200820</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="The Dearly Departed" type="Archetype" source="Warlock: The Dearly Departed" id="ID_FT16_TDDOP_ARCHETYPE_WARLOCK_DEARLY_DEPARTED">
        <supports>Otherworldly Patron</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You have made a pact with the spirit of someone you loved, or with the god of death that was their jailor. This spirit’s soul has been returned to you in the mortal plane, and is referred to as your Dearly Departed. Your Dearly Departed can be anyone of great importance to you, who passed away with unfinished business. In exchange for being reunited with this spirit, you must pay with your vitality. For every year that your Dearly Departed’s soul is in the mortal plane with you, you lose a year of your own lifespan. Once the business of your Dearly Departed is concluded and they are at rest, their spirit will leave the mortal plane and return to their eternal grave.</p>
            <div element="ID_FT16_TDDOP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEARLY_DEPARTED_EXPANDED_SPELL_LIST" />
            <div element="ID_FT16_TDDOP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEARLY_DEPARTED_SPECTRAL_TRAINING" />
            <div element="ID_FT16_TDDOP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEARLY_DEPARTED_BITTERSWEET_MEMORIES" />
            <div element="ID_FT16_TDDOP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEARLY_DEPARTED_ONLY_A_SHADOW" />
            <div element="ID_FT16_TDDOP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEARLY_DEPARTED_RESTLESS_SOUL" />
            <div element="ID_FT16_TDDOP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEARLY_DEPARTED_ULTIMATE_SACRIFICE" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FT16_TDDOP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEARLY_DEPARTED_EXPANDED_SPELL_LIST" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FT16_TDDOP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEARLY_DEPARTED_SPECTRAL_TRAINING" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FT16_TDDOP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEARLY_DEPARTED_BITTERSWEET_MEMORIES" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FT16_TDDOP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEARLY_DEPARTED_ONLY_A_SHADOW" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FT16_TDDOP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEARLY_DEPARTED_RESTLESS_SOUL" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FT16_TDDOP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEARLY_DEPARTED_ULTIMATE_SACRIFICE" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Expanded Spell List" type="Archetype Feature" source="Warlock: The Dearly Departed" id="ID_FT16_TDDOP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEARLY_DEPARTED_EXPANDED_SPELL_LIST">
            <description>
                <p>Your pact with your Dearly Departed or their jailor allows you to choose from an expanded list of spells when you learn a warlock spell. The following spells are added to the warlock spell list for you.</p>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Spell Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1st</td><td><em>false life, sanctuary</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>2nd</td><td><em>gentle repose, warding bond</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>life transference, speak with dead</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>4th</td><td><em>banishment, death ward</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>antilife shell, raise dead</em></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <spellcasting name="Warlock" extend="true">
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_FALSE_LIFE</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_SANCTUARY</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_GENTLE_REPOSE</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_WARDING_BOND</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_LIFE_TRANSFERENCE</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_DEAD</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_BANISHMENT</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_DEATH_WARD</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_ANTILIFE_SHELL</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_RAISE_DEAD</extend>
            </spellcasting>
        </element>
        <element name="Spectral Training" type="Archetype Feature" source="Warlock: The Dearly Departed" id="ID_FT16_TDDOP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEARLY_DEPARTED_SPECTRAL_TRAINING">
            <description>
                <p>At 1st level, as their spirit now resides with you, your Dearly Departed shares some of the skills they learned during their life. Cantrips learned this way count as warlock cantrips for you, but they don’t count against your number of cantrips known. Choose one of the following presets to represent your Dearly Departed:</p>
                <ul class="unstyled">
                    <li><b>Jester.</b> You learn the vicious mockery and minor illusion cantrips. You can cast <i>Tasha’s hideous laughter</i> once with this feature and regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest.</li>
                    <li><b>Mage.</b> You learn two of the following cantrips: <i>acid splash</i>, <i>fire bolt</i>, <i>shocking grasp</i>, <i>poison spray</i>, <i>ray of frost</i>, or <i>thunderclap</i>. You additionally learn one of the following cantrips: <i>control flames</i>, <i>gust</i>, <i>mold earth</i>, or <i>shape water</i>.</li>
                    <li><b>Priest.</b> You learn the <i>sacred flame</i> and <i>spare the dying</i> cantrips. You can cast <i>shield of faith</i> once with this feature and regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest.</li>
                    <li><b>Thief</b>. You gain proficiency with one finesse or ranged martial weapon. Once per round, you can deal additional damage equal to half your level (rounded down, minimum of one) to one creature you hit with a weapon attack.</li>
                    <li><b>Warrior.</b> You gain proficiency with two melee martial weapons, or one martial weapon and shields. You also gain proficiency with medium armor.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Spectral Training" supports="Dearly Departed Spectral Training" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Jester" type="Archetype Feature" source="Warlock: The Dearly Departed" id="ID_FT16_TDDOP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DD_SPECTRAL_TRAINING_JESTER">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <supports>Dearly Departed Spectral Training</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>You learn the vicious mockery and minor illusion cantrips. You can cast <i>Tasha’s hideous laughter</i> once with this feature and regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                    <description>You can cast Tasha’s hideous laughter once with this feature.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_VICIOUS_MOCKERY" spellcasting="Warlock" known="true" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MINOR_ILLUSION" spellcasting="Warlock" known="true" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TASHAS_HIDEOUS_LAUGHTER" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Mage" type="Archetype Feature" source="Warlock: The Dearly Departed" id="ID_FT16_TDDOP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DD_SPECTRAL_TRAINING_MAGE">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <supports>Dearly Departed Spectral Training</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>You learn two of the following cantrips: <i>acid splash</i>, <i>fire bolt</i>, <i>shocking grasp</i>, <i>poison spray</i>, <i>ray of frost</i>, or <i>thunderclap</i>. You additionally learn one of the following cantrips: <i>control flames</i>, <i>gust</i>, <i>mold earth</i>, or <i>shape water</i>.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Spectral Training)" number="2" spellcasting="Warlock" known="true" supports="ID_PHB_SPELL_ACID_SPLASH|ID_PHB_SPELL_FIRE_BOLT|ID_PHB_SPELL_SHOCKING_GRASP|ID_PHB_SPELL_POSION_SPRAY|ID_PHB_SPELL_RAY_OF_FROST|ID_XGTE_SPELL_THUNDERCLAP" />
                    <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Spectral Training)" spellcasting="Warlock" known="true" supports="ID_XGTE_SPELL_CONTROL_FLAMES|ID_XGTE_SPELL_GUST|ID_XGTE_SPELL_MOLD_EARTH|ID_XGTE_SPELL_SHAPE_WATER" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Priest" type="Archetype Feature" source="Warlock: The Dearly Departed" id="ID_FT16_TDDOP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DD_SPECTRAL_TRAINING_PRIEST">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <supports>Dearly Departed Spectral Training</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>You learn the <i>sacred flame</i> and <i>spare the dying</i> cantrips. You can cast <i>shield of faith</i> once with this feature and regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>You can cast shield of faith once with this feature.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SACRED_FLAME" spellcasting="Warlock" known="true" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPARE_THE_DYING" spellcasting="Warlock" known="true" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHIELD_OF_FAITH" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Thief" type="Archetype Feature" source="Warlock: The Dearly Departed" id="ID_FT16_TDDOP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DD_SPECTRAL_TRAINING_THIEF">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <supports>Dearly Departed Spectral Training</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>You gain proficiency with one finesse or ranged martial weapon. Once per round, you can deal additional damage equal to half your level (rounded down, minimum of one) to one creature you hit with a weapon attack.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>Once per round, you can deal additional damage equal to half your level (rounded down, minimum of one) to one creature you hit with a weapon attack.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <select type="Proficiency" name="Weapon Proficiency, Spectral Training" supports="Weapon,(Finesse||(Ranged,Martial))" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Warrior" type="Archetype Feature" source="Warlock: The Dearly Departed" id="ID_FT16_TDDOP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DD_SPECTRAL_TRAINING_WARRIOR">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <supports>Dearly Departed Spectral Training</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>You gain proficiency with two melee martial weapons, or one martial weapon and shields. You also gain proficiency with medium armor.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_MEDIUM_ARMOR" />
                    <select type="Proficiency" name="Martial Proficiency, Spectral Training" number="2" supports="(Shield||(Martial, Melee))" />
                </rules>
            </element>
        <element name="Bittersweet Memories" type="Archetype Feature" source="Warlock: The Dearly Departed" id="ID_FT16_TDDOP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEARLY_DEPARTED_BITTERSWEET_MEMORIES">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 1st level, when you expend a warlock spell slot, your mind is flooded with memories of your Dearly Departed, and you gain temporary hit points equal to the spell slot expended.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you expend a warlock spell slot, you gain temporary hit points equal to the spell slot expended.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Only a Shadow" type="Archetype Feature" source="Warlock: The Dearly Departed" id="ID_FT16_TDDOP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEARLY_DEPARTED_ONLY_A_SHADOW">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, your Dearly Departed has been given enough vitality to manifest itself. You can cast <i>animate dead</i> as a 3rd-level spell without expending a spell slot once with this feature and regain the ability do so when you finish a long rest. When cast this way, you follow all the normal rules of the spell, with the following changes:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>You can only target a corpse in order to create zombie, and you cannot control more than one zombie at a time.</li>
                    <li>Once created, your Dearly Departed’s soul inhabits the zombie, transforming the corpse’s appearance into an exact replica of themselves when they were alive. As they take damage, they progressively appear to be more undead.</li>
                    <li>Despite their appearance, your dearly departed is not alive. Their chest may rise and fall and there is color to their face, but the corpse they inhabit draws no breath and is cold to the touch. When your undead servant dies, the corpse it inhabited returns to its original appearance.</li>
                </ul>
                <p>In addition, your undead servant has the personality and memory of your Dearly Departed. They are considered to be the same level as you, they can speak the languages they knew in life, and they have the following changes:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>They can equip and use the weapons and armor they are proficient with or the spells that they know, as displayed in the Spectral Training feature. They also have proficiency in light armor and 2 skills of your choice.</li>
                    <li>They use your spell DC and modifier when casting spells, and they use your Charisma modifier, instead of Dexterity or Strength, for weapon attack and damage rolls that they are proficient with.</li>
                    <li>Their spells deal one die less of damage, and their weapons are lowered one die value. For example, a Mage’s <i>fire bolt</i> now deals 1d10 at 6th level instead of 2d10, and a Warrior’s greataxe now deals 1d10 instead of 1d12.</li>
                    <li>At 6th level, their health is 6d8 (27). Every time you gain a level, their health increases by 1d8 hit points.</li>
                    <li>Upon creating your zombie, you can choose to switch their Strength and Dexterity scores. You can also choose an attribute among the following: Wisdom, Intelligence, and Charisma. That attribute score becomes a 14.</li>
                </ul>
                <p>If you do not recast <i>animate dead</i> after 24 hours, or if you lose control of your undead summon, your Dearly Departed’s spirit will be forcibly ripped from the corpse, and it returns to being a usual zombie.</p>
                <div class="sidebar">
                    <p>Optional rule: For aesthetic purposes or to make life easier on your DM, you can choose to not have your undead servant be able to speak, or only speak in short, garbled phrases. Perhaps once your undead servant is a ghoul at 10th level, they can speak more clearly, or maybe you need to rely on speak with dead. That decision is up to your table.</p>
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You can cast animate dead as a 3rd-level spell without expending a spell slot. You can only target a corpse in order to create zombie, and you cannot control more than one zombie at a time. Once created, your Dearly Departed’s soul inhabits the zombie, transforming the corpse’s appearance into an exact replica of themselves when they were alive. Their health is {{level:warlock}}d8 hit points.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Restless Soul" type="Archetype Feature" source="Warlock: The Dearly Departed" id="ID_FT16_TDDOP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEARLY_DEPARTED_RESTLESS_SOUL">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 10th level, when you use your Only a Shadow feature, you now raise a ghoul, instead of a zombie, as your undead servant. This ghoul retains its previous benefits, including the zombie’s special trait: Undead Fortitude.</p>
                <p class="indent">Your undead servant also gain an additional benefit based on the preset you chose in your Spectral Training feature:</p>
                <ul class="unstyled">
                    <li><b>Jester.</b> Once per long rest, they can give them themselves advantage on any attack roll, saving throw, or ability check. They can use this ability after the original roll, but before the outcome is revealed.</li>
                    <li><b>Mage.</b> When they cast one of their Spectral Training cantrips, they add your Charisma modifier to the damage it deals.</li>
                    <li><b>Priest.</b> They gain resistance to radiant and necrotic damage. When they cast spare the dying to stabilize a dying creature, the stabilized creature also regains 1 hit point.</li>
                    <li><b>Thief.</b> They learn a Fighting Style from the Ranger’s list. They can’t take a fighting style more than once.</li>
                    <li><b>Warrior.</b> They learn a Fighting Style from the Paladin’s list. They can’t take a fighting style more than once.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you use your Only a Shadow feature, you now raise a ghoul, instead of a zombie, as your undead servant. This ghoul retains its previous benefits, including the zombie’s special trait: Undead Fortitude.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FT16_TDDOP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DD_RESTLESS_SOUL_JESTER" requirements="ID_FT16_TDDOP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DD_SPECTRAL_TRAINING_JESTER" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FT16_TDDOP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DD_RESTLESS_SOUL_MAGE" requirements="ID_FT16_TDDOP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DD_SPECTRAL_TRAINING_MAGE" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FT16_TDDOP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DD_RESTLESS_SOUL_PRIEST" requirements="ID_FT16_TDDOP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DD_SPECTRAL_TRAINING_PRIEST" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FT16_TDDOP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DD_RESTLESS_SOUL_THIEF" requirements="ID_FT16_TDDOP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DD_SPECTRAL_TRAINING_THIEF" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FT16_TDDOP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DD_RESTLESS_SOUL_WARRIOR" requirements="ID_FT16_TDDOP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DD_SPECTRAL_TRAINING_WARRIOR" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Jester Restless Soul" type="Archetype Feature" source="Warlock: The Dearly Departed" id="ID_FT16_TDDOP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DD_RESTLESS_SOUL_JESTER">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>Once per long rest, they can give themselves advantage on any attack roll, saving throw, or ability check. They can use this ability after the original roll, but before the outcome is revealed.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                    <description>Your departed can give themself advantage on any attack roll, saving throw, or ability check. They can use this ability after the original roll, but before the outcome is revealed.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Mage Restless Soul" type="Archetype Feature" source="Warlock: The Dearly Departed" id="ID_FT16_TDDOP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DD_RESTLESS_SOUL_MAGE">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>When they cast one of their Spectral Training cantrips, they add your Charisma modifier to the damage it deals.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>When your departed casts one of their Spectral Training cantrips, they add {{charisma:modifier}} to the damage it deals.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Priest Restless Soul" type="Archetype Feature" source="Warlock: The Dearly Departed" id="ID_FT16_TDDOP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DD_RESTLESS_SOUL_PRIEST">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>They gain resistance to radiant and necrotic damage. When they cast <i>spare the dying</i> to stabilize a dying creature, the stabilized creature also regains 1 hit point.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>Your departed has resistance to radiant and necrotic damage. When they cast spare the dying to stabilize a dying creature, the stabilized creature also regains 1 hit point.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Thief Restless Soul" type="Archetype Feature" source="Warlock: The Dearly Departed" id="ID_FT16_TDDOP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DD_RESTLESS_SOUL_THIEF">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>They learn a Fighting Style from the Ranger’s list. They can’t take a fighting style more than once.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet alt="Departed Fighting Style">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <select type="Class Feature" name="Fighting Style, Restless Soul" supports="Fighting Style, Ranger" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Warrior Restless Soul" type="Archetype Feature" source="Warlock: The Dearly Departed" id="ID_FT16_TDDOP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DD_RESTLESS_SOUL_WARRIOR">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>They learn a Fighting Style from the Paladin’s list. They can’t take a fighting style more than once.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet alt="Departed Fighting Style">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <select type="Class Feature" name="Fighting Style, Restless Soul" supports="Fighting Style, Paladin" />
                </rules>
            </element>
        <element name="Ultimate Sacrifice" type="Archetype Feature" source="Warlock: The Dearly Departed" id="ID_FT16_TDDOP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEARLY_DEPARTED_ULTIMATE_SACRIFICE">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 14th level, when you would fail your last death saving throw, if your Dearly Departed is inhabiting your undead servant, they immediately sacrifice themselves, losing all their hit points and disintegrating. You are stabilized and heal an amount equal to half the hit points your undead servant lost this way (rounded down, minimum of one).</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a long rest. </p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>When you would fail your last death saving throw, if your Dearly Departed is inhabiting your undead servant, they immediately sacrifice themselves, losing all their hit points and disintegrating. You are stabilized and heal an amount equal to half the hit points your undead servant lost this way (rounded down, minimum of one).</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>


</elements>