<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>KibblesTasty’s Plant Spells</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="spells-plant-spells.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/kibblestasty/spells-plant-spells.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Kibbles’ Plant Spells" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_KIBBLESTASTY_GMBINDER_SOURCE_KIBBLES_PLANT_SPELLS">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation">PS</set>
            <set name="url">https://www.gmbinder.com/share/-Mekwj2YyvP6EhLfW7hY</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" abbreviation="KT" url="https://www.gmbinder.com/profile/kibblestasty">KibblesTasty</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20210727</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Sprout Tree" type="Spell" source="Kibbles’ Plant Spells" id="ID_KT_PS_SPELL_SPROUT_TREE">
        <supports>Druid</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Targeting a 5 foot square on the ground within range, you cause a tree to sprout from the ground, growing rapidly to 20 feet tall with a 2 foot radius trunk. A Large or smaller creature in this space must make a Dexerity saving throw. On failure, they are lifted 20 feet into the air in the branches of the tree; the tree stops growing if it would hit a ceiling or other object when growing. On a success, they can move 5 feet to an occupied space of their choice (if there is no space they can move, they automatically fail). A creature can choose to fail their saving throw. A Huge or large creature automatically passes their save.</p>
            <p class="indent">The tree serves as half cover to any creature within its branches, and three quarters cover from attacks originated on the other side of its trunk. This spell can only target a surface through with a tree could grow (for example, you could not target solid rock). At the DMs discretion, it can burst through up to 6 inches of most material. The tree has an AC of 13 and 50 hit points.</p>
            <p class="indent">The tree remains there, but may die rapidly if sprouted in unsuitable location or environment. It’s wood is flammable only when dried, and serves no useful purpose other than firewood.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">transmutation</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">30 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Bramble Binding" type="Spell" source="Kibbles’ Plant Spells" id="ID_KT_PS_SPELL_BRAMBLE_BINDING">
        <supports>Druid, Ranger</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Brambles burst from your hand, lashing out a target within range. The target must make a Dexterity saving throw. On failure, they take 4d4 piercing damage, and if the target is Large or smaller, it becomes entangled by brambles. While entangled by brambles it cannot move, but it can free itself as as an action (taking no additional damage) or rip itself free using half of its movement and taking an additional 2d4 piecing damage. On a successful save they take half as much damage and are not entangled by brambles.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, both the initial damage and the damage taken ripping free of the brambles increases by 1d4 for each slot level above 1st.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">transmutation</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">30 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Grasping Roots" type="Spell" source="Kibbles’ Plant Spells" id="ID_KT_PS_SPELL_GRASPING_ROOTS">
        <supports>Druid, Ranger</supports>
        <description>
            <p>A twisting burst of roots launch from your hand reaching to grab a Large or smaller target. The target must make a Strength saving throw. On success, the target is moved 5 feet in a direction of your choice. On a failure, the target is moved 20 feet in a direction of your choice. A creature can choose to fail this save.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, you move a creature an additional 5 feet for each slot level above 1st.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">transmutation</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">30 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Bramble Barrier" type="Spell" source="Kibbles’ Plant Spells" id="ID_KT_PS_SPELL_BRAMBLE_BARRIER">
        <supports>Druid, Ranger</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You create a line of brambles that erupts within range This line is 30 feet long and 5 feet wide, made of up of six 5-foot squares of brambles. Each patch much connect to another patch and be placed on the ground. The bramble patches are difficult terrain and a creature that enters a square of brambles takes 4d4 piecing damage and must make a Constitution saving throw. On failure, their speed drops to zero.</p>
            <p class="indent">The brambles wither and die after 1 day if the area is not suitable for them to grow. Each 5-foot-square portion of brambles requires at least 1 minute to clear by hand, or can be cleared if they take 5 or more fire damage. The brambles crumble to dust immediately if you cast this spell again.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, you can create two additional 5-foot squares of brambles for each slot level above 3rd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">transmutation</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Carnivorous Garden" type="Spell" source="Kibbles’ Plant Spells" id="ID_KT_PS_SPELL_CARNIVOROUS_GARDEN">
        <supports>Druid</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Targeting four empty spaces within range, rooted carnivorous plants erupt from the ground, filling a 5 foot cube each. Terrain within 5 feet of them becomes difficult terrain. When the plants appear, they attack a creature of your choice within 5 feet of them. Make a melee spell attack, dealing 2d8 piercing damage on hit. Each plant can make one attack.</p>
            <p class="indent">If a creature ends their turn within 5 feet of one of the carnivorous plants, it automatically attacks them unless you use reaction to prevent it from doing so. It uses your spell attack modifier, an deals 2d8 piercing damage on hit.</p>
            <p class="indent">The plants have an AC 14 and 30 hit points, and have vulnerability to slashing and fire damage. If they have 1 or more hit points, they magically regenerate to full hit points at the start of your turn. When the spell ends the plants wither and die leaving behind difficult terrain unless they were killed be fire damage.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, you can summon 1 additional carnivorous plant per spell level.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">4</set>
            <set name="school">trasmutation</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self (60 ft)</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a dried carnivorous plant</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 muinte.</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Summon Plant" type="Spell" source="Kibbles’ Plant Spells" id="ID_KT_PS_SPELL_SUMMON_PLANT">
        <supports>Druid</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The creature is an ally to you and your companions. In combat, the creature shares your initiative count, but it takes its turn immediately after yours. It obeys your verbal commands (no action required by you). If you don’t issue any, it takes the Dodge action and uses its move to avoid danger.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, use the higher level wherever the spell’s level appears in the stat block.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">conjuration</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">90 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">(a carved wooden figurine worth at least 300 gp</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 hour.</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
</elements>