<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name></name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="class-keeper.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/classes/class-keeper/class-keeper.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="The Keeper" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_GM_BINDER_SOURCE_The Keeper">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p>The Keeper is a class for connecting with an otherworldly creature, and forming a relationship with the spirits of the world.</p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation"></set>
            <set name="url">https://www.gmbinder.com/share/-LGluXzbqcd8QtFr48As</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" url="https://www.gmbinder.com/profile/notthesmoooze">NotTheSmooze</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20200129</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Keeper" type="Class" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_CLASS_KEEPER">
        <description>
            <p>Standing not quite alone in the centre of a gloomy woodland glade, a human parts the mists surrounding them with the head of their sceptre, demanding the knowledge of the forest spirits for the third and  inal time. The command takes hold, and the human falls perfectly still as their mind is seized by a vision. Suspecting vulnerability, a powerful beast spirit steps into the glade, eager to make the interloper regret their brazen attitude, but before it can strike, a formless shroud of shock-white frost coalesces into the shape of a knight bearing sword and shield, ready to defend its master.</p>
            <p class="indent">Hand grasped tightly around the leash locked to their companion’s neck, a tie ling makes slow, con ident strides towards their foe, the hellhound bound to them growling all the while, spitting sparks and cinders from the gaps between its jagged teeth. The dog’s spine arches, and it howls, loud and angry. The tie ling barks an order as their body is  illed with infernal vigor, burning spirits crawling under their skin. In an instant, the leash is dropped, their companion blitzing towards the nearest enemy with hate in its eyes, its master close behind.</p>
            <p class="indent">Islands of calm in an ocean of chaos, two partners dance to a symphony only they can hear, the violence surrounding them seeming all the quieter for the bond they share. A whirling stormcloud bound into humanoid shape by scorched rags and bandages envelops their genasi companion, and a crack of lightning strikes the ground at their feet. Where two figures once stood, a blue-skinned giant clutching a thunderbolt readies themselves for battle, veins pulsing with electric blue light, and the dance continues.</p>
            <p class="indent">Keepers and their companions are a living gate between the magical and the mundane, de ined by their bond to each other and the covenant they form. Wielding esoteric magic, they exert their will on the world by commanding the tiny unseen spirits and connections that permeate the multiverse, drawing on that power to summon otherworldly beings, bind the wills of others, discover hidden secrets, and make their voices heard.</p>
            <h4>MODEST MAGIC</h4>
            <p>Seven gods live in every grain of rice. A thousand more live in every meal, and a thousand thousand more than that in every home. Such is the wisdom of a keeper. Where many spellcasters call forth their power from within or channel energy from a higher being, keepers engross themselves in the spirits of place near and dear to wherever they might be, forming relationships with them—whether their bond be gentle, domineering, or outright hostile—and calling on them for strength.</p>
            <p class="indent">In this way, keepers captivate the world’s attention, and in turn, its power. They must be careful, however, to avoid the opposite. A keeper can earn much favour from spirits by making bold declarations of their nature and intent, and lose it just as quickly by breaking their promises. As such, keepers are wise enough to say what they mean, at least while the universe is listening. After all, life is a challenge when the whole world is against you, but when all creation is on your side, you couldn’t ask for a more powerful ally.</p>
            <h4>OPEN THE GATE</h4>
            <p>All things must come to dust. Each and every mortal will one day suffer the ravages of time, be withered by age, injury, sickness, or malice. Even immortals must fall in the end, coming to nothing, or simply fading, forgotten. Spirits, less grounded in reality, know this truth all too well. Rarely, these spirit-beings might even slip from the world entirely, falling between the cracks as they lose their grip on the objects and places which anchor them.</p>
            <p class="indent">Rather than vanish, however, a number of these beings  ind a semblance of life in the form of a covenant, a compact sealed with a mortal, binding the pair together, sharing the lives they possess with one another. In this way, the spirit acts as a gate to the magical world, allowing their mortal partner to immerse themselves in things unearthly and occult, while the mortal acts as a gate to the mundane, the material, through which the spirit might  lee the jaws of oblivion.</p>
            <h4>CREATING A KEEPER</h4>
            <p>As you create your keeper, you must ask yourself two questions above all others: what is your companion, and what are they to you? Did you  ind and care for a newborn creature or egg, only to be surprised when it later declared itself your companion? Were you in danger, and saved by forming a bond with your companion, or did you hunt, tame, and bring a spirit being to heel, forcing it to serve you?</p>
            <p class="indent">Your companion’s nature has great effect on your bond. Are they a celestial spirit who came to you in a moment of need, in return for your aid spreading their in luence? Did you trick a fiend into your service, wielding its true name like a leash? Or did you bargain with a fey, earning its teachings in exchange for some strange sacri ice you would later regret? Perhaps you even created your companion, raising them from death or hosting a spirit within a body of your own construction.</p>
            <p class="indent">Consider also your magical abilities. Your bond is the source of your power, but how develop your mystical knowledge? Were you taught by your family, following ages old tradition, or did your companion tutor you in the workings of your new powers? Perhaps you still don’t truly understand the rules, simply figuring them out as you plunge ever deeper into the occult.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">QUICK BUILD</h5>
            <p>You can make a keeper quickly by following these suggestions. First, make Strength or Dexterity your highest ability score if you plan to focus on martial combat, or Charisma if you’d rather prioritize your occult talents. Second, choose the hermit or sage background. Third, follow the guide to creating your companion detailed at the end of the class description.</p>
            <h2>CLASS FEATURES</h2>
            <p>As a keeper, you gain the following class features.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">HIT POINTS</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Hit Dice:</strong> 1d8 per keeper level</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at 1st Level:</strong> 8 + your Constitution modifier</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at Higher Levels:</strong> 1d8 (or 5) + your Constitution modifier per keeper level after 1st</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">PROFICIENCIES</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled mb">
                <li><strong>Armor:</strong> Light armour, medium armour, shields</li>
                <li><strong>Weapons:</strong> Simple weapons, martial weapons</li>
                <li><strong>Tools:</strong> None</li>
            </ul>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Saving Throws:</strong> Constitution, Charisma</li>
                <li><strong>Skills:</strong> Choose two from Animal Handling, Arcana, History, Insight, Intimidation, Medicine, Perception, Performance, Persuasion, and Religion</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">EQUIPMENT</h5>
            <p>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>(a) a martial weapon and a shield or (b) two martial weapons</li>
                <li>(a) a light crossbow and 20 bolts or (b) three daggers</li>
                <li>(a) leather armour or (b) scale mail</li>
                <li>(a) an explorer’s pack or (b) a priest’s pack</li>
                <li>An esoteric implement</li>
            </ul>
            <p class="indent">Alternatively, you can start with 5d4 x 10 gp and spend it on items from Chapter 5 of the <em>Player’s Handbook</em>.</p>
            <div class="reference">
                <h5 class="caption">Multiclassing</h5>
                <p>The prerequisite for multiclassing as a keeper is a Strength or Dexterity score of 13 and a Charisma score of 13. When you multiclass into keeper, you gain proficiency in light armour, medium armour, shields, simple weapons, and martial weapons. When determining your total spell slots, you add one half of your keeper levels (rounded down) to the total.</p>
            </div>
			<h5 class="caption">THE class</h5>
            <table class="class-features">
                <thead>
                    <tr><th class="col-5">Level</th><th>Proficiency Bonus</th><th class="left">Features</th><th>1st</th><th>2nd</th><th>3rd</th><th>4th</th><th>5th</th></tr>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                    <tr><td>1st</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Bound Companion, Occultist’s Seal, Gate of Rest</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>2nd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Awakened Sight, Spellcasting</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Gate of Battle, Spirit Covenant</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>4th</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Spirit Covenant feature</td><td>4</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>6th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Awakened Sight improvement, Practitioner’s Font</td><td>4</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>7th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Spirit Covenant feature</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>8th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">—</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>10th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Gate of Travel</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>11th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Spirit Covenant feature</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>12th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>13th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">—</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>1</td><td>—</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>14th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Witch Gate (5th level)</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>1</td><td>—</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>15th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Retribution</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>16th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>17th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Witch Gate (6th level)</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>1</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>18th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Spirit Covenant feature</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>1</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>19th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>20th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Witch Gate (7th level), World Gate</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td></tr>
                </tbody>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_CLASS_FEATURE_KEEPER_BOUND_COMPANION" />
            <div element="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_CLASS_FEATURE_KEEPER_OCCULTISTS_SEAL" />
            <div element="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_CLASS_FEATURE_KEEPER_GATE_OF_REST" />
            <div element="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_CLASS_FEATURE_KEEPER_AWAKENED_SIGHT" />
            <div element="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_CLASS_FEATURE_KEEPER_SPELLCASTING" />
            <div element="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_CLASS_FEATURE_KEEPER_GATE_OF_BATTLE" />
            <div element="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_CLASS_FEATURE_KEEPER_SPIRIT_COVENANT" />
            <div element="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_CLASS_FEATURE_KEEPER_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" />
            <div element="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_CLASS_FEATURE_KEEPER_PRACTITIONERS_FONT" />
            <div element="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_CLASS_FEATURE_KEEPER_GATE_OF_TRAVEL" />
            <div element="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_CLASS_FEATURE_KEEPER_WITCH_GATE" />
            <div element="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_CLASS_FEATURE_KEEPER_RETRIBUTION" />
            <div element="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_CLASS_FEATURE_KEEPER_WORLD_GATE" />
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="hd">d8</set>
            <set name="short">A class that connects with an otherworldly creature, and forms a relationship with the spirits of the world.</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_MEDIUM_ARMOR" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_SHIELDS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_MARTIAL_WEAPONS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CONSTITUTION" requirements="!ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_MULTICLASS_KEEPER" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CHARISMA" requirements="!ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_MULTICLASS_KEEPER" />
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency, Keeper" supports="Keeper" number="2" requirements="!ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_MULTICLASS_KEEPER" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_CLASS_FEATURE_KEEPER_BOUND_COMPANION" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_CLASS_FEATURE_KEEPER_OCCULTISTS_SEAL" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_CLASS_FEATURE_KEEPER_GATE_OF_REST" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_CLASS_FEATURE_KEEPER_AWAKENED_SIGHT" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_CLASS_FEATURE_KEEPER_SPELLCASTING" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_CLASS_FEATURE_KEEPER_GATE_OF_BATTLE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_CLASS_FEATURE_KEEPER_SPIRIT_COVENANT" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_CLASS_FEATURE_KEEPER_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" level="4" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_CLASS_FEATURE_KEEPER_PRACTITIONERS_FONT" level="6" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_CLASS_FEATURE_KEEPER_GATE_OF_TRAVEL" level="10" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_CLASS_FEATURE_KEEPER_WITCH_GATE" level="14" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_CLASS_FEATURE_KEEPER_RETRIBUTION" level="15" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_CLASS_FEATURE_KEEPER_WORLD_GATE" level="20" />
        </rules>
        <multiclass id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_MULTICLASS_KEEPER">
            <prerequisite>Strength or Dexterity 13, Charisma 13</prerequisite>
            <requirements>([str:13]||[dex:13]),[cha:13]</requirements>
            <setters>
                <set name="multiclass proficiencies">Light armor, medium armor, shields, simple weapons and martial weapons.</set>
            </setters>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS" />
            </rules>
        </multiclass>
    </element>
        <element name="Bound Companion" type="Class Feature" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_CLASS_FEATURE_KEEPER_BOUND_COMPANION">
            <description>
                <p>By 1st level, you have completed a ritual, binding you and another creature together.</p>
                <p class="indent">You decide your bound companion’s statistics using the guide detailed at the end of the class description.</p>
                <p class="indent">If your bound companion is ever slain, the connection between you is tested. You take necrotic damage equal to twice your character level. This damage ignores resistance and immunity, and reduces your hit point maximum by an amount equal to the damage taken (to a minimum of 1) which lasts until you finish a long rest.</p>
                <p class="indent">If you finish a long rest while your bound companion is slain, your bond inevitably draws you back together. At the end of the long rest, your companion reforms near to you, having gained the benefits of a long rest, in a manner appropriate to its nature. A fire elemental might be reborn in a bonfire, while a ghost might simply arrive with a cold wind.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>If your bound companion is ever slain, the connection between you is tested. You take {{bound-companion:necrotic-damage}} necrotic damage. This damage reduces your hit point maximum, which lasts until you finish a long rest.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="bound-companion:necrotic-damage" value="level" />
                <stat name="bound-companion:necrotic-damage" value="level" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Occultist’s Seal" type="Class Feature" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_CLASS_FEATURE_KEEPER_OCCULTISTS_SEAL">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 1st level, the binding placed upon your companion grounds it in reality, tying it to the material world. This more physical presence grants it a number of benefits.</p>
                <p class="indent">Your companion obeys your commands as best it can. It takes its turn on your initiative, and you determine its actions, decisions, attitudes, and so on. If you are incapacitated or absent, your companion acts on its own.</p>
                <p class="indent">Your companion’s anchoring in this world is fledgling. As a result, it can’t attack until you reach 3rd level in this class.</p>
                <p class="indent">Your companion has features and game statistics determined in part by your level. Your companion uses your proficiency bonus rather than its own.</p>
                <p class="indent">Your companion gains no benefit from armour or weapons, whether or not it is physically capable of using them. Your companion has a natural armour class of 12 + your proficiency bonus.</p>
                <p class="indent">For each keeper level after 1st, your companion gains an additional Hit Die and increases its hit points accordingly. Your companion’s Hit Dice are d8s, regardless of its size. When your companion is reduced to 0 hit points, it makes death saving throws as a player character would.</p>
                <p class="indent">Your companion’s level is equal to your keeper level for the purpose of spells and features like <em>polymorph</em> and <em>true polymorph</em>.</p>
                <p class="indent">Whenever you gain the Ability Score Improvement class feature, your companion’s abilities also improve. Your companion can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or it can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, your companion can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature unless its description specifies otherwise.</p>
                <p class="indent">You decide your companion’s alignment and ideal. At your option, you can pick from or roll on the the tables below to determine its traits and flaws. Its bond is always "I must protect my keeper. We are greater together than alone."</p>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>d4</td><td>Trait</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1</td><td>My keeper is mortal, and mortals are frail. It’s my job to keep them safe.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>2</td><td>I show affection by making threats.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3</td><td>I hoard any valuables I can find.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>4</td><td>My keeper is the only family I’ve ever known. I trust them absolutely.</td></tr>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>d4</td><td>Flaw</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1</td><td>Dogs bark while I’m near, and cats never trust me.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>2</td><td>I’m jealous of anyone too close to my keeper.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3</td><td>I’m loathe to explain what’s obvious to a spirit being like myself.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>4</td><td>Flaw? What flaws?</td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Your companion uses your proficiency bonus rather than its own.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Gate of Rest" type="Class Feature" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_CLASS_FEATURE_KEEPER_GATE_OF_REST">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 1st level, your companion can retreat to a pocket dimension, a private domain of your creation. As an action, you can temporarily dismiss your companion. It disappears into this domain, where it awaits your call. As an action while it is temporarily dismissed, you can cause your companion to reappear in any unoccupied space within 30 feet of you.</p>
                <p class="indent">Your companion leaves this domain if you die, and can’t return unless you are resurrected.</p>
                <div class="sidebar">
                    <h5 class="caption">Variant: Gate of Disguise</h5>
                    <p>If you’d rather your companion blend in than hide, your Dungeon Master might allow this variant feature, which replaces the Gate of Rest feature.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><strong><em>Gate of Disguise.</em></strong> At 1st level, choose a Small or smaller beast. Your companion can use its action to polymorph into the guise of that beast, or back into its true form. While polymorphed, none of your companion’s statistics change. Your companion remains disguised until it takes an action or reaction.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Your companion’s guise must resemble your companion in some way. For example, a monstrous horned wolf might take the form of an unusually ferocious dog.</p>
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>You can temporarily dismiss your companion to a pocket dimension or summon it from this same dimension, causing your companion to reappear in any unoccupied space within 30 feet of you.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Awakened Sight" type="Class Feature" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_CLASS_FEATURE_KEEPER_AWAKENED_SIGHT">
            <description>
                <p>At 2nd level, your eyes open, ripples of magic and intent now visible to your sight. When you make an Arcana, Investigation, Perception, or Survival check, you can add half your Charisma modifier (rounded up, minimum of 1) to the result.</p>
                <p class="indent">Starting at 6th level, you instead add your Charisma modifier (minimum of 1).</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you make an Arcana, Investigation, Perception, or Survival check, you can add half your Charisma modifier (rounded up, minimum of 1) to the result.</description>
                <description level="6">When you make an Arcana, Investigation, Perception, or Survival check, you can add {{awakened-sight:charisma-mod}} to the result.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="awakened-sight:charisma-mod" value="1" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="awakened-sight:charisma-mod" value="charisma:modifier" bonus="base" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Spellcasting" type="Class Feature" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_CLASS_FEATURE_KEEPER_SPELLCASTING">
            <description>
                <p>By 2nd level, you’ve earned the attention of the world around you, and established yourself as a force of change. See Chapter 10 of the <em>Player’s Handbook</em> for the general rules of spellcasting and the end of this document for the Keeper spell list.</p>
                <h5>PREPARING AND CASTING SPELLS</h5>
                <p>The Keeper table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your spells. To cast one of your keeper spells of 1st level or higher, you must expend a slot of the spell’s level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.</p>
                <p class="indent">You prepare the list of keeper spells that are available for you to cast, choosing from the keeper spell list. When you do so, choose a number of keeper spells equal to your Charisma modifier + your keeper level (minimum of one spell). The spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots.</p>
                <p class="indent">For example, if you are a 5th-level keeper, you have four 1st-level and two 2nd-level spell slots. With a Charisma of 14, your list of prepared spells can include seven spells of 1st or 2nd-level, in any combination. If you prepare the 1st-level spell command, you can cast it using a 1st-level or a 2nd-level slot. Casting the spell doesn’t remove it from your list of prepared spells.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can change your list of prepared spells when you finish a long rest. Preparing a new list of keeper spells requires time spent bonding with the spirits surrounding you: at least 1 minute per spell level for each spell on your list.</p>
                <h5>SPELLCASTING ABILITY</h5>
                <p>Charisma is your spellcasting ability for your keeper spells, since their power comes from your ability to command the world around you. You use your Charisma whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Charisma modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a keeper spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.</p>
                <center>
                    <p><strong>Spell save DC</strong> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier</p>
                    <p><strong>Spell attack modifier</strong> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier</p>
                </center>
                <h5>RITUAL CASTING</h5>
                <p>You can cast a keeper spell as a ritual if that spell has the ritual tag and you have the spell prepared.</p>
                <h5>SPELLCASTING FOCUS</h5>
                <p>You can use an esoteric implement (detailed at the end of this document) as a spellcasting focus for your keeper spells.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <spellcasting name="Keeper" ability="Charisma" prepare="true">
                <list known="true">Keeper</list>
            </spellcasting>
            <rules>
    			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS_SPELLCASTING_SLOTS_HALF" requirements="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS"/>
                <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_RITUAL_CASTING" />
                <!-- <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_INTERNAL_PROFICIENCY_SPELLFOCUS_GROUP_ESOTERIC_IMPLEMENT" /> -->
                <stat name="keeper:spellcasting:slots:1" value="2" level="2" />
                <stat name="keeper:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="3" />
                <stat name="keeper:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="5" />
                <stat name="keeper:spellcasting:slots:2" value="2" level="5" />
                <stat name="keeper:spellcasting:slots:2" value="1" level="7" />
                <stat name="keeper:spellcasting:slots:3" value="2" level="9" />
                <stat name="keeper:spellcasting:slots:3" value="1" level="11" />
                <stat name="keeper:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="13" />
                <stat name="keeper:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="15" />
                <stat name="keeper:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="17" />
                <stat name="keeper:spellcasting:slots:5" value="1" level="17" />
                <stat name="keeper:spellcasting:slots:5" value="1" level="19" />
                <stat name="keeper:spellcasting:prepare" value="charisma:modifier" />
                <stat name="keeper:spellcasting:prepare" value="level:keeper" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Gate of Battle" type="Class Feature" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_CLASS_FEATURE_KEEPER_GATE_OF_BATTLE">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 3rd level, your companion has grown in power, further grounding itself, and can now attack.</p>
                <p class="indent">Choose one of the following damage types: acid, bludgeoning, cold, fire, force, lightning, necrotic, piercing, poison, psychic, radiant, slashing, or thunder. Whenever a feature refers to your companion’s damage type, you use this damage type.</p>
                <p class="indent">Your companion gains an attack option that it can use with the Attack action. This attack is a melee spell attack with a range of 5 feet. Your companion is proficient with this attack, and can add its Strength, Dexterity, Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma modifier to its attack and damage rolls. Its damage is your companion’s damage type, and its damage die is a d6.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Your companion can now make a melee spell attack with a range of 5 feet and does 1d6 {{companion-damage:type}} damage when it attacks. Your companion is proficient with this attack.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Companion Damage Type" supports="Keeper Companion Damage" level="3" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="acid" type="Class Feature" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMPANION_DAMAGE_ACID">
                <supports>Keeper Companion Damage</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>Your companion does acid damage on a successful attack.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false"/>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="companion-damage:type" inline="true" value="acid" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="bludgeoning" type="Class Feature" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMPANION_DAMAGE_BLUDGEONING">
                <supports>Keeper Companion Damage</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>Your companion does bludgeoning damage on a successful attack.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false"/>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="companion-damage:type" inline="true" value="bludgeoning" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="cold" type="Class Feature" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMPANION_DAMAGE_COLD">
                <supports>Keeper Companion Damage</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>Your companion does cold damage on a successful attack.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false"/>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="companion-damage:type" inline="true" value="cold" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="fire" type="Class Feature" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMPANION_DAMAGE_FIRE">
                <supports>Keeper Companion Damage</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>Your companion does fire damage on a successful attack.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false"/>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="companion-damage:type" inline="true" value="fire" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="force" type="Class Feature" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMPANION_DAMAGE_FORCE">
                <supports>Keeper Companion Damage</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>Your companion does force damage on a successful attack.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false"/>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="companion-damage:type" inline="true" value="force" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="lightning" type="Class Feature" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMPANION_DAMAGE_LIGHTNING">
                <supports>Keeper Companion Damage</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>Your companion does lightning damage on a successful attack.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false"/>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="companion-damage:type" inline="true" value="lightning" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="necrotic" type="Class Feature" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMPANION_DAMAGE_NECROTIC">
                <supports>Keeper Companion Damage</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>Your companion does necrotic damage on a successful attack.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false"/>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="companion-damage:type" inline="true" value="necrotic" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="piercing" type="Class Feature" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMPANION_DAMAGE_PIERCING">
                <supports>Keeper Companion Damage</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>Your companion does piercing damage on a successful attack.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false"/>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="companion-damage:type" inline="true" value="piercing" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="poison" type="Class Feature" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMPANION_DAMAGE_POISON">
                <supports>Keeper Companion Damage</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>Your companion does poison damage on a successful attack.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false"/>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="companion-damage:type" inline="true" value="poison" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="psychic" type="Class Feature" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMPANION_DAMAGE_PSYCHIC">
                <supports>Keeper Companion Damage</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>Your companion does psychic damage on a successful attack.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false"/>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="companion-damage:type" inline="true" value="psychic" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="radiant" type="Class Feature" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMPANION_DAMAGE_RADIANT">
                <supports>Keeper Companion Damage</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>Your companion does radiant damage on a successful attack.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false"/>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="companion-damage:type" inline="true" value="radiant" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="slashing" type="Class Feature" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMPANION_DAMAGE_SLASHING">
                <supports>Keeper Companion Damage</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>Your companion does slashing damage on a successful attack.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false"/>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="companion-damage:type" inline="true" value="slashing" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="thunder" type="Class Feature" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMPANION_DAMAGE_THUNDER">
                <supports>Keeper Companion Damage</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>Your companion does thunder damage on a successful attack.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false"/>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="companion-damage:type" inline="true" value="thunder" />
                </rules>
            </element>
        <element name="Spirit Covenant" type="Class Feature" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_CLASS_FEATURE_KEEPER_SPIRIT_COVENANT">
            <description>
                <p>At 3rd level, you define the seal binding you and your companion together, and the gateway you form between the mortal world and the spiritual. Choose the Covenant of the Legion, Covenant of the Vessel, or the Covenant of Unity. Your choice grants you features at 3rd level, and then again 5th, 7th, 11th, and 18th level.</p>
                <h5>COVENANT SPELLS</h5>
                <p>Each covenant has a list of associated spells. You gain access to these spells at the levels specified in the covenant description. Once you gain access to a covenant spell, you always have it prepared. Covenant spells don’t count against the number of spells you can prepare each day.</p>
                <p class="indent">If you gain a covenant spell that doesn’t appear on the keeper spell list, the spell is nonetheless a keeper spell for you.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Archetype" name="Spirit Covenant" supports="Keeper Spirit Covenant" level="3" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Ability Score Improvement" type="Class Feature" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_CLASS_FEATURE_KEEPER_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1.</p>
                <p class="indent">As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Keeper 4)" supports="Improvement Option,Keeper,4" level="4" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Keeper 8)" supports="Improvement Option,Keeper,8" level="8" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Keeper 12)" supports="Improvement Option,Keeper,12" level="12" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Keeper 16)" supports="Improvement Option,Keeper,16" level="16" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Keeper 19)" supports="Improvement Option,Keeper,19" level="19" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Practitioner’s Font" type="Class Feature" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_CLASS_FEATURE_KEEPER_PRACTITIONERS_FONT">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, your companion’s attacks count as magical for the purpose of overcoming resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage, and ignore resistance to damage of your companion’s damage type.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, during a short rest, you can call on the bond between you and your companion, summoning it even from death. At the end of the short rest, your companion reforms near to you with half its maximum hit points, having gained the benefits of a short rest, and can immediately spend Hit Dice to recover hit points.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you call on your companion with this feature, you can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description usage="1/Long Rest">During a short rest, you can summon your companion from death. At the end of the short rest, your companion reforms near to you with half its maximum hit points, having gained the benefits of a short rest, and can immediately spend Hit Dice to recover hit points. Additionally, your companion’s attacks count as magical for the purpose of overcoming resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage, and ignore resistance to {{companion-damage:type}} damage. </description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Gate of Travel" type="Class Feature" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_CLASS_FEATURE_KEEPER_GATE_OF_TRAVEL">
            <description>
                <p>At 10th level, you can ride the bond between you and your companion like a wave. As a bonus action while your companion is within 120 feet of you, you can teleport to an unoccupied space within 5 feet of it, or teleport it to an unoccupied space within 5 feet of you. Alternatively, you can both teleport, swapping places. You don’t need to see your companion to teleport using this feature.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can use this feature twice. You regain all expended uses of it when you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="2/Short Rest">
                <description>While your companion is within 120 feet of you, you can teleport to an unoccupied space within 5 feet of it, or teleport it to an unoccupied space within 5 feet of you. Alternatively, you can both teleport, swapping places. You don’t need to see your companion to teleport using this feature.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Witch Gate" type="Class Feature" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_CLASS_FEATURE_KEEPER_WITCH_GATE">
            <description>
                <p>By 14th level, your companion is a gate to the magical world, and you are the key. You gain one 5th-level spell slot, which you can use to cast your keeper spells.</p>
                <p class="indent">At higher levels, you gain additional spell slots: one 6th level spell slot at 17th level, and one 7th level spell slot at 20th level. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="keeper:spellcasting:slots:5" value="1" level="14" />
                <stat name="keeper:spellcasting:slots:6" value="1" level="17" />
                <stat name="keeper:spellcasting:slots:7" value="1" level="20" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Retribution" type="Class Feature" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_CLASS_FEATURE_KEEPER_RETRIBUTION">
            <description>
                <p>At 15th level, when you or your companion is reduced to 0 hit points, the other can retaliate in fury, demanding aid from nearby spirits. If they do so, the retaliator immediately regains hit points equal to your keeper level + your Charisma modifier, and for 1 minute, the first creature it hits with an attack on each of its turns takes an extra 2d8 damage of your companion’s damage type.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you or your companion uses this feature, it can’t be used again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>When you or your companion is reduced to 0 hit points, the other can retaliate immediately regaining {{retribution:regain-hp}} hit points, and for 1 minute, the first creature it hits with an attack on each of its turns takes an extra 2d8 {{companion-damage:type}} damage.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="retribution:regain-hp" value="level:keeper" level="15" />
                <stat name="retribution:regain-hp" value="charisma:modifier" level="15" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="World Gate" type="Class Feature" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_CLASS_FEATURE_KEEPER_WORLD_GATE">
            <description>
                <p>By 20th level, you are a gate to the material world, and your companion is the key. While your companion is alive, you do not age. Additionally, if you die while your companion still lives, the connection between you returns you to the world of the living; if your companion finishes a long rest while you are dead, you can return to life, reforming your body near to your companion, having gained the benefits of a long rest. You can reform your body as a younger version of yourself, if you wish.</p>
                <p class="indent">If a spell, such as <em>raise dead</em>, has the sole effect of restoring you to life, the caster can cast the spell on your companion as though it were your corpse.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>While your companion is alive, you do not age. Additionally, if you die while your companion still lives, the connection between you returns you to the world of the living; if your companion finishes a long rest while you are dead, you can return to life, reforming your body near to your companion, having gained the benefits of a long rest. You can reform your body as a younger version of yourself, if you wish.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ANIMALHANDLING">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ARCANA">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_HISTORY">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INTIMIDATION">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_MEDICINE">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERFORMANCE">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERSUASION">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_RELIGION">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>


  <!-- 1st Level -->
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ALARM">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANIMAL_FRIENDSHIP">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BANE">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLESS">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_CAUSE_FEAR">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CHARM_PERSON">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMMAND">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMPELLED_DUEL">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CURE_WOUNDS">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMPREHEND_LANGUAGES">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_EVIL_AND_GOOD">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_MAGIC">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISGUISE_SELF">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HEALING_WORD">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HEROISM">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PURIFY_FOOD_AND_DRINK">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SANCTUARY">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_ANIMALS">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_UNSEEN_SERVANT">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
  <!-- 2nd Level -->
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AID">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANIMAL_MESSENGER">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ARCANE_LOCK">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AUGURY">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CALM_EMOTIONS">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENHANCE_ABILITY">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENTHRALL">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GENTLE_REPOSE">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INVISIBILITY">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_KNOCK">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LESSER_RESTORATION">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LOCATE_ANIMALS_OR_PLANTS">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LOCATE_OBJECT">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_NYSTULS_MAGIC_AURA">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SEE_INVISIBILITY">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SKYWRITE">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
  <!-- 3rd Level -->
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANIMATE_DEAD">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CLAIRVOYANCE">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONJURE_ANIMALS">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISPEL_MAGIC">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GLYPH_OF_WARDING">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGIC_CIRCLE">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_NONDETECTION">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PHANTOM_STEED">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SENDING">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_DEAD">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_PLANTS">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_SUMMON_LESSER_DEMONS">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TONGUES">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
  <!-- 4th Level -->
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ARCANE_EYE">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BANISHMENT">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_CHARM_MONSTER">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONJURE_MINOR_ELEMENTALS">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONJURE_WOODLAND_BEINGS">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DIMENSION_DOOR">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LOCATE_CREATURE">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MORDENKAINENS_FAITHFUL_HOUND">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_SUMMON_GREATER_DEMON">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
  <!-- 5th Level -->
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANIMATE_OBJECTS">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMMUNE_WITH_NATURE">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONJURE_ELEMENTAL">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONTACT_OTHER_PLANE">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_DANSE_MACABRE">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISPEL_EVIL_AND_GOOD">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GEAS">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HALLOW">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_INFERNAL_CALLING">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PLANAR_BINDING">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SCRYING">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TELEPORTATION_CIRCLE">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
  <!-- 6th Level -->
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ARCANE_GATE">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONJURE_FEY">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CREATE_UNDEAD">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FORBIDDANCE">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PLANAR_ALLY">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_SOUL_CAGE">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TRUE_SEEING">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
  <!-- 7th Level -->
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONJURE_CELESTIAL">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PLANE_SHIFT">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SYMBOL">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TELEPORT">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
    </append>

</elements>