<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
            <elements>
    <info>
        <name>The Keeper Class Spells</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="spells.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/classes/class-keeper/spells.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Practitioner’s Rites" type="Spell" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_SPELL_PRACTITIONERS_RITES">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You invoke a rite, entreating a boon from nearby spirits. When you cast the spell, choose one of the following rites, the target of which must be within 10 feet of you throughout the casting.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Rite of Elegy.</strong> You speak the name of a dead humanoid, and imbue a creature or object precious to it in life—such as a loved one or treasured belonging—with nostalgia. If the dead humanoid became an undead with unfinished business, such as a ghost, spectre, or poltergeist, and is within 1 mile of you, it must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or spend its turns moving as close to the target as it can for 1 hour or until it takes damage.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Rite of Fertility.</strong> One willing creature you touch is imbued with life. Any attempts the affected creature makes to conceive a child within the next 24 hours are successful. If the creature is pregnant, the pregnancy cannot fail or be terminated without the creature’s consent, and any disease affecting the creature will not harm their offspring.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Rite of Warding.</strong> One homestead or small building is sheltered by a protective blessing until you leave the building or fall unconscious. As part of casting the spell, you touch a number of thresholds, such as doors, windows, or other entryways. For the duration, each threshold has resistance to all damage, and any fey, fiend, or undead that attempts to enter must succeed on a Charisma saving throw be unable to willingly pass through until the end of its next turn. On a successful save, the creature is immune to this effect for 24 hours.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Rite of Wild Sanctuary.</strong> One animal you touch with an Intelligence of 6 or lower is shepherded by gentle spirits. The animal has a +10 bonus to all checks made to evade capture and will be led to the nearest source of enough food, water, and shelter to sustain them until they find a safe habitat to live in.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">conjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 minute</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">Chalk and a handful of edible food, which the spell consumes</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Vengeful Spirit" type="Spell" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_SPELL_VENGEFUL_SPIRIT">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You beckon a spirit to your side, feeding it a vengeful rage. The spirit rushes towards a creature or object within range, seeking to destroy it. Make a melee spell attack against the target. On a hit, the target takes 3d8 bludgeoning, piercing, or slashing damage (your choice). Hit or miss, the spirit then vanishes.</p>
            <p class="indent">If the target has attacked you or targeted you with a harmful spell since the end of your last turn, the spirit’s lust for vengeance is set aflame. If the attack hit, the spirit hounds the target a moment longer, preventing it from taking reactions until the start of its next turn.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 1st.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">conjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Possession" type="Spell" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_SPELL_POSSESSION">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You enter a trance, your mind eclipsing the spirit of a willing creature within range. While in the trance, you possess the target. The target is incapacitated and loses control of its body, but remains dreamily aware of its surroundings. Your body falls into a catatonic state; you are unaware of your body’s surroundings, and it can’t take actions or move.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you possess a creature’s body, you control it. Your game statistics are replaced by the statistics of the creature, though you retain your alignment and your Intelligence, Wisdom, and Charisma scores. You also retain all of your skill and saving throw proficiencies, in addition to gaining those of the creature. You retain the benefit of your own class features. If the target has any class levels, you can’t use any of its class features.</p>
            <p class="indent">You must make a Constitution saving throw to maintain your concentration on this spell whenever your body or the target’s body takes damage. The spell ends early if the target is no longer willing.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> If you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the duration is 8 hours. Using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher grants a duration that doesn’t require concentration, the spell lasting until you dismiss it (no action required).</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">enchantment</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 hour</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Skinchange" type="Spell" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_SPELL_SKINCHANGE">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You invite a willing creature into the guise of a mundane animal. A creature you touch transforms into a beast with a challenge rating of 1/4 or lower. This spell has no effect on a creature with 0 hit points.</p>
            <p class="indent">While in this form, the target’s game statistics are replaced by the statistics of the beast, but it retains its hit points, Intelligence, Wisdom, and Charisma scores. The target retains its alignment and personality, though its mannerisms may be slightly affected by the nature of the beast.</p>
            <p class="indent">The creature is limited in the actions it can perform by the nature of its new form, and it can’t speak, cast spells, or take any other action that requires hands or speech.</p>
            <p class="indent">The target’s gear melds into the new form. The creature can’t activate, use, wield, or otherwise benefit from any of its equipment.</p>
            <p class="indent">The spell ends early if the target is reduced to 0 hit points, or if they end the spell on their turn (no action required).</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 minute</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">blood, hide, or other remains taken from the desired beast, applied to the target as the spell is cast</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 hour</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Dreamscape" type="Spell" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_SPELL_DREAMSCAPE">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You share yourself, and allow others the same opportunity. For the duration of the spell, you and any creature of your choice within range can use their action to enter a shared dreamscape, entering a meditative trance or falling asleep (target’s choice).</p>
            <p class="indent">The appearance of the dreamscape is up to you; you and any creature of your choice can shape the environment of the dreamscape, creating landscapes, objects, and other images, such as showing past memories. The dreamscape relies on the creativity of its residents, and cannot create something that has not been seen or imagined by a creature within the dreamscape. A creature within the dreamscape can leave at any time, waking from their trance or sleep.</p>
            <p class="indent">Regardless of its contents, the dreamscape soothes the soul with its catharsis. A creature that spends at least 4 hours of a long rest within the dreamscape recovers an additional level of exhaustion at the end of the rest.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">illusion</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self (30-foot radius)</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">8 hours</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Summon Dragonkin" type="Spell" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_SPELL_SUMMON_DRAGONKIN">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You call draconic spirits into the shape of a drake spirit, which appears in an unoccupied space you can see within range. The drake spirit disappears when it drops to 0 hit points or when the spell ends. When you summon the drake, it is imbued with the nature of a certain kind of dragon. It gains a climbing speed, a burrowing speed, or a swimming speed of 20 feet. Additionally, choose acid, cold, fire, lightning, or poison. The drake gains resistance to the chosen damage type, and its bite deals an extra 1d6 damage of that type when it hits.</p>
            <p class="indent">The drake is friendly to you and your companions. Roll initiative for the drake, which has its own turns. It obeys any verbal commands that you issue to it (no action required by you). If you don’t issue any commands to the drake, it defends itself from hostile creatures but otherwise takes no actions.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the drake spirit gains 10 temporary hit points for each slot level above 3rd. If you use a spell slot of 5th level or higher, the duration is concentration, up to 24 hours.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">conjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">30 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a gemstone worth at least 100 gp</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 hour</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Wake Plantlife" type="Spell" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_SPELL_WAKE_PLANTLIFE">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You briefly instill a semblance of life within a Huge or smaller plant you can see within range, transforming it into an awakened tree (MM 317), though it has an Intelligence and Charisma score of 1, and it can’t speak. The target grows until it is Huge, if it was smaller. If the target already had an Intelligence score, it is unaffected.</p>
            <p class="indent">The tree is friendly to you and your companions. Roll initiative for the tree, which has its own turns. While the tree is within 1 mile of you, you can telepathically communicate with it. The tree obeys any commands you issue to it (no action required by you). If you don’t issue any commands to the tree, it defends itself from hostile creatures but otherwise takes no actions. If the tree is reduced to 0 hit points, the spell ends.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, you can target one additional plant for every two slot levels above 4th.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">4</set>
            <set name="school">transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 8 hours</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Spirit Feast" type="Spell" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_SPELL_SPIRIT_FEAST">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You rush towards a dying creature and gorge yourself on its spirit. As part of casting the spell, you can move up to your speed. If you end this movement within 5 feet of the target, you devour its spirit. You regain 40 hit points, and the target can’t be resurrected by any means short of a wish spell.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">5</set>
            <set name="school">necromancy</set>
            <set name="time">1 reaction, which you take when a creature you can see within 60 feet of you dies</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Ties That Bind" type="Spell" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_SPELL_TIES_THAT_BIND">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You radiate kinship in an aura with a 60-foot radius, reminding your allies of their support for each other. Until the spell ends, the aura moves, centered on you. While in the aura, each friendly creature in the aura (including you) can’t be charmed, and deals extra damage the first time it hits with an attack on each of its turns. This damage equals 1d6 + the number of allies affected by this spell, to a maximum of 10.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">5</set>
            <set name="school">evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self (60-foot radius)</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 10 minutes</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="House of Life" type="Spell" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_SPELL_HOUSE_OF_LIFE">
        <supports>Keeper</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You shape, structure, and bind a house of life, which appears in an unoccupied space you can see within range. The house has the same statistics as a flesh golem (MM 169), though it lacks the Berserk trait.</p>
            <p class="indent">The house is friendly to you and your companions. Roll initiative for the house, which has its own turns. It obeys any verbal commands that you issue to it (no action required by you). If you don’t issue any commands to the house, it defends itself from hostile creatures but otherwise takes no actions.</p>
            <p class="indent">If a willing creature dies within 60 feet of the house, you can use your reaction to cage its soul within the house. The soul remains within the house until the house is destroyed, or until it chooses to leave. A soul within the house can control it. Its game statistics are replaced by the statistics of the house, though it retains its alignment and its Intelligence, Wisdom, and Charisma scores. It also retains all of its skill and saving throw proficiencies, in addition to gaining those of the house, and it retains the benefits of its own class features.</p>
            <p class="indent">The house collapes into a puddle of flesh when it is reduced to 0 hit points, or after 24 hours. To maintain the house’s form for another 24 hours, you must cast this spell on the house again before the current 24-hour period ends. When you cast this spell to maintain a house’s form, it has a casting time of 1 minute, and you can ignore the spell’s material components.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">7</set>
            <set name="school">necromancy</set>
            <set name="time">1 hour</set>
            <set name="range">10 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">50 pounds of flesh and two cupped handfuls of blood taken from a humanoid or beast, which are consumed by the spell, and an esoteric implement, which is buried within the house’s chest as the spell is cast</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
            </elements>