<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Keeper Subclasses</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="subclasses.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/classes/class-keeper/subclasses.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Covenant of the Legion" type="Archetype" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_KEEPER_COVENANT_OF_THE_LEGION">
        <supports>Keeper Spirit Covenant</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Keepers of this covenant command such a presence that their will is enough to overwhelm the spirits of the world around them. When these legionnaires walk, the wind is at their back, their way is clear, and their pace is swift as they follow their path to victory, their most loyal companion and follower always by their side. They speak with the voice of a conqueror, and the universe listens.</p>
            <p class="indent flavor">"Hear me and obey! I claim this place and name it mine! Let all who would oppose me speak now, or fall silent forevermore!"</p>
            <div element="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LEGION_COVENANT_SPELLS" />
            <div element="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LEGION_HEARTHKEEPER" />
            <div element="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LEGION_SWORN_PROTECTOR" />
            <div element="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LEGION_MARCH_OF_THE_LEGION" />
            <div element="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LEGION_UNSEEN_SERFDOM" />
            <div element="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LEGION_OATHBOUND_GUARDIAN" />
            <div element="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LEGION_DEMESNE" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LEGION_COVENANT_SPELLS" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LEGION_HEARTHKEEPER" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LEGION_SWORN_PROTECTOR" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LEGION_MARCH_OF_THE_LEGION" level="5" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LEGION_UNSEEN_SERFDOM" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LEGION_OATHBOUND_GUARDIAN" level="11" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LEGION_DEMESNE" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Covenant Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LEGION_COVENANT_SPELLS">
            <description>
                <p>You gain covenant spells at the keeper levels listed.</p>
                <h5 class="caption">Covenant of The Legion Spells</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Keeper Level</td><td>Spell</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td><i>command</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><i>silence</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><i>spirit guardians</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>13th</td><td><i>freedom of movement</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>14th</td><td><i>dominate person</i></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMMAND" prepared="true" spellcasting="Keeper" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SILENCE" prepared="true" spellcasting="Keeper" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPIRIT_GUARDIANS" prepared="true" spellcasting="Keeper" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FREEDOM_OF_MOVEMENT" prepared="true" spellcasting="Keeper" level="13" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DOMINATE_PERSON" prepared="true" spellcasting="Keeper" level="14" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Hearthkeeper" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LEGION_HEARTHKEEPER">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 3rd level, you learn to speak with the spiritual denizens of an area. You can spend 10 minutes entreating or ordering these spirits, burning simple offerings, or otherwise commanding the attention of the world around you.</p>
                <p class="indent">If you do so, you learn one fact of your choice about any of the following subjects as they relate to the area within 1 mile of you:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Frequently visited buildings and places of business</li>
                    <li>Historically significant events</li>
                    <li>Powerful aberrations, celestials, fey, fiends, elementals, or undead</li>
                    <li>Safe sources of food, water, and places to rest</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">Mortals and spirits experience life in fundamentally different ways. In offering their wisdom, the spirits’ advice may be cryptic, spoken like a prophecy, or conveyed through potentially disturbing dreams and visions.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You can spend 10 minutes entreating or ordering these spirits, burning simple offerings, or otherwise commanding the attention of the world around you to learn on fact relating to the area within 1 mile of you.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Sworn Protector" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LEGION_SWORN_PROTECTOR">
            <description>
                <p>By 3rd level, your companion is your faithful servant and protector. When a creature your companion can see attacks you, your companion can use its reaction to move up to its speed towards the attacker, imposing disadvantage on the attack roll if it ends this movement within 5 feet of the attacker.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When a creature your companion can see attacks you, your companion can use its reaction to move up to its speed towards the attacker, imposing disadvantage on the attack roll if it ends this movement within 5 feet of the attacker.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="March of the Legion" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LEGION_MARCH_OF_THE_LEGION">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 5th level, your companion can attack twice, instead of once, whenever it takes the Attack action on its turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Your companion can attack twice, instead of once, whenever it takes the Attack action on its turn.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Unseen Serfdom" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LEGION_UNSEEN_SERFDOM">
            <description>
                <p>At 7th level, you gain access to the unseen servant spell. You always have it prepared, and it doesn’t count against the number of spells you can prepare each day.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, when you cast unseen servant, you can create a number of additional servants equal to half your keeper level. When you cast unseen servant in this way, each servant has a Strength score equal to the number of unseen servants under your command (maximum Strength score of 12), and you can mentally command any or all of the servants when you use your bonus action to command a servant, issuing the same command to each one.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you cast unseen servant in this way, you can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>When you cast unseen servant, you can create up to {{level:keeper:half}} additional servants. When cast this way, each servant has a Strength (maximum of 12) equal to the number of servants. You can mentally command the servants as a bonus action.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_UNSEEN_SERVANT" spellcasting="Keeper" prepared="true" level="7" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Oathbound Guardian" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LEGION_OATHBOUND_GUARDIAN">
            <description>
                <p>At 11th level, your companion is your devoted guardian. When you use your Sworn Servant feature, your companion can make a melee attack against the attacker as part of the same reaction.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, while your companion is within 5 feet of a hostile creature, that creature has disadvantage on any attack roll targeting you.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you use your Sworn Servant feature, your companion can make a melee attack against the attacker as part of the same reaction. Additionally, while your companion is within 5 feet of a hostile creature, that creature has disadvantage on any attack roll targeting you.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Demesne" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LEGION_DEMESNE">
            <description>
                <p>At 18th level, you can perform a ritual to claim ownership of a location no larger than 500 feet on a side, such as an area of forest, manor, castle, or other area, establishing it as your demesne. To perform the ritual, you must spend at least 24 consecutive hours within the area without resting, falling unconscious, or being reduced to 0 hit points, during which any creature within 1 mile of you is made aware of your claim and the consequences of the ritual. If you successfully complete the ritual, you claim the area as your demesne.</p>
                <p class="indent">Within your demesne, you can shape it to your will. You can use your action to manipulate an area you can see within your demesne no larger than a 20-foot cube, destroying solid structures, raising or depressing land, changing the weather and temperature to your liking, manifesting sounds or smells, or changing the material of a structure or surface - such as changing a stone wall to one of wood, ice, or flesh. If you manipulate an area to cause harm, each hostile creature within the area must make a Charisma saving throw against your keeper spell save DC. A creature takes 4d8 damage of a type of your choice on a failure, or half as much damage on a success.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, you can spend 1 minute creating a portal within 5 feet of you, linked to an identical portal within your demense. Both portals must fit within a 10-foot-cube. A creature can use its action while within 5 feet of one portal to step through, appearing from the other. The portal lasts until you dismiss it (no action required), or until you create another portal using this feature.</p>
                <p class="indent">If you claim another demesne, your lose ownership of your former demesne, and any changes you made within are slowly undone over the course of a week. Anything created by this feature vanishes when it leaves your demesne, and any changes made to an object are rapidly undone if it leaves your demesne.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>If you successfully complete the 24-hour ritual, you claim the area in which you performed it as your demesne. You can shape your desmesne to your will. You can spend 1 minute to create a portal back to your desmesne.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
    
    <element name="Covenant of the Vessel" type="Archetype" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_KEEPER_COVENANT_OF_THE_VESSEL">
        <supports>Keeper Spirit Covenant</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Every keeper treads a measure in the world of the mystical. Some, however, go further, truly joining with the magical world. Called vessels, these keepers cut away fragments of their self, the bedrock of their identity, and fill the gaps with spirits kin to their companion. These vessels are imbued with wild, electrifying power, but must remain vigilant, or risk losing themselves to the spirits they invite within.</p>
            <p class="indent flavor">"Hungry spirits, rattlin’ around inside me; something wild, to run faster, hit harder... It’s enough to make you feel hollow."</p>
            <div element="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VESSEL_COVENANT_SPELLS" />
            <div element="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VESSEL_BURNING_THE_CANDLE" />
            <div element="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VESSEL_SPIRIT_RIDING" />
            <div element="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VESSEL_EXTRA_ATTACK" />
            <div element="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VESSEL_HOLLOWED_HEART" />
            <div element="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VESSEL_SOUL_TWITCH" />
            <div element="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VESSEL_SPIRIT_VAULT" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VESSEL_COVENANT_SPELLS" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VESSEL_BURNING_THE_CANDLE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VESSEL_SPIRIT_RIDING" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VESSEL_EXTRA_ATTACK" level="5" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VESSEL_HOLLOWED_HEART" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VESSEL_SOUL_TWITCH" level="11" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VESSEL_SPIRIT_VAULT" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Covenant Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VESSEL_COVENANT_SPELLS">
            <description>
                <p>You gain covenant spells at the keeper levels listed.</p>
                <h5 class="caption">Covenant of The Vessel Spells</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Keeper Level</td><td>Spell</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td><i>expeditious retreat</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><i>alter self</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><i>haste</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>13th</td><td><i>guardian of nature<sup>XGtE</sup></i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>14th</td><td><i>spirit feast<sup>KS</sup></i></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_EXPEDITIOUS_RETREAT" prepared="true" spellcasting="Keeper" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ALTER_SELF" prepared="true" spellcasting="Keeper" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HASTE" prepared="true" spellcasting="Keeper" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_GUARDIAN_OF_NATURE" prepared="true" spellcasting="Keeper" level="13" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_SPELL_SPIRIT_FEAST" prepared="true" spellcasting="Keeper" level="14" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Burning the Candle" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VESSEL_BURNING_THE_CANDLE">
            <description>
                <p>By 3rd level, the spirits invited within have changed you, making you restless, agitated, and just a touch inhuman. You cannot sleep, magically or otherwise, and no longer need to, but you can still be knocked unconscious. To gain the benefits of a long rest, you can spend all 8 hours doing light activity, such as pacing and keeping watch.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You cannot sleep, magically or otherwise, and no longer need to, but you can still be knocked unconscious. To gain the benefits of a long rest, you can spend all 8 hours doing light activity, such as pacing and keeping watch.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Spirit Riding" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VESSEL_SPIRIT_RIDING">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 3rd level, your will is steeled, strong enough to withstand assault from within.</p>
                <p class="indent">While within 60 feet of you, your companion can use its action to beckon spirits of its nature to enter your body, imbuing you with a portion of their strength through a practice called riding. These spirits remain for 10 minutes. Your Spirit Riding ends early if you die or if you dismiss it (no action required). Your companion can’t use this feature while you’re Spirit Riding.</p>
                <p class="indent">While Spirit Riding, you gain the following benefits:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Whenever you hit a creature with a weapon attack on your turn, you can push the creature up to 5 feet away from you and immediately move up to half your speed to an unoccupied space within 5 feet of the target.</li>
                    <li>Immediately after you take damage, you gain temporary hit points equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum of 1).</li>
                    <li>You cannot be frightened. If you are frightened when you begin Spirit Riding, the effect is suspended while you are Spirit Riding.</li>
                    <li>You ignore the effects of any levels of exhaustion.</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">The first time you use this ability, you suffer no adverse effect. Each time you use this feature again before you finish a short or long rest, you suffer one level of exhaustion.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>While within 60 feet of you, your companion can use its action to beckon spirits of its nature to enter your body, imbuing you with a portion of their strength through a practice called riding. The first time you use this ability, you suffer no adverse effect. Each time you use this feature again before you finish a short or long rest, you suffer one level of exhaustion.</description>
                <description level="11">While within 60 feet of you, your companion can use its action to beckon spirits of its nature to enter your body, imbuing you with a portion of their strength through a practice called riding. The first two times you use this ability, you suffer no adverse effect. Each time you use this feature again before you finish a short or long rest, you suffer one level of exhaustion.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Extra Attack" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VESSEL_EXTRA_ATTACK">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 5th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
    			<stat name="extra attack:count" value="2" level="5" bonus="extra attack" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Hollowed Heart" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VESSEL_HOLLOWED_HEART">
            <description>
                <p>At 7th level, your harrowed spirit can consume fragments of the dead. By spending 1 minute within 5 feet of a creature’s corpse, you can learn what skill and tool proficiencies the creature possessed, what languages it spoke, and its type.</p>
                <p class="indent">When you use this feature, you can also choose to harvest fragments of its spirit. If you do so, you gain proficiency in two skills or tools of your choice, chosen from the proficiencies the creature possessed in life, which remain until you harvest fragments of another creature’s spirit. You can replace one or both of these selections with languages the creature spoke. If the creature did not speak a language, you can instead communicate with and be understood by any of its kind.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>By spending 1 minute within 5 feet of a creature’s corpse, you can learn what skill and tool proficiencies the creature possessed, what languages it spoke, and its type. When you use this feature, you can also choose to harvest fragments of its spirit. If you do so, you gain proficiency in two skills or tools of your choice, chosen from the proficiencies the creature possessed in life, which remain until you harvest fragments of another creature’s spirit.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency, Hollowed Heart" number="2" supports="Skill" level="7" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Soul Twitch" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VESSEL_SOUL_TWITCH">
            <description>
                <p>By 11th level, the spirits within you frenzy at the slightest provocation. When you hit a creature with a weapon attack while Spirit Riding, you can roll one of the weapon’s damage dice one additional time and add it to the damage of the attack if that creature has damaged you or your companion since the end of your last turn.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, you can Spirit Ride twice between rests with no adverse effect.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you hit a creature with a weapon attack while Spirit Riding, you can roll one of the weapon’s damage dice one additional time and add it to the damage of the attack if that creature has damaged you or your companion since the end of your last turn.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Spirit Vault" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VESSEL_SPIRIT_VAULT">
            <description>
                <p>At 18th level, your body is animated by the spirits held within. You ignore the effects of the first five levels of exhaustion, and while Spirit Riding, having 0 hit points doesn’t knock you unconscious. You still must make death saving throws, and you suffer the normal effects of taking damage while at 0 hit points.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, when your Spirit Riding ends, you can open the vault within your soul and release a hurricane of hungry spirits. Each creature within 30 feet of you must make a Constitution saving throw against your keeper spell save DC. A creature takes 8d8 necrotic damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a success. A target killed by this damage is devoured whole. You regain hit points equal to your Charisma modifier for each creature devoured in this way. If your Spirit Riding ended early because you died and the spirits devour a creature, you are returned to life with 1 hit point.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you open the vault, you can’t open it again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You ignore the effects of the first five levels of exhaustion, and while Spirit Riding, having 0 hit points doesn’t knock you unconscious. You still must make death saving throws, and you suffer the normal effects of taking damage while at 0 hit points. Additionally, when your Spirit Riding ends, you can open the vault within your soul and release a hurricane of hungry spirits. Each creature within 30 feet of you must make a Constitution saving throw against your keeper spell save DC. A creature takes 8d8 necrotic damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a success.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
    
    <element name="Covenant of Unity" type="Archetype" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_KEEPER_COVENANT_OF_UNITY">
        <supports>Keeper Spirit Covenant</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The bond between Keeper and companion typically implies a measure of servitude on the companion’s part, but this is not always the case. For some, the bond is much more intimate, and the line between the two halves is blurred. These merged beings, often called unions or fusions, embody the relationship between each partner, their mind and body shaped by the interplay between their halves.</p>
            <p class="indent flavor">"I’m not just two people, fighting together. Everything they care about? Their love, their hate? I’m that, and so much more."</p>
            <div element="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNITY_COVENANT_SPELLS" />
            <div element="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNITY_UNITY" />
            <div element="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNITY_KINDRED_SPIRITS" />
            <div element="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNITY_EQUILIBRIUM" />
            <div element="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNITY_HARMONY" />
            <div element="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNITY_SYNTHESIS" />
            <div element="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNITY_FUSION" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNITY_COVENANT_SPELLS" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNITY_UNITY" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNITY_KINDRED_SPIRITS" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNITY_EQUILIBRIUM" level="5" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNITY_HARMONY" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNITY_SYNTHESIS" level="11" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNITY_FUSION" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Covenant Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNITY_COVENANT_SPELLS">
            <description>
                <p>You gain covenant spells at the keeper levels listed.</p>
                <h5 class="caption">Covenant of Unity Spells</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Keeper Level</td><td>Spell</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td><i>shield of faith</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><i>aid</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><i>dreamscape<sup>KS</sup></i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>13th</td><td><i>aura of purity</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>14th</td><td><i>ties that bind<sup>KS</sup></i></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHIELD_OF_FAITH" prepared="true" spellcasting="Keeper" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AID" prepared="true" spellcasting="Keeper" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_SPELL_DREAMSCAPE" prepared="true" spellcasting="Keeper" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AURA_OF_PURITY" prepared="true" spellcasting="Keeper" level="13" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_SPELL_TIES_THAT_BIND" prepared="true" spellcasting="Keeper" level="14" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Unity" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNITY_UNITY">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 3rd level, while you and your companion are within 5 feet of each other, either of you can use your action to unify with the other, merging into a single creature. You grow up to 8 feet tall, and your equipment grows with you; you become Medium, if you were smaller. Your companion vanishes, becoming a part of you: it is incapacitated, has a speed of 0, and cannot be targeted by any attack, spell, or harmful effect.</p>
                <p class="indent">While unified, you have resistance to all damage, and each time you take damage, your companion takes the same amount of damage. Whenever you make an ability check, you can make the check using your companion’s statistics, rather than your own.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, you manifest natural weapons similar to your companion’s. These weapons count as natural melee weapons with which you are proficient, and you use your Strength or Dexterity modifier for attack and damage rolls you make with them. They deal 1d8 damage on a hit, and their damage is your companion’s damage type. When you use the Attack action with these natural weapons on your turn, you can make one attack with them as a bonus action.</p>
                <p class="indent">Your unification lasts for a number of hours equal to half your keeper level. It ends early if you or your companion are reduced to 0 hit points. You can also end the unification early on your turn (no action required).</p>
                <p class="indent">When your unification ends, you and your companion revert to your ordinary forms, appearing in the nearest unoccupied spaces within 5 feet of you. If you revert due to being reduced to 0 hit points, you and your companion fall prone.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can use this feature twice. You regain all expended uses of it when you finish a long rest. Beginning at 11th level, you can use this feature three times between rests.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="{{unity:uses}}/Long Rest">
                <description>While you and your companion are within 5 feet of each other, either of you can use your action to unify with the other, merging into a single creature. You grow up to 8 feet tall, and your equipment grows with you; you become Medium, if you were smaller. Your companion vanishes, becoming a part of you: it is incapacitated, has a speed of 0, and cannot be targeted by any attack, spell, or harmful effect. Your unification lasts up to {{level:keeper:half}} hours.</description>
                <description level="18" usage="Unlimited">While you and your companion are within 5 feet of each other, either of you can use your action to unify with the other, merging into a single creature. You grow up to 8 feet tall, and your equipment grows with you; you become Medium, if you were smaller. Your companion vanishes, becoming a part of you: it is incapacitated, has a speed of 0, and cannot be targeted by any attack, spell, or harmful effect. Your unification lasts up to {{level:keeper:half}} hours.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="unity:uses" value="2" level="3" />
                <stat name="unity:uses" value="1" level="11" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Kindred Spirits" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNITY_KINDRED_SPIRITS">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 3rd level, while you and your companion are on the same plane of existence, you can each communicate with the other telepathically. You don’t need to see each other to communicate in this way.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>While you and your companion are on the same plane of existence, you can each communicate with the other telepathically. You don’t need to see each other to communicate in this way.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Equilibrium" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNITY_EQUILIBRIUM">
            <description>
                <p>At 5th level, once per turn, when you or your companion hits a creature with an attack, the attack deals an extra 1d6 damage of your companion’s damage type. While unified, you can deal this extra damage twice on your turn.</p>
                <p class="indent">This extra damage increases to 2d6 when you reach 11th level in this class.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Once per turn, when you or your companion hits a creature with an attack, the attack deals an extra {{equilibrium:damage-dice}}d6 {{companion-damage:type}}. While unified, you can deal this extra damage twice on your turn.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="equilibrium:damage-dice" value="1" level="5" />
                <stat name="equilibrium:damage-dice" value="1" level="11" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Harmony" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNITY_HARMONY">
            <description>
                <p>At 7th level, you can forge an intimate connection with another being. As an action, you can force a creature you can see within 60 feet of you to make a Wisdom saving throw, which it can choose to fail. If the creature you choose has an Intelligence of 1, it is unaffected.</p>
                <p class="indent">On a failed save, the target is charmed by you for 1 minute. While charmed, you and the target can communicate telepathically, can sense each other’s emotional state, and have advantage on all Wisdom and Charisma checks made to interact with each other. You and the target don’t need to share a language to understand each other.</p>
                <p class="indent">On a successful save, or if you or your allies do anything harmful to the target, you can’t use this feature on that creature again until you finish a long rest.</p>
                <p class="indent">The effect ends early if you or your companions do anything harmful to the target, or if you use the feature again.</p>
                <div class="sidebar">
                    <h5>Me, Myself, and I</h5>
                    <p>Unions are often creatures uniquely their own. At your option, you can pick from or roll on the following table to create a quirk for your union.</p>
                    <table>
                        <thead>
                            <tr><td>d6</td><td>Quirk</td></tr>
                        </thead>
                        <tr><td>1</td><td>You struggle with the concept of ’personal space’.</td></tr>
                        <tr><td>2</td><td>You’re naive; you actually were born yesterday.</td></tr>
                        <tr><td>3</td><td>You only exist while your halves are unified—you wish they spent more time that way.</td></tr>
                        <tr><td>4</td><td>You try to avoid conflict between your halves. A house divided cannot stand.</td></tr>
                        <tr><td>5</td><td>Your halves fight constantly. Your personality is nearly irreconcilable.</td></tr>
                        <tr><td>6</td><td>Two hearts means twice the passion.</td></tr>
                    </table>
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>You can force a creature with a 2 or higher Intelligence you can see within 60 feet of you to make a Wisdom saving throw, which it can choose to fail. On a failed save, the target is charmed by you for 1 minute.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Synthesis" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNITY_SYNTHESIS">
            <description>
                <p>At 11th level, when you or your companion unify, you can expend one spell slot to renew yourselves in your new form. Roll 2d8, plus 2d8 for each slot level higher than 1st. You restore hit points equal to the total, which you can divide as you choose between you and your companion.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you or your companion unify, you can expend one spell slot to renew yourselves in your new form. Roll 2d8, plus 2d8 for each slot level higher than 1st. You restore hit points equal to the total, which you can divide as you choose between you and your companion.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Fusion" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Keeper" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_KEEPER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNITY_FUSION">
            <description>
                <p>At 18th level, you can use your Unity feature an unlimited number of times, and it lasts until you choose to end it or until you or your companion is reduced to 0 hit points.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, your power over connections allows you to truly unify with another being, fusing your souls. As an action while you aren’t unified, you can fuse with a willing creature you touch. Your bodies become one, but you both retain your class features and independent initiatives.</p>
                <p class="indent">You use the higher of your ACs, speeds, ability scores, and sizes. Any spell or feature that targets one of you targets both of you. You add your hit point maximums and current hit points together, using a shared pool. If one of you succeeds on a saving throw, you both succeed. You remain fused for 10 minutes, or until your pool of hit points is empty, reverting to your original forms. If you revert due to being reduced to 0 hit points, you both fall prone with 1 hit point.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you fuse with another creature, you can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>While you aren’t unified, you can fuse with a willing creature you touch. Your bodies become one, but you both retain your class features and independent initiatives. You use the higher of your ACs, speeds, ability scores, and sizes. Any spell or feature that targets one of you targets both of you. You add your hit point maximums and current hit points together, using a shared pool. If one of you succeeds on a saving throw, you both succeed. You remain fused for 10 minutes, or until your pool of hit points is empty, reverting to your original forms. If you revert due to being reduced to 0 hit points, you both fall prone with 1 hit point.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
    
</elements>