<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Slayer Spells</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="spells.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/classes/slayer/spells.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>

    <element name="Bonding Serpents" type="Spell" source="Slayer Class" id="ID_REVLID_SLAYER_SPELL_BONDING_SERPENTS">
        <supports>Slayer</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The next time you hit a creature with a weapon attack before this spell ends, the target must make a Strength saving throw. On failure, the target’s limbs are bound to you by serpents of otherworldly smoke.</p>
            <p class="indent">Every foot the target travels costs it an additional foot of movement, unless that movement brings it closer to you. This spell ends early if the target is outside of the spell’s radius at the end of your turn.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the spell’s radius increases by 10 feet for every slot level above 1st.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Conjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
            <set name="range">Self (20-foot radius)</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Scouring Serpents" type="Spell" source="Slayer Class" id="ID_REVLID_SLAYER_SPELL_SCOURING_SERPENTS">
        <supports>Slayer</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The next time you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack before this spell ends, the target is constricted by streamers of elemental energy, suffering an additional 1d4 cold, fire, or lightning damage (your choice).</p>
            <p class="indent">At the start of each of its turns until the spell ends, the target must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, it takes a further 1d4 damage of the same type. On a successful save, it suffers no damage.</p>
            <p class="indent">This spell ends early if you attack any other creature.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the size of the spell’s damage die increases to 1d6 (2nd), 1d8 (3rd), 1d10 (4th), or 1d12 (5th).</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Conjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Springheel Tread" type="Spell" source="Slayer Class" id="ID_REVLID_SLAYER_SPELL_SPRINGHEEL_TREAD">
        <supports>Slayer</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Until the spell ends, you gain a climbing speed equal to your walking speed. You may climb up, down, and across vertical surfaces without occupying your hands. In addition, any falling damage you suffer is halved.</p>
            <p class="indent">You only benefit from this spell’s effects if you moved further than your walking speed on your last turn.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, your walking speed increases by 5 feet for each slot level above 1st, up to 5th level.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a gummy mix of sap and ash</set>
            <set name="duration">1 hour</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Destructive Step" type="Spell" source="Slayer Class" id="ID_REVLID_SLAYER_SPELL_DESTRUCTIVE_STEP">
        <supports>Slayer</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You flicker forward, trailing elemental energy like a comet. You move up to 20 feet in a straight line in any direction, ending your movement in an unoccupied space. This movement does not provoke opportunity attacks, and is unaffected by difficult terrain. Your movement ends early if you hit an obstacle, though you can move through spaces occupied by hostile creatures.</p>
            <p class="indent">Every creature within 5 feet of a space you moved through or into must make a Dexterity saving throw. A creature takes 2d8 cold, fire, or lightning damage (your choice) on a failed save, or half as much as damage on a successful one.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the spell’s damage increases by 1d8 and the distance you move increases by 10 feet for each slot level above 2nd, to a maximum of 5d8 and 50 feet.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
            <set name="range">Self (20-foot line)</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Mirage Step" type="Spell" source="Slayer Class" id="ID_REVLID_SLAYER_SPELL_MIRAGE_STEP">
        <supports>Slayer</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Your speed baffles attackers, as you create one afterimage to redirect attacks. Each time a creature targets you with an attack, roll a d20 to determine whether the attacker mistakenly targets your afterimage. If you roll an 11 or higher, you can change the attack’s target to your afterimage.</p>
            <p class="indent">An afterimage’s AC is equal to your spell save DC. If an attack hits an afterimage, it is destroyed. An afterimage can be destroyed only by an attack that hits it. It ignores all other damage and effects.</p>
            <p class="indent">Whenever an afterimage is destroyed, you can use your reaction to move up to 10 feet, ending your movement in an unoccupied space. This movement does not provoke opportunity attacks, and is unaffected by difficult terrain or interceding hostile creatures. The spell ends when all afterimages are destroyed, or if you end your turn without moving at least 10 feet.</p>
            <p class="indent">A creature is unaffected by this spell if it relies on senses other than sight, or if it can perceive illusions as false.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, you create an extra afterimage for every slot level above 2nd, to a maximum of four. With two afterimages, you must roll an 8 or higher to change the attack’s target. With three afterimages, you must roll a 6 or higher. With four afterimages, you must roll a 4 or higher.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Illusion</set>
            <set name="time">1 reaction, which you take when you are attacked</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">1 minute</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Vanishing Step" type="Spell" source="Slayer Class" id="ID_REVLID_SLAYER_SPELL_VANISHING_STEP">
        <supports>Slayer</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You flash forward, faster than sight. You become invisible until the start of your next turn, and immediately move up to 20 feet, ending your movement in an unoccupied space. This movement does not provoke opportunity attacks, and is unaffected by difficult terrain or hostile creatures.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the distance you move increases by 10 feet for each slot level above 2nd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Illusion</set>
            <set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 turn</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Kindle Self" type="Spell" source="Slayer Class" id="ID_REVLID_SLAYER_SPELL_KINDLE_SELF">
        <supports>Slayer</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Your skin hisses and steams as your magic boils away ailments. You can cast this spell in response to suffering any one of the following conditions: blinded, deafened, paralyzed, or poisoned. You lose 2d4 hit points, and remove that condition. Until this spell ends, you can use your reaction to do so again.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Necromancy</set>
            <set name="time">1 reaction</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">1 minute</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Odic Wellspring" type="Spell" source="Slayer Class" id="ID_REVLID_SLAYER_SPELL_ODIC_WELLSPRING">
        <supports>Slayer</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The life force that suffuses nature is absorbed to heal your wounds. At the end of each of your turns, you regain hit points equal to 1d4 + your spellcasting modifier.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">4</set>
            <set name="school">Necromancy</set>
            <set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">mixture of herbs and blood</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Primordial Torrent" type="Spell" source="Slayer Class" id="ID_REVLID_SLAYER_SPELL_PRIMORDIAL_TORRENT">
        <supports>Slayer</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You burst forward, leaving a wave of elemental energy in your wake. You immediately move up to 50 feet in a straight line, in a direction of your choice. This movement does not provoke opportunity attacks and is unaffected by difficult terrain or hostile creatures.</p>
            <p class="indent">After you have moved, each creature in a 50-foot cone must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or take 6d12 cold, fire, or lightning damage (your choice), and be knocked prone. A creature that succeeds on its saving throw takes half as much damage and isn’t knocked prone.</p>
            <p class="indent">This cone must touch the space you occupied when you cast this spell. If you moved less than 50 feet when you cast this spell, the size of the cone is reduced to match the distance you moved.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">5</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self (50-foot cone)</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

</elements>