<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>The Witch v3</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="class-witch.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/dmhavuhk/class-witch.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="The Witch v3" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_DMHAVUHK_GMBINDER_SOURCE_The Witch v3">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation">TW3</set>
            <set name="url">https://www.gmbinder.com/share/-MLpjmG_1fflojWeEixr</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" abbreviation="DMH" url="https://www.gmbinder.com/profile/dmhavuhk">DMHavuhk</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20210115</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Witch" type="Class" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_CLASS_WITCH">
        <description>
            <p>Standing alone in the swamp, knee deep in water, a half-orc woman places her hand upon the trunk of a very large tree. She mutters a question under her breath, and her vision moves through the vines that run throughout the swamp, as the swamp itself shows her the answer she seeks.</p>
            <p class="indent">Within a small purple tent in the market district of a large city, a tiefling sits hunched over a crystal ball, as he peers through reality to predict the future of the young boy who is paying him.</p>
            <p class="indent">Standing amidst a sea of corpses, the elven woman turns her gaze to one of the few remaining soldiers, as he cowers and begs for his life. She begins to cackle maniacally, as pain begins to wash throughout the soldier’s entire body.</p>
            <p class="indent">Witches are the outcasts of society, powerful spellcasters who study magics frowned upon by most people. Usually preferring to stay away from cities and towns, witches seclude themselves to forests and swamps, away from the prying eyes of others, where they can practice their arcane arts in peace.</p>
            <h4>SCHOLARS OF THE DARK ARTS</h4>
            <p>Similarly to their wizardly brethren, witches use their knowledge of the arcane to perform their magic, studying spells and rituals. However, unlike wizards, witches are not bound by silly things like laws and morals. Free to study the secrets of the arcane in peace, witches are able to study magics that others would not dare look into; Powerful spells that rip the life from others, rituals that bring forth horrible fiends, and potent curses that cripple their targets.</p>
            <p class="indent">Witches are not inherently evil. While there are many who pursue this path as a way to gain power, most simply wish to pursue their studies without the restrictions of magic institutions and colleges. Others are simply born into the life of a witch, never knowing the rules or morals of standard mages, simply studying what catches their interest. A rare few are born with a gift for the dark arts, abandoning society to futher improve their natural talents.</p>
            <h4>FAMILIAR MAGIC</h4>
            <p>While witches come in many shapes and forms, almost all of them carry a familiar with them. While many mages keep familiars with them, witches tend to have a special bond with their familiars, often becoming very attached to the creatures. Their familiars act as both companion and protector, acting as scouts and conduits for the witch’s magic.</p>
            <p class="indent">As a witch grows in power, their familiar reflects this as well, becoming more capable of delivering a witch’s magic. Powerful witches are known to carry familiars that are able to hold their own against seasoned warriors. The most powerful witches have familiars that are able to share the burden of their magic, performing feats of spellcasting far outside the limits of any normal wizard.</p>
            <h4>CREATING A WITCH</h4>
            <p>While creating your witch character, one of the first things you should decide is why they follow the path of a witch. Were you once a member of a prestigious magic academy, but left due to the limitations of what you could learn? Perhaps you found an old tome that directed you in the ways of old magic. Or perhaps you were simply born into the life of a witch, never knowing any different.</p>
            <p class="indent">What kind of life did your character live before their adventuring career began? Did you isolate yourself from the world, hiding away in forests and caves where you could practice you magic in peace? Did you try to integrate yourself with society, hiding away your magical prowess? Maybe you were well known as the witch that lived at the edge of town, interacting with the townsfolk only when they came by. Were you a part of a coven of witches? How large is it? Where is it based? Do you all live together, or do you simply meet every so often to perform your rituals?</p>
            <p class="indent">What led you to go out into the world and begin adventuring? Was it a craving for more power? An opportunity to test the skills and spells that you have learned over your years of study? Perhaps your coven sent you out on a quest or a journey to hone your skills. Or maybe your coven was raided by the nearby law enforcement, and now you’re on the run.</p>
            <h5>QUICK BUILD</h5>
            <p>You can make a witch quickly by following these suggestions. First, Intelligence should be your highest ability score, followed by Wisdom or Constitution. Second, choose the Sage or Hermit background.</p>
            <h2>CLASS FEATURES</h2>
            <p>As a witch, you gain the following class features.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">HIT POINTS</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Hit Dice:</strong> 1d6 per witch level</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at 1st Level:</strong> 6 + your Constitution modifier</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at Higher Levels:</strong> 1d6 (or 4) + your Constitution modifier per witch level after 1st</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">PROFICIENCIES</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled mb">
                <li><strong>Armor:</strong> None</li>
                <li><strong>Weapons:</strong> Simple weapons</li>
                <li><strong>Tools:</strong> None</li>
            </ul>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>saving throws:</strong> Intelligence, Wisdom</li>
                <li><strong>Skills:</strong> Choose two from Arcana, Deception, Insight, Intimidation, Medicine, Nature, Perception, Persuasion, Religion, and Survival</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">EQUIPMENT</h5>
            <p>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>(a) a quarterstaff or (b) any simple weapon</li>
                <li>(a) an arcane focus or (b) a component pouch</li>
                <li>(a) an explorer’s pack or (b) a dungeoneer’s pack</li>
                <li>Two daggers</li>
            </ul>
            <p>Alternatively, you can ignore the equipment listed above and in your background, and buy 4d4 x 10gp worth of equipment from chapter 5 of the <i>Player’s Handbook</i>.</p>
        <!-- class table here -->
            <h5 class="caption">THE WITCH</h5>
            <table class="class-features">
                <thead>
                    <tr><td class="col-5">Level</td><td class="col-10">Proficiency Bonus</td><td class="left">Features</td><td class="col-10">Curses</td><td class="col-10">Cantrips Known</td><td>1st</td><td>2nd</td><td>3rd</td><td>4th</td><td>5th</td><td>6th</td><td>7th</td><td>8th</td><td>9th</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td> 1st</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Spellcasting, Curses, Witch’s Familiar</td><td>2</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 2nd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Witch’s Coven</td><td>2</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 3rd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">—</td><td>2</td><td>3</td><td>4</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 4th</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>3</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 5th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Metamorphic Familiar</td><td>3</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 6th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Coven Feature, Additional Curse</td><td>3</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 7th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">—</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>1</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 8th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 9th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">—</td><td>5</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>1</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>10th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Greater Familiar, Additional Curse</td><td>5</td><td>5</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>11th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">—</td><td>5</td><td>5</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>12th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>6</td><td>5</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">—</td><td>6</td><td>5</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>14th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Coven Feature, Additional Curse</td><td>6</td><td>5</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>15th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">—</td><td>7</td><td>5</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>16th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>7</td><td>5</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>17th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">—</td><td>7</td><td>5</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>1</td></tr>
                <tr><td>18th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Coven Feature, Additional Curse</td><td>8</td><td>5</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>1</td></tr>
                <tr><td>19th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>8</td><td>5</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>1</td></tr>
                <tr><td>20th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Split Mind</td><td>8</td><td>5</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>1</td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_DMH_TW3_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_SPELLCASTING" />
            <div element="ID_DMH_TW3_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_CURSES" />
            <div element="ID_DMH_TW3_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_WITCHS_FAMILIAR" />
            <div element="ID_DMH_TW3_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_WITCHS_COVEN" />
            <div element="ID_DMH_TW3_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" />
            <div element="ID_DMH_TW3_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_METAMORPHIC_FAMILIAR" />
            <div element="ID_DMH_TW3_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_GREATER_FAMILIAR" />
            <div element="ID_DMH_TW3_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_SPLIT_MIND" />
            <h5>MULTICLASSING</h5>
            <p>The prerequisite for multiclassing into a witch is an Intelligence of 13. You do not gain any additional proficiencies for multiclassing into witch.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="hd">d6</set>
            <set name="short">A spellcaster that delves into curses, covens, familiars and spirits.</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" requirements="!ID_DMH_TW3_MULTICLASS_WITCH" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_INTELLIGENCE" requirements="!ID_DMH_TW3_MULTICLASS_WITCH" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_WISDOM" requirements="!ID_DMH_TW3_MULTICLASS_WITCH" />
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency, Witch" supports="Skill, DMH Witch" number="2" requirements="!ID_DMH_TW3_MULTICLASS_WITCH" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_DMH_TW3_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_SPELLCASTING" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_DMH_TW3_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_CURSES" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_DMH_TW3_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_WITCHS_FAMILIAR" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_DMH_TW3_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_WITCHS_COVEN" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_DMH_TW3_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" level="4" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_DMH_TW3_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_METAMORPHIC_FAMILIAR" level="5" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_DMH_TW3_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_GREATER_FAMILIAR" level="10" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_DMH_TW3_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_SPLIT_MIND" level="10" />
        </rules>
        <multiclass id="ID_DMH_TW3_MULTICLASS_WITCH">
            <prerequisite>Intelligence 13</prerequisite>
            <requirements>[int:13]</requirements>
            <setters>
                <set name="multiclass proficiencies">You do not gain any additional proficiencies for multiclassing into witch.</set>
            </setters>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS" />
            </rules>
        </multiclass>
    </element>
        <element name="Spellcasting" type="Class Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_SPELLCASTING">
            <description>
                <p>Drawing upon your arcane knowledge, you can cast spells to influence those around you. See chapter 10 of the PHB for the general rules of spellcasting, and the end of this document for the witch spell list.</p>
                <h5>CANTRIPS</h5>
                <p>At 1st level, you know three cantrips of your choice from the witch spell list. You gain additional witch cantrips of your choice at higher levels, as shown in the Cantrips Known column of the Witch table.</p>
                <h5>PREPARING AND CASTING SPELLS</h5>
                <p>The Witch table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your witch spells of 1st Level and higher. To cast one of these spells, you must expend a slot of the spell’s level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.</p>
                <p class="indent">You prepare the list of witch spells that are available for you to cast, choosing from the witch spell list. When you do so, choose a number of witch spells equal to your Intelligence modifier + your witch level (minimum of one spell). The spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots.</p>
                <p class="indent">For example, if you are a 3rd-level witch, you have four 1st-level and two 2nd-level Spell Slots. With an Intelligence of 16, your list of prepared spells can include six spells of 1st or 2nd Level, in any combination. If you prepare the 1st-level spell witch bolt, you can cast it using a 1st-level or 2nd-level slot. Casting the spell doesn’t remove it from your list of prepared spells.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can change your list of prepared spells when you finish a long rest. Preparing a new list of witch spells requires time spent recalling the rituals and incantations for the spells: at least 1 minute per spell Level for each spell on your list.</p>
                <h5>SPELLCASTING ABILITY</h5>
                <p>Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for your witch spells, as your power comes from your study of the dark arts. You use your Intelligence whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Intelligence modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a witch spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.</p>
                <p style="text-align: center;"><b>Spell Save DC</b> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier</p>
                <p style="text-align: center;"><b>Spell attack modifier</b> = your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier</p>
                <h5>RITUAL CASTING</h5>
                <p>You can cast a witch spell as a ritual if that spell has the ritual tag and you have the spell prepared.</p>
                <h5>SPELLCASTING FOCUS</h5>
                <p>You can use an arcane focus (see chapter 5 of the PHB "Equipment") as a spellcasting focus for your witch spells.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <spellcasting name="Witch" ability="Intelligence" prepare="true">
                <list known="true">DMH Witch</list>
            </spellcasting>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS_SPELLCASTING_SLOTS_FULL" requirements="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS" />
                <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_RITUAL_CASTING" />
    			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_INTERNAL_PROFICIENCY_SPELLFOCUS_GROUP_ARCANE_FOCUS" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:1" value="2" level="1" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="2" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="3" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:2" value="2" level="3" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:2" value="1" level="4" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:3" value="2" level="5" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:3" value="1" level="6" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="7" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="8" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="9" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:5" value="1" level="9" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:5" value="1" level="10" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:5" value="1" level="18" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:6" value="1" level="11" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:6" value="1" level="19" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:7" value="1" level="13" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:7" value="1" level="20" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:8" value="1" level="15" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:9" value="1" level="17" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:prepare" value="intelligence:modifier" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:prepare" value="level:witch" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Witch)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), 0" level="1" number="3" spellcasting="Witch" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Witch)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), 0" level="4" number="1" spellcasting="Witch" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Witch)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), 0" level="10" number="1" spellcasting="Witch" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Curses" type="Class Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_CURSES">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 1st level, you gain the ability to use curses, words of power that can cripple or charm your foes. You learn two curses of your choice, which are detailed at the end of this class description. You gain one additional curse at 6th, 10th, 14th, and 18th level. Additionally, when you gain a level in this class, you may choose one curse and replace it with another one.</p>
                <p class="indent">As a bonus action on your turn, you can attempt to curse a creature within 60ft of you. You may only have one curse active at a time, and the curse automatically ends if the creature moves more than 60ft away from you. You can use your curses twice at 1st level, and gain additional uses of your curses as you level up, as shown in the Curses column of the Witch table. You regain all expended uses of your curses when you finish a long rest.</p>
                <h5>Curses</h5>
                <p>Curses are words of power, simple words or phrases that carry enough malicious intent to bring their meaning to life. Many witches often find themselves uttering a curse by accident, simply through force of habit or a slip of the tongue.</p>
                <p class="indent">Most curses only last for a short period of time, and can be resisted by the target if they have a strong enough body or mind. The ’Remove Curse’ spell instantly ends any curse.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="{{curses:uses}}/Long Rest">
                <description>Curse Save {{spellcasting:dc:int}}</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="curses:uses" value="2" level="1" />
                <stat name="curses:uses" value="1" level="4" />
                <stat name="curses:uses" value="1" level="7" />
                <stat name="curses:uses" value="1" level="9" />
                <stat name="curses:uses" value="1" level="12" />
                <stat name="curses:uses" value="1" level="15" />
                <stat name="curses:uses" value="1" level="18" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Curse" supports="DMH Witch Curse" number="2" level="1" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Curse" supports="DMH Witch Curse" level="6" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Curse" supports="DMH Witch Curse" level="10" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Curse" supports="DMH Witch Curse" level="14" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Curse" supports="DMH Witch Curse" level="18" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Witch’s Familiar" type="Class Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_WITCHS_FAMILIAR">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 1st level, you gain a familiar, a fey creature who is able to transform itself into other animals. You learn the find familiar spell. You always have the spell prepared, and it does not count towards the number of spells you can prepare. When you gain this feature, choose one of the forms that a familiar can take. This becomes your familiar’s base form. When you summon your familiar in this form, the gold in materials you must spend to summon it is halved.</p>
                <div class="sidebar">
                    <h5 class="caption">Optional Rule: Intelligent Familiar</h5>
                    <p>Some players would like their familiar to be sentient, capable of speaking and giving advice. In such a situation, increase the familiar’s intelligence to 10, and give them the ability to speak any language that the witch speaks.</p>
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you summon your familiar in its base form, the gold in materials you must spend to summon it is halved.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIND_FAMILIAR" spellcasting="Witch" prepared="true" />
                <select type="Companion" name="Witch’s Familiar" supports="Familiar" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Witch’s Coven" type="Class Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_WITCHS_COVEN">
            <description>
                <p>Witches often band together in groups called covens, sharing information and magical secrets. The witches in these covens often specialize in a certain form of magic, such as summoning or augury. While joining one of these covens is the easiest way to learn these secrets, some witches prefer to keep to themselves, and instead learn the coven’s secrets in other ways.</p>
                <p class="indent">At 2nd level, you join a coven, which will shape the kind of witch you will become. Choose one of the following archetypes: Coven of Seers, Coven of the Wyld, Coven of Spirits, Coven of Spite, or Coven of Crones.</p>
                <p class="indent">Your choice grants you features at 2nd level, and again at 6th, 14th, and 18th level.</p>
                <h5>COVEN SPELLS</h5>
                <p>Each coven has a list of spells -it’s coven spells- that you gain at witch levels noted in the domain description. Once you gain a Coven Spell, you always have it prepared, and it doesn’t count against the number of spells you can prepare each day.</p>
                <p class="indent">If you have a coven spell that does not appear on the witch spell list, the spell is nonetheless a witch spell for you.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Archetype" name="Witch’s Coven" supports="DMH Witch Coven" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Ability Score Improvement" type="Class Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Witch 4)" supports="Improvement Option,Witch,4" level="4" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Witch 8)" supports="Improvement Option,Witch,8" level="8" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Witch 12)" supports="Improvement Option,Witch,12" level="12" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Witch 16)" supports="Improvement Option,Witch,16" level="16" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Witch 19)" supports="Improvement Option,Witch,19" level="19" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Metamorphic Familiar" type="Class Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_METAMORPHIC_FAMILIAR">
            <description>
                <p>At 5th level, you’ve grown accustomed to summoning and changing the form of your familiar, opening up new possibilities. When you summon your familiar in its base form, you can choose to give it one of the following traits. You can change your familiar’s trait during a long rest. At 15th level, you can choose to give your familiar two traits, and you can change one or both of them during a long rest.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Flight.</b> Your familiar gains a a flying speed of 30 feet if it didn’t already have it. Additionally, your familiar doesn’t provoke attacks of opportunity when it flies out of an opponents reach.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Aquatic Adaptation.</b> Your familiar gains a swim speed of 30 feet if it didn’t already have it, and it is able to breathe underwater.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Invisibility.</b> As an action, your familiar can magically turn invisible until it attacks, you cast a spell through it, or its concentration ends (As if concentrating on a spell).</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Magic Resistance.</b> Your familiar has advantage on saving throws against spells and other magical effects. Your familiar shares this trait with you if you are within 10 feet of your familiar.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Telepathy.</b> Your familiar can open a telepathic link between you and another creature. The link lasts until the familiar creates a new telepathic link, you or the other creature end the link (No action required), or one of you moves more than 100 feet away from the familiar. While the link is active, you and the other creature can communicate telepathically. Additionally, the other creature is able to see through your familiar’s senses, as per the find familiar spell.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you summon your familiar in its base form, you can choose to give it one of the following traits: Flight, Aquatic Adaptation, Invisibility, Magic Resistance or Telepathy. You can change your familiar’s trait during a long rest.</description>
                <description level="15">When you summon your familiar in its base form, you can choose to give it two of the following traits: Flight, Aquatic Adaptation, Invisibility, Magic Resistance or Telepathy. You can change one or both of them during a long rest.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Greater Familiar" type="Class Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_GREATER_FAMILIAR">
            <description>
                <p>At 10th level, your familiar becomes even more powerful, enabling it to better serve you. Your familiar gains the following features:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Your familar’s hit point maximum is equal to twice your witch level.</li>
                    <li>You can cast any spell through your familiar, regardless of the spell’s range.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can cast any spell through your familiar, regardless of the spell’s range.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="companion:hp:max" value="level:witch" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="companion:hp:max" value="level:witch" bonus="greater familiar" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Split Mind" type="Class Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_SPLIT_MIND">
            <description>
                <p>At 20th level, you and your familiar share an unbreakable bond, allowing them to carry the burden of your spells for you. When you are concentrating on a spell, you can use a bonus action to share the spell with your familiar, allowing them to concentrate on it for you. While your familiar is concentrating on a spell, you cannot cast other spells through your familiar, however you are free to concentrate on a different spell. Your familiar makes concentration checks in the same way that you do, but does not benefit from features that affect concentration checks, such as the War Caster feat.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>When you are concentrating on a spell, you can use a bonus action to share the spell with your familiar, allowing them to concentrate on it for you. While your familiar is concentrating on a spell, you cannot cast other spells through your familiar, however you are free to concentrate on a different spell. Your familiar makes concentration checks in the same way that you do, but does not benefit from features that affect concentration checks, such as the War Caster feat.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>

    <element name="Coven of Seers" type="Archetype" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_WITCH_COVEN_OF_SEERS">
        <supports>DMH Witch Coven</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Witches of the Coven of Seers are those gifted with foresight, the ability to glance through time to predict the future. They are able to use their magic to see through time, learning long lost secrets of the past, uncovering forgotten knowledge, peering into someone’s mind, or glimpsing into the future. Seers are the most commonly known witches, and though they are generally untrusted, there are many who would risk bargaining with a witch to gain insight into their future.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">Coven of Seers Spells</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Witch Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>augury, detect thoughts</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>clairvoyance, sending</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>7th</td><td><em>arcane eye, divination</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>9th</td><td><em>legend lore, scrying</em></td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_SEERS_PREDICTION" />
            <div element="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_SEERS_MINDS_EYE" />
            <div element="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_SEERS_BETWEEN_THE_LINES" />
            <div element="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_SEERS_PROPHECY" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AUGURY" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" prepared="true" level="3" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_THOUGHTS" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" prepared="true" level="3" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CLAIRVOYANCE" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" prepared="true" level="5" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SENDING" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" prepared="true" level="5" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ARCANE_EYE" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" prepared="true" level="7" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DIVINATION" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" prepared="true" level="7" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LEGEND_LORE" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" prepared="true" level="9" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SCRYING" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" prepared="true" level="9" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_SEERS_PREDICTION" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_SEERS_MINDS_EYE" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_SEERS_BETWEEN_THE_LINES" level="14" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_SEERS_PROPHECY" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Prediction" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_SEERS_PREDICTION">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 2nd level, you can peer into the near future, and attempt to force the future you see to come to pass. When you see creature make an attack roll, ability check, or saving throw, you can use your reaction to roll a d4, adding or subtracting the result to the creature’s roll.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can do this after the creature rolls but before the outcome of the roll is determined.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can use this ability a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier. When you finish a long rest, you regain all expended uses.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Reaction" usage="{{intelligence:modifier}}/Long Rest">
                <description>When you see creature make an attack roll, ability check, or saving throw, you can roll a d4, adding or subtracting the result to the creature’s roll.</description>
                <description level="14">When you see creature make an attack roll, ability check, or saving throw, you can roll two d4s, adding or subtracting the highest result to the creature’s roll.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Mind’s Eye" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_SEERS_MINDS_EYE">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, you become able to sense the presence of others around you, even when you cannot see or hear them. You gain blindsight within 30ft, allowing you to know the exact location of any hidden or invisible creatures within that radius. In addition, you can use an action to open your third eye, allowing you to sense if you are being magically watched.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>You can open your third eye, allowing you to sense if you are being magically watched.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_BLINDSIGHT" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Between the lines" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_SEERS_BETWEEN_THE_LINES">
            <description>
                <p>At 14th level, you recognize that fate holds more than one outcome, and that your prediction is only one of many possibilities. When you use your ’Prediction’ ability, you roll twice instead of once, and take the higher number.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Prophecy" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_SEERS_PROPHECY">
            <description>
                <p>At 18th level, you have learned how to predict everything that will happen in the near future, giving you the ability to prevent it. As an action, you can choose to begin predicting the future. Until the start of your next turn, allies that can hear you within 60 feet have advantage on all attack rolls, ability checks, and saving throws, and enemies have disadvantage on attack rolls against those allies.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this ability, you cannot do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>Until the start of your next turn, allies that can hear you within 60 feet have advantage on all attack rolls, ability checks, and saving throws, and enemies have disadvantage on attack rolls against those allies.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>

    <element name="Coven of Spite" type="Archetype" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_WITCH_COVEN_OF_SPITE">
        <supports>DMH Witch Coven</supports>
        <description>
            <p>For many, the path of the witch is one of freedom. While many witches are stigmatized as dark magicians and demon summoners, most choose this path as a way to be free of the restrictions of other mages. However, a select few choose to become witches not to be free to study magic in any way they see fit, but as a way to cause pain and suffering. Witches of the Coven of Spite see the potential in magic to torture and inflict pain, taking influence from demons, vampires, and other creatures of such ilk.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">Coven of The Spite Spells</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Witch Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>darkness, ray of enfeeblement</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>bestow curse, fear</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>7th</td><td><em>blight, phantasmal killer</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>9th</td><td><em>enervation, negative energy flood</em></td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_SPITE_CURSE_OF_SPITE" />
            <div element="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_SPITE_HEXMASTER" />
            <div element="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_SPITE_VAMPIRIC_CURSE" />
            <div element="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_SPITE_CACKLE" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DARKNESS" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" prepared="true" level="3" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RAY_OF_ENFEEBLEMENT" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" prepared="true" level="3" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BESTOW_CURSE" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" prepared="true" level="5" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FEAR" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" prepared="true" level="5" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLIGHT" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" prepared="true" level="7" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PHANTASMAL_KILLER" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" prepared="true" level="7" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ENERVATION" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" prepared="true" level="9" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_NEGATIVE_ENERGY_FLOOD" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" prepared="true" level="9" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_SPITE_CURSE_OF_SPITE" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_SPITE_HEXMASTER" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_SPITE_VAMPIRIC_CURSE" level="14" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_SPITE_CACKLE" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Curse of Spite" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_SPITE_CURSE_OF_SPITE">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 2nd level, you’ve begun delving into the darker side of magic. The magic is simple to learn, as it only has one purpose; to cause pain. You have a pool of d6s called curse die. The number of dice is equal to your witch level.</p>
                <p class="indent">When you cast a spell of 1st level or higher that targets another creature, you can choose to expend a number of curse die, dealing necrotic damage equal to the number rolled on the dice. The maximum number of dice you can spend at once equals your Intelligence modifier (minimum of one die).</p>
                <p class="indent">Your pool regains all expended dice when you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="{{level:witch}} Curse Dice/Long Rest">
                <description>You have a pool of {{level:witch}} curse dice (d6s). When you cast a spell of 1st level or higher that targets another creature, you can choose to expend a up to {{int-mod:min-one}} curse dice, dealing necrotic damage equal to the number rolled on the dice.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Hexmaster" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_SPITE_HEXMASTER">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, your proficiency with magic allows you to cut through a target’s defenses. Your spells and abilities ignore resistance to necrotic damage. In addition, your visage strikes fear into the hearts of those around you, giving hostile creatures within 10 feet of you disadvantage on saving throws against spells and abilities that cause the <b>frightened</b> condition.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Your spells and abilities ignore resistance to necrotic damage. In addition, your visage strikes fear into the hearts of those around you, giving hostile creatures within 10ft of you disadvantage on saving throws against spells and abilities that cause the frightened condition.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Vampiric Curse" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_SPITE_VAMPIRIC_CURSE">
            <description>
                <p>At 14th level, you’ve taken inspiration from vampires and other creatures that drain the life force of others. When you deal damage with your curse dice, you reduce the target’s hit point maximum by an equal amount. Additionally, you regain hit points equal to half the damage dealt by your curse dice.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you deal damage with your curse dice, you reduce the target’s hit point maximum by an equal amount. Additionally, you regain hit points equal to half the damage dealt by your curse dice.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Cackle" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_SPITE_CACKLE">
            <description>
                <p>At 18th level, your voice alone is enough to cause pain to those around you. As an action, you can begin cackling manically. For the next minute, creatures you choose within 60ft of you that can hear you must make a Wisdom saving throw at the start of their turn. On a failure, the creature is frightened of you. While frightened in this way, the creature has disadvantage on saving throws against your spells. The creature may repeat the saving throw at the start of their turn, taking 2d10 psychic damage on a failure, and ending the effect on a success.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this ability, you cannot use it again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You can cackling manically. For the next minute, creatures you choose within 60ft of you that can hear you must make a Wisdom saving throw (DC {{spellcasting:dc:int}}) at the start of their turn or be frightened of you. While frightened in this way, the creature has disadvantage on saving throws against your spells. The creature may repeat the saving throw at the start of their turn, taking 2d10 psychic damage on a failure, and ending the effect on a success.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>

    <element name="Coven of the Wyld" type="Archetype" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_WITCH_COVEN_OF_THE_WYLD">
        <supports>DMH Witch Coven</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Wyld Witches have a connection to nature, allowing them to exert their will on the wildlife around them. They also have an affinity for alchemy, allowing them to brew potions and other concoctions. These are the kinds of witches people mention in fairy tails, the green skinned hags living alone in the woods, leaning over a cauldron filled with a viscous purple liquid. While they may be untrustworthy, a Wyld Witch’s potion may be the only thing that can save you from your demise.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">Coven of the Wyld Spells</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Witch Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>barkskin, spike growth</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>plant growth, speak with plants</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>7th</td><td><em>blight, giant insect</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>9th</td><td><em>commune with nature, insect plague</em></td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_THE_WYLD_BONUS_PROFICIENCY" />
            <div element="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_THE_WYLD_POTION_BREWING" />
            <div element="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_THE_WYLD_ALCHEMICAL_KNOWLEDGE" />
            <div element="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_THE_WYLD_ADVANCED_BREWING" />
            <div element="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_THE_WYLD_QUICK_MIX" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BARKSKIN" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" prepared="true" level="3" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPIKE_GROWTH" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" prepared="true" level="3" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PLANT_GROWTH" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" prepared="true" level="5" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_PLANTS" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" prepared="true" level="5" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLIGHT" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" prepared="true" level="7" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GIANT_INSECT" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" prepared="true" level="7" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMMUNE_WITH_NATURE" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" prepared="true" level="9" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INSECT_PLAGUE" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" prepared="true" level="9" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_THE_WYLD_BONUS_PROFICIENCY" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_THE_WYLD_POTION_BREWING" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_THE_WYLD_ALCHEMICAL_KNOWLEDGE" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_THE_WYLD_ADVANCED_BREWING" level="14" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_THE_WYLD_QUICK_MIX" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Bonus Proficiency" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_THE_WYLD_BONUS_PROFICIENCY">
            <description>
                <p>When you choose this coven at 2nd level, you gain proficiency with the Nature skill and Herbalism Kits.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_NATURE" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_HERBALISM_KIT" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Potion Brewing" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_THE_WYLD_POTION_BREWING">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 2nd level, you learn to spend your spare time brewing potions. You learn to create two potions, which are detailed below. You learn to create an additional potion type at 6th, 10th, 14th, and 18th level.</p>
                <p class="indent">During a long rest, you can choose to spend some of that time brewing potions. At the end of a long rest, you create one potion. When creating potions that have multiple options, such as ’Elixir of Resistance’, you must choose one of the options while creating the potion. The potions do not require any herbs or material components, as they are primarily magical. Because of this, you are only able to create a maximum of 3 potions. If you create a 4th potion, one of your other potions loses its magical properties (Your choice).</p>
                <h5>Potion Options</h5>
                <p>Potions created by the Wyld Witch come in one of three forms: <b>Elixirs</b>, which can be consumed to provide beneficial effects, <b>Poisons</b>, which cause harmful effects to those who ingest or contact them, and <b>Oils</b>, which can be applied to weapons or armour.</p>
                <div class="sidebar">
                    <h5 class="caption">Rules for using Potions</h5>
                    <p><b>Drinking Elixirs:</b> Drinking an elixir costs an action. Your DM can choose to make this cost a bonus action instead. </p>
                    <p><b>Applying Poison:</b> Each vial of poison carries 3 charges. Applying poison to a weapon costs an action and 1 charge. The poison on the weapon wears off after 1 minute or after the first hit. This applies to both melee and ranged weapons. </p>
                    <p><b>Applying Oils:</b> Applying an oil takes 1 minute. The effect of the oil lasts for 1 hour.</p>
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>At the end of a long rest, you create one potion. You can have up to 3 potions brewed at the same time.</description>
                <description level="14">At the end of a short or long rest, you create one potion. You can have up to 3 potions brewed at the same time.</description>
                <description level="18">At the end of a short or long rest, you create up to three potions. You can have up to 3 potions brewed at the same time.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Coven of the Wyld Potion" supports="Coven of the Wyld Potion" number="2" level="2" />
                <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Coven of the Wyld Potion" supports="Coven of the Wyld Potion" level="6" />
                <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Coven of the Wyld Potion" supports="Coven of the Wyld Potion" level="10" />
                <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Coven of the Wyld Potion" supports="Coven of the Wyld Potion" level="14" />
                <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Coven of the Wyld Potion" supports="Coven of the Wyld Potion" level="18" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Alchemical Knowledge" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_THE_WYLD_ALCHEMICAL_KNOWLEDGE">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, you have become very accustomed to creating potions, and have a deep understanding of how they function. You have advantage on checks based on identifying potions and poisons. In addition, you have resistance to poison damage, and advantage on saving throws against being poisoned.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You have advantage on checks based on identifying potions and poisons. In addition, you have advantage on saving throws against being poisoned.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_POISON" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Advanced Brewing" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_THE_WYLD_ADVANCED_BREWING">
            <description>
                <p>At 14th level, you have become much more proficient at brewing potions. You are able to use your ’Potion Brewing’ feature during a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Quick Mix" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_THE_WYLD_QUICK_MIX">
            <description>
                <p>At 18th level, you have gained the ability to quickly mix a concoction in times of peril. When brewing potions during a long rest, you can brew up to three potions at the same time. They do not have to be the same type of potions.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, as an action, you can use your ’Potion Brewing’ to create one of your elixirs, poisons, or oils. Once you use this ability, you cannot do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You can use your ’Potion Brewing’ to create one of your elixirs, poisons, or oils.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>

    <element name="Coven of Spirits" type="Archetype" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_WITCH_COVEN_OF_SPIRITS">
        <supports>DMH Witch Coven</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Witches of the Coven of Spirits have a connection to The Ethereal Plane, the home of ghosts and spirits. This connection allows them to take on a more ethereal form, phasing in and out of the Ethereal Plane. This allows the witch to avoid blows, making them proficient fighters. Over time, the witch begins to exhibit ghost-like qualities, with some being able to separate their spirit from their body in times of peril.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">Coven of Spirits Spells</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Witch Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>blur, invisibility</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>blink, spirit guardians</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>7th</td><td><em>banishment, greater invisibility</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>9th</td><td><em>antilife shell, cone of cold</em></td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_SPIRITS_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" />
            <div element="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_SPIRITS_ETHEREAL_FORM" />
            <div element="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_SPIRITS_SWIFT_STRIKE" />
            <div element="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_SPIRITS_SPIRIT_CALLER" />
            <div element="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_SPIRITS_DEATH_WALKER" />
            <div element="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_SPIRITS_EMERGENCY_SHIFT" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLUR" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" prepared="true" level="3" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INVISIBILITY" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" prepared="true" level="3" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLINK" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" prepared="true" level="5" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPIRIT_GUARDIANS" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" prepared="true" level="5" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BANISHMENT" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" prepared="true" level="7" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GREATER_INVISIBILITY" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" prepared="true" level="7" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANTILIFE_SHELL" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" prepared="true" level="9" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONE_OF_COLD" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" prepared="true" level="9" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_SPIRITS_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_SPIRITS_ETHEREAL_FORM" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_SPIRITS_SWIFT_STRIKE" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_SPIRITS_SPIRIT_CALLER" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_SPIRITS_DEATH_WALKER" level="14" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_SPIRITS_EMERGENCY_SHIFT" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Bonus Proficiencies" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_SPIRITS_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES">
            <description>
                <p>When you choose this coven at 2nd level, you gain proficiency with Shields and Martial Weapons.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_SHIELDS" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_MARTIAL_WEAPONS" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Ethereal Form" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_SPIRITS_ETHEREAL_FORM">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 2nd level, your connection to the Ethereal Plane allows you to partially phase in and out. As a bonus action on your turn, you can transform for 1 minute. While in your Ethereal Form, you gain the following benefits:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>While not wearing armour, your AC equals 13 + Your Intelligence Modifier. You can use a shield and still gain this benefit.</li>
                    <li>You gain a fly speed equal to your movement speed. You fall if you end your turn in the air and nothing else is holding you aloft. At 14th level, you no longer fall if you end your turn in the air.</li>
                    <li>Creatures have disadvantage on attacks of opportunity against you.</li>
                    <li>You can choose to have your attacks deal force damage instead of their normal damage types.</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">You can transform a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="{{proficiency}}/Long Rest">
                <description>You can assume your Ethereal Form for up to 1 minute. While in your Ethereal Form, you gain the following benefits: your AC is {{ethereal-form:ac}}. You gain a fly speed of {{speed}}, falling if you end your turn in the air. Creatures have disadvantage on attacks of opportunity against you. You can choose to have your attacks deal force damage instead of their normal damage types.</description>
                <description level="14">You can assume your Ethereal Form for up to 1 minute. While in your Ethereal Form, you gain the following benefits: your AC is {{ethereal-form:ac}}. You gain a fly speed of {{speed}}. Creatures have disadvantage on attacks of opportunity against you. You can choose to have your attacks deal force damage instead of their normal damage types.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="ethereal-form:ac" value="13" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="ethereal-form:ac" value="intelligence:modifier" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Swift Strike" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_SPIRITS_SWIFT_STRIKE">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, when you cast a spell that has a range of self or touch, you can make one attack as a bonus action.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>When you cast a spell that has a range of self or touch, you can make one attack as a bonus action.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Spirit Caller" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_SPIRITS_SPIRIT_CALLER">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 6th level, your connection to the Ethereal Plane allows you to call on the spirits of the dead. You gain the ability to call on the spirit of a creature that you know is dead. To do so, you need to know their name, and you must be near their corpse or near the place that they died. Once you call on the spirit, they act as if under the effects of the <i>speak with dead</i> spell.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this ability, you cannot do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You can call a spirit of a creature that you know is dead. You need to call them by name and you must be near the corpse or place they died. Once you call on the spirit, they act as if under the effects of the speak with dead spell.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Death Walker" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_SPIRITS_DEATH_WALKER">
            <description>
                <p>At 14th level, your attunement to the ethereal plane has strengthened your spirit, allowing it to exist separately from your body. When you are reduced to 0 hit points and not killed outright, you can choose to separate your spirit from your body, allowing you to continue fighting. While in your spirit form, you continue making death saving throws as normal, but you also gain the following benefits:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Your spirit is immune to all damage.</li>
                    <li>Your spirit is able to move freely, and has a fly speed of 30ft, however it must remain within 60ft of your body.</li>
                    <li>You are able to attack, cast spells, and use curses as normal, however you cannot affect your own body.</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">Your spirit remains until you are stabilized, regain any hit points, or you die. Once you use this feature, you cannot do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>When you are reduced to 0 hit points and not killed outright, you can choose to separate your spirit from your body, allowing you to continue fighting. While in your spirit form, you continue making death saving throws as normal, but you also gain the following benefits: Your spirit is immune to all damage. Your spirit is able to move freely, and has a fly speed of 30ft, however it must remain within 60ft of your body. You are able to attack, cast spells, and use curses as normal, however you cannot affect your own body. Your spirit remains until you are stabilized, regain any hit points, or you die.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Emergency Shift" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_SPIRITS_EMERGENCY_SHIFT">
            <description>
                <p>By 18th level, your body has grown used to partially shifting in and out of the Ethereal Plane. Now, you’ve gained the ability to quickly shunt yourself into the Ethereal Plane to avoid harm. When you are hit with an attack, targeted by a spell or ability that would deal damage, or caught within an area of affect that would deal damage, you can use your reaction to quickly shift into the Ethereal Plane, avoiding all of the damage. You remain in the Ethereal Plane until the start of your next turn.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this ability, you cannot do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Reaction" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>When you are hit with an attack, targeted by a spell or ability that would deal damage, or caught within an area of affect that would deal damage, you can use your reaction to quickly shift into the Ethereal Plane, avoiding all of the damage. You remain in the Ethereal Plane until the start of your next turn.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>

    <element name="Coven of Crones" type="Archetype" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_WITCH_COVEN_OF_CRONES">
        <supports>DMH Witch Coven</supports>
        <description>
            <p>It is often said that the first witches were inspired by hags, learning how to channel magic in strange and uncontrolled ways from the fey creatures. Witches of the Coven of Crones take this a step further, learning spells and rituals that allow them to emulate the magic of hags, forming covens and making pacts with others. Many of these witches learn their magic directly from hags, making deals with the fey in exchange for knowledge, which they soon come to regret.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">Coven of Crones Spells</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Witch Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>alter self, invisibility</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>bestow curse, remove curse</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>7th</td><td><em>polymorph, witch’s broom</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>9th</td><td><em>geas, scrying</em></td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_CRONES_COVENANT_OF_THREE" />
            <div element="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_CRONES_FEY_PROTECTION" />
            <div element="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_CRONES_HAGS_EYE" />
            <div element="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_CRONES_BOND_OF_MAGIC" />
            <div element="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_CRONES_PROTECTION_OF_THE_COVENANT" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ALTER_SELF" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" prepared="true" level="3" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INVISIBILITY" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" prepared="true" level="3" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BESTOW_CURSE" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" prepared="true" level="5" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_REMOVE_CURSE" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" prepared="true" level="5" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_POLYMORPH" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" prepared="true" level="7" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_DMH_TW3_SPELL_WITCHS_BROOM" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" prepared="true" level="7" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GEAS" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" prepared="true" level="9" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SCRYING" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" prepared="true" level="9" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_CRONES_COVENANT_OF_THREE" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_CRONES_FEY_PROTECTION" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_CRONES_HAGS_EYE" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_CRONES_BOND_OF_MAGIC" level="14" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_CRONES_PROTECTION_OF_THE_COVENANT" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Covenant of Three" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_CRONES_COVENANT_OF_THREE">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 2nd level, your study of hags has granted you the ability to perform a ritual to form a coven. You can perform a 10 minute ritual with 2 other willing humanoids, forming a coven with them. This coven lasts until you finish a long rest, one of the members of the coven falls to 0 hit points, or one of the coven members chooses to end the coven (No action required). You can only be in one coven at a time.</p>
                <p class="indent">When you create the coven, choose a number of spells equal to your proficiency modifier. These must be spells that you have prepared and they must be of 5th level or lower. While the coven is active, you can use your reaction on one of the coven member’s turns to allow them to cast one of these spells. The spell is cast using your spellcasting ability, and thus uses your spell attack bonus and spell save DC, and casting the spell consumes one of your spell slots.</p>
                <p class="indent">After one of your coven members casts a spell using this feature, you cannot cast spells other than cantrips until the end of your next turn. Additionally, if one of your coven members uses this feature to cast a concentration spell, you lose concentration on any spells you are concentrating on, and vice versa.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can perform a 10 minute ritual with 2 other willing humanoids, forming a coven with them. This coven lasts until you finish a long rest, one of the members of the coven falls to 0 hit points, or one of the coven members chooses to end the coven (No action required). You can only be in one coven at a time. When you create the coven, choose up to {{proficiency}} spells you have prepared of 5th level or lower.
                While the coven is active, you can use your reaction on one of the coven member’s turns to allow them to cast one of these spells. The spell is cast using your spellcasting ability, and thus uses your spell attack bonus and spell save DC, and casting the spell consumes one of your spell slots.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Fey Protection" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_CRONES_FEY_PROTECTION">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, working with the fey has granted your protection against some of their magic. You have advantage on saving throws against being charmed or frightened.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You have advantage on saving throws against being charmed or frightened.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Hag’s Eye" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_CRONES_HAGS_EYE">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 6th level, you have learned how to create a Hag’s Eye, an amulet that allows you and your coven members to observe the world around it. By performing a 1 hour ritual with your coven members, you can create a Hag’s Eye. The eye has an AC of 10 and hit points equal to your witch level.  </p>
                <p class="indent">If the coven is broken, then the eye becomes inert until the coven is reformed. If the eye is destroyed, then members of the coven have disadvantage on attack rolls and perceptions checks that rely on sight until they finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>By performing a 1 hour ritual with your coven members, you can create a Hag’s Eye. The eye has an AC of 10 and {{level:witch}} hit points. As an action, a coven member can see through the eye, seeing whatever the eye does, as long as the eye is on the same plane of existence.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Bond of Magic" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_CRONES_BOND_OF_MAGIC">
            <description>
                <p>At 14th level, the magical bond you share with the members of your coven allows you to share your magical protection. You and your coven members share your resistances and immunities.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, when a member of the coven is affected by a spell, you can choose for the spell to affect all members of the coven. Once you use this ability, you cannot do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You and your coven members share your resistances and immunities. Additionally, when a member of the coven is affected by a spell, you can choose for the spell to affect all members of the coven. Once you use this ability, you cannot do so again until you finish a long rest.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Protection of the Covenant" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_CRONES_PROTECTION_OF_THE_COVENANT">
            <description>
                <p>At 18th level, the members of your coven are able to use your magical bond to protect each other. You gain a second reaction that can only be used for your ’Covenant of Three’ or ’Protection of the Covenant’ features.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, when one of the coven members is attacked or forced to make a saving throw, another coven member can use their reaction to grant the target their AC or saving throw Modifier. For example, if the witch is being attacked, a fighter in the coven can use their reaction to grant the witch their AC. Similarly, if the fighter is forced to make an Intelligence saving throw, the witch can allow the fighter to use their Intelligence saving throw Modifier instead of the fighter’s. You must choose to use this feature before any rolls are made.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You gain a second reaction that can only be used for your ’Covenant of Three’ or ’Protection of the Covenant’ features. Additionally, when one of the coven members is attacked or forced to make a saving throw, another coven member can use their reaction to grant the target their AC or saving throw Modifier. </description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>

    <!-- Witch Curses -->
        <element name="Agony" type="Class Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_CURSE_AGONY">
            <supports>DMH Witch Curse</supports>
            <description>
                <p>The target is wracked with pain, making every minor cut feel like a fatal injury. The creature must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failure, for the next minute, whenever any creature deals damage to the cursed creature, they may reroll 1s on the damage die. They must use the new roll.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Curse">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Bind" type="Class Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_CURSE_BIND">
            <supports>DMH Witch Curse</supports>
            <description>
                <p>You attempt to charm the creature’s legs, preventing them from moving. The creature must make a Strength saving throw. On a failure, for the next minute, the creature’s speed is 0. The creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of their turn, ending the curse on a success.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Curse">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Bleed" type="Class Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_CURSE_BLEED">
            <supports>DMH Witch Curse</supports>
            <description>
                <p>You curse a creature, causing blood to pour from any open wounds. The creature must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failure, for the next minute, they cannot regain hit points, and suffer an additional 1d4 damage whenever they are hit by a weapon attack. This curse does not work on undead or constructs.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Curse">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Doubt" type="Class Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_CURSE_DOUBT">
            <supports>DMH Witch Curse</supports>
            <description>
                <p>You force feelings of doubt into a creature’s heart, making them hesitate. The creature must make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failure, for the next minute, whenever they try to attack a creature, they must make an additional Wisdom saving throw. If they fail, they must use their action for something other than attacking. This curse does not stop them from harming creatures with area effects, such as a Dragon’s Breath Attack. The cursed creature may repeat the saving throw at the end of their turn or whenever they take damage, ending the curse on a success.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Curse">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Empathy" type="Class Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_CURSE_EMPATHY">
            <supports>DMH Witch Curse</supports>
            <description>
                <p>You form a bond with the target, forcing them to feel your pain. The creature must make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failure, for the next minute, whenever you take damage, you can use your reaction to cause the target to take psychic damage equal to your witch level. At the end of the cursed creatures turn, or whenever they take damage from this curse, they can repeat the saving throw, ending the curse on a sucess.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Curse" action="Reaction">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Mark" type="Class Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_CURSE_MARK">
            <supports>DMH Witch Curse</supports>
            <description>
                <p>The target has a magical mark placed on them, guiding others spells and weapons. The creature must make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failure, for the next minute, creatures other than you have advantage on attack rolls against the cursed creature. Once the cursed target has been hit with an attack, the mark disappears, reappearing at the start of your next turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Curse">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Rage" type="Class Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_CURSE_RAGE">
            <supports>DMH Witch Curse</supports>
            <description>
                <p>You force feelings of rage into a creature’s heart, causing them to lash out at everyone around them. The creature must make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failure, on the creature’s next turn, the cursed creature must spend their action attacking the nearest creature. If they have multi-attack, they must use it.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Curse">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Scar" type="Class Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_CURSE_SCAR">
            <supports>DMH Witch Curse</supports>
            <description>
                <p>You place an invisible mark on a creature, allowing you to monitor them, no matter how far away they are. The creature must make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failure, they are marked until you end the effect. While the target is marked, you sense the direction to the creature’s location, and know how far away they are. A creature that succeeds on their saving throw is immune to this curse for 24 hours.</p>
                <p class="indent">Unlike other curses, Scar does not end if the target creature moves more than 60ft away.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Curse">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Silence" type="Class Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_CURSE_SILENCE">
            <supports>DMH Witch Curse</supports>
            <description>
                <p>You attempt to charm the creatures tongue, forcing them to be silent. The creature must make a Charisma saving throw. On a failure, they are silenced until the end of their next turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Curse">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Terror" type="Class Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_CURSE_TERROR">
            <supports>DMH Witch Curse</supports>
            <description>
                <p>You force feeling of fear into a creature’s heart, shaking them to their core. The creature must make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failure, choose an creature or object that you can see. For the next minute, the cursed creature is considered <i>frightened</i> of the creature or object you chose. The cursed creature may repeat the saving throw at the end of their turn, ending the curse on a success.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Curse">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Truth" type="Class Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_CURSE_TRUTH">
            <supports>DMH Witch Curse</supports>
            <description>
                <p>You attempt to charm the creature’s tongue, preventing them from lying. The creature must make a Charisma saving throw. If they fail, they are unable to tell a deliberate lie for 1 minute. A creature that succeeds on their saving throw is immune to this curse for 24 hours.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Curse">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Wither" type="Class Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_CURSE_WITHER">
            <supports>DMH Witch Curse</supports>
            <description>
                <p>You cause the creature to rapidly age, slowing them down. The creature must make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failure, for the next minute, they lose the ability to take reactions, and on their turn, they can use an Action or a Bonus Action, not both. At the end of the creature’s turn, they can repeat the saving throw, ending the effect on a success.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Curse">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>

    <!-- Coven of the Wyld Potion Options -->
        <element name="Elixir of Healing" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_THE_WYLD_POTION_ELIXIR_OF_HEALING">
            <supports>Coven of the Wyld Potion</supports>
            <description>
                <p>A creature can drink this elixir to regain 2d8 hit points. The healing increases to 4d8 at 6th level, 6d8 at 10th level, and 8d8 at 14th level.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Wyld Potion">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Elixir of Resistance" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_THE_WYLD_POTION_ELIXIR_OF_RESISTANCE">
            <supports>Coven of the Wyld Potion</supports>
            <description>
                <p>When you create this elixir, choose a damage type: Acid, Fire, Cold, Lightning, Poison, Radiant, or Necrotic. A creature that drinks this elixir gains resistance to that damage type for 10 minutes. At 10th level, the duration increases to 1 hour.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Wyld Potion">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Elixir of Vitality" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_THE_WYLD_POTION_ELIXIR_OF_VITALITY">
            <supports>Coven of the Wyld Potion</supports>
            <description>
                <p>A creature that drinks this elixir is instantly cured of any disease or poison afflicting them.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Wyld Potion">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Silver Tongue Elixir" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_THE_WYLD_POTION_SILVER_TONGUE_ELIXIR">
            <supports>Coven of the Wyld Potion</supports>
            <description>
                <p>A creature that drinks this elixir has advantage on Charisma checks for 10 minutes. At 10th level, the duration increases to 1 hour.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Wyld Potion">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Elixir of Potential" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_THE_WYLD_POTION_ELIXIR_OF_POTENTIAL">
            <supports>Coven of the Wyld Potion</supports>
            <description>
                <p>When you create this elixir, choose an ability score: Strength, Dexterity, Constitution, Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma. A creature that drinks this elixir has the chosen ability score increased by +2 for 1 minute. This bonus cannot increase an ability score past 20. At 10th level, the duration increases to 1 hour, and at 14th level, the bonus increases to +4.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Wyld Potion">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Elixir of Life" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_THE_WYLD_POTION_ELIXIR_OF_LIFE">
            <supports>Coven of the Wyld Potion</supports>
            <description>
                <p>A creature that drinks this elixir gains 5 temporary hit points at the start of its turn for 1 minute. The amount of temporary hit points gained increases to 7 at 6th level, 10 at 10th level, and 12 at 14th level.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Wyld Potion">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Elixir of Speed" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_THE_WYLD_POTION_ELIXIR_OF_SPEED">
            <supports>Coven of the Wyld Potion</supports>
            <description>
                <p>A creature that drinks this elixir has their speed increased by 10 feet for 1 hour. This bonus increases to 20 feet at 10th level.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Wyld Potion">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Pure Poison" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_THE_WYLD_POTION_PURE_POISON">
            <supports>Coven of the Wyld Potion</supports>
            <description>
                <p>A creature that is subjected to this poison must make a Constitution saving throw, suffering 3d4 poison damage on a fail, or half as much on a success. This damage increases to 4d4 at 6th level, 5d4 at 10th level, and 6d4 at 14th level.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Wyld Potion">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Paralysis Poison" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_THE_WYLD_POTION_PARALYSIS_POISON">
            <supports>Coven of the Wyld Potion</supports>
            <description>
                <p>A creature that is subjected to this poison must make a Constitution saving throw, or be poisoned until the end of their next turn. The poisoned creature is paralyzed.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once a creature has been affected by this poison, they become immune to its effects for 24 hours.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Wyld Potion">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Drow Poison" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_THE_WYLD_POTION_DROW_POISON">
            <supports>Coven of the Wyld Potion</supports>
            <description>
                <p>A creature that is subjected to this poison must make a Constitution saving throw, or be poisoned for 1 hour. If the creature fails the saving throw by 5 or more, the creature is also unconscious while poisoned in this way. The creature wakes up if it takes damage or if another creature takes an action to shake it awake.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Wyld Potion">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Weakening Poison" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_THE_WYLD_POTION_WEAKENING_POISON">
            <supports>Coven of the Wyld Potion</supports>
            <description>
                <p>A creature that is subjected to this poison must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failure, any weapon attack they make deals 1d4 less damage for 1 minute.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once a creature has been affected by this poison, they become immune to its effects for 24 hours.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Wyld Potion">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Oil of Sharpness" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_THE_WYLD_POTION_OIL_OF_SHARPNESS">
            <supports>Coven of the Wyld Potion</supports>
            <description>
                <p>A creature can spend 1 minute applying this oil to a non-magical weapon or 10 pieces of ammo. For the next hour, the weapon or ammo has a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls. This bonus increases to +2 at 10t level, and +3 at 14th level.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Wyld Potion">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Elemental Oil" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_THE_WYLD_POTION_ELEMENTAL_OIL">
            <supports>Coven of the Wyld Potion</supports>
            <description>
                <p>A creature can spend 1 minute applying this oil to a non-magical weapon. For the next hour, the weapon deals an additional 1d4 fire, cold, or lightning damage. The damage increases to 1d6 at 6th level, 1d8 at 10th level, and 1d10 at 14th level.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Wyld Potion">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Armour Polish Oil" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_THE_WYLD_POTION_ARMOUR_POLISH_OIL">
            <supports>Coven of the Wyld Potion</supports>
            <description>
                <p>A creature can spend 1 minute applying this oil to a piece of non-magical armour or shield. For the next hour, the armour grants an additional +1 bonus to the creature’s AC. This bonus increases to +2 at 10t level, and +3 at 14th level.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Wyld Potion">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Iron Skin Oil" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COVEN_OF_THE_WYLD_POTION_IRON_SKIN_OIL">
            <supports>Coven of the Wyld Potion</supports>
            <description>
                <p>A creature can spend 1 minute applying this oil to their skin. For the next hour, the creature’s AC cannot be lower than 13, regardless of what kind of armour it is wearing. The AC increases to 15 at 10th level, and 17 at 14th level.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Wyld Potion">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>

    <!-- Witch Skills -->
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ARCANA">
        <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_DECEPTION">
        <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT">
        <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INTIMIDATION">
        <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_MEDICINE">
        <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_NATURE">
        <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION">
        <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERSUASION">
        <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_RELIGION">
        <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SURVIVAL">
        <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
    </append>

    <!-- Witch Spell List -->
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLADE_WARD">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CHILL_TOUCH">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FRIENDS">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_FROSTBITE">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LIGHT">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGE_HAND">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MINOR_ILLUSION">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_POISON_SPRAY">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PRESTIDIGITATION">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_PRIMAL_SAVAGERY">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RAY_OF_FROST">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHOCKING_GRASP">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_TOLL_THE_DEAD">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ABSORB_ELEMENTS">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ALARM">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ARMOR_OF_AGATHYS">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ARMS_OF_HADAR">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BANE">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_CAUSE_FEAR">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CHARM_PERSON">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMPREHEND_LANGUAGES">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_MAGIC">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISGUISE_SELF">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISSONANT_WHISPERS">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FALSE_LIFE">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FEATHER_FALL">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HELLISH_REBUKE">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HEX">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INFLICT_WOUNDS">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGE_ARMOR">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PROTECTION_FROM_GOOD_AND_EVIL">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RAY_OF_SICKNESS">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHIELD">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SILENT_IMAGE">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SLEEP">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TASHAS_HIDEOUS_LAUGHTER">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WITCH_BOLT">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ALTER_SELF">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ARCANE_LOCK">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLINDNESS_DEAFNESS">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CROWN_OF_MADNESS">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DARKNESS">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DARKVISION">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_THOUGHTS">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HOLD_PERSON">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INVISIBILITY">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_KNOCK">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LEVITATE">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LOCATE_OBJECT">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGIC_MOUTH">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MIRROR_IMAGE">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MISTY_STEP">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PHANTASMAL_FORCE">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RAY_OF_ENFEEBLEMENT">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_SHADOW_BLADE">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SILENCE">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SUGGESTION">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANIMATE_DEAD">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BESTOW_CURSE">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COUNTERSPELL">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISPEL_MAGIC">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ENEMIES_ABOUND">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FEAR">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FLY">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GASEOUS_FORM">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GLYPH_OF_WARDING">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HYPNOTIC_PATTERN">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LEOMUNDS_TINY_HUT">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_LIFE_TRANSFERENCE">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LIGHTNING_BOLT">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGIC_CIRCLE">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAJOR_IMAGE">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_NONDETECTION">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_REMOVE_CURSE">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SENDING">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_DEAD">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SLOW">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_SUMMON_LESSER_DEMONS">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TONGUES">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_VAMPIRIC_TOUCH">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ARCANE_EYE">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BANISHMENT">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLIGHT">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_CHARM_MONSTER">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONFUSION">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DIMENSION_DOOR">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DOMINATE_BEAST">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GREATER_INVISIBILITY">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HALLUCINATORY_TERRAIN">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PHANTASMAL_KILLER">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_POLYMORPH">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_SHADOW_OF_MOIL">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_SICKENING_RADIANCE">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_SUMMON_GREATER_DEMON">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANIMATE_OBJECTS">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AWAKEN">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CLOUDKILL">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONTAGION">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_DANSE_MACABRE">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISPEL_EVIL_AND_GOOD">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DOMINATE_PERSON">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ENERVATION">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DREAM">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GEAS">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HOLD_MONSTER">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_INFERNAL_CALLING">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MODIFY_MEMORY">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_NEGATIVE_ENERGY_FLOOD">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PLANAR_BINDING">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SCRYING">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SEEMING">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TELEPORTATION_CIRCLE">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ARCANE_GATE">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_BONES_OF_THE_EARTH">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CIRCLE_OF_DEATH">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CREATE_UNDEAD">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISINTEGRATE">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_EYEBITE">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FLESH_TO_STONE">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FORBIDDANCE">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HARM">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGIC_JAR">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MASS_SUGGESTION">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_MENTAL_PRISON">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PLANAR_ALLY">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PROGRAMED_ILLUSION">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_SOUL_CAGE">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ETHEREALNESS">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FINGER_OF_DEATH">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FORCECAGE">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MIRAGE_ARCANE">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PLANE_SHIFT">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_POWER_WORD_PAIN">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PROJECT_IMAGE">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SEQUESTER">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SYMBOL">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TELEPORT">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ABI_DALZIMS_HORRID_WILTING">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANTIPATHY_SYMPATHY">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CLONE">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DEMIPLANE">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DOMINATE_MONSTER">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FEEBLEMIND">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GLIBNESS">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_MADDENING_DARKNESS">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAZE">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MIND_BLANK">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_POWER_WORD_STUN">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ASTRAL_PROJECTION">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FORESIGHT">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GATE">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_IMPRISONMENT">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_MASS_POLYMORPH">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_POWER_WORD_KILL">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_PSYCHIC_SCREAM">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHAPECHANGE">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TRUE_POLYMORPH">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WEIRD">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
        </append>

    <!-- New Witch Spells -->
        <element name="Animate Hair" type="Spell" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_SPELL_ANIMATE_HAIR">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
            <description>
                <p>Your hair extends and comes to life, attempting to restrain your foes. Make a grapple check against a creature within 5 feet of you, using your Spell Attack Bonus instead of Athletics. While a creature is grappled by your hair, it takes 1d4 damage at the start of your turn.</p>
                <p class="indent">The spell’s damage increases by 1d4 when you reach 5th level (2d4), 11th level (3d4), and 17th level (4d4).</p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="keywords"></set>
                <set name="level">0</set>
                <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
                <set name="isRitual">false</set>
                <set name="time">1 action</set>
                <set name="range">Self</set>
                <set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
                <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
                <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
                <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
                <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
        <element name="Cursed Land" type="Spell" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_SPELL_CURSED_LAND">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
            <description>
                <p>You touch a point and lay a curse on the land, infusing it with dark magic. The area can have a radius of up to 60 feet, and the spell fails if an area is under the effects of the hallow spell. The affected area is subject to the following effects:</p>
                <p class="indent">First, all forms of plant life within the area wither and die, and the ground is no longer able to support life. Any attempts at growing plants through magical or non-magical means automatically fails.</p>
                <p class="indent">Second, you can bind an extra effect to the area. Choose the effect from the following list, or choose an effect offered by the DM. Some of these effects apply to creatures in the area, you can designate whether the effect applies to all creatures, creatures that follow a specific deity or leader, or creatures of a specific sort, such as ores or trolls. When a creature that would be affected enters the spell’s area for the first time on a turn or starts its turn there, it can make a Charisma saving throw. On a success, the creature ignores the extra effect until it leaves the area.</p>
                <p class="indent">Bolster Evil. Fiends and Undead gain a bonus to attack and damage rolls equal to your Intelligence Modifier while within the area.</p>
                <p class="indent">Fear Affected creatures are Frightened while in the area.</p>
                <p class="indent">Misfortune. Affected creatures subtract 1d4 from their attack rolls and saving throws.</p>
                <p class="indent">Necrosis. Affected creatures take an additional 1d8 necrotic damage from attacks and spells.</p>
                <p class="indent">Toxic Aura. Affected creatures have disadvantage on attack rolls and skill checks while in the area.</p>
                <p class="indent">Turn Resistance. Undead within the area have advantage on saving throws against turning effects.</p>
                <p class="indent">Withering Field. Affected creatures gain 1 point of exhaustion.</p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="keywords"></set>
                <set name="level">5</set>
                <set name="school">evocation</set>
                <set name="isRitual">false</set>
                <set name="time">24 hours</set>
                <set name="range">Touch</set>
                <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
                <set name="materialComponent">Herbs, oils, and gems worth 1000gp, which the spell consumes</set>
                <set name="duration">Until dispelled</set>
                <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
        <element name="Curse of Vulnerability" type="Spell" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_SPELL_CURSE_OF_VULNERABILITY">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
            <description>
                <p>You touch a creature, and it must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw. On a failure, they gain vulnerability to one damage type of your choice. A creature can repeat this saving throw at the start of their turn, ending the effect on a success.</p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="keywords"></set>
                <set name="level">7</set>
                <set name="school">necromancy</set>
                <set name="isRitual">false</set>
                <set name="time">1 action</set>
                <set name="range">Touch</set>
                <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
                <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
                <set name="duration">Concentration, 1 minute</set>
                <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
        <element name="Witch’s Broom" type="Spell" source="The Witch v3" id="ID_DMH_TW3_SPELL_WITCHS_BROOM">
            <supports>DMH Witch</supports>
            <description>
                <p>You enchant an ordinary broom with the power of flight. The broom has an AC of 10 and a number of hit points equal to 2 times your witch level. While riding the broom, you have a fly speed of 40 feet. The broom can carry up to two people, but while two people are riding it, its speed is reduced to 20 feet.</p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="keywords"></set>
                <set name="level">4</set>
                <set name="school">transmutation</set>
                <set name="isRitual">false</set>
                <set name="time">1 minute</set>
                <set name="range">Touch</set>
                <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
                <set name="materialComponent">A mundane broom</set>
                <set name="duration">1 hour</set>
                <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            </setters>
        </element>


</elements>