<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Fey’Ri Demon Elves</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="race-feyri.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/dmhavuhk/race-feyri.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Fey’Ri Race" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_DMH_FEYRI_SOURCE_FEYRI_RACE">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation">FEYRI</set>
            <set name="url">https://www.gmbinder.com/share/-MMvBiGPfZvHkW9AT2Oq</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" abbreviation="DMH" url="https://www.gmbinder.com/profile/dmhavuhk">DMHavuhk</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20210116</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Fey’Ri" type="Race" source="Fey’Ri Race" id="ID_DMH_FEYRI_RACE_FEYRI">
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Rinn was never a normal girl. I knew that from a young age. She never seemed to get along with the other children, and she seemed to find some sick pleasure in hurting them. I tried my best to discourage it, but it almost seemed natural to her. But as she grew up, I stared to understand why she seemed so different from the rest of us. Her skin started to turn paler, almost stark white, and a pair of horns began to sprout from her forehead. She wasn’t elven, she was Fey’ri. I should have known that the demon blood in my veins would eventually rear its ugly head. I should have know that this could happen.</p>
            <p class="flavor indent">But now that I understand that Rinn is different, I can raise her better. Some of my friends brought up the idea of dropping her off at some orphanage or just leaving her in the streets. But I could never do that. No matter what, she is my daughter, and I will never abandon her. If the blood of demons will try to make her a monster, then I will just have to use my love to make her better. She cannot control how she was born, but together, we can help guide her towards the right path, and see who she will become.</p>
            <p class="indent">The Fey’ri, also known as Demon Elves of Daemonfey, are to elves what tieflings are to humans. They are elves cursed with a demonic bloodline, whether is be due to a pact made with an entity of the Abyss that their family made generations ago, or due to a spiteful demon cursing an elf’s birth. Often times, a Fey’ri can be born from a normal elven family, seemingly for no reason, and some can appear as normal elves for years, sometimes even into adulthood. However, their demonic blood will eventually rear its ugly face, and any who see their demonic features will instantly know what they are.</p>
            <h4>DEMONIC BLOODLINE</h4>
            <p>The Fey’ri look elven in most ways, however their demonic heritage manifests in many different ways, such as horns, tails, wings, extra arms, and unusual skin colors, from extremely pale, to odd colors such as purple or red.</p>
            <p class="indent">However, thanks to the magic granted to them by their demonic bloodline, Fey’ri have the ability to mask their appearance, making themselves appear to others as a normal elf, allowing them to blend into society. Its rare to see a Fey’ri in cities, as most will not openly walk around with their demonic features on display.</p>
            <h4>THE VALUE OF FREEDOM</h4>
            <p>Above all else, the Fey’ri value freedom. This comes from both their elven heritage, and the desire to escape the grasp of their demonic blood. Most Fey’ri simply wish to live a normal life, with no one knowing of their curse.</p>
            <p class="indent">However, others embrace their demonic blood, and wish to live free without persecution from others. To them, their demonic features are simply another part of who they are, not something to be hidden, and not something to feel shame from. These Fey’ri usually band together to make their own towns and civilizations.</p>
            <h4>FEY’RI NAMES</h4>
            <p>Due to being born to elven families, many Fey’ri simply have elven names. However, for those that were born to and raised by other Fey’ri, they use names that are a mix of elvish and abyssal, though most usually have a fake elven name that they use when speaking to those that do not know of their demonic heritage.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b>Male Names:</b> Adran, Aelar, Aramil, Arannis, Aust, Beiro, Berrian, Carric, Enialis, Erdan, Erevan, Galinndan, Hadarai, Heian, Himo, Immeral, Ivellios, Laucian, Mindartis, Paelias, Peren, Quarion, Riardon, Rolen, Soveliss, Thamior, Tharivol, Theren, Varis</p>
            <p class="indent"><b>Female Names:</b> Adrie, Althaea, Anastrianna, Andraste, Antinua, Bethrynna, Birel, Caelynn, Drusilia, Enna, Felosial, Ielenia, Jelenneth, Keyleth, Leshanna, Lia, Meriele, Mialee, Naivara, Quelenna, Quillathe, Sariel, Shanairra, Shava, Silaqui, Theirastra, Thia, Vadania, Valanthe, Xanaphia</p>
            <p class="indent"><b>Androgynous Names:</b> </p>
            <h4>FEY’RI TRAITS</h4>
            <p>Fey’Ri share certain traits with their elven cousins, but due to their demonic ancestry, they have some innately magical abilities.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong> Your Dexterity and Intelligence scores both increase by 1.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Age.</em></strong> Fey’Ri mature at the same rate as humans, reaching adulthood by age 20, though most aren’t considered adults until they are 100. Due to their elven heritage, they can live for centuries, with many being able to live as long as 1000 years.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Alignment.</em></strong> Fey’Ri follow the alignment preferences of their elven families.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Size.</em></strong> Similarly to elves, fey’ri range from around 5 feet to well over 6 feet tall. Your size is medium.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Speed.</em></strong> Your base walking speed is 30 feet.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Darkvision.</em></strong> Thanks to both your elven and demonic heritage, you have superior vision in dark and dim conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can’t discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Demonfey Ancestry.</em></strong> You have advantage on saving throws against being charmed, and magic can’t put you to sleep.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Trance.</em></strong> Fey’ri don’t need to sleep, instead only needing to meditate for 4 hours to gain the benefits of a long rest.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Elven Mask.</em></strong> Fey’Ri are able to use their magic to hide their demonic features. As an action, you can change your appearance, appearing to others as a normal elf. You can change back to your normal form as an action.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Languages.</em></strong> You know Common, Elvish, and Abyssal.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Subrace.</em></strong> A Fey’ri’s demonic blood can manifest itself in many different ways, giving them different demonic features and abilities. Fey’ri have been classified into four different categories: Barbed Fey’ri, Brute Fey’ri, Forked Fey’ri, and Winged Fey’ri.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <stat name="intelligence" value="1" />
            <stat name="dexterity" value="1" />
			<stat name="innate speed" value="30" bonus="base" />
			<grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_MEDIUM" />
			<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON" />
			<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_ELVISH" />
			<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_ABYSSAL" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_DMH_FEYRI_RACIAL_TRAIT_FEYRI_DARKVISION" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_DMH_FEYRI_RACIAL_TRAIT_FEYRI_DEMONFEY_ANCESTRY" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_DMH_FEYRI_RACIAL_TRAIT_FEYRI_TRANCE" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_DMH_FEYRI_RACIAL_TRAIT_FEYRI_ELVEN_MASK" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_DMH_FEYRI_RACIAL_TRAIT_FEYRI_SUBRACE" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Darkvision" type="Racial Trait" source="Fey’Ri Race" id="ID_DMH_FEYRI_RACIAL_TRAIT_FEYRI_DARKVISION">
            <description>
                <p>Thanks to both your elven and demonic heritage, you have superior vision in dark and dim conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can’t discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_DARKVISION" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Demonfey Ancestry" type="Racial Trait" source="Fey’Ri Race" id="ID_DMH_FEYRI_RACIAL_TRAIT_FEYRI_DEMONFEY_ANCESTRY">
            <description>
                <p>You have advantage on saving throws against being charmed, and magic can’t put you to sleep.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You have advantage on saving throws against being charmed, and magic can’t put you to sleep.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Trance" type="Racial Trait" source="Fey’Ri Race" id="ID_DMH_FEYRI_RACIAL_TRAIT_FEYRI_TRANCE">
            <description>
                <p>Fey’ri don’t need to sleep, instead only needing to meditate for 4 hours to gain the benefits of a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You don’t need to sleep, instead only needing to meditate for 4 hours to gain the benefits of a long rest.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Elven Mask" type="Racial Trait" source="Fey’Ri Race" id="ID_DMH_FEYRI_RACIAL_TRAIT_FEYRI_ELVEN_MASK">
            <description>
                <p>Fey’Ri are able to use their magic to hide their demonic features. As an action, you can change your appearance, appearing to others as a normal elf. You can change back to your normal form as an action.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>You can change your appearance, appearing to others as a normal elf. You can change back to your normal form as an action.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Subrace" type="Racial Trait" source="Fey’Ri Race" id="ID_DMH_FEYRI_RACIAL_TRAIT_FEYRI_SUBRACE">
            <description>
                <p>A Fey’ri’s demonic blood can manifest itself in many different ways, giving them different demonic features and abilities. Fey’ri have been classified into four different categories: Barbed Fey’ri, Brute Fey’ri, Forked Fey’ri, and Winged Fey’ri.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false" />
            <rules>
                <select type="Sub Race" name="Fey’Ri Subrace" supports="Fey’Ri" />
            </rules>
        </element>


    <element name="Barbed Fey’ri" type="Sub Race" source="Fey’Ri Race" id="ID_DMH_FEYRI_SUBRACE_FEYRI_BARBED_FEYRI">
        <supports>Fey’Ri</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Barbed Fey’ri are born with long tails, which have large barbs and thorns attached to them, usually towards the end of the tail. These Fey’ri make proficient fighters, often using their tails in combat to catch their enemies off guard and to strike at fleeing foes. This is reinforced by the magic granted to them, which makes them proficient warriors and killers.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong> Your Strength score increases by 1.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Barbed Tail.</em></strong> You have a long barbed tail, which you can use in combat. Your tail is a natural weapon, has a reach of 10 feet, and deals 1d4 + your Strength modifier damage on a hit. When you hit a creature with an attack of opportunity using your tail, their speed is reduced by 10 feet until the start of your next turn.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Blade Magic.</em></strong> You know the green flame blade cantrip. When you reach 3rd level, you can cast the zephyr strike spell once using this trait, and regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest. At 5th level, you can cast the shadow blade spell once using this trait, and regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <stat name="strength" value="1" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_DMH_FEYRI_RACIAL_TRAIT_FEYRI_BARBED_BARBED_TAIL" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_DMH_FEYRI_RACIAL_TRAIT_FEYRI_BARBED_BLADE_MAGIC" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Barbed Tail" type="Racial Trait" source="Fey’Ri Race" id="ID_DMH_FEYRI_RACIAL_TRAIT_FEYRI_BARBED_BARBED_TAIL">
            <description>
                <p>You have a long barbed tail, which you can use in combat. Your tail is a natural weapon, has a reach of 10 feet, and deals 1d4 + your Strength modifier damage on a hit. When you hit a creature with an attack of opportunity using your tail, their speed is reduced by 10 feet until the start of your next turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Tail. Melee Weapon Attack: {{melee:attack}} to hit, reach 10 ft, one target. Hit: 1d4 + {{strength:modifier}} bludgeoning damage. When you hit a creature with an attack of opportunity using your tail, their speed is reduced by 10 feet until the start of your next turn.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Blade Magic" type="Racial Trait" source="Fey’Ri Race" id="ID_DMH_FEYRI_RACIAL_TRAIT_FEYRI_BARBED_BLADE_MAGIC">
            <description>
                <p>You know the <i>green flame blade</i> cantrip. When you reach 3rd level, you can cast the <i>zephyr strike</i> spell once using this trait, and regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest. At 5th level, you can cast the <i>shadow blade</i> spell once using this trait, and regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description level="3" usage="1/Long Rest">You can cast zephyr strike once.</description>
                <description level="5" usage="1/Long Rest">You can cast zephyr strike and shadow blade once each.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="blade magic:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="3" />
                <stat name="blade magic:spellcasting:slots:2" value="1" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_SCAG_SPELL_GREEN_FLAME_BLADE" spellcasting="Blade Magic" level="1" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ZEPHYR_STRIKE" spellcasting="Blade Magic" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_SHADOW_BLADE" spellcasting="Blade Magic" level="5" />
            </rules>
        </element>

    <element name="Brute Fey’ri" type="Sub Race" source="Fey’Ri Race" id="ID_DMH_FEYRI_SUBRACE_FEYRI_BRUTE_FEYRI">
        <supports>Fey’Ri</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Brute Fey’ri are somewhat misnamed. They gained the name due to the extra pair of arms they sport, which caused many to believe that these Fey’ri were stronger than others. However, their second pair of arms are usually much weaker, being unable to hold and carry heavy objects, and incapable of wielding weapons.</p>
            <p class="indent">However, what these additional arms lack in strength, they make up for with utility. Many Brute Fey’ri make for excellent battle mages, using their main arms for wielding weapons, while their additional arms are used to hold components and cast magical spells.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong> Your Constitution score increases by 1.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Extra Arms.</em></strong> You have a second pair of arms. These arms are not strong enough to wield weapons or shields, however they can be used in different ways. You can use these arms to grab and hold objects and perform somatic components for spells.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Grasping Magic.</em></strong> You know the mage hand cantrip. When you reach 3rd level, you can cast the arms of hadar spell once using this trait, and regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest. At 5th level, you can cast the hold person spell once using this trait, and regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <stat name="constitution" value="1" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_DMH_FEYRI_RACIAL_TRAIT_FEYRI_BRUTE_EXTRA_ARMS" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_DMH_FEYRI_RACIAL_TRAIT_FEYRI_BRUTE_GRASPING_MAGIC" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Extra Arms" type="Racial Trait" source="Fey’Ri Race" id="ID_DMH_FEYRI_RACIAL_TRAIT_FEYRI_BRUTE_EXTRA_ARMS">
            <description>
                <p>You have a second pair of arms. These arms are not strong enough to wield weapons or shields, however they can be used in different ways. You can use these arms to grab and hold objects and perform somatic components for spells.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can use your extra arms to grab and hold objects and perform somatic components for spells.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Grasping Magic" type="Racial Trait" source="Fey’Ri Race" id="ID_DMH_FEYRI_RACIAL_TRAIT_FEYRI_BRUTE_GRASPING_MAGIC">
            <description>
                <p>You know the mage hand cantrip. When you reach 3rd level, you can cast the arms of hadar spell once using this trait, and regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest. At 5th level, you can cast the hold person spell once using this trait, and regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description level="3" usage="1/Long Rest">You can cast arms of hadar once.</description>
                <description level="5" usage="1/Long Rest">You can cast arms of hadar and hold person once each.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="grasping magic:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="3" />
                <stat name="grasping magic:spellcasting:slots:2" value="1" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGE_HAND" spellcasting="Grasping Magic" level="1" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ARMS_OF_HADAR" spellcasting="Grasping Magic" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HOLD_PERSON" spellcasting="Grasping Magic" level="5" />
            </rules>
        </element>

    <element name="Forked Fey’ri" type="Sub Race" source="Fey’Ri Race" id="ID_DMH_FEYRI_SUBRACE_FEYRI_FORKED_FEYRI">
        <supports>Fey’Ri</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Forked Fey’ri are the most cunning of their kind, and make for shrewd merchants and diplomats. Their name comes from their forked tongue, and their innate ability to convince and deceive others. Often, these Fey’ri seem untrustworthy at first, but after a short conversation with them, many people seem to regard them as a close friend, almost as if their words have charmed them.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong> Your Charisma score increases by 1.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Forked Tongue.</em></strong> Your demonic ancestry makes your words and promises sound more reasonable. You gain proficiency with one of the following skills; deception, intimidation, or persuasion.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Deceptive Magic.</em></strong> You know the friends cantrip. When you reach 3rd level, you can cast the charm person spell once using this trait, and regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest. At 5th level, you can cast the suggestion spell once using this trait, and regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <stat name="charisma" value="1" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_DMH_FEYRI_RACIAL_TRAIT_FEYRI_FORKED_FORKED_TONGUE" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_DMH_FEYRI_RACIAL_TRAIT_FEYRI_FORKED_DECEPTIVE_MAGIC" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Forked Tongue" type="Racial Trait" source="Fey’Ri Race" id="ID_DMH_FEYRI_RACIAL_TRAIT_FEYRI_FORKED_FORKED_TONGUE">
            <description>
                <p>Your demonic ancestry makes your words and promises sound more reasonable. You gain proficiency with one of the following skills; deception, intimidation, or persuasion.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency, Forked Tongue" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_DECEPTION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INTIMIDATION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERSUASION" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Deceptive Magic" type="Racial Trait" source="Fey’Ri Race" id="ID_DMH_FEYRI_RACIAL_TRAIT_FEYRI_FORKED_DECEPTIVE_MAGIC">
            <description>
                <p>You know the <i>friends</i> cantrip. When you reach 3rd level, you can cast the <i>charm person</i> spell once using this trait, and regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest. At 5th level, you can cast the <i>suggestion</i> spell once using this trait, and regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description level="3" usage="1/Long Rest">You can cast charm person once.</description>
                <description level="5" usage="1/Long Rest">You can cast charm person and suggestion once each.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="deceptive magic:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="3" />
                <stat name="deceptive magic:spellcasting:slots:2" value="1" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FRIENDS" spellcasting="Deceptive Magic" level="1" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CHARM_PERSON" spellcasting="Deceptive Magic" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SUGGESTION" spellcasting="Deceptive Magic" level="5" />
            </rules>
        </element>

    <element name="Winged Fey’ri" type="Sub Race" source="Fey’Ri Race" id="ID_DMH_FEYRI_SUBRACE_FEYRI_WINGED_FEYRI">
        <supports>Fey’Ri</supports>
        <description>
            <p>As their name suggests, Winged Fey’ri sport one or more pairs of wings, which allow them to take to the skies. However, these wings are not very powerful, and most Fey’ri can only use them for a short amount of time before needing to let them rest. Even so, their wings give them a potent edge in combat, making them much faster and more mobile than their opponents.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong> Your Dexterity score increases by 1.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Demonic Wings.</em></strong> Starting at 3rd level, you can use your action to cause one or more pairs of demonic wings to sprout from your back. For the next minute, you gain a fly speed of 30 feet. Once you use this feature, you cannot do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Winged Magic.</em></strong> You know the gust cantrip. When you reach 3rd level, you can cast the feather fall spell once using this trait, and regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest. At 5th level, you can cast the gust of wind spell once using this trait, and regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <stat name="dexterity" value="1" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_DMH_FEYRI_RACIAL_TRAIT_FEYRI_WINGED_DEMONIC_WINGS" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_DMH_FEYRI_RACIAL_TRAIT_FEYRI_WINGED_WINGED_MAGIC" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Demonic Wings" type="Racial Trait" source="Fey’Ri Race" id="ID_DMH_FEYRI_RACIAL_TRAIT_FEYRI_WINGED_DEMONIC_WINGS">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 3rd level, you can use your action to cause one or more pairs of demonic wings to sprout from your back. For the next minute, you gain a fly speed of 30 feet. Once you use this feature, you cannot do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You manifest your demonic wings, giving you a fly speed of 30 feet for the next minute.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Winged Magic" type="Racial Trait" source="Fey’Ri Race" id="ID_DMH_FEYRI_RACIAL_TRAIT_FEYRI_WINGED_WINGED_MAGIC">
            <description>
                <p>You know the <i>gust</i> cantrip. When you reach 3rd level, you can cast the <i>feather fall</i> spell once using this trait, and regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest. At 5th level, you can cast the <i>gust of wind</i> spell once using this trait, and regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description level="3" usage="1/Long Rest">You can cast feather fall once.</description>
                <description level="5" usage="1/Long Rest">You can cast feather fall and gust of wind once each.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="winged magic:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="3" />
                <stat name="winged magic:spellcasting:slots:2" value="1" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_GUST" spellcasting="Winged Magic" level="1" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FEATHER_FALL" spellcasting="Winged Magic" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GUST_OF_WIND" spellcasting="Winged Magic" level="5" />
            </rules>
        </element>
</elements>