<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Freedom Subclasses; The Unsworn and The Pactbreaker</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="subclasses-freedom-subclasses.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/dmhavuhk/subclasses-freedom-subclasses.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Freedom Subclasses" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_DMHAVUHK_GMBINDER_SOURCE_Freedom Subclasses">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation">FSUP</set>
            <set name="url">https://www.gmbinder.com/share/-MM-fY5b55eqj_wIAsGR</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" abbreviation="DMH" url="https://www.gmbinder.com/profile/dmhavuhk">DMHavuhk</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20210118</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="The Unsworn" type="Archetype" source="Freedom Subclasses" id="ID_DMH_FSUP_ARCHETYPE_PALADIN_UNSWORN">
        <supports>Sacred Oath</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The path of a paladin is not an easy one. Holding to an oath can be a difficult endeavour. There are many paladins that break the oaths that they have sworn. Perhaps they were not able to uphold the tenants of their oath, or they abandoned the oath they swore to an evil god. For whatever reason, your oath has been broken. But while most people who break their oath lose everything they had gained, you’ve managed to hold on to a small ember. With enough time and training, perhaps you can fan this ember into a flame.</p>
            <div element="ID_DMH_FSUP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNSWORN_TENANTS_OF_THE_UNSWORN" />
            <div element="ID_DMH_FSUP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNSWORN_CHANNEL_DIVINITY" />
            <div element="ID_DMH_FSUP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNSWORN_AURA_OF_FREEDOM" />
            <div element="ID_DMH_FSUP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNSWORN_LAST_HOPE" />
            <div element="ID_DMH_FSUP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNSWORN_PALADINS_VALOUR" />
            <div class="sidebar">
                <h5 class="caption">Expanded Spell List?</h5>
                <p>The Unsworn lacks an expanded spell list due to the nature of these subclasses. Your DM can decide if you are able to use the expanded spell list of your previous oath/patron, or if you simply do not get an expanded spell list.</p>
            </div>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMH_FSUP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNSWORN_TENANTS_OF_THE_UNSWORN" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMH_FSUP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNSWORN_CHANNEL_DIVINITY" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMH_FSUP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNSWORN_AURA_OF_FREEDOM" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMH_FSUP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNSWORN_LAST_HOPE" level="15" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMH_FSUP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNSWORN_PALADINS_VALOUR" level="20" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Tenants of the Unsworn" type="Archetype Feature" source="Freedom Subclasses" id="ID_DMH_FSUP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNSWORN_TENANTS_OF_THE_UNSWORN">
            <description>
                <p>As ex-paladins, the Unsworn do not have any oaths that they are forced to follow. There are some that still attempt to uphold the tenants of their previous oath, in an attempt to regain their lost light, but most Unsworn are free to carve their own path.</p>
                <div class="sidebar">
                    <h5 class="caption">Optional Rule; Weakened Powers</h5>
                    <p>Without an oath, your DM may decide that your paladin powers have lessened. If they do so, your abilities change in the following ways:</p>
                    <ul>
                        <li>Lay on hands. The pool of hit points for your lay on hands is 3 x your paladin level.</li>
                        <li>Divine Smite. Your Divine Smite deals 1d8 damage with a 1st level spell slot, instead of 2d8.</li>
                    </ul>
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet />
        </element>
        <element name="Channel Divinity" type="Archetype Feature" source="Freedom Subclasses" id="ID_DMH_FSUP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNSWORN_CHANNEL_DIVINITY">
            <description>
                <p>When you take this oath at 3rd level, you gain the following two Channel Divinity options.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Break The Shackles.</b> You can use your Channel Divinity to break the bindings and shackles that holds people down. As a bonus action, you can touch a creature and end a single condition affecting them. If you are under the effects of a condition that would make you incapable of taking actions, such as the paralyzed condition, you can use this Channel Divinity to end that condition and take your turn as normal.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Lingering Light.</b> You can harness what little light you still hold onto to protect those in need. When you or a creature you can see within 30ft takes damage, you can use your reaction and expend your Channel Divinity to grant them a number of temporary hit points equal to your Paladin level + Your Charisma modifier.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false" />
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMH_FSUP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNSWORN_CD_BREAK_THE_SHACKLES" level="3" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMH_FSUP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNSWORN_CD_LINGERING_LIGHT" level="3" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Channel Divinity: Break The Shackles" type="Archetype Feature" source="Freedom Subclasses" id="ID_DMH_FSUP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNSWORN_CD_BREAK_THE_SHACKLES">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>You can use your Channel Divinity to break the bindings and shackles that holds people down. As a bonus action, you can touch a creature and end a single condition affecting them. If you are under the effects of a condition that would make you incapable of taking actions, such as the paralyzed condition, you can use this Channel Divinity to end that condition and take your turn as normal.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Channel Divinity" alt="Break The Shackles" action="Bonus Action">
                    <description>If you are under the effects of a condition that would make you incapable of taking actions, you can end that condition and take your turn as normal.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Channel Divinity: Lingering Light" type="Archetype Feature" source="Freedom Subclasses" id="ID_DMH_FSUP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNSWORN_CD_LINGERING_LIGHT">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>You can harness what little light you still hold onto to protect those in need. When you or a creature you can see within 30 ft takes damage, you can use your reaction and expend your Channel Divinity to grant them a number of temporary hit points equal to your Paladin level + your Charisma modifier.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Channel Divinity" alt="Lingering Light" action="Reaction">
                    <description>When you or a creature you can see within 30 ft takes damage, you can grant them {{lingering-light:temp-hp}} temporary hit points.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="lingering-light:temp-hp" value="level:paladin" />
                    <stat name="lingering-light:temp-hp" value="charisma:modifier" />
                </rules>
            </element>
        <element name="Aura of Freedom" type="Archetype Feature" source="Freedom Subclasses" id="ID_DMH_FSUP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNSWORN_AURA_OF_FREEDOM">
            <description>
                <p>At 7th level, you and creatures within 10 feet are immune to the grapple and restrained conditions, and can ignore difficult terrain.</p>
                <p class="indent">At 18th level, the range of this aura increases to 30 feet.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You and creatures within {{aura-of-freedom:range}} feet are immune to the grapple and restrained conditions, and can ignore difficult terrain.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="aura-of-freedom:range" value="10" level="7" />
                <stat name="aura-of-freedom:range" value="10" level="18" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Last Hope" type="Archetype Feature" source="Freedom Subclasses" id="ID_DMH_FSUP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNSWORN_LAST_HOPE">
            <description>
                <p>At 15th level, you can call on the light within you when hope is lost in a last ditch effort to protect those around you. You gain an additional use of your Channel Divinity. When you use this additional use, your Channel Divinity is more potent.</p>
                <ul>
                    <li><b>Break the Shackles.</b> The range of this ability increases to 30ft. Additionally, you can affect a number of creatures equal to your Charisma modifier.</li>
                    <li><b>Lingering Light.</b> The number of temporary hit points granted is equal to twice your paladin level + your charisma modifier.</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">After you use this feature, you gain two points of exhaustion, and you cannot use it again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You gain an additional use of your Channel Divinity. When you use this additional use, your Channel Divinity is more potent. The range of Break the Shackles increases to 30 feet and you can affect {{charisma:modifier}} creatures. Lingering Light grants {{last-hope:temp-hp}} temporary hit points.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="last-hope:temp-hp" value="lingering-light:temp-hp" level="15" />
                <stat name="last-hope:temp-hp" value="lingering-light:temp-hp" level="15" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Paladin’s Valour" type="Archetype Feature" source="Freedom Subclasses" id="ID_DMH_FSUP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNSWORN_PALADINS_VALOUR">
            <description>
                <p>You may not follow an oath any longer, but you are still a paladin at heart, and you have a reason to fight. At 20th level, you can use an action to rally yourself, preparing to fight for what you believe in. For 1 minute, you gain the following benefits:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>You regain 10 hit points at the start of your turn.</li>
                    <li>You have advantage on all saving throws.</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this ability, you cannot do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>You can rally yourself and for 1 minute, you: Regain 10 hit points at the start of your turn, and you have advantage on all saving throws.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>


    <element name="The Pactbreaker" type="Archetype" source="Freedom Subclasses" id="ID_DMH_FSUP_ARCHETYPE_WARLOCK_PACTBREAKER">
        <supports>Otherworldly Patron</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Once, you were sworn to a greater power, bound by pact to an otherworldly being, your life was no longer your own. But now, the pact is broken. Your soul is free, and while you can no longer draw from your previous source of power, you’ve stolen quite a bit of arcane knowledge from your previous patron, knowledge which you can use to continue down the path of a warlock. Now you only need to decipher and learn how to use it.</p>
            <div element="ID_DMH_FSUP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTBREAKER_YOUR_OWN_MASTER" />
            <div element="ID_DMH_FSUP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTBREAKER_SPELL_MIMIC" />
            <div element="ID_DMH_FSUP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTBREAKER_STRENGTH_OF_THE_UNBOUND" />
            <div element="ID_DMH_FSUP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTBREAKER_FORCED_PACT" />
            <div class="sidebar">
                <h5 class="caption">Expanded Spell List?</h5>
                <p>The Pactbreaker lacks an expanded spell list due to the nature of these subclasses. Your DM can decide if you are able to use the expanded spell list of your previous oath/patron, or if you simply do not get an expanded spell list.</p>
            </div>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMH_FSUP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTBREAKER_YOUR_OWN_MASTER" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMH_FSUP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTBREAKER_SPELL_MIMIC" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMH_FSUP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTBREAKER_STRENGTH_OF_THE_UNBOUND" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMH_FSUP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTBREAKER_FORCED_PACT" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Your Own Master" type="Archetype Feature" source="Freedom Subclasses" id="ID_DMH_FSUP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTBREAKER_YOUR_OWN_MASTER">
            <description>
                <p>At 1st level, you are no longer beholden to the whims of you master, and are free to study the eldritch arts in whatever way you see fit. You can choose to use Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma as your spellcasting modifier. Additionally, when you finish a long rest, you can change one of your Warlock spells or Eldritch Invocations.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you finish a long rest, you can change one of your Warlock spells or Eldritch Invocations.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Spell Mimic" type="Archetype Feature" source="Freedom Subclasses" id="ID_DMH_FSUP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTBREAKER_SPELL_MIMIC">
            <description>
                <p>Without a patron granting you knowledge, learning new spells can be difficult, but you’ve found a new way to study magic. At 6th level, when you see a creature cast a spell, you can use your reaction to attempt to mimic the spell. The caster must make an Intelligence saving throw. If they are willing to share their knowledge, they automatically fail this saving throw. On a failure, you are able to cast the spell you saw once without expending a spell slot. You still cast this spell at the same level as your other warlock spells.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this ability, you cannot do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest" action="Reaction">
                <description>When you see a creature cast a spell, you can attempt to mimic the spell. The caster must make an Intelligence saving throw (DC {{spellcasting:dc:cha}}). If they are willing to share their knowledge, they automatically fail this saving throw. On a failure, you are able to cast the spell you saw once without expending a spell slot. You still cast this spell at the same level as your other warlock spells.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Strength of the Unbound" type="Archetype Feature" source="Freedom Subclasses" id="ID_DMH_FSUP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTBREAKER_STRENGTH_OF_THE_UNBOUND">
            <description>
                <p>At 10th level, you’ve grown used to your freedom, and aren’t willing to give it up. You have advantage on saving throws against the charm, paralyzed, and restrained conditions. Additionally, if you succeed on a saving throw against one of these spells, the creature that forced you to make the save takes force damage equal to your warlock level.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You have advantage on saving throws against the charm, paralyzed, and restrained conditions. Additionally, if you succeed on a saving throw against one of these spells, the creature that forced you to make the save takes {{level:warlock}} force damage.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Forced Pact" type="Archetype Feature" source="Freedom Subclasses" id="ID_DMH_FSUP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTBREAKER_FORCED_PACT">
            <description>
                <p>You still remember what it feels like to be under the control of your patron, and have learned how to impose your will on others in the same way. At 14th level, you can use your action to forcefully form a pact with a creature within 30ft. The pact lasts for 1 minute, or until you lose concentration. At the start of the creature’s turn, they must make a Charisma Saving Throw. On a failure, you choose their actions for this turn.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this ability, you cannot do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest" action="Action">
                <description>You can forcefully form a pact with a creature within 30ft. The pact lasts for 1 minute, or until you lose concentration. At the start of the creature’s turn, they must make a Charisma Saving Throw. On a failure, you choose their actions for this turn.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    <!-- New Eldritch Invocations -->
        <element name="Arcane Study" type="Class Feature" source="Freedom Subclasses" id="ID_DMH_FSUP_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_ARCANE_STUDY">
            <supports>Eldritch Invocation</supports>
            <requirements>ID_DMH_FSUP_ARCHETYPE_WARLOCK_PACTBREAKER, ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_PACT_BOON_PACT_OF_THE_TOME</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Pactbreaker Patron, Pact of the Tome feature</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Pactbreaker Patron, Pact of the Tome feature</p>
                <p class="indent">You gain proficiency with the Arcana skill. Additionally, you may add one spell from the Wizard spell list to your spell list. This does not count towards the number of spells you can learn. You can change this spell when you gain a level in this class.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false" />
            <rules>
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ARCANA" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Spell, Natural Study" spellcasting="Warlock" known="true" supports="Wizard,$(spellcasting:slots)" allowReplace="true" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Blade of Freedom" type="Class Feature" source="Freedom Subclasses" id="ID_DMH_FSUP_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_BLADE_OF_FREEDOM">
            <supports>Eldritch Invocation</supports>
            <requirements>ID_DMH_FSUP_ARCHETYPE_WARLOCK_PACTBREAKER, ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_PACT_BOON_PACT_OF_THE_BLADE</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Pactbreaker Patron, Pact of the Blade feature</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Pactbreaker Patron, Pact of the Blade feature</p>
                <p class="indent">When you hit an attack with your pact weapon against a creature that is grappling or restraining a creature, you can force them to end the condition. Additionally, when attacking creatures that have swallowed another creature, you deal an extra damage die of damage.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you hit an attack with your pact weapon against a creature that is grappling or restraining a creature, you can force them to end the condition. Additionally, when attacking creatures that have swallowed another creature, you deal an extra damage die of damage.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Broken Chain" type="Class Feature" source="Freedom Subclasses" id="ID_DMH_FSUP_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_BROKEN_CHAIN">
            <supports>Eldritch Invocation</supports>
            <requirements>ID_DMH_FSUP_ARCHETYPE_WARLOCK_PACTBREAKER, ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_PACT_BOON_PACT_OF_THE_CHAIN</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Pactbreaker Patron, Pact of the Chain feature</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Pactbreaker Patron, Pact of the Chain feature</p>
                <p class="indent">You can telepathically communicate with your familiar and see through their senses no matter how far away they are, provided that they you are on the same plane of existence. Additionally, the range in which you can deliver touch spells through your familiar is increased to 150 feet.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can telepathically communicate with your familiar and see through their senses no matter how far away they are, provided that they you are on the same plane of existence. Additionally, the range in which you can deliver touch spells through your familiar is increased to 150 feet.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Divine Study" type="Class Feature" source="Freedom Subclasses" id="ID_DMH_FSUP_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_DIVINE_STUDY">
            <supports>Eldritch Invocation</supports>
            <requirements>ID_DMH_FSUP_ARCHETYPE_WARLOCK_PACTBREAKER, ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_PACT_BOON_PACT_OF_THE_TOME</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Pactbreaker Patron, Pact of the Tome feature</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Pactbreaker Patron, Pact of the Tome feature</p>
                <p class="indent">You gain proficiency with the Religion skill. Additionally, you may add one spell from the Cleric spell list to your spell list. This does not count towards the number of spells you can learn. You can change this spell when you gain a level in this class.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false" />
            <rules>
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_RELIGION" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Spell, Natural Study" spellcasting="Warlock" known="true" supports="Cleric,$(spellcasting:slots)" allowReplace="true" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Eldritch Chain" type="Class Feature" source="Freedom Subclasses" id="ID_DMH_FSUP_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_ELDRITCH_CHAIN">
            <supports>Eldritch Invocation</supports>
            <requirements>ID_DMH_FSUP_ARCHETYPE_WARLOCK_PACTBREAKER, [level:warlock:5], ID_PHB_SPELL_ELDRITCH_BLAST</requirements>
            <prerequisite>5th level, Pactbreaker Patron, eldritch blast cantrip</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 5th level, Pactbreaker Patron, eldritch blast cantrip</p>
                <p class="indent">When you hit a creature with at least 2 beams of your <i>eldritch blast</i>, you can attempt to grapple them. You use your spell attack bonus in place of Athletics for this grapple check.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you hit a creature with at least 2 beams of your eldritch blast, you can attempt to grapple them. You use your spell attack bonus in place of Athletics for this grapple check.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Natural Study" type="Class Feature" source="Freedom Subclasses" id="ID_DMH_FSUP_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_NATURAL_STUDY">
            <supports>Eldritch Invocation</supports>
            <requirements>ID_DMH_FSUP_ARCHETYPE_WARLOCK_PACTBREAKER, ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_PACT_BOON_PACT_OF_THE_TOME</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Pactbreaker Patron, Pact of the Tome feature</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Pactbreaker Patron, Pact of the Tome feature</p>
                <p class="indent">You gain proficiency with the Nature skill. Additionally, you may add one spell from the Druid spell list to your spell list. This does not count towards the number of spells you can learn. You can change this spell when you gain a level in this class.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false" />
            <rules>
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_NATURE" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Spell, Natural Study" spellcasting="Warlock" known="true" supports="Druid,$(spellcasting:slots)" allowReplace="true" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Otherworldly Protection" type="Class Feature" source="Freedom Subclasses" id="ID_DMH_FSUP_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_OTHERWORLDLY_PROTECTION">
            <supports>Eldritch Invocation</supports>
            <requirements>ID_DMH_FSUP_ARCHETYPE_WARLOCK_PACTBREAKER, [level:warlock:9]</requirements>
            <prerequisite>9th level, Pactbreaker Patron</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 9th level, Pactbreaker Patron</p>
                <p class="indent">You can cast <i>protection from evil and good</i> at will, without expending a spell slot or material components.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can cast protection from evil and good at will, without expending a spell slot or material components.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PROTECTION_FROM_EVIL_AND_GOOD" spellcasting="Warlock" known="true" />
            </rules>
        </element>

</elements>