<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Ardent Martial Archetype</name>
        <author url="https://www.reddit.com/u/devikyn">u/devikyn</author>
        <update version="0.0.2">
            <file name="fighter-ardent.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/user/gm-binder-devikyn/the-renewed-psionic/fighter-ardent.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Ardent" type="Archetype" source="The Renewed Psionic" id="ID_GM_BINDER_TRP_ARCHETYPE_FIGHTER_ARDENT">
        <supports>Martial Archetype</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Ardents are fiercely driven psionic fighters that center their personalities around certain inevitable philosophies, rather than honing the discipline of their minds. Universal truths afford power to these psionically talented warriors, who train their mind and body in accordance with a lifetime of understanding and personal experiences. Ardents are driven by emotion towards goals that align with their philosophies, as their conviction leads them to ever greater understanding and, subsequently, power.</p>
            <div element="ID_GM_BINDER_TRP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARDENT_ARDENT_INEVITABILITY" />
            <div element="ID_GM_BINDER_TRP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARDENT_PSIONICS" />
            <div element="ID_GM_BINDER_TRP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARDENT_PSISTRIKE" />
            <div element="ID_GM_BINDER_TRP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARDENT_BASTILLE_OF_EMOTION" />
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GM_BINDER_TRP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARDENT_ARDENT_INEVITABILITY" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GM_BINDER_TRP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARDENT_PSIONICS" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GM_BINDER_TRP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARDENT_PSISTRIKE" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GM_BINDER_TRP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARDENT_BASTILLE_OF_EMOTION" level="15" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Ardent Inevitability" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Renewed Psionic" id="ID_GM_BINDER_TRP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARDENT_ARDENT_INEVITABILITY">
        <description>
            <p>At 3rd level, your dedication towards embracing an inevitable facet of the universe begins to manifest as psionic power. You embrace two of the options listed under "Ardent Inevitabilities" below. You embrace another option at 10th and 18th level in this class.</p>
            <p class="indent">Your first choice of ardent inevitability becomes your focus. While you are focused on an inevitability, you have the benefits listed under that option. You can only focus on one inevitability at a time, and you can change your focus to another inevitability option that you know when you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>While you are focused on an inevitability, you have the benefits listed under that option. You can only focus on one inevitability at a time, and you can change your focus to another inevitability option that you know when you finish a long rest.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Ardent Inevitability (Level 3)" supports="Ardent Inevitability" level="3" />
            <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Ardent Inevitability (Level 10)" supports="Ardent Inevitability" level="10" />
            <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Ardent Inevitability (Level 18)" supports="Ardent Inevitability" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Psionics" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Renewed Psionic" id="ID_GM_BINDER_TRP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARDENT_PSIONICS">
        <description>
            <p>Also at 3rd level, the psionic well of power you draw upon through your focus on philosophy allows you to learn psionic manifestations.</p>
            <h5>PSIONIC TALENTS</h5>
            <p>You learn two talents of your choice from the psion manifestation list. You learn an additional psion talent of your choice at 10th level.</p>
            <h5>LEARNING MANIFESTATIONS</h5>
            <p>You know two psion manifestations of your choice, and one manifestation of your choice from any manifestation list. The Ardent Psionics table shows when you learn more manifestations of 1st level or higher. Each manifestation must be chosen from the psion manifestation list, and must be of a level no greater than that shown in the Manifestation Level Limit column for your fighter level.</p>
            <p class="indent">At 8th, 14th, and 20th levels in this class, the manifestations you choose can come from any manifestation list.</p>
            <p class="indent">Whenever you gain a level in this class, you can replace one of the manifestations you know with another manifestation of your choice. The new manifestation must be of a level no greater than that shown in the Manifestation Level Limit column for your fighter level, and it must be a psion manifestation, unless you’re replacing the manifestation you gained at 3rd, 8th, 14th, or 20th level from any manifestation list.</p>
            <h5>PSIONIC POWER</h5>
            <p>The Ardent Psionics table shows how much psionic power you have to invoke your manifestations of 1st level and higher. To invoke one of these manifestations, you must expend psionic power equal to the manifestation’s level when you invoked it. You regain all expended psionic power when you finish a long rest.</p>
            <p class="indent">For example, if you are a level 8 fighter and you know the 1st-level manifestation psidarts, you can spend 1 psionic power to invoke psidarts at 1st level or 2 psionic power to invoke psidarts at 2nd level. There is a limit to the amount of psionic power you can sustain at a time; you can’t invoke a manifestation if its psionic power cost is greater than your Psionic Power Limit.</p>
            <h5>MENTAL FATIGUE</h5>
            <p>Each time you use a psionic manifestation, you incur some amount of mental fatigue. Mental fatigue causes additional stress when repeatedly invoking similar psionic manifestations.</p>
            <p class="indent">Whenever you invoke a psionic manifestation, you gain one level of mental fatigue for the level at which you invoked the manifestation. Each time you gain mental fatigue, the psionic power cost to activate manifestations of that level increases by one. For example, the first time you invoke the ethereal weapon manifestation after finishing a long rest, it costs 1 point of psionic power, and your mental fatigue level for 1st level manifestations increases to 1. Subsequently, if you invoke psidarts or any other 1st level manifestation, its psionic power cost is 2, and your mental fatigue level increases to 2.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you have accumulated 4 levels of mental fatigue for a given manifestation level, your mind adapts to the task, and you no longer gain mental fatigue for that manifestation level until your fatigue is reduced below 4. Your mental fatigue for all manifestation levels returns to 0 when you finish a long rest.</p>
            <h5>Psionic Ability</h5>
            <p>Intelligence is your ability for your psionic manifestations, since they are created out of psionic energy and shaped by your mind. You use your Intelligence whenever a talent or manifestation refers to your psionic ability. In addition, you use your Intelligence modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a psionic talent or manifestion you use and when making an attack roll with one.</p>
            <p class="indent">Psionic save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier</p>
            <p class="indent">Psionic attack modifier = your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="spellcastingClass">Ardent</set>
            <set name="spellcastingAbility">Intelligence</set>
            <set name="spellcaster">true</set>
        </setters>
        <spellcasting name="Ardent" ability="Intelligence" prepare="false">
            <list known="true">Ardent</list>
        </spellcasting>
        <sheet usage="{{ardent:psionic-power}}/Long Rest">
            <description>Psionic Power Limit: {{ardent:psionic-power-limit}}</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Spell" name="Ardent Talent (Level 3)" number="2" supports="Psion,0" level="3" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Ardent Talent (Level 10)" number="1" supports="Psion,0" level="10" />

            <stat name="ardent:spellcasting:slots:1" value="0" level="3" />
            <stat name="ardent:spellcasting:slots:2" value="0" level="7" />
            <stat name="ardent:spellcasting:slots:3" value="0" level="13" />
            <stat name="ardent:spellcasting:slots:4" value="0" level="19" />

            <stat name="ardent:psionic-power" value="3" level="3" />
            <stat name="ardent:psionic-power" value="3" level="4" />
            <stat name="ardent:psionic-power" value="9" level="7" />
            <stat name="ardent:psionic-power" value="4" level="10" />
            <stat name="ardent:psionic-power" value="7" level="13" />
            <stat name="ardent:psionic-power" value="5" level="16" />
            <stat name="ardent:psionic-power" value="4" level="19" />

            <stat name="ardent:psionic-power-limit" value="2" level="3" />
            <stat name="ardent:psionic-power-limit" value="1" level="4" />
            <stat name="ardent:psionic-power-limit" value="1" level="10" />
            <stat name="ardent:psionic-power-limit" value="1" level="16" />
            
            <select type="Spell" name="Ardent Manifestation (Level 3)" number="2" supports="$(spellcasting:slots),Psion" level="3" spellcasting="Ardent" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Ardent Manifestation (Level 3)" number="1" supports="$(spellcasting:slots),Manifestation" level="3" spellcasting="Ardent" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Ardent Manifestation (Level 4)" number="1" supports="$(spellcasting:slots),Psion" level="4" spellcasting="Ardent" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Ardent Manifestation (Level 7)" number="1" supports="$(spellcasting:slots),Psion" level="7" spellcasting="Ardent" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Ardent Manifestation (Level 8)" number="1" supports="$(spellcasting:slots),Manifestation" level="8" spellcasting="Ardent" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Ardent Manifestation (Level 10)" number="1" supports="$(spellcasting:slots),Psion" level="10" spellcasting="Ardent" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Ardent Manifestation (Level 11)" number="1" supports="$(spellcasting:slots),Psion" level="11" spellcasting="Ardent" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Ardent Manifestation (Level 13)" number="1" supports="$(spellcasting:slots),Psion" level="13" spellcasting="Ardent" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Ardent Manifestation (Level 14)" number="1" supports="$(spellcasting:slots),Manifestation" level="14" spellcasting="Ardent" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Ardent Manifestation (Level 16)" number="1" supports="$(spellcasting:slots),Psion" level="16" spellcasting="Ardent" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Ardent Manifestation (Level 19)" number="1" supports="$(spellcasting:slots),Psion" level="19" spellcasting="Ardent" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Ardent Manifestation (Level 20)" number="1" supports="$(spellcasting:slots),Manifestation" level="20" spellcasting="Ardent" />

        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Psi-Strike" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Renewed Psionic" id="ID_GM_BINDER_TRP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARDENT_PSISTRIKE">
        <description>
            <p>At 7th level, you learn to concentrate your psionic energy into a single, powerful strike.</p>
            <p class="indent">As a bonus action, you can spend an amount of psionic power up to your psionic power limit in order to add extra psychic damage equal to two times the amount of psionic power spent to your next weapon attack that hits. This bonus is wasted if not used by the end of your turn.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Bonus Action">
            <description>You can spend an amount of psionic power up to your psionic power limit in order to add extra psychic damage equal to two times the amount of psionic power spent to your next weapon attack that hits. This bonus is wasted if not used by the end of your turn.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Bastille of Emotion" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Renewed Psionic" id="ID_GM_BINDER_TRP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARDENT_BASTILLE_OF_EMOTION">
        <description>
            <p>At 15th level, you have developed such a strong connection with the philosophies of the universe that you can touch the emotions of those around you.</p>
            <p class="indent">As an action, you open your senses to read the emotional state of all creatures within 60 feet of you. You learn the basic emotional states of each creature within range that you can see - these can be states such as happy, sad, excited, distressed, brave, fearful, loved, hated, angry, or calm, for example.</p>
            <p class="indent">When you use this action, you can also force one affected creature to make a Wisdom saving throw against your psionic save DC. On a failed save, you can change that creature’s basic emotional state. When you do, you can cause it to stop feeling one of its current emotions of your choice and to start feeling another one of your choice. The creature is not aware that you attempted to manipulate its emotions in this way. A creature that succeeds its saving throw becomes immune to this effect for 1 hour.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Action">
            <description>You open your senses to read the emotional state of all creatures within 60 feet of you. You learn the basic emotional states of each creature within range that you can see - these can be states such as happy, sad, excited, distressed, brave, fearful, loved, hated, angry, or calm, for example. When you use this action, you can also force one affected creature to make a Wisdom saving throw against your psionic save DC. On a failed save, you can change that creature’s basic emotional state. The creature is not aware that you attempted to manipulate its emotions in this way. A creature that succeeds its saving throw becomes immune to this effect for 1 hour.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

  <!-- Ardent Inevitabilities -->
    <element name="Ardent Inevitability: Conflict and Justice" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Renewed Psionic" id="ID_GM_BINDER_TRP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARDENT_INEVITABILITY_CONFLICT_AND_JUSTICE">
        <supports>Ardent Inevitability</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You can deal extra damage equal to your Intelligence modifier when you score a critical hit, and when you are hit with a melee attack, your attacker takes psychic damage equal to your Intelligence modifier.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet alt="Conflict and Justice" usage="Ardent Inevitability">
            <description>You can deal {{intelligence:modifier}} points extra damage when you score a critical hit, and when you are hit with a melee attack, your attacker takes {{intelligence:modifier}} points psychic damage.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Ardent Inevitability: Creation and Destruction" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Renewed Psionic" id="ID_GM_BINDER_TRP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARDENT_INEVITABILITY_CREATION_AND_DESTRUCTION">
        <supports>Ardent Inevitability</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You can add your Intelligence modifier to the total amount healed whenever you roll a hit die during a short rest, and your weapon attacks deal maximum damage against objects, rather than rolling.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet alt="Creation and Destruction" usage="Ardent Inevitability">
            <description>You can add {{intelligence:modifier}} to the total amount healed whenever you roll a hit die during a short rest, and your weapon attacks deal maximum damage against objects, rather than rolling.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Ardent Inevitability: Death and Life" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Renewed Psionic" id="ID_GM_BINDER_TRP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARDENT_INEVITABILITY_DEATH_AND_LIFE">
        <supports>Ardent Inevitability</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You can add your Intelligence modifier to your death saving throws, and you have advantage on Wisdom (Medicine) checks to stabilize others.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet alt="Death and Life" usage="Ardent Inevitability">
            <description>You can add {{intelligence:modifier}} to your death saving throws, and you have advantage on Wisdom (Medicine) checks to stabilize others.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Ardent Inevitability: Fate and Freedom" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Renewed Psionic" id="ID_GM_BINDER_TRP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARDENT_INEVITABILITY_FATE_AND_FREEDOM">
        <supports>Ardent Inevitability</supports>
        <description>
            <p>When you finish a long rest, roll a d20 and record the result (you can’t have more than one result recorded at a time.) When you roll initiative, you can choose to replace the d20 result with the recorded number. Also, you have advantage on Strength and Dexterity checks made to escape effects that grapple or restrain you.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet alt="Fate and Freedom" usage="Ardent Inevitability">
            <description>When you finish a long rest, roll a d20 and record the result (you can’t have more than one result recorded at a time.) When you roll initiative, you can choose to replace the d20 result with the recorded number. Also, you have advantage on Strength and Dexterity checks made to escape effects that grapple or restrain you.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Ardent Inevitability: Light and Darkness" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Renewed Psionic" id="ID_GM_BINDER_TRP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARDENT_INEVITABILITY_LIGHT_AND_DARKNESS">
        <supports>Ardent Inevitability</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You gain darkvision to a distance of 60 feet. If you already have darkvision, its range increases by 30 feet instead.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet alt="Light and Darkness" usage="Ardent Inevitability">
            <description>You gain darkvision to a distance of 60 feet. If you already have darkvision, its range increases by 30 feet instead.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Ardent Inevitability: Law and Chaos" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Renewed Psionic" id="ID_GM_BINDER_TRP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARDENT_INEVITABILITY_LAW_AND_CHAOS">
        <supports>Ardent Inevitability</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You have advantage on saving throws against being charmed or frightened.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet alt="Law and Chaos" usage="Ardent Inevitability">
            <description>You have advantage on saving throws against being charmed or frightened.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
</elements>