<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Three Thoughts on Conjuration</name>
        <description>Conjuration magics are varied and diverse – and the wizards who practice them are equally so. Many of them choose to specialize in one particular aspect of the school. The three main divisions in the study of conjuration are the School of Creation, the School of Orientation, and the School of Summoning. Although each school focuses on a specific field of study, they all study the basics of the parent school of conjuration, and gain some skill in conjuration magic in general.</description>
        <update version="0.0.2">
            <file name="wizard-three-conjuration-schools.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/subclasses/wizard/wizard-three-conjuration-schools.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Three Thoughts on Conjuration" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_REGULAR_TTOC_SOURCE_THREE_THOUGHTS_ON_CONJURATION">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p>Conjuration magics are varied and diverse – and the wizards who practice them are equally so. Many of them choose to specialize in one particular aspect of the school. The three main divisions in the study of conjuration are the School of Creation, the School of Orientation, and the School of Summoning. Although each school focuses on a specific field of study, they all study the basics of the parent school of conjuration, and gain some skill in conjuration magic in general.</p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation">TTOC</set>
            <set name="url">https://www.gmbinder.com/share/-LejSO1u93Tu8XKWI0wT</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" url="https://www.gmbinder.com/profile/regular">Regular</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20200203</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="School of Creation" type="Archetype" source="Three Thoughts on Conjuration" id="ID_REGULAR_TTOC_ARCHETYPE_WIZARD_SCHOOL_OF_CREATION">
        <supports>Arcane Tradition</supports>
        <description>
            <p>As a conjurer, you condense arcane energies to conjure objects simply out the magic you wield and your sheer focus and will. Those who study under the School of Creation favor spells that produce objects and effects out of thin air, from billowing clouds of killing fog to focused and destructive physical manifestations of elemental forces. As you begin your study, your conjurations may be fleeting, but as your powers grow, you learn to make your creations linger even when detached from your magic.</p>
            <p class="indent">Students of this school are seen as practical wizards, always ready to conjure up a tool for any situation. Much like the School of Illusion, the art of conjuration is often only limited by the wizard’s own imagination.</p>
            <div element="ID_REGULAR_TTOC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CREATION_CONJURATION_SAVANT" />
            <div element="ID_REGULAR_TTOC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CREATION_MINOR_CREATION" />
            <div element="ID_REGULAR_TTOC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CREATION_MATERIALIZE_WEAPON" />
            <div element="ID_REGULAR_TTOC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CREATION_FOCUSED_CONJURATION" />
            <div element="ID_REGULAR_TTOC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CREATION_TRUE_CREATION" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_REGULAR_TTOC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CREATION_CONJURATION_SAVANT" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_REGULAR_TTOC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CREATION_MINOR_CREATION" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_REGULAR_TTOC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CREATION_MATERIALIZE_WEAPON" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_REGULAR_TTOC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CREATION_FOCUSED_CONJURATION" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_REGULAR_TTOC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CREATION_TRUE_CREATION" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Conjuration Savant" type="Archetype Feature" source="Three Thoughts on Conjuration" id="ID_REGULAR_TTOC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CREATION_CONJURATION_SAVANT">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning when you select this school at 2nd level, the gold and time you must spend to copy a conjuration spell into your spellbook is halved.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Beginning when you select this school at 2nd level, the gold and time you must spend to copy a conjuration spell into your spellbook is halved.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Minor Creation" type="Archetype Feature" source="Three Thoughts on Conjuration" id="ID_REGULAR_TTOC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CREATION_MINOR_CREATION">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 2nd level when you select this school, you can use your action to conjure an inanimate object in your hand or on the ground in an unoccupied space that you can see within 10 feet of you. This object can be no larger than 3 feet on a side and weigh no more than 10 pounds, and its form must be that of a nonmagical object that you have seen. The object is visibly magical, radiating dim light out to 5 feet.</p>
                <p class="indent">The object disappears after 1 hour, when you use this feature again, if it takes any damage, or if it deals any damage.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>You can conjure an inanimate object in your hand or on the ground in an unoccupied space that you can see within 10 feet of you. This object can be no larger than 3 feet on a side and weigh no more than 10 pounds, and its form must be that of a nonmagical object that you have seen. The object is visibly magical, radiating dim light out to 5 feet. The object disappears after 1 hour, when you use this feature again, if it takes any damage, or if it deals any damage.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Materialize Weapon" type="Archetype Feature" source="Three Thoughts on Conjuration" id="ID_REGULAR_TTOC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CREATION_MATERIALIZE_WEAPON">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, you can use a bonus action to conjure a hovering magical weapon to fight by your side. It takes the form of a melee weapon of your choice and appears in an unoccupied space you can see within 30 feet of you. When you conjure the weapon and as a bonus action on each of your turns, you can cause it to fly up to 30 feet and use it to make one melee spell attack against one creature within 5 feet of it. The attack deals magical bludgeoning, piercing, or slashing damage (your choice when you conjure the weapon) equal to 1d8 + your Intelligence modifier on a hit.</p>
                <p class="indent">The weapon disappears after one minute. It disappears early if you become incapacitated or if you dismiss it (no action required). Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>You can conjure a hovering magical melee weapon of your choice in an unoccupied space you can see within 30 feet of you. When you conjure the weapon and as a bonus action on each of your turns, you can cause it to fly up to 30 feet and make one melee spell attack against one creature within 5 feet of it. The attack deals 1d8 + {{intelligence:modifier}} magical bludgeoning, piercing, or slashing damage (your choice when you conjure the weapon) on a hit.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Focused Conjuration" type="Archetype Feature" source="Three Thoughts on Conjuration" id="ID_REGULAR_TTOC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CREATION_FOCUSED_CONJURATION">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 10th level, while you are concentrating on a conjuration spell, your concentration can’t be broken.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>While you are concentrating on a conjuration spell, your concentration can’t be broken.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="True Creation" type="Archetype Feature" source="Three Thoughts on Conjuration" id="ID_REGULAR_TTOC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CREATION_TRUE_CREATION">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 14th level, you add the <em>creation</em> spell to your spellbook, if it is not there already.</p>
                <p class="indent">Also, you can cast the <em>creation</em> spell at 7th-level with this feature once without expending a spell slot. When you do so, you can only conjure nonmagical objects made from vegetable matter, stone, crystal, or metal. Additionally, the spell’s duration is instantaneous, and the object you create is not an illusion and is completely real – it does not disappear over time and it cannot be dispelled.</p>
                <p class="indent">You regain the use of this feature when you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You can cast the creation spell at 7th-level with this feature once without expending a spell slot. When you do so, you can only conjure nonmagical objects made from vegetable matter, stone, crystal, or metal. Additionally, the spell’s duration is instantaneous, and the object you create is not an illusion and is completely real – it does not disappear over time and it cannot be dispelled.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CREATION" spellcasting="Wizard" level="14" known="true"></grant>
            </rules>
        </element>


    <element name="School of Orientation" type="Archetype" source="Three Thoughts on Conjuration" id="ID_REGULAR_TTOC_ARCHETYPE_WIZARD_SCHOOL_OF_ORIENTATION">
        <supports>Arcane Tradition</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Students of the School of Orientation focus on the aspect of conjuration that deals with teleportation. You favor spells that transport creatures or objects across vast distances, even to other planes of existence, in an instant. As a member of this school, you can use your mastery of spatial magic to teleport distances and shift places with your allies instantaneously.</p>
            <p class="indent">Practitioners of the School of Orientation often traverse the world – or even the multiverse – in search for further knowledge, aided of course by their talent for swift and immediate travel.</p>
            <div element="ID_REGULAR_TTOC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORIENTATION_CONJURATION_SAVANT" />
            <div element="ID_REGULAR_TTOC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORIENTATION_BENIGN_TRANSPOSITION" />
            <div element="ID_REGULAR_TTOC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORIENTATION_CHARGED_TELEPORTATION" />
            <div element="ID_REGULAR_TTOC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORIENTATION_GREATER_TRANSPOSITION" />
            <div element="ID_REGULAR_TTOC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORIENTATION_DEFENSIVE_REMATERIALIZATION" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_REGULAR_TTOC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORIENTATION_CONJURATION_SAVANT" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_REGULAR_TTOC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORIENTATION_BENIGN_TRANSPOSITION" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_REGULAR_TTOC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORIENTATION_CHARGED_TELEPORTATION" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_REGULAR_TTOC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORIENTATION_GREATER_TRANSPOSITION" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_REGULAR_TTOC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORIENTATION_DEFENSIVE_REMATERIALIZATION" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Conjuration Savant" type="Archetype Feature" source="Three Thoughts on Conjuration" id="ID_REGULAR_TTOC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORIENTATION_CONJURATION_SAVANT">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning when you select this school at 2nd level, the gold and time you must spend to copy a conjuration spell into your spellbook is halved.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Beginning when you select this school at 2nd level, the gold and time you must spend to copy a conjuration spell into your spellbook is halved.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Benign Transposition" type="Archetype Feature" source="Three Thoughts on Conjuration" id="ID_REGULAR_TTOC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORIENTATION_BENIGN_TRANSPOSITION">
            <description>
                <p>At 2nd level, you can use an action to choose a Large or smaller creature within 30 feet of you. If that creature is willing, you both teleport, swapping places. Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Short Rest">
                <description>You can choose a Large or smaller creature within 30 feet of you. If that creature is willing, you both teleport, swapping places.</description>
                <description level="10" action="Bonus Action">You can choose a Large or smaller creature within 90 feet of you. If that creature is willing, you both teleport, swapping places. You can alternatively choose two willing creatures to swap with each other, instead of choosing one creature to swap with you. If you do, both creatures must be within 90 feet of you and each other.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Charged Teleportation" type="Archetype Feature" source="Three Thoughts on Conjuration" id="ID_REGULAR_TTOC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORIENTATION_CHARGED_TELEPORTATION">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 6th level, you can use an action to teleport up to 60 feet to an unoccupied space that you can see. Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a long rest or you use a spell slot to cast a conjuration spell of 1st level or higher.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>You can teleport up to 60 feet to an unoccupied space that you can see. Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a long rest or you use a spell slot to cast a conjuration spell of 1st level or higher.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Greater Transposition" type="Archetype Feature" source="Three Thoughts on Conjuration" id="ID_REGULAR_TTOC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORIENTATION_GREATER_TRANSPOSITION">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 10th level, your Benign Transposition feature gains the following improvements:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>You can use the feature as a bonus action rather than an action.</li>
                    <li>The range of the feature increases to 90 feet.</li>
                    <li>You can alternatively choose two willing creatures to swap with each other, instead of choosing one creature to swap with you. If you do, both creatures must be within 90 feet of you and each other.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Defensive Rematerialization" type="Archetype Feature" source="Three Thoughts on Conjuration" id="ID_REGULAR_TTOC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORIENTATION_DEFENSIVE_REMATERIALIZATION">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 14th level, whenever you teleport using a spell or feature, until the start of your next turn, attacks against you have disadvantage and you make Strength and Dexterity saving throws with advantage.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Whenever you teleport using a spell or feature, until the start of your next turn, attacks against you have disadvantage and you make Strength and Dexterity saving throws with advantage.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>


    <element name="School of Summoning" type="Archetype" source="Three Thoughts on Conjuration" id="ID_REGULAR_TTOC_ARCHETYPE_WIZARD_SCHOOL_OF_SUMMONING">
        <supports>Arcane Tradition</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Summoners are arcanists that beckon creatures from other planes or places to their side for aid. As a student of this school, you strive to master magic that calls upon otherworldly allies, and the powers you possess can be shaped to strengthen the creatures you conjure.</p>
            <p class="indent">Most summoners employ the service of a familiar – an extraplanar entity that shares a magical bond with their summoner. Many summoners conjure fey in the form of beasts, some prefer elemental forces that have taken living form, and others still choose to deal with unpredictable and dangerous fiends. Summoners can even sometimes summon a specific creature each time they call for allies if the mage and entity manage to form a bond.</p>
            <div element="ID_REGULAR_TTOC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUMMONING_CONJURATION_SAVANT" />
            <div element="ID_REGULAR_TTOC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUMMONING_SUMMONERS_FAMILIAR" />
            <div element="ID_REGULAR_TTOC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUMMONING_ARCANE_SUMMONER" />
            <div element="ID_REGULAR_TTOC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUMMONING_FOCUSED_CONJURATION" />
            <div element="ID_REGULAR_TTOC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUMMONING_DURABLE_SUMMONS" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_REGULAR_TTOC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUMMONING_CONJURATION_SAVANT" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_REGULAR_TTOC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUMMONING_SUMMONERS_FAMILIAR" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_REGULAR_TTOC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUMMONING_ARCANE_SUMMONER" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_REGULAR_TTOC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUMMONING_FOCUSED_CONJURATION" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_REGULAR_TTOC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUMMONING_DURABLE_SUMMONS" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Conjuration Savant" type="Archetype Feature" source="Three Thoughts on Conjuration" id="ID_REGULAR_TTOC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUMMONING_CONJURATION_SAVANT">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning when you select this school at 2nd level, the gold and time you must spend to copy a conjuration spell into your spellbook is halved.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Beginning when you select this school at 2nd level, the gold and time you must spend to copy a conjuration spell into your spellbook is halved.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Summoner’s Familiar" type="Archetype Feature" source="Three Thoughts on Conjuration" id="ID_REGULAR_TTOC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUMMONING_SUMMONERS_FAMILIAR">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 2nd level when you select this school, you add the find familiar spell to your spellbook if it is not there already. Its casting time is one action for you, and you ignore the spell’s material components when you cast it. You can communicate telepathically with your familiar and perceive through your familiar’s senses as long as you are on the same plane of existence.</p>
                <p class="indent">When you cast the spell, you can choose one of the normal forms for your familiar or one of the following special forms: flying snake, gazer, imp, pseudodragon, quasit, sprite, or tressym.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Arcane Summoner" type="Archetype Feature" source="Three Thoughts on Conjuration" id="ID_REGULAR_TTOC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUMMONING_ARCANE_SUMMONER">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 6th level, you add the <em>conjure animals</em> spell to your spellbook, and it is considered a wizard spell for you. Damage from creatures you conjure count as magical for the purpose of overcoming resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage. When you cast a conjuration spell that summons creatures with a casting time longer than one action, you can cast it as an action instead.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Damage from creatures you conjure count as magical for the purpose of overcoming resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage. When you cast a conjuration spell that summons creatures with a casting time longer than one action, you can cast it as an action instead.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONJURE_ANIMALS" known="true" spellcasting="Wizard" level="6" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Focused Conjuration" type="Archetype Feature" source="Three Thoughts on Conjuration" id="ID_REGULAR_TTOC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUMMONING_FOCUSED_CONJURATION">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 10th level, while you are concentrating on a conjuration spell, your concentration can’t be broken.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>While you are concentrating on a conjuration spell, your concentration can’t be broken.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Durable Summons" type="Archetype Feature" source="Three Thoughts on Conjuration" id="ID_REGULAR_TTOC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUMMONING_DURABLE_SUMMONS">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 14th level, any creature that you summon or create with a conjuration spell has 30 temporary hit points.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Any creature that you summon or create with a conjuration spell has 30 temporary hit points.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>


</elements>