<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>School of Entropy Arcane Tradition</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="wizard-school-of-entropy.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/subclasses/wizard/wizard-school-of-entropy.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="The School of Entropy" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_GALEVEKON_RDDT_SOURCE_The School of Entropy">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation">TSOE</set>
            <set name="url">https://i.redd.it/io4hp8kjghs41.jpg</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" abbreviation="GV" url="https://www.reddit.com/u/Gale_Vekon">u/Gale_Vekon</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20200414</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
    <element name="School of Entropy" type="Archetype" source="The School of Entropy" id="ID_GV_TSOE_ARCHETYPE_WIZARD_SCHOOL_OF_ENTROPY">
        <supports>Arcane Tradition</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Called the true domain of necromancy the School 6 Entropy goes many steps further down the forbidden path of harnessing the powers of life and death, dabblin in equal parts arcane and divine. These scholars study entropic forces obsessively seeking to master negative energy thought to once have been beyond their reach.</p>
            <div element="ID_GV_TSOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ENTROPY_ENTROPY_SAVANT" />
            <div element="ID_GV_TSOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ENTROPY_DRAIN_LIFE" />
            <div element="ID_GV_TSOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ENTROPY_NECROSIS" />
            <div element="ID_GV_TSOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ENTROPY_DEATHS_REACH" />
            <div element="ID_GV_TSOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ENTROPY_NECROLORD" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GV_TSOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ENTROPY_ENTROPY_SAVANT" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GV_TSOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ENTROPY_DRAIN_LIFE" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GV_TSOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ENTROPY_NECROSIS" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GV_TSOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ENTROPY_DEATHS_REACH" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GV_TSOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ENTROPY_NECROLORD" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Entropy Savant" type="Archetype Feature" source="The School of Entropy" id="ID_GV_TSOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ENTROPY_ENTROPY_SAVANT">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning when you select this school at 2nd level, the gold and time you must spend to copy a necromancy spell, or a spell that deals necrotic damage, into your spellbook is halved.</p>
                <p class="indent">Also, all spells that deal necrotic damage or are from the necromancy school are considered to be on the wizard spell list for you, allowing you to add such spells to your spellbook. These spells are considered wizard spells for you, but other wizards can't copy these spells from your spellbook into their own spellbook.</p>
            </description>
            <spellcasting name="Wizard" extend="true">
                <extend>Necromancy</extend>
            </spellcasting>
            <sheet>
                <description>The gold and time you must spend to copy a necromancy spell, or a spell that deals necrotic damage, into your spellbook is halved.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Drain Life" type="Archetype Feature" source="The School of Entropy" id="ID_GV_TSOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ENTROPY_DRAIN_LIFE">
            <description>
                <p>At 2nd level, your knowledge of life and death allows you to steal the life energy from creatures touched by your dark spells. Once per turn when you reduce one or more creatures to 0 hit points with a spell of 1st level or higher; you gain temporary hit points equal to twice the level of the spell, or three times the spells level if the spell dealt necrotic damage or belongs to the school of necromancy. You don't gain this benefit for killing constructs.</p>
                <p class="indent">Alternatively, when a creature you can see within 30 feet of you is reduced to 0 hit points, you may use your reaction to reap its life energy gaining temporary hit points as though you killed it with a necromancy spell of 1st level.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Once per turn when you reduce one or more creatures to 0 hit points with a spell of 1st level or higher; you gain temporary hit points equal to twice the level of the spell, or three times the spells level if the spell dealt necrotic damage or belongs to the school of necromancy. You don't gain this benefit for killing constructs. Alternatively, when a creature you can see within 30 feet of you is reduced to 0 hit points, you may use your reaction to reap its life energy gaining temporary hit points as though you killed it with a necromancy spell of 1st level.</description>
                <description level="14">Once per turn when you reduce one or more creatures to 0 hit points with a spell of 1st level or higher; you gain temporary hit points equal to {{intelligence:modifier}} + twice the level of the spell, or three times the spells level if the spell dealt necrotic damage or belongs to the school of necromancy. You don't gain this benefit for killing constructs. Alternatively, when a creature you can see within 30 feet of you is reduced to 0 hit points, you may use your reaction to reap its life energy gaining temporary hit points as though you killed it with a necromancy spell of 1st level.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Necrosis" type="Archetype Feature" source="The School of Entropy" id="ID_GV_TSOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ENTROPY_NECROSIS">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 6th level, you've learned to suffuse your spells with negative energy, leaving your enemies weakened and vulnerable. Whenever you successfully hit one or more creatures with a spell that deals necrotic damage, or one or more creatures fail a saving throw against a spell you cast from the necromancy school, you can choose a number of those creatures up to your half your wizard level, rounded down, to suffer one of the following effects until the end of your next turn:</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong>Festering Wounds.</strong> The creature suffers an additional 1d4 necrotic damage whenever it receives any piercing, slashing, or necrotic damage.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong>Withering Muscle.</strong> The creature's movement speeds are reduced by 10, and it subtracts 1d4 from all damage rolls it makes.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong>Decaying Mind.</strong> The target has disadvantage on Constitution saving throws to maintain concentration, as well as Intelligence, Wisdom, and Charisma checks.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong>Rotting Flesh.</strong> The creature cannot regain hit points, and has disadvantage on Strength and Dexterity sldll checks.</p>
                <p class="indent">Constructs are immune to this feature. You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier(minimum 1) You regain all expended uses on a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Whenever you successfully hit one or more creatures with a spell that deals necrotic damage, or one or more creatures fail a saving throw against a spell you cast from the necromancy school, you can choose up to {{level:wizard:half}} of those creatures to suffer one of the following effects until the end of your next turn: Festering Wounds, Whithering Muscle, Decaying Mind, or Rotting Flesh.</description>
                <description level="14">Whenever you successfully hit one or more creatures with a spell that deals necrotic damage, or one or more creatures fail a saving throw against a spell you cast from the necromancy school, you can choose up to {{level:wizard:half}} of those creatures to suffer two of the following effects until the end of your next turn: Festering Wounds, Whithering Muscle, Decaying Mind, or Rotting Flesh.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Death's Reach" type="Archetype Feature" source="The School of Entropy" id="ID_GV_TSOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ENTROPY_DEATHS_REACH">
            <description>
                <p>At 10th level, you can briefly tap into the Negative Energ plane and imbue the weave around you with its energies. As a bonus action you enhance your spells, causing the range on any spell from the school of necromancy or a spell that does necrotic damage, to be doubled. Spells with a range of touch gain a range of 30 feet. These benefits last until the end of</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, necrotic damage you deal ignores resistances and treats immunities as resistance.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>You enhance your spells, causing the range on any spell from the school of necromancy or a spell that does necrotic damage, to be doubled. Spells with a range of touch gain a range of 30 feet. These benefits last until the end of your turn. Additionally, necrotic damage you deal ignores resistances and treats immunities as resistance.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Necrolord" type="Archetype Feature" source="The School of Entropy" id="ID_GV_TSOE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ENTROPY_NECROLORD">
            <description>
                <p>At 14th level, you've become a master of negative energy and entropy, and your body is sustained by it. You no longer need to eat, drink, sleep, or breathe, gain resistance to necrotic and poison damage, and immunity the necrotic damage of your own spells and abilities. When you cast a spell that deals necrotic damage, you can choose any number of targets you can see to be immune to the damage of your spell.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally when you affect creatures with your Necrosis feature, you may have them suffer two effects instead of one. You still expend only one use of the Necrosis feature.</p>
                <p class="indent">Finally, when you use your Drain Life feature, you gain additional temporary hit points equal to your Intelligence modifier.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You no longer need to eat, drink, sleep, or breathe, and immunity the necrotic damage of your own spells and abilities. When you cast a spell that deals necrotic damage, you can choose any number of targets you can see to be immune to the damage of your spell.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_NECROTIC" />
                <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_POISON" />
            </rules>
        </element>

</elements>