<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Yorviing’s Sorcerous Grimoire: Children of the Wild</name>
        <update version="0.0.2">
            <file name="children-of-the-wild.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/yorviings-sorcerous-grimoire/children-of-the-wild.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Arachnid Magic" type="Archetype" source="Children of the Wild" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_SORCERER_ARACHNID_MAGIC">
        <supports>Sorcerous Origin</supports>
        <description>
            <p>To many, even the sight of spiders can instill fear into the hearts of others. However, you have learned to not only to instill this fear, but also to use the power of spiders as well. You are a sorcerer who has mastered the might and abilities of spiders, manipulating other creatures and web alike.</p>
            <p class="indent">Perhaps you were bitten by a magical spider, or your birth was affected by magical abilites from Lolth. Whatever the case may be, you are a frightening and powerfully skilled sorcerer.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">ARACHNID MAGIC QUIRKS</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d6</td><td>Quirk</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>You have several sets of eyes, some larger and some smaller.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>Eating bugs is a common occurrence for you.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>You have incredibly patience, and can wait in one spot for a long period of time before what you are expecting to happen occurs.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>People often look upon you with fear in your appearance, but many still respect your abilities and wisdom.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>Small fangs protrude from your mouth, and your teeth are sharp.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>You care very deeply for young children, and often try to help in protecting them.</td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARACHNID_MAGIC_MAGIC_OF_THE_SPIDER" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARACHNID_MAGIC_VICIOUS_CONSTITUTION" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARACHNID_MAGIC_SPIDER_MOVEMENT" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARACHNID_MAGIC_WEB_FAMILIARITY" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARACHNID_MAGIC_HEIGHTENED_WEBBING" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARACHNID_MAGIC_DEN_OF_THE_WIDOW" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SORCERER_ADDITIONAL_PLAYER_OPTIONS" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SORCERER_ADDITIONAL_PLAYER_OPTIONS" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARACHNID_MAGIC_MAGIC_OF_THE_SPIDER" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARACHNID_MAGIC_VICIOUS_CONSTITUTION" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARACHNID_MAGIC_SPIDER_MOVEMENT" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARACHNID_MAGIC_WEB_FAMILIARITY" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARACHNID_MAGIC_HEIGHTENED_WEBBING" level="14" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARACHNID_MAGIC_DEN_OF_THE_WIDOW" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Magic of the Spider" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Wild" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARACHNID_MAGIC_MAGIC_OF_THE_SPIDER">
            <description>
                <p>Your connection to spiders gives you the option to learn some additional spells that focus on spiders and trapping. When your Spellcasting feature lets you learn a sorcerer spell of 1st level or higher, you gain an additional spell from the list below. These spells do not count towards the total number of spells you know, and the spells count as a sorcerer spells for you.</p>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Sorcerer Level</td><td>Spell</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1st</td><td><em>snare</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>web</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>feign death</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>7th</td><td><em>locate creature</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><em>hold monster</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>11th</td><td><em>eyebite</em></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_SNARE" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="1" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WEB" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FEIGN_DEATH" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LOCATE_CREATURE" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="7" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HOLD_MONSTER" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_EYEBITE" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="11" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Vicious Constitution" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Wild" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARACHNID_MAGIC_VICIOUS_CONSTITUTION">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 1st level, you have become accustomed to the venom within a spider’s fangs, and can even use it yourself. You have advantage on Constitution saving throws against poison. You also learn the <em>poison spray</em> cantrip.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, your gender lends you additional benefits. If you are a female, you count as one size larger when determining your carrying capacity and the weight you can push, drag, or lift. If you are a male, your movement speed increases by 5 feet. If your character has no gender, then you may choose between these two.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You have advantage on Constitution saving throws against poison. If you are a female, you count as one size larger when determining your carrying capacity and the weight you can push, drag, or lift. If you are a male, your movement speed increases by 5 feet. If your character has no gender, then you may choose between these two.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_POISON_SPRAY" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Spider Movement" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Wild" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARACHNID_MAGIC_SPIDER_MOVEMENT">
            <description>
                <p>At 1st level, your familiarity with spiders has allowed you to communicate with them. You ignore movement restrictions caused by webbing. You also are able to speak to spiders as if under the <em>speak with animals</em> spell.</p>
                <div class="reference">
                    <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_ANIMALS" />
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You ignore movement restrictions caused by webbing. You also are able to speak to spiders as if under the speak with animals spell.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_ANIMALS" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Web Familiarity" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Wild" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARACHNID_MAGIC_WEB_FAMILIARITY">
            <description>
                <p>By 6th level, you have become adept at moving like a spider. You gain a climbing speed equal to your walking speed, and you can climb difficult surfaces, including upside down on ceilings, without needing to make an ability check.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, you are now able to call upon your spider allies to aid you. As an action, you can spend 2 sorcery points to cast <em>conjure animals</em>, though you are only able to summon giant wolf spiders, swarm of spiders, or giant spiders.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="2 Sorcery Points">
                <description>You can climb difficult surfaces, including upside down on ceilings, without needing to make an ability check. As an action, you can spend 2 sorcery points to cast conjure animals, though you are only able to summon giant wolf spiders, swarm of spiders, or giant spiders.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="speed:climb" value="speed" bonus="base" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Heightened Webbing" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Wild" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARACHNID_MAGIC_HEIGHTENED_WEBBING">
            <description>
                <p>At 14th level, you have heightened your webbing skills. While in contact with a web, you know the exact location of any other creature in contact with the same web, and your movement speed is doubled when moving on webs.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, as a reaction to falling, you can shoot a strand of webbing towards a wall or ceiling to stop you from falling. This webbing has a maximum range of 100 feet, and can withstand up to 200 lbs of weight before the web breaks. You can climb up this web with a climbing speed equal to your movement speed.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>While in contact with a web, you know the exact location of any other creature in contact with the same web, and your movement speed is doubled when moving on webs. As a reaction to falling, you can shoot a strand of webbing towards a wall or ceiling to stop you from falling. This webbing has a maximum range of 100 feet, and can withstand up to 200 lbs of weight before the web breaks. You can climb up this web with a climbing speed equal to your movement speed.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Den of the Widow" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Wild" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARACHNID_MAGIC_DEN_OF_THE_WIDOW">
            <description>
                <p>By 18th level, your spider like constitution has granted you immunity to the poisoned condition.</p>
                <p class="indent">You also gain the ability to transform any area into your domain. As an action, you can spend 6 sorcery points to devour a small spider, then spew forth from your throat large amounts of webbing, which works as if you cast the spell web. However, the spell has the following changes:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>The spell’s range covers that of a 90 foot cube.</li>
                    <li>The webbing has resistance to fire damage.</li>
                    <li>The spell does not require concentration.</li>
                    <li>While moving on this webbing, you and any spiders you summon have their movement speed increased by 10 feet.</li>
                    <li>The webbing lasts for 1 minute, at which point the webbing wilts away.</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you cannot do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="6 Sorcery Points, 1/Long Rest">
                <description>You are immune to the poisoned condition. As an action, you can spend 6 sorcery points to devour a small spider, then spew forth from your throat large amounts of webbing, which works as if you cast the spell web. The spell’s range covers that of a 90 foot cube. The webbing has resistance to fire damage. The spell does not require concentration. While moving on this webbing, you and any spiders you summon have their movement speed increased by 10 feet. The webbing lasts for 1 minute, at which point the webbing wilts away.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    
    <element name="Fungal Sorcery" type="Archetype" source="Children of the Wild" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_SORCERER_FUNGAL_SORCERY">
        <supports>Sorcerous Origin</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The magics that exist within the Underdark and some dark forests of the world can sometimes alter the natural terrain and plant life that dwells within them. Your magic stems from the magical abilities of the fungi and mushrooms that live in the deep caverns of the Underdark, or the dim lower levels of ancient forests.</p>
            <p class="indent">Perhaps you lived amongst these plants for years, and their magic rubbed off on you. Some sorcerers of this origin may have had some interaction with myconids, who granted them certain magical powers, or perhaps there is some myconid blood in your family. Either way, those sorcerers who have command over the fungi of the world have a deep respect for nature and the processes of decay and rebirth through nature.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">FUNGAL SORCERY QUIRKS</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d6</td><td>Quirk</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>Small mushrooms seem to grow on parts of your body. Perhaps they even glow.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>You love to sleep in damp soil.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>Through death, new life can begin anew.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>You tend to talk very slowly and deliberately.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>The community is always more important than the individual.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>Hallucinogenic foods and drinks are a nice break from the dangers of the world.</td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FUNGAL_SORCERY_MAGIC_OF_THE_FUNGI" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FUNGAL_SORCERY_FUNGAL_VITALITY" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FUNGAL_SORCERY_REVITALIZED_FUNGUS" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FUNGAL_SORCERY_SPORE_MANIPULATION" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FUNGAL_SORCERY_FUNGAL_MASTERY" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FUNGAL_SORCERY_PLANT_OF_REGENERATION" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SORCERER_ADDITIONAL_PLAYER_OPTIONS" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SORCERER_ADDITIONAL_PLAYER_OPTIONS" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FUNGAL_SORCERY_MAGIC_OF_THE_FUNGI" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FUNGAL_SORCERY_FUNGAL_VITALITY" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FUNGAL_SORCERY_REVITALIZED_FUNGUS" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FUNGAL_SORCERY_SPORE_MANIPULATION" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FUNGAL_SORCERY_FUNGAL_MASTERY" level="14" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FUNGAL_SORCERY_PLANT_OF_REGENERATION" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Magic of the Fungi" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Wild" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FUNGAL_SORCERY_MAGIC_OF_THE_FUNGI">
            <description>
                <p>Your connection to fungi gives you the option to learn some additional spells that focus on plants, hallucination, and poison. When your Spellcasting feature lets you learn a sorcerer spell of 1st level or higher, you gain an additional spell from the list below. These spells do not count towards the total number of spells you know, and the spells count as a sorcerer spells for you.</p>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Sorcerer Level</td><td>Spell</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1st</td><td><em>entangle</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>protection from poison</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>plant growth</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>7th</td><td><em>hallucinatory terrain</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><em>wrath of nature</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>11th</td><td><em>harm</em></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENTANGLE" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="1" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PROTECTION_FROM_POISON" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PLANT_GROWTH" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HALLUCINATORY_TERRAIN" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="7" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_WRATH_OF_NATURE" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HARM" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="11" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Fungal Vitality" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Wild" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FUNGAL_SORCERY_FUNGAL_VITALITY">
            <description>
                <p>At 1st level, you have learned to use fungi to help you at death’s door. When you are reduced to 0 hit points but not killed outright, a small mushroom sprouts from your body, and you can drop to 1 hit point instead. You can’t use this feature again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>When you are reduced to 0 hit points but not killed outright, a small mushroom sprouts from your body, and you can drop to 1 hit point instead.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Revitalized Fungus" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Wild" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FUNGAL_SORCERY_REVITALIZED_FUNGUS">
            <description>
                <p>At 1st level, you have learned to make use of dead and decaying life matter just as fungi do. By touching a corpse, you can grow mushrooms on the corpse that have the nutritional value of one full meal for a number of creatures equal to your Charisma modifier.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can use this feature once per long rest, though you must choose a different corpse each time you use this feature.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>By touching a corpse, you can grow mushrooms on the corpse that have the nutritional value of one full meal up to {{charisma:modifier}} creatures. You must use a different corpse each time.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Spore Manipulation" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Wild" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FUNGAL_SORCERY_SPORE_MANIPULATION">
            <description>
                <p>By 6th level, your familiarity with fungi and spores has granted you increased resilience. You gain resistance to poison and necrotic damage.</p>
                <p class="indent">You also have learned to tap into the power of spores to creature effects that can both harm and hinder creatures. As an action, you can spend 3 sorcery points to create one of the following effects:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li><strong><em>Spores of Hallucination:</em></strong> As an action, you can eject spores at one creature you can see within 30 feet of you. The target must succeed on a Constitution saving throw against your sorcerer spell save DC or be poisoned for 1 minute. The poisoned target is incapacitated while it hallucinates. The target can then repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.</li>
                    <li><strong><em>Spores of Pacification:</em></strong> As an action, you can eject spores at one creature you can see within 30 feet of you. The target must succeed on a Constitution saving throw against your sorcerer spell save DC or be stunned for 1 minute. The target can then repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the condition on itself on a success.</li>
                    <li><strong><em>Spores of Rapport:</em></strong> As an action, you can eject spores from your body up to a 30-foot radius. These spores can go around corners and affect only creatures with an Intelligence of 2 or higher that aren’t undead, constructs, or elementals. Affected creatures can then communicate telepathically with one another while they are within 30 feet of each other. The effect lasts for 1 hour.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="3 Sorcery Points">
                <description>You can create one of the following effects: Spores of Hallucination, Spores of Pacification, or Spores of Rapport.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_POISON" />
                <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_NECROTIC" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Fungal Mastery" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Wild" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FUNGAL_SORCERY_FUNGAL_MASTERY">
            <description>
                <p>By 14th level, your use of spores has increased tremendously. Whenever you use your Spore Manipulation feature, the range increases to 60 feet for Spores of Hallucination and Spores of Pacification, and a 60-foot radius for Spores of Rapport*.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Whenever you use your Spore Manipulation feature, the range increases to 60 feet for Spores of Hallucination and Spores of Pacification, and a 60-foot radius for Spores of Rapport*.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Plant of Regeneration" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Wild" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FUNGAL_SORCERY_PLANT_OF_REGENERATION">
            <description>
                <p>By 18th level, your connection to fungi now powers your constitution. You gain immunity to disease and immunity to poison and necrotic damage, and are immune to the poisoned condition.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, you are immune to being charmed by spells that would cause you hallucinate or see an illusion.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You are immune to disease, to poison and necrotic damage, and the poisoned condition. You are immune to being charmed by spells that would cause you hallucinate or see an illusion.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    
    <element name="Insect Being" type="Archetype" source="Children of the Wild" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_SORCERER_INSECT_BEING">
        <supports>Sorcerous Origin</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The insects and bugs that inhabit the world are often small in size, though they possess incredible strength and a vast understanding of working together. You are a sorcerer who makes use of the might of insects, and thus are able to command them and change parts of your body to adapt like they can.</p>
            <p class="indent">Perhaps you grew up amongst powerful insects, and their magic altered you, or you come from a powerful bloodline of magical users who commanded control over the bugs of the world. However you came to these abilities, you are a commendable ally and a powerful sorcerer.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">INSECT BEING QUIRKS</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d6</td><td>Quirk</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>You always seem to have small insects crawling on your body, such as ants or beetles.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>You tend to think in terms of ‘we’ instead of ‘I’.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>You often eat with small, frequent bites.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>Your eyes have the appearance of compound eyes.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>Others swear that you make a buzzing or humming noise when you move.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>You enjoy being amongst blooming flowers.</td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INSECT_BEING_MAGIC_OF_THE_PESTS" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INSECT_BEING_HIVE_KIN" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INSECT_BEING_COMMANDING_SWARM" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INSECT_BEING_INSECT_STRENGTH" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INSECT_BEING_METAMORPHOSIS_FORM" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INSECT_BEING_HEIGHTENED_METAMORPHOSIS" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SORCERER_ADDITIONAL_PLAYER_OPTIONS" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SORCERER_ADDITIONAL_PLAYER_OPTIONS" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INSECT_BEING_MAGIC_OF_THE_PESTS" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INSECT_BEING_HIVE_KIN" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INSECT_BEING_COMMANDING_SWARM" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INSECT_BEING_INSECT_STRENGTH" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INSECT_BEING_METAMORPHOSIS_FORM" level="14" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INSECT_BEING_HEIGHTENED_METAMORPHOSIS" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Magic of the Pests" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Wild" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INSECT_BEING_MAGIC_OF_THE_PESTS">
            <description>
                <p>Your familiarity with insects gives you the option to learn some non-sorcerer spells that focus on bugs and insect-like traits. When your Spellcasting feature lets you learn a sorcerer spell of 1st level or higher, you gain an additional spell from the list below. These spells do not count towards the total number of spells you know, and the spells count as a sorcerer spells for you.</p>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Sorcerer Level</td><td>Spell</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1st</td><td><em>jump</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>spider climb</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>fly</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>7th</td><td><em>giant insect</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><em>insect plague</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>11th</td><td><em>mass suggestion</em></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_JUMP" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="1" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPIDER_CLIMB" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FLY" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GIANT_INSECT" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="7" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INSECT_PLAGUE" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MASS_SUGGESTION" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="11" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Hive Kin" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Wild" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INSECT_BEING_HIVE_KIN">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 1st level, the time you have spent with insects has adapted you to their vision. Your darkvision increases by 30 feet, up to a maximum of 120 feet. You also learn the <em>infestation</em> cantrip, and you can speak to ants, flies, and other insects as if you were under the effects of the <em>speak with animals</em> spell.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Your darkvision increases by 30 feet, up to a maximum of 120 feet. You can speak to ants, flies, and other insects as if you were under the effects of the speak with animals spell.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_INFESTATION" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_ANIMALS" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Commanding Swarm" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Wild" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INSECT_BEING_COMMANDING_SWARM">
            <description>
                <p>At 1st level, you can use insects to carry out tasks for you like they would for themselves. You learn the spell <em>unseen servant</em>, and it does not count towards your total number of spells known. However, when you cast this spell, you can instead choose to have your unseen servant assume the form of a swarm of tiny insects, the specific insect being of your choice. While the swarm as a whole is still considered as one servant for the purposes of AC, Strength, and hit points, you can issue up to several commands at once equal to your Charisma modifier.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you cast unseen servant, you can instead choose to have your unseen servant assume the form of a swarm of tiny insects, the specific insect being of your choice. While the swarm as a whole is still considered as one servant for the purposes of AC, Strength, and hit points, you can issue up to {{charisma:modifier}} commands at once.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_UNSEEN_SERVANT" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Insect Strength" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Wild" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INSECT_BEING_INSECT_STRENGTH">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, you are able to endure and move like most insects can. You gain resistance to poison damage and have advantage on saving throws against poison. You can also move along vertical surfaces and ceilings as if you were under the effects of the spell <em>spider climb</em>>.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You have advantage on saving throws against poison. You can also move along vertical surfaces and ceilings as if you were under the effects of the spell spider climb.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_POISON" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Metamorphosis Form" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Wild" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INSECT_BEING_METAMORPHOSIS_FORM">
            <description>
                <p>By 14th level, you have learned how to undergo a metamorphosis to change parts of your body to be more like those of an insect. Over the course of a long rest, you can choose to encase yourself completely in a cocoon, emerging at the end of the long rest to find yourself gaining two of the listed physical traits below:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Stinger or Mandible: You grow a stinger or mandibles. Whenever you are within 5 feet of a creature, you can use your bonus action to sting or bite them. The creature must make a Constitution saving throw against your spell save DC, taking poison damage equal to your sorcerer level and becoming poisoned on a failed save, and half as much poison damage on a success. Creatures immune to being poisoned automatically succeed. Any creature who fails the saving throw can repeat it at the end of their next.</li>
                    <li>Two Sets of Wings: You grow two sets of wings, the design of which resembles that of a particular insect, such as a wasp, moth, or fly. You gain a flying speed of 40 feet.</li>
                    <li>Exoskeleton: Your body becomes hardened in a chitin-like shell. Your armor class increases by 3 when you are not wearing armor or using a shield, and you reduce slashing, piercing, and bludgeoning damage you take from non-magical weapons by 2.</li>
                    <li>Strengthened Limbs: Your limbs become hardy and strong. Your movement speed increases by 10 feet, and you count as one size larger when determining your carrying capacity and the weight you can push, drag, or lift.</li>
                    <li>Hardy Constitution: Your body can endure extreme environmental conditions. You ignore difficult terrain, and can ignore the effects of extreme heat and extreme cold.</li>
                    <li>Aquatic Adaptation: You have learned how to move in the water. You gain a swimming speed equal to your walking speed, and you can breathe both water and air.</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">You can change one or two of these features out whenever you take a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Over the course of a long rest, you can choose to encase yourself completely in a cocoon, emerging at the end of the long rest to find yourself gaining two of the listed physical traits: Stinger or Mandible; Two Sets of Wings; Exoskeleton; Strengthened Limbs; Hardy Constitution; or Aquatic Adaptation. You can change one or two of these features out whenever you take a long rest.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Heightened Metamorphosis" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Wild" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INSECT_BEING_HEIGHTENED_METAMORPHOSIS">
            <description>
                <p>By 18th level, you have acclimated your body to being like that of a powerful insect. You gain immunity to poison and disease.</p>
                <p class="indent">In addition, you can use your action to spend sorcery points to enhance your metamorphosis form, and for each 2 sorcery points you spend, you may gain one additional trait from your Metamorphosis Form feature. These additional features last for 1 hour, or until you become incapacitated.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You have immunity to poison and disease. In addition, you can use your action to spend sorcery points to enhance your metamorphosis form, and for each 2 sorcery points you spend, you may gain one additional trait from your Metamorphosis Form feature. These additional features last for 1 hour, or until you become incapacitated.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    
    <element name="Oceanborn" type="Archetype" source="Children of the Wild" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_SORCERER_OCEANBORN">
        <supports>Sorcerous Origin</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The powers of the sea, much like the sea itself, are vast, mysterious, and powerful. You are a sorcerer of the oceans and seas, having power over their waters and the creatures who live inside of them. Your family could have been filled with powerful sailors or beings of the depths, or maybe you almost drowned, and this awakened great magics that had lied dormant within you. Or, it could be that your bloodline somehow originated in the Elemental Plane of Water. Whatever the case may be, the magic that exists at your command is a powerful force, and can easily be one of the strongest forms of magic that exists.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">OCEANBORN QUIRKS</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d6</td><td>Quirk</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>Something of the sea, such as barnacles, seaweeds, coral, fins, or scales, are on parts of your body.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>Your fingers and toes are webbed, and you have gills on your neck.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>The great beasts of the sea are to be both feared and respected.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>The world, much like the seas, is both beautiful and unpredictable.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>You prefer to carry some containers of fresh and salt water with you at all time.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>Like the oceans of the world, the way you are deep inside might not be how you appear on the surface.</td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OCEANBORN_MAGIC_OF_THE_OCEAN" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OCEANBORN_CREATURE_OF_THE_SEAS" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OCEANBORN_WATERS_OF_THE_DEEP" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OCEANBORN_STRENGTH_OF_THE_TIDES" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OCEANBORN_FORM_OF_THE_HYDRONIC" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OCEANBORN_CALL_OF_THE_DEPTHS" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SORCERER_ADDITIONAL_PLAYER_OPTIONS" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SORCERER_ADDITIONAL_PLAYER_OPTIONS" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OCEANBORN_MAGIC_OF_THE_OCEAN" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OCEANBORN_CREATURE_OF_THE_SEAS" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OCEANBORN_WATERS_OF_THE_DEEP" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OCEANBORN_STRENGTH_OF_THE_TIDES" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OCEANBORN_FORM_OF_THE_HYDRONIC" level="14" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OCEANBORN_CALL_OF_THE_DEPTHS" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Magic of the Ocean" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Wild" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OCEANBORN_MAGIC_OF_THE_OCEAN">
            <description>
                <p>Your familiarity with water and the seas gives you the option to learn some spells that focus on water and ice. When your Spellcasting feature lets you learn a sorcerer spell of 1st level or higher, you gain an additional spell from the list below. These spells do not count towards the total number of spells you know, and the spells count as a sorcerer spells for you.</p>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Sorcerer Level</td><td>Spell</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1st</td><td><em>create or destroy water</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>misty step</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>tidal wave</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>7th</td><td><em>control water</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><em>maelstrom</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>11th</td><td><em>wall of ice</em></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CREATE_OR_DESTROY_WATER" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="1" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MISTY_STEP" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_TIDAL_WAVE" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONTROL_WATER" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="7" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_MAELSTROM" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WALL_OF_ICE" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="11" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Creature of the Seas" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Wild" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OCEANBORN_CREATURE_OF_THE_SEAS">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 1st level, you have become accustomed to living in or near the water. You gain a swim speed equal to movement speed, and you can breathe water and air. You also learn how to read, write, and speak Aquan, and you can speak to sea creatures as if under the effects of the spell <em>speak with animals</em>.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can breathe water and air. You can speak to sea creatures as if under the effects of the spell speak with animals.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="speed:swim" value="speed" bonus="base" />
                <grant type="Language" id="ID_MM_LANGUAGE_AQUAN" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Waters of the Deep" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Wild" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OCEANBORN_WATERS_OF_THE_DEEP">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 1st level, your control over water has begun to flourish. You learn the shape water cantrip, and it counts as a sorcerer cantrip for you.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, your watery nature allows you to move like water itself. You can move through an enemy’s space but can’t willingly end your move there.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can move through an enemy’s space but can’t willingly end your move there.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_SHAPE_WATER" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Strength of the Tides" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Wild" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OCEANBORN_STRENGTH_OF_THE_TIDES">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, your watery nature has granted you increased protection. You gain resistance to fire and acid damage.</p>
                <p class="indent">In addition, you have learned how to summon water to hinder your foes. When you see a target within 30 feet of you make an attack, you can use your reaction to summon a wall of water in front of the target to impose disadvantage on the attack roll. At 14th level, the range increases to 60 feet. Once you have used this feature, you cannot do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Reaction" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>When you see a target within {{strength-of-the-tides:range}} feet of you make an attack, you can use your reaction to summon a wall of water in front of the target to impose disadvantage on the attack roll.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_FIRE" />
                <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_ACID" />
                <stat name="strength-of-the-tides:range" value="30" level="6" />
                <stat name="strength-of-the-tides:range" value="30" level="14" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Form of the Hydronic" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Wild" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OCEANBORN_FORM_OF_THE_HYDRONIC">
            <description>
                <p>At 14th level, your watery composition allows you even greater maneuverability and defense. You have advantage on Dexterity checks made against being grappled.</p>
                <p class="indent">You also are able to push opponents back with a geyser blast of water. When you are hit by a melee attack, you can use your reaction to send a geyser of powerful water shooting towards the attacker. The attacker must also make a Strength saving throw against your sorcerer spell save DC. On a failed save, the attacker is pushed in a straight line up to 10 feet away from you.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You have advantage on Dexterity checks made against being grappled. When you are hit by a melee attack, you can use your reaction to send a geyser of powerful water shooting towards the attacker. The attacker must also make a Strength saving throw (save DC {{spellcasting:dc:cha}}). On a failed save, the attacker is pushed in a straight line up to 10 feet away from you.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Call of the Depths" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Wild" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OCEANBORN_CALL_OF_THE_DEPTHS">
            <description>
                <p>By 18th level, you have become an embodiment of the power of water. You gain immunity to fire and acid damage. Additionally, you can call upon a fearsome magical beast of water to come to your aid. As an action, you can spend 6 sorcery points to cast the spell <em>illusory dragon</em>, however the spell changes in the following ways:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>The illusion assumes the shape and appearance of a creature of the sea, such as a kraken, water dragon, shark, or octopus.</li>
                    <li>The magic used to creature the illusion is pulled from the Elemental Plane of Water, and is made of water and mist.</li>
                    <li>The size of the illusion is Gargantuan.</li>
                    <li>The only damage types you can have the illusion deal are acid, cold, or lightning.</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">Once you have used this feature, you cannot do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="6 Sorcery Points, 1/Long Rest" action="Action">
                <description>You have immunity to fire and acid damage. As an action, you can spend 6 sorcery points to cast the spell illusory dragon, however the spell changes in the following ways: The illusion assumes the shape and appearance of a creature of the sea, such as a kraken, water dragon, shark, or octopus. The magic used to creature the illusion is pulled from the Elemental Plane of Water, and is made of water and mist. The size of the illusion is Gargantuan. The only damage types you can have the illusion deal are acid, cold, or lightning.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    
    <element name="Primal Hunter" type="Archetype" source="Children of the Wild" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_SORCERER_PRIMAL_HUNTER">
        <supports>Sorcerous Origin</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Your innate magic stems from the power that resides within the roaming beasts of the land, the natural hunters and strong predators. Sorcerers of this origin can sometimes trace their lineage back to some special encounter with a powerful beast, or an entity from the Beastlands. Others are descended from ancient shifters or lycanthropes, or even powerful predators of the wilds. Fewer still are those who grew up among the animals of a magical place, thus learning to adapt to be like them. Rare, deadly, and more wild than civilized, sorcerers of this origin are some of the greatest hunters and trackers of the world, and wield their magic alongside their animalistic nature.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">PRIMAL HUNTER QUIRKS</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d6</td><td>Quirk</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>The more rare the meat, the better the taste.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>Your body bears many traits of a particular animal, such as a wolf, bear, badger, lion, rat, or boar. You may have a body covered in fur, pointed hairy ears, sharp teeth, more of a snout than a nose, claws instead of fingernails, tusks, horns, or a tail.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>The wild animals are more family to you than civilized peoples.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>You sniff the air when you are tracking or hunting something.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>There are two kinds of creatures in this world: the hunters and the hunted.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>The stronger the opponent, the more respect you hold for them.</td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PRIMAL_HUNTER_MAGIC_OF_THE_BEASTS" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PRIMAL_HUNTER_PRIMAL_NATURE" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PRIMAL_HUNTER_MARKED_PREY" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PRIMAL_HUNTER_PACK_MIND" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PRIMAL_HUNTER_IMPROVED_MARKED_PREY" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PRIMAL_HUNTER_FORM_OF_THE_HUNTER" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SORCERER_ADDITIONAL_PLAYER_OPTIONS" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SORCERER_ADDITIONAL_PLAYER_OPTIONS" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PRIMAL_HUNTER_MAGIC_OF_THE_BEASTS" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PRIMAL_HUNTER_PRIMAL_NATURE" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PRIMAL_HUNTER_MARKED_PREY" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PRIMAL_HUNTER_PACK_MIND" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PRIMAL_HUNTER_IMPROVED_MARKED_PREY" level="14" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PRIMAL_HUNTER_FORM_OF_THE_HUNTER" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Magic of the Beasts" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Wild" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PRIMAL_HUNTER_MAGIC_OF_THE_BEASTS">
            <description>
                <p>Your familiarity with animals and beasts gives you the option to learn some spells that focus on animals, hunting, and tracking. When your Spellcasting feature lets you learn a sorcerer spell of 1st level or higher, you gain an additional spell from the list below. These spells do not count towards the total number of spells you know, and the spells count as a sorcerer spells for you.</p>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Sorcerer Level</td><td>Spell</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1st</td><td><em>longstrider</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>find traps</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>conjure animals</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>7th</td><td><em>locate creature</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><em>commune with nature</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>11th</td><td><em>find the path</em></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LONGSTRIDER" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="1" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIND_TRAPS" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONJURE_ANIMALS" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LOCATE_CREATURE" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="7" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMMUNE_WITH_NATURE" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIND_THE_PATH" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="11" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Primal Nature" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Wild" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PRIMAL_HUNTER_PRIMAL_NATURE">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 1st level, you share the sight and movement of beasts. Your darkvision increases by 30 feet, to a maximum of 120 feet, and you gain a climbing speed equal to your movement speed.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, you can speak with beasts, such as wolves or bears, as if under the <em>speak with animals</em> spell, and you learn the <em>primal savagery</em> cantrip, which does not count towards the total number of cantrips that you know.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Your darkvision increases by 30 feet, to a maximum of 120 feet. You can speak with beasts, such as wolves or bears, as if under the speak with animals spell.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="speed:climb" value="speed" bonus="base" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_PRIMAL_SAVAGERY" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Marked Prey" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Wild" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PRIMAL_HUNTER_MARKED_PREY">
            <description>
                <p>At 1st level, you have learned how to single out a target, as a predator tracks their prey. As a bonus action, choose one creature you can see within 30 feet of you. The target is marked for 1 minute. This mark ends early if the target dies, you die, or you are incapacitated. Until the mark ends, you gain the following benefits:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>You do not provoke opportunity attacks from the marked target.</li>
                    <li>You add your Proficiency bonus to damage rolls against the marked target.</li>
                    <li>You have advantages on Wisdom (Perception) checks made to keep tracking the marked target’s movement, so long as the marked target stays on the same plane as you.</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">You can’t use this feature again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="{{marked-prey:uses}}/Long Rest">
                <description>Choose one creature you can see within {{marked-prey:range}} feet of you. The target is marked for 1 minute. This mark ends early if the target dies, you die, or you are incapacitated. Until the mark ends, you gain the following benefits: You do not provoke opportunity attacks from the marked target. You add your Proficiency bonus to damage rolls against the marked target. ou have advantages on Perception checks made to keep tracking the marked target’s movement, so long as the marked target stays on the same plane as you.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="marked-prey:uses" value="1" level="1" />
                <stat name="marked-prey:uses" value="1" level="14" />
                <stat name="marked-prey:range" value="30" level="1" />
                <stat name="marked-prey:range" value="30" level="14" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Pack Mind" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Wild" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PRIMAL_HUNTER_PACK_MIND">
            <description>
                <p>By 6th level, your magic aids you in the hunt. Your movment speed increases by 10 feet, and by spending 3 sorcery points, you gain advantage on attack rolls against a creature if at least one of the your allies is within 5 feet of the creature and the ally isn’t incapacitated. This effect lasts for 1 minute.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, your beast-like senses now grant you advantage on any Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on hearing or smell.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>By spending 3 sorcery points, you gain advantage on attack rolls against a creature if at least one of the your allies is within 5 feet of the creature and the ally isn’t incapacitated. This effect lasts for 1 minute. You advantage on any Perception checks that rely on hearing or smell.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="innate speed:misc" value="10" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Improved Marked Prey" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Wild" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PRIMAL_HUNTER_IMPROVED_MARKED_PREY">
            <description>
                <p>By 14th level, you are a master of the hunt. You may now use your Marked Prey feature twice per long rest. Additionally, your Marked Prey feature’s range increases to 60 feet, and your movement speed increases by 10 feet.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="innate speed:misc" value="10" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Form of the Hunter" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Wild" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PRIMAL_HUNTER_FORM_OF_THE_HUNTER">
            <description>
                <p>By 18th level, the savage magic of predators has fully manifested itself within you, and you have learned how to draw upon that power to assume a large, beast-like form of your choice. As an action, you may spend 6 sorcery points to transform yourself into a beast form of yourself. This form lasts for 1 minute, you die, or you are incapacitated. While this effect is active, you gain the following benefits:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>You have resistance to damage from spells.</li>
                    <li>Your movement speed increases by 10 feet.</li>
                    <li>You count as one size larger when determining the weight you can push, drag, or lift.</li>
                    <li>When you use the primal savagery cantrip, you can affect up to two additional creatures within 5 feet of the original target.</li>
                    <li>Whenever you reduce one target to 0 hit points on your turn, you regain hit points equal to half your sorcerer level.</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">Once you have used this feature, you cannot do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="6 Sorcery Points, 1/Long Rest">
                <description>You may spend 6 sorcery points to transform yourself into a beast form of yourself. This form lasts for 1 minute, you die, or you are incapacitated. While this effect is active, you gain the following benefits: You have resistance to damage from spells. Your movement speed increases by 10 feet. You count as one size larger when determining the weight you can push, drag, or lift. When you use the primal savagery cantrip, you can affect up to two additional creatures within 5 feet of the original target. Whenever you reduce one target to 0 hit points on your turn, you regain hit points equal to half your sorcerer level.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    
    <element name="Swampheart" type="Archetype" source="Children of the Wild" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_SORCERER_SWAMPHEART">
        <supports>Sorcerous Origin</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The swamps of the world are home to some of the most adaptable creatures of the wild. You are no exception to this rule, aside from the magic that courses throughout your veins. It may have been the case that the wild magics that reside in some of the world’s most ancient swamps, or that you maybe had infused your blood with that of another entity of the swamp you had called home. You are a sorcerer of the swamp, and a powerful practitioner of magics that deal in acids, poisons, and maneuverability through both water and land, making you a great asset or a terrible foe.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">SWAMPHEART QUIRKS</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d6</td><td>Quirk</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>Most call the swamp an area to avoid, whereas you call it home.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>You have webbed feet and hands, or a thick, waterproof coat of hair or fur.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>Don’t judge a place or the things residing in it by looks alone.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>You’re used to living frequently in both water and on land.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>Moss or vines grows on parts of your body.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>You’re used to eating small bugs, fish, and amphibians.</td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SWAMPHEART_MAGIC_OF_THE_SWAMPS" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SWAMPHEART_LIFE_OF_THE_MARSH" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SWAMPHEART_BREATH_FULL_OF_MUD" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SWAMPHEART_ONE_OF_THE_FEN" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SWAMPHEART_PESTS_OF_THE_WETLANDS" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SWAMPHEART_WRATH_OF_THE_SWAMP" />
            <div class="sidebar">
                <h5 class="caption">Swampheart Ideals</h5>
                <p>A special note for Swampheart sorcerers is that they often live alone in bogs and swamps throughout the land, enjoying a life often undisturbed by others. Another potential creative route that you can take with your Swampheart Sorcerer is including one, or multiple, of the following Ideals that your character lives by.</p>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>d6</td><td>Ideal</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1</td><td>Somebody once told you that the world was gonna roll you.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>2</td><td>You’ve been told that you are not the sharpest tool in the shed.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3</td><td>To you, once the years start coming, they will not stop coming.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>4</td><td>You have always felt that it doesn’t make sense not to live for fun.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5</td><td>In life, there is so much to do, and, of course, so much to see.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>6</td><td>You think that one will never shine if you don’t ever glow.</td></tr>
                </table>
            </div>
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SORCERER_ADDITIONAL_PLAYER_OPTIONS" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SORCERER_ADDITIONAL_PLAYER_OPTIONS" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SWAMPHEART_MAGIC_OF_THE_SWAMPS" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SWAMPHEART_LIFE_OF_THE_MARSH" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SWAMPHEART_BREATH_FULL_OF_MUD" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SWAMPHEART_ONE_OF_THE_FEN" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SWAMPHEART_PESTS_OF_THE_WETLANDS" level="14" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SWAMPHEART_WRATH_OF_THE_SWAMP" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Magic of the Swamps" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Wild" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SWAMPHEART_MAGIC_OF_THE_SWAMPS">
            <description>
                <p>Your familiarity with swamps gives you the option to learn some spells that focus on fogs, acid, and nature. When your Spellcasting feature lets you learn a sorcerer spell of 1st level or higher, you gain an additional spell from the list below. These spells do not count towards the total number of spells you know, and the spells count as a sorcerer spells for you.</p>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Sorcerer Level</td><td>Spell</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1st</td><td><em>fog cloud</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>melf’s acid arrow</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>stinking cloud</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>7th</td><td><em>grasping vine</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><em>wrath of nature</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>11th</td><td><em>wall of thorns</em></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FOG_CLOUD" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="1" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MELFS_ACID_ARROW" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_STINKING_CLOUD" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GRASPING_VINE" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="7" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_WRATH_OF_NATURE" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WALL_OF_THORNS" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="11" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Life of the Marsh" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Wild" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SWAMPHEART_LIFE_OF_THE_MARSH">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 1st level, the magic of the swamps has altered your very being. You can breathe air and water, and you gain a swimming speed equal to your walking speed. In addition, you learn the shape water cantrip, which does not count towards the total number of cantrips you know.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can breathe air and water.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="speed:swim" value="speed" bonus="base" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Breath Full of Mud" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Wild" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SWAMPHEART_BREATH_FULL_OF_MUD">
            <description>
                <p>At 1st level, you have learned to use the mud from bogs to help you. As an action, you spew forth viscid mud onto one creature within 15 feet of you. If the target is Medium or smaller, it must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw against you spell save DC or be restrained for up to 1 minute. A creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success. At 14th level, you can target creatures of Large or smaller.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>You spew forth viscid mud onto one creature within 15 feet of you. If the target is Medium or smaller, it must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw (save DC {{spellcasting:dc:cha}}) or be restrained for up to 1 minute. A creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.</description>
                <description level="14">You spew forth viscid mud onto one creature within 15 feet of you. If the target is Large or smaller, it must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw (save DC {{spellcasting:dc:cha}}) or be restrained for up to 1 minute. A creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="One of the Fen" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Wild" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SWAMPHEART_ONE_OF_THE_FEN">
            <description>
                <p>By 6th level, you have adapted more to bogs and fens. You gain resistance to acid damage, and you ignore difficult terrain caused by swamps, bogs, and fens.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, your familiarity with swamps has allowed you additional benefits. You cannot become lost in a swamp, by both magical and non-magical means, and you have advantage on Wisdom (Survival) checks made while in swamps or marsh.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You ignore difficult terrain caused by swamps, bogs, and fens. You cannot become lost in a swamp, by both magical and non-magical means, and you have advantage on Survival checks made while in swamps or marsh.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_ACID" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Pests of the Wetlands" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Wild" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SWAMPHEART_PESTS_OF_THE_WETLANDS">
            <description>
                <p>At 14th level, you have learned how to summon the pests of the swamp to your aid. When you are hit by a melee attack, you can use your reaction to summon a light green cloud filled with a swarm of insects to the attacker as the insects pierce into their skin. The attacker must also make a Constitution saving throw against your sorcerer spell save DC. On a failed save, the attacker takes acid damage equal to half your sorcerer level.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you are hit by a melee attack, you can use your reaction to summon a light green cloud filled with a swarm of insects to the attacker as the insects pierce into their skin. The attacker must also make a Constitution saving throw against your sorcerer spell save DC. On a failed save, the attacker takes acid damage equal to half your sorcerer level.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Wrath of the Swamp" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Wild" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SWAMPHEART_WRATH_OF_THE_SWAMP">
            <description>
                <p>By 18th level, you know that the powers of the swamp can always aid you, no matter where you are. You gain immunity to acid damage.</p>
                <p class="indent">In addition, as an action you can spend 6 sorcery points to slam your hands into the ground, transforming the nearby terrain to create a swamp that grows to a circle with a 30 foot radius centered on you. You and a number of creatures up to your Charisma modifier are immune to the swamp’s magic. This swamp has the following effects:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>This land is difficult terrain.</li>
                    <li>The swamp is filled with a dense fog, and each creature within the swamp has disadvantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on sight or smell.</li>
                    <li>Each creature who is in the swamp’s range when this effect is cast must make a Constitution saving throw against your spell save DC, or become poisoned. Creatures who cannot be poisoned are immune, and creatures who succeed the saving throw initially are immune to the swamps poison. A creature who is poisoned can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns.</li>
                    <li>When a creature does not move on it’s turn while within range of this ability, it must make a Dexterity saving throw against your spell save DC, or begin to sink into the swamp and become grappled.</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you cannot do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="6 Sorcery Points, 1/Long Rest">
                <description>You have immunity to acid damage. You can spend 6 sorcery points to slam your hands into the ground, transforming the nearby terrain to create a swamp that grows to a circle with a 30 foot radius centered on you. You and up to {{charisma:modifier}} creatures are immune to the swamp’s magic. This swamp has the following effects: This land is difficult terrain. The swamp is filled with a dense fog, and each creature within the swamp has disadvantage on Perception checks that rely on sight or smell. Each creature who is in the swamp’s range when this effect is cast must make a Constitution saving throw against your spell save DC, or become poisoned. Creatures who cannot be poisoned are immune, and creatures who succeed the saving throw initially are immune to the swamps poison. A creature who is poisoned can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns. When a creature does not move on it’s turn while within range of this ability, it must make a Dexterity saving throw against your spell save DC, or begin to sink into the swamp and become grappled.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

  <!-- Additional Player Options for Children of the Cycles -->
    <element name="Additional Player Options" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Wild" id="ID_YORVIING_COTW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SORCERER_ADDITIONAL_PLAYER_OPTIONS">
      <description>
          <p>What are sorcerers without their unique qualities? From how the world reacts to them to how they wield their magic, sorcerers have rare and incredible features that make them who they are. Below are four d6 roll tables that are geared more towards the origins presented in this compendium, and as such will focus more on aspects related to the seasons, nature, etc.</p>
          <p class="indent">However they can be used for anyone building a sorcerer, particularly if someone has a specific character or backstory in mind. Feel free to use any of these roll tables for your sorcerer! And DM’s, perhaps these tables can help you in creating unique NPC’s!</p>
          <h4>Additional Arcane Origins</h4>
          <p>Use this roll table for additional options for how your sorcerer discovered or gained their powers. What was the source? What does it tie to in the world?</p>
          <table>
              <thead>
                  <tr><td>d6</td><td>Arcane Origin</td></tr>
              </thead>
              <tr><td>1</td><td>Your bloodline is tied to the land itself.</td></tr>
              <tr><td>2</td><td>An entity from another plane, such as the Beastlands or the Elemental Plane of Water, blessed your family.</td></tr>
              <tr><td>3</td><td>Your magical powers stem from a birth overseen by powerful elementals or beasts.</td></tr>
              <tr><td>4</td><td>You were raised by the animals of the wilds, and discovered your magic through them.</td></tr>
              <tr><td>5</td><td>Your family comes from an ancient line of druids.</td></tr>
              <tr><td>6</td><td>Your family raised you to be a protector of the lands and animals.</td></tr>
          </table>
          <h4>Additional Reactions</h4>
          <p>Use this roll table for additional options on how the world and the people in it react to your sorcerer. Are they appalled and fearful, or are they in awe and full of praise for you and your abilities?</p>
          <table>
              <thead>
                  <tr><td>d6</td><td>Reaction</td></tr>
              </thead>
              <tr><td>1</td><td>Your powers are seen as signalling the start of a golden era for animals or nature.</td></tr>
              <tr><td>2</td><td>Some fear your power, perhaps as a result of your actions, or simply your appearance.</td></tr>
              <tr><td>3</td><td>Your magical abilities brought forth a renewed interest of nature in your village or city.</td></tr>
              <tr><td>4</td><td>The magic you wield is seen as being a part of the natural world, just like the weather and animal migrations.</td></tr>
              <tr><td>5</td><td>Your powers came suddenly and abruptly, causing you to lose control and thus become despised by your community.</td></tr>
              <tr><td>6</td><td>Animals and critters in your community interacted with you more than the people did.</td></tr>
          </table>
          <h4>Additional Supernatural Marks</h4>
          <p>Use this roll table for additional options for the unique qualities that your sorcerer has that sets them apart from other wielders of magic. Is it source of pride and power, or a mark of shame that should remain hidden?</p>
          <table>
              <thead>
                  <tr><td>d6</td><td>Supernatural Mark</td></tr>
              </thead>
              <tr><td>1</td><td>Your eyes resemble that of a an insect or animals’.</td></tr>
              <tr><td>2</td><td>You have webbed fingers and toes, long fur, or some other animal part.</td></tr>
              <tr><td>3</td><td>Your breath smells salty, foul, or like that of a panting animal.</td></tr>
              <tr><td>4</td><td>You always smell earthy or dirty, even when scrubbed clean.</td></tr>
              <tr><td>5</td><td>Your feet and toes resemble fins, paws, claws, or have an insect-like appearance</td></tr>
              <tr><td>6</td><td>Your speech sounds like a collection of chittering noises, warbled by water, or rough.</td></tr>
          </table>
          <h4>Additional Signs of Sorcery</h4>
          <p>Use this roll table tof additional options for the effects that wielding your magic has on either you or the surrounding environment. Is your magic a telltale signal of who you are, like a trademark? Or is it something that reveals more about who you are and where your magic originates?</p>
          <table>
              <thead>
                  <tr><td>d6</td><td>Sign of Sorcery</td></tr>
              </thead>
              <tr><td>1</td><td>You follow or begin the verbal components of spells in the sound of an animal calling.</td></tr>
              <tr><td>2</td><td>Your eyes flash with wild fury when you use the somatic components of spells.</td></tr>
              <tr><td>3</td><td>You deliver the somatic components of spells in a wild display of movement.</td></tr>
              <tr><td>4</td><td>When you begin casting a spell, tiny creatures of the land or sea begin crawling over your body, then disappear when you are finished casting.</td></tr>
              <tr><td>5</td><td>The air around you when you cast a spell smells of salt water, bog water, or like an animal’s den.</td></tr>
              <tr><td>6</td><td>Your body’s hair, fur, or feathers stand up immediately before and after you cast a spell.</td></tr>
          </table>
      </description>
      <sheet display="false">
          <description></description>
      </sheet>
      <rules>
          <select type="List" name="Arcane Origin">
            <item id="1">Your bloodline is tied to the land itself.</item>
            <item id="2">An entity from another plane, such as the Beastlands or the Elemental Plane of Water, blessed your family.</item>
            <item id="3">Your magical powers stem from a birth overseen by powerful elementals or beasts.</item>
            <item id="4">You were raised by the animals of the wilds, and discovered your magic through them.</item>
            <item id="5">Your family comes from an ancient line of druids.</item>
            <item id="6">Your family raised you to be a protector of the lands and animals.</item>
          </select>
          <select type="List" name="Reaction">
            <item id="1">Your powers are seen as signalling the start of a golden era for animals or nature.</item>
            <item id="2">Some fear your power, perhaps as a result of your actions, or simply your appearance.</item>
            <item id="3">Your magical abilities brought forth a renewed interest of nature in your village or city.</item>
            <item id="4">The magic you wield is seen as being a part of the natural world, just like the weather and animal migrations.</item>
            <item id="5">Your powers came suddenly and abruptly, causing you to lose control and thus become despised by your community.</item>
            <item id="6">Animals and critters in your community interacted with you more than the people did.</item>
          </select>
          <select type="List" name="Supernatural Mark">
            <item id="1">Your eyes resemble that of a an insect or animals’.</item>
            <item id="2">You have webbed fingers and toes, long fur, or some other animal part.</item>
            <item id="3">Your breath smells salty, foul, or like that of a panting animal.</item>
            <item id="4">You always smell earthy or dirty, even when scrubbed clean.</item>
            <item id="5">Your feet and toes resemble fins, paws, claws, or have an insect-like appearance</item>
            <item id="6">Your speech sounds like a collection of chittering noises, warbled by water, or rough.</item>
          </select>
          <select type="List" name="Sign of Sorcery">
            <item id="1">You follow or begin the verbal components of spells in the sound of an animal calling.</item>
            <item id="2">Your eyes flash with wild fury when you use the somatic components of spells.</item>
            <item id="3">You deliver the somatic components of spells in a wild display of movement.</item>
            <item id="4">When you begin casting a spell, tiny creatures of the land or sea begin crawling over your body, then disappear when you are finished casting.</item>
            <item id="5">The air around you when you cast a spell smells of salt water, bog water, or like an animal’s den.</item>
            <item id="6">Your body’s hair, fur, or feathers stand up immediately before and after you cast a spell.</item>
          </select>
      </rules>
    </element>
  
</elements>