<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Yorviing’s Sorcerous Grimoire: Children of the Cycles</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="children-of-the-cycles.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/yorviings-sorcerous-grimoire/children-of-the-cycles.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Flower Child" type="Archetype" source="Children of the Cycles" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_SORCERER_FLOWER_CHILD">
        <supports>Sorcerous Origin</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The season of spring is a time of rebrith, renewal, and revitalizing growth, as animals awaken from hibernation, flowers begin to bloom, and the land returns from the dreary blanket of winter to the welcoming warmth of blue skies and vibrant green growth.</p>
            <p class="indent">You are a sorcerer of this powerful energy, and manifest it in the form of one spring’s most signature features: blooming flowers. Perhaps you were born on the first day of spring, or are the descendent of a powerful dryad or a deity of nature. You may even have come from a bloodline of powerful druids, or had your powers awakened by a magical flower. Whatever the case may be, you are a sorcerer of joy and vibrance, but a powerful one still.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">FLOWER CHILD QUIRKS</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d6</td><td>Quirk</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>You always smell like sweet, blooming flowers.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>From your hair to your skin to your clothing, you are quite a colorful individual.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>Animals that help to pollinate flowers are your favorite kind.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>You know that everything has its chance to shine, its chance to ‘bloom’.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>You keep flowers with you at all times, and your skin has occasional little thorns on it.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>You are at your best when spring is in the air, and everything is beginning to return from winter.</td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FLOWER_CHILD_MAGIC_OF_THE_SPRING" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FLOWER_CHILD_NATURAL_KNOWLEDGE" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FLOWER_CHILD_FLOWER_SPEECH" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FLOWER_CHILD_REJUVENATING_BLOOM" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FLOWER_CHILD_BLOSSOMING_LIFE" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FLOWER_CHILD_FLORAL_MASTERY" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SORCERER_ADDITIONAL_PLAYER_OPTIONS" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SORCERER_ADDITIONAL_PLAYER_OPTIONS" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FLOWER_CHILD_MAGIC_OF_THE_SPRING" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FLOWER_CHILD_NATURAL_KNOWLEDGE" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FLOWER_CHILD_FLOWER_SPEECH" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FLOWER_CHILD_REJUVENATING_BLOOM" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FLOWER_CHILD_BLOSSOMING_LIFE" level="14" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FLOWER_CHILD_FLORAL_MASTERY" level="18" />
            <select type="List" name="Quirk">
                <item id="1">You always smell like sweet, blooming flowers.</item>
                <item id="2">From your hair to your skin to your clothing, you are quite a colorful individual.</item>
                <item id="3">Animals that help to pollinate flowers are your favorite kind.</item>
                <item id="4">You know that everything has its chance to shine, its chance to ‘bloom’.</item>
                <item id="5">You keep flowers with you at all times, and your skin has occasional little thorns on it.</item>
                <item id="6">You are at your best when spring is in the air, and everything is beginning to return from winter.</item>
            </select>
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Magic of the Spring" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Cycles" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FLOWER_CHILD_MAGIC_OF_THE_SPRING">
            <description>
                <p>Your connection to spring and flowers gives you the option to learn some additional spells that focus on plants and vines. When your Spellcasting feature lets you learn a sorcerer spell of 1st level or higher, you gain an additional spell from the list below. These spells do not count towards the total number of spells you know, and the spells count as a sorcerer spells for you.</p>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Sorcerer Level</td><td>Spell</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1st</td><td><em>entangle</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>spike growth</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>plant growth</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>7th</td><td><em>grasping vine</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><em>wrath of nature</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>11th</td><td><em>wall of thorns</em></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENTANGLE" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="1" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPIKE_GROWTH" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PLANT_GROWTH" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GRASPING_VINE" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="7" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_WRATH_OF_NATURE" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WALL_OF_THORNS" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="11" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Natural Knowledge" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Cycles" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FLOWER_CHILD_NATURAL_KNOWLEDGE">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 1st level, your knowledge of flowers and nature has granted you proficiency in the Nature skill and the Herbalism Kit.</p>
                <p class="indent">You also learn the <em>thorn whip</em> cantrip, which counts as a sorcerer cantrip for you.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_NATURE" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_HERBALISM_KIT" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_THORN_WHIP" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Flower Speech" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Cycles" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FLOWER_CHILD_FLOWER_SPEECH">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 1st level, you have gained the ability to communicate with flowers. You can speak to flowers and plants as if using the <em>speak with plants</em> spell.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, bees, butterflies, hummingbirds, and any animal who helps to spread pollen treat you with respect, and whenever you make a Charisma check when interacting with any of these types of animals or flowers, your Proficiency bonus is doubled if it applies to the check.</p>
                <div class="reference">
                    <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_PLANTS" />
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can speak to flowers and plants as if using the <em>speak with plants</em> spell. Additionally, bees, butterflies, hummingbirds, and any animal who helps to spread pollen treat you with respect, and whenever you make a Charisma check when interacting with any of these types of animals or flowers, your Proficiency bonus is doubled if it applies to the check.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_PLANTS" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Rejuvenating Bloom" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Cycles" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FLOWER_CHILD_REJUVENATING_BLOOM">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 6th level, your connection to flowers has granted you the ability to move through nonmagical difficult terrain at the cost of no extra movement. You can also pass through nonmagical plants without being slowed by them and without taking damage from them if they have thorns, spines, or a similar hazard.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, you are able to send rejuvenating energy to your allies. As an action, you can spend 3 sorcery points to let flowers that are either on you or held by you bloom, sending pollen and sweet aromas towards others, allowing creatures of your choice up to your Charisma modifier and within a 30 feet radius of you to gain temporary hit points equal to half your sorcerer level, as well as having advantage on saving throws against being charmed for 1 minute. This range increases to 60 feet at 14th level.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="3 Sorcery Points" >
                <description>Pick up to {{charisma:modifier}} creatures within {{rejuvenating-bloom:range}} feet. Those creatures gain {{level:sorcerer:half}} temporary hit points and gain advantage on saving throws against being charmed for 1 minute. Additionally, you can move through nonmagical difficult terrain at the cost of no extra movement. You can also pass through nonmagical plants without being slowed by them and without taking damage from them if they have thorns, spines, or a similar hazard.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="rejuvenating-bloom:range" value="30" level="6" />
                <stat name="rejuvenating-bloom:range" value="30" level="14" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Blossoming Life" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Cycles" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FLOWER_CHILD_BLOSSOMING_LIFE">
            <description>
                <p>At 14th level, you have learned how to use nourishing energy akin to how flowers and plants can. You do not need to consume food per long rest so long as you have spent at least 1 hour in direct sunlight.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, you can cause your blooming flowers to carry additional healing qualities. When you use your Rejuvenation Bloom feature, creatures who benefit from it regain hit points equal to half your sorcerer level, and have advantage on saving throws against being poisoned for 1 minute.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You do not need to consume food per long rest so long as you have spent at least 1 hour in direct sunlight. When you use your Rejuvenation Bloom feature, creatures who benefit from it regain hit points equal to half your sorcerer level, and have advantage on saving throws against being poisoned for 1 minute.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Floral Mastery" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Cycles" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FLOWER_CHILD_FLORAL_MASTERY">
            <description>
                <p>By 18th level, you have become a beautiful aspect of nature. You gain immunity to the charmed condition, and when a plant creature attacks you, that creature must make a Wisdom saving throw against your sorcerer spell save DC. On a failed save, the creature must choose a different target, or the attack automatically misses. On a successful save, the creature is immune to this effect for 24 hours. The creature is aware of this effect before it makes its attack against you.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, you have learned how to send blooming flowers onto your enemies that benefit your allies. As an action, you can spend 4 sorcery points to cause flowers to spread to creatures of your choice within a 90 foot area. Each creature must make a Constitution saving throw against your sorcerer spell save DC, or the flower roots itself onto their body, and the creature takes piercing damage equal to your sorcerer level. When the creature takes damage, the flower sends into the air a sweet smelling pollen within a 10 foot radius of the creature. Allies of your choice who are within this area regain hit points equal to your Charisma modifier. A creature who has a flower rooted into them can repeat the saving throw again, or take additional piercing damage equal to half your sorcerer level on a failed save, and ending the effect on a success. Creatures without blood, such as constructs or invisible undead, are immune to this effect.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you have used this feature, you cannot do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="4 Sorcery Points, 1/Long Rest">
                <description>Choose creatures within a 90 foot area. ach creature must make a Constitution saving throw (save DC {{spellcasting:dc}}), or the flower roots itself onto their body, and the creature takes {{level:sorcerer}} piercing damage. Allies of your choice who are within 10 feet of a creature that takes damage regain {{charisma:modifier}} hit points. A creature who has a flower rooted into them can repeat the saving throw at the end of their turn, or take additional {{level:sorcerer:half}} piercing damage. Creatures without blood are immune.
                Additionally, you are immune to the charmed condition. When a plant creature attacks you, that creature must make a Wisdom saving throw against your sorcerer spell save DC. On a failed save, the creature must choose a different target, or the attack automatically misses. On a successful save, the creature is immune to this effect for 24 hours.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    
    <element name="Sunblessed" type="Archetype" source="Children of the Cycles" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_SORCERER_SUNBLESSED">
        <supports>Sorcerous Origin</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The season of summer is a time for things in nature to thrive, to bask under the warm brilliance of the sun. The days become longer, and many flock to activities outside, all the while as the sun shines gloriously above them.</p>
            <p class="indent">You are a sorcerer imbued with the heat of summer and the might of the midday sun. Thus, the power of both flame and solar radiance are yours to command. Perhaps you were born during a summer solstice, or an incredible celestial being blessed your family long ago. However you came to have these powers, you are a wielder of both fire and the strength of the sun.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">SUNBLESSED QUIRKS</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d6</td><td>Quirk</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>You enjoy being in sunlight as much as possible.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>Your body never appears to be effected by long exposure to sunlight.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>The footsteps you leave seem to singe, as if slightly burned.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>Your eyes seem to shine or twinkle brightly, and your skin is always warm to the touch.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>You envy the power of the sun, as you wish that you could be so grossly incandescent.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>Your hair is a vibrant blonde, red, or auburn color.</td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUNBLESSED_MAGIC_OF_THE_SUN" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUNBLESSED_SOUL_OF_THE_SUN" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUNBLESSED_LIGHT_OF_THE_DAWN" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUNBLESSED_STRENGTH_OF_THE_FLAME" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUNBLESSED_HEART_OF_THE_SUNFLARE" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUNBLESSED_ASPECT_OF_HIGH_NOON" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SORCERER_ADDITIONAL_PLAYER_OPTIONS" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SORCERER_ADDITIONAL_PLAYER_OPTIONS" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUNBLESSED_MAGIC_OF_THE_SUN" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUNBLESSED_SOUL_OF_THE_SUN" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUNBLESSED_LIGHT_OF_THE_DAWN" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUNBLESSED_STRENGTH_OF_THE_FLAME" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUNBLESSED_HEART_OF_THE_SUNFLARE" level="14" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUNBLESSED_ASPECT_OF_HIGH_NOON" level="18" />
            <select type="List" name="Quirk">
                <item id="1">You enjoy being in sunlight as much as possible.</item>
                <item id="2">Your body never appears to be effected by long exposure to sunlight.</item>
                <item id="3">The footsteps you leave seem to singe, as if slightly burned.</item>
                <item id="4">Your eyes seem to shine or twinkle brightly, and your skin is always warm to the touch.</item>
                <item id="5">You envy the power of the sun, as you wish that you could be so grossly incandescent.</item>
                <item id="6">Your hair is a vibrant blonde, red, or auburn color.</item>
            </select>
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Magic of the Sun" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Cycles" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUNBLESSED_MAGIC_OF_THE_SUN">
            <description>
                <p>Your connection to summer and the sun gives you the option to learn some additional spells that focus on fire, heat, and solar radiance. When your Spellcasting feature lets you learn a sorcerer spell of 1st level or higher, you gain an additional spell from the list below. These spells do not count towards the total number of spells you know, and the spells count as a sorcerer spells for you.</p>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Sorcerer Level</td><td>Spell</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1st</td><td><em>guiding bolt</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>continual flame</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>daylight</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>7th</td><td><em>aura of life</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><em>dawn</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>11th</td><td><em>sunbeam</em></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GUIDING_BOLT" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="1" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONTINUAL_FLAME" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DAYLIGHT" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AURA_OF_LIFE" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="7" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_DAWN" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SUNBEAM" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="11" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Soul of the Sun" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Cycles" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUNBLESSED_SOUL_OF_THE_SUN">
            <description>
                <p>At 1st level, you learn the <em>light</em> and <em>control flames</em> cantrips. In addition, you have advantage on Perception checks made in daylight.</p>
                <p class="indent">You also learn to read, write, and speak Celestial, and you always know the position of the sun, even when underground.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You always know the position of the sun, even when underground.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LIGHT" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_CONTROL_FLAMES" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" />
                <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_CELESTIAL" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Light of the Dawn" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Cycles" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUNBLESSED_LIGHT_OF_THE_DAWN">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 1st level, as a bonus action you can cause your body to radiate bright light in a 10 foot radius from you, with dim light out an additional 10 feet. You can end this effect at any time.</p>
                <p class="indent">In addition, you can attune yourself to the sun to gain additional strength from it. By spending 1 minute in direct sunlight by meditating, you gain temporary hit points equal to half your sorcerer level plus your Charisma modifier.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you have used this feature, you cannot do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>You can cause your body to radiate bright light in a 10 foot radius from you, with dim light out an additional 10 feet. You can end this effect at any time. Once per long rest, you can spend 1 minute in direct sunlight meditating, and gain {{light-of-the-dawn:temp-hp}} temporary hit points.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="light-of-the-dawn:temp-hp" value="level:sorcerer:half" />
                <stat name="light-of-the-dawn:temp-hp" value="charisma:modifier" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Strength of the Flame" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Cycles" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUNBLESSED_STRENGTH_OF_THE_FLAME">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, you gain resistance to fire and radiant damage.</p>
                <p class="indent">In addition, whenever you start casting a spell of 1st level or higher that deals fire or radiant damage, blinding flames or light suddenly shine from you. This light causes creatures of your choice that you can see within 10 feet of you to make a Wisdom saving throw against your spell save DC. On a failed save, the target is blinded until the beginning of their next turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Whenever you start casting a spell of 1st level or higher that deals fire or radiant damage, creatures of your choice that you can see within 10 feet of you need to make a Wisdom saving throw (save DC {{spellcasting:dc}}). On a failed save, the target is blinded until the beginning of their next turn.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_FIRE" />
                <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_RADIANT" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Heart of the Sunflare" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Cycles" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUNBLESSED_HEART_OF_THE_SUNFLARE">
            <description>
                <p>By 14th level, you have become accustomed to heat and brightness. You are unaffected by the effects of extreme heat, and you are immune to the blinded condition.</p>
                <p class="indent">In addition, when you cast a spell that deals fire or radiant damage, you can spend 2 sorcery points to make one target of the spell receive additional fire or radiant damage equal to half your sorcerer level.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You are unaffected by the effects of extreme heat, and you are immune to the blinded condition. when you cast a spell that deals fire or radiant damage, you can spend 2 sorcery points to make one target of the spell receive {{level:sorcerer:half}} additional fire or radiant damage.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Aspect of High Noon" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Cycles" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUNBLESSED_ASPECT_OF_HIGH_NOON">
            <description>
                <p>At 18th level, your very essence is powered by the sun. You gain immunity to fire and radiant damage.</p>
                <p class="indent">In addition, as an action, you can spend 5 sorcery points to wreathe yourself in bright flames or light. For up to 1 minute while in this form, you gain the following benefits:</p>
                <p class="indent">Spells you cast that deal fire or radiant damage ignore resistances to fire and radiant damage, and treat immunities to fire and radiant damage as resistances.</p>
                <p class="indent">Whenever you are subject to fire or radiant damage, you instead regain hit points equal to 1/4th the damage dealt.</p>
                <p class="indent">Lights or flames within a 20 foot radius of you cannot be extinguished or dimmed by any means. Any extinguished lights or flames become reignited when they are within this aura.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you have used this feature, you cannot do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="5 Sorcery Points, 1/Long Rest" action="Action">
                <description>You are immune to fire and radiant damage. Additionally, once per long rest, as an action, you can spend 5 sorcery points to wreathe yourself in bright flames for up to 1 minute. Spells you cast that deal fire or radiant damage ignore resistances to fire and radiant damage, and treat immunities to fire and radiant damage as resistances. Whenever you are subject to fire or radiant damage, you instead regain hit points equal to 1/4th the damage dealt. Lights or flames within a 20 foot radius of you cannot be extinguished or dimmed by any means. Any extinguished lights or flames become reignited when they are within this aura.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    
    <element name="Autumnal Spirit" type="Archetype" source="Children of the Cycles" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_SORCERER_AUTUMNAL_SPIRIT">
        <supports>Sorcerous Origin</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The season of autumn is a curious one; the season brings people together, to celebrate successful harvests and rejoice in festivals, but it also is a reminder that all things will slowly meet their end and wither away to bring life to something new. Yet even with this process, there is beauty and joy to be found in the passing of life into death, as the cold snaps away at once were warm, summer days.</p>
            <p class="indent">You are a sorcerer who wields the power of cold, decay, and bountiful harvests, and as such are both a welcome ally and a powerful foe. Your powers could have originated from an entity of death and decay, or from a powerful god of harvest. Or, perhaps your bloodline stems from a culture that relishes in the season of autumn, and are keepers of crops. Whatever the case may be, you are a wielder of the magics that surround the season of autumn.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">AUTUMNAL SPIRIT QUIRKS</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d6</td><td>Quirk</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>Your eyes are orange, auburn, deep brown, yellow, or grey in color.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>Many call upon you to be present during a harvest, as if you are a good luck charm.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>You smell like cinnamon, pumpkins, apples, hay, apples, damp wood, or fallen leaves.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>You are a rather melancholy individual.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>when you are near trees, they will shed a few of their leaves, as if in autumn.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>You are always ready to plan or attend a festival.</td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AUTUMNAL_SPIRIT_MAGIC_OF_THE_FALL" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AUTUMNAL_SPIRIT_ONE_WITH_THE_FALL" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AUTUMNAL_SPIRIT_KNOWLEDGE_OF_HARVESTS" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AUTUMNAL_SPIRIT_GUARDIANS_OF_THE_FIELDS" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AUTUMNAL_SPIRIT_CLOAK_OF_FALLEN_LEAVES" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AUTUMNAL_SPIRIT_MASTER_OF_AUTUMN" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SORCERER_ADDITIONAL_PLAYER_OPTIONS" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SORCERER_ADDITIONAL_PLAYER_OPTIONS" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AUTUMNAL_SPIRIT_MAGIC_OF_THE_FALL" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AUTUMNAL_SPIRIT_ONE_WITH_THE_FALL" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AUTUMNAL_SPIRIT_KNOWLEDGE_OF_HARVESTS" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AUTUMNAL_SPIRIT_GUARDIANS_OF_THE_FIELDS" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AUTUMNAL_SPIRIT_CLOAK_OF_FALLEN_LEAVES" level="14" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AUTUMNAL_SPIRIT_MASTER_OF_AUTUMN" level="18" />
            <select type="List" name="Quirk">
                <item id="1">Your eyes are orange, auburn, deep brown, yellow, or grey in color.</item>
                <item id="2">Many call upon you to be present during a harvest, as if you are a good luck charm.</item>
                <item id="3">You smell like cinnamon, pumpkins, apples, hay, apples, damp wood, or fallen leaves.</item>
                <item id="4">You are a rather melancholy individual.</item>
                <item id="5">when you are near trees, they will shed a few of their leaves, as if in autumn.</item>
                <item id="6">You are always ready to plan or attend a festival.</item>
            </select>
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Magic of the Fall" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Cycles" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AUTUMNAL_SPIRIT_MAGIC_OF_THE_FALL">
            <description>
                <p>Your connection to autumn gives you the option to learn some additional spells that focus on cold, decay, and harvests. When your Spellcasting feature lets you learn a sorcerer spell of 1st level or higher, you gain an additional spell from the list below. These spells do not count towards the total number of spells you know, and the spells count as a sorcerer spells for you.</p>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Sorcerer Level</td><td>Spell</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1st</td><td><em>fog cloud</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>spike growth</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>sleet storm</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>7th</td><td><em>blight</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><em>druid grove</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>11th</td><td><em>heroes’ feast</em></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FOG_CLOUD" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="1" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPIKE_GROWTH" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SLEET_STORM" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLIGHT" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="7" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_DRUID_GROVE" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HEROES_FEAST" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="11" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="One With the Fall" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Cycles" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AUTUMNAL_SPIRIT_ONE_WITH_THE_FALL">
            <description>
                <p>By 1st level, you have attuned yourself to nature and autumn. You gain proficiency in the Nature skill, and you learn the <em>druidcraft</em> cantrip.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_NATURE" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DRUIDCRAFT" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Knowledge of Harvests" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Cycles" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AUTUMNAL_SPIRIT_KNOWLEDGE_OF_HARVESTS">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 1st level, your experience with harvests and preparing feasts has granted you additional benefits. You gain proficiency in sickles, and can use one as an arcane focus.</p>
                <p class="indent">In addition, once per long rest, you may spend 10 minutes scouring the land for edible crops, such as fruits and vegetables, equal to your Charisma modifier. Any creature who eats one of these foods gains the following benefits:</p>
                <p class="indent">Creatures can use their bonus action to eat one fruit or vegetable. They cannot eat more than one fruit or vegetable per turn.</p>
                <p class="indent">Creatures regain hit points equal to your Charisma modifier.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You may spend 10 minutes scouring the land for edible crops, such as fruits and vegetables, finding {{charisma:modifier}}. Any creature who spends a bonus action eating one fruit or vegetable regains {{charisma:modifier}} hit points.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SICKLE" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Guardians of the Fields" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Cycles" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AUTUMNAL_SPIRIT_GUARDIANS_OF_THE_FIELDS">
            <description>
                <p>By 6th level, you have become accustomed to the cooler climates of autumn, and the natural states of decay that autumn brings. You gain resistance to cold and necrotic damage.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, you can call upon the guardians of harvests to come to your aid. As an action, you toss into the air a handful of straw or hay, spending 3 sorcery points to summon a scarecrow (Monster Manual, pg. 268).</p>
                <p class="indent">The scarecrow obeys your commands, and acts on your initiative order. The scarecrow exists until they are reduced to 0 hit points or are dispelled as a bonus action.</p>
                <p class="indent">Also, whenever you are within 10 feet of your summoned scarecrow, you have advantage on Charisma saving throws against being frightened.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="3 Sorcery Points">
                <description>You can summon a scarecrow that obeys your commands and acts on your initiative. The scarecrow exists until they are reduced to 0 hit points or are dispelled as a bonus action. Whenever you are within 10 feet of your summoned scarecrow, you have advantage on Charisma saving throws against being frightened.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_COLD" />
                <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_NECROTIC" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Cloak of Fallen Leaves" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Cycles" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AUTUMNAL_SPIRIT_CLOAK_OF_FALLEN_LEAVES">
            <description>
                <p>By 14th level, the plants of the land have become your ally. You can cast <em>speak with plants</em> at will.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, as a bonus action, you may summon a cloak of fallen leaves to wrap around you. While wearing this cloak, once on each of your turns, you can use 10 ft. of your movement to step magically into one living tree within your reach and emerge from a second living tree within 60 ft. of the first tree, appearing in an unoccupied space within 5 ft. of the second tree. Both trees must be large or bigger.</p>
                <p class="indent">Whenever you enter a tree, the tree changes in appearance as if it was autumn, and reverts back whenever you exit a tree.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>You may summon a cloak of fallen leaves to wrap around you. While wearing this cloak, once on each of your turns, you can use 10 ft. of your movement to step magically into one living tree within your reach and emerge from a second living tree within 60 ft. of the first tree, appearing in an unoccupied space within 5 ft. of the second tree. Both trees must be large or bigger. Also, you can cast speak with plans at will.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_PLANTS" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Master of Autumn" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Cycles" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AUTUMNAL_SPIRIT_MASTER_OF_AUTUMN">
            <description>
                <p>At 18th level, you have become one with the autumnal chills and decay. You gain immunity to cold and necrotic damage.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, whenever a creature eats one of the fruits or vegetables gathered from your Knowledge of Harvests feature, they gain resistance to either cold or necrotic damage (your choice) for 1 hour.</p>
                <p class="indent">Also, when you use your Guardian of the Fields feature, you may summon one additional scarecrow for each additional sorcery point you spend, up to a maximum of four scarecrows.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You have immunity to cold and necrotic damage. Whenever a creature eats one of the fruits or vegetables gathered from your Knowledge of Harvests feature, they gain resistance to either cold or necrotic damage (your choice) for 1 hour. When you use your Guardian of the Fields feature, you may summon one additional scarecrow for each additional sorcery point you spend, up to a maximum of four scarecrows.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    
    <element name="Winterheart" type="Archetype" source="Children of the Cycles" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_SORCERER_WINTERHEART">
        <supports>Sorcerous Origin</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The season of winter brings forth a time of cold winds, hibernation, and grey skies. Most of the land lies under blankets of white snow, and as the days shorten only the strongest and fiercest animals and people even dare to thrive amidst the cold.</p>
            <p class="indent">You are a sorcerer who controls the might of winter, with the power of ice and howling winds at your fingertips. Perhaps you were born during the harshest winter the land had ever seen, or you almost died during a blizzard. Or, you may have been almost frozen at some point in your life, your powers awakening from the experience. However you came to obtain your magical abilities, you are a being of pure wintery magic.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">WINTERHEART QUIRKS</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d6</td><td>Quirk</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>Your skin is always icy to the touch.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>Whenever you breathe, you can always see the air escape you as if you are in cold climates.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>Your hair and skin are an almost snow-white in color.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>There are always small chunks of ice in your hair or on your body, regardless of surrounding temperature.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>You have very thick, shaggy hair or fur.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>When you walk on natural terrain such as grass or plants, the ground and plants ice over in your footsteps.</td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WINTERHEART_MAGIC_OF_THE_WINTER" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WINTERHEART_FREEZING_FURY" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WINTERHEART_TUNDRA_SURVIVALIST" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WINTERHEART_ICY_WIND" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WINTERHEART_FROZEN_MOBILITY" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WINTERHEART_CALL_OF_THE_WINTER" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SORCERER_ADDITIONAL_PLAYER_OPTIONS" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SORCERER_ADDITIONAL_PLAYER_OPTIONS" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WINTERHEART_MAGIC_OF_THE_WINTER" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WINTERHEART_FREEZING_FURY" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WINTERHEART_TUNDRA_SURVIVALIST" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WINTERHEART_ICY_WIND" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WINTERHEART_FROZEN_MOBILITY" level="14" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WINTERHEART_CALL_OF_THE_WINTER" level="18" />
            <select type="List" name="Quirk">
                <item id="1">Your skin is always icy to the touch.</item>
                <item id="2">Whenever you breathe, you can always see the air escape you as if you are in cold climates.</item>
                <item id="3">Your hair and skin are an almost snow-white in color.</item>
                <item id="4">There are always small chunks of ice in your hair or on your body, regardless of surrounding temperature.</item>
                <item id="5">You have very thick, shaggy hair or fur.</item>
                <item id="6">When you walk on natural terrain such as grass or plants, the ground and plants ice over in your footsteps.</item>
            </select>
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Magic of the Winter" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Cycles" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WINTERHEART_MAGIC_OF_THE_WINTER">
            <description>
                <p>Your connection to winter gives you the option to learn some additional spells that focus on ice and wind. When your Spellcasting feature lets you learn a sorcerer spell of 1st level or higher, you gain an additional spell from the list below. These spells do not count towards the total number of spells you know, and the spells count as a sorcerer spells for you.</p>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Sorcerer Level</td><td>Spell</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1st</td><td><em>armor of agathys</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>snilloc’s snowball swarm</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>sleet storm</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>7th</td><td><em>ice storm</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><em>cone of cold</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>11th</td><td><em>investiture of wind</em></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ARMOR_OF_AGATHYS" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="1" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_SNILLOCS_SNOWBALL_SWARM" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SLEET_STORM" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ICE_STORM" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="7" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONE_OF_COLD" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_INVESTITURE_OF_WIND" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="11" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Freezing Fury" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Cycles" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WINTERHEART_FREEZING_FURY">
            <description>
                <p>At 1st level, you know how to tap into the power of cold spells. You learn the <em>ray of frost</em> cantrip.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, when you hit a creature with a spell that deals cold damage, you can reduce that creature’s speed by 5 feet until the end of their next turn. This increases to 10 feet at 14th level.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you hit a creature with a spell that deals cold damage, you can reduce that creature’s speed by 5 feet until the end of their next turn.</description>
                <description level="14">When you hit a creature with a spell that deals cold damage, you can reduce that creature’s speed by 10 feet until the end of their next turn.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RAY_OF_FROST" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Tundra Survivalist" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Cycles" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WINTERHEART_TUNDRA_SURVIVALIST">
            <description>
                <p>At 1st level, your familiarity with cold regions and winter have made you a hardier individual. You gain proficiency in the Survival skill.</p>
                <p class="indent">In addition, you are also naturally adapted to cold climates, and can move across difficult terrain made of ice or snow without expending extra movement.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You are also naturally adapted to cold climates, and can move across difficult terrain made of ice or snow without expending extra movement.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SURVIVAL" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Icy Wind" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Cycles" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WINTERHEART_ICY_WIND">
            <description>
                <p>By 6th level, you gain resistance to cold damage.</p>
                <p class="indent">In addition, as an action, you can spend 3 sorcery points to create a warding wind of snow and ice on yourself that lasts until you finish a long rest. The icy wind has hit points equal to twice your sorcerer level. Whenever you take damage, the icy wind takes the damage instead. If this damage reduces the ward to 0 hit points, you take any remaining damage.</p>
                <p class="indent">While the icy wind has 0 hit points, it can’t absorb damage, but its magic remains. On your turn, if you cast a spell that deals cold damage or end your turn on ground composed of snow or ice, the icy wind regains a number of hit points equal to half your sorcerer level.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you create the icy wind, you can’t create it again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="3 Sorcery Points, 1/Long Rest">
                <description>You can create a warding wind of snow and ice on yourself that lasts until you finish a long rest. The wind has {{icy-wind:hp}} hit points. Whenever you take damage, the icy wind takes the damage instead. If this damage reduces the ward to 0 hit points, you take any remaining damage. While the icy wind has 0 hit points, it can’t absorb damage. On your turn, if you cast a spell that deals cold damage or end your turn on ground composed of snow or ice, the icy wind regains a number of hit points equal to half your sorcerer level.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_COLD" />
                <stat name="icy-wind:hp" value="level:sorcerer" />
                <stat name="icy-wind:hp" value="level:sorcerer" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Frozen Mobility" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Cycles" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WINTERHEART_FROZEN_MOBILITY">
            <description>
                <p>At 14th level, your power over ice can be used to help you move about the land and air. As an action, you can summon ice to emerge from beneath you, lifting you off the ground and into the air. While maintaining concentration, you can use this ice to maneuver you through the air as if you had a flying speed equal to your movement speed, so long as at least one of your feet maintains a connection to the ice. Whenever your feet leave the ice, the ice shatters into tiny pieces of ice.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>You can summon ice to emerge from beneath you, lifting you off the ground and into the air. While maintaining concentration, you can use this ice to maneuver you through the air as if you had a flying speed of {{speed}} feet, so long as at least one of your feet maintains a connection to the ice. Whenever your feet leave the ice, the ice shatters into tiny pieces of ice.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Call of the Winter" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Cycles" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WINTERHEART_CALL_OF_THE_WINTER">
            <description>
                <p>By 18th level, your connection to the chills of winter has granted you immunity to cold damage, as well as resistance to fire damage.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, you may create a mighty storm of frost, filled with chilling air, dense fog, and flakes of ice. As an action, you can spend 5 sorcery points to create a powerful force of whirling, cold wind centered in a 20 foot radius centered on you, and reaching about 15 feet in height. This storm lasts for 1 minute, or until you lose concentration. While active, this storm has the following effects:</p>
                <p class="indent">Howling winds filled with chilling air and ice flakes whirl around you. Creatures who are within this area suffer 4d8 cold damage and 4d8 slashing damage as the cold winds and sharp ice flakes batter them. Creatures must also make a Strength saving throw against your spell save DC or be pushed 20 feet out of the storm.</p>
                <p class="indent">Ranged attacks made against you have disadvantage.</p>
                <p class="indent">Creatures stuck in the storm move at half their normal speed as the chilling air and fog make navigation difficult.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you have used this feature, you cannot do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="5 Sorcery Points, 1/Long Rest">
                <description>You are immune to cold damage. As an action, you can spend 5 sorcery points to create a powerful force of whirling, cold wind centered in a 20 foot radius centered on you, and reaching about 15 feet in height. This storm lasts for 1 minute, or until you lose concentration. Creatures who are within this area suffer 4d8 cold damage and 4d8 slashing damage as the cold winds and sharp ice flakes batter them. Creatures must also make a Strength saving throw against your spell save DC or be pushed 20 feet out of the storm. Ranged attacks made against you have disadvantage. Creatures stuck in the storm move at half their normal speed as the chilling air and fog make navigation difficult.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_FIRE" />
            </rules>
        </element>

    
    <element name="Moontouched" type="Archetype" source="Children of the Cycles" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_SORCERER_MOONTOUCHED">
        <supports>Sorcerous Origin</supports>
        <description>
            <p>To many, the moon is an important aspect of both nature and culture: it helps keep track of the passage of time, represents the feminine side of nature, and effects the tides of the ocean. It also is a symbol for the night, and holds strong connections to lycanthropy and, as some claim, even lunacy.</p>
            <p class="indent">You are a sorcerer who derives their power from the moon and its cycles. Perhaps you were born during a full or new moon, or even during an eclipse, perhaps even planned by your family or village in an attempt to bring forth someone who can help against a tide of lycanthropes. Or, you may have had an experience under the light of the moon that changed your life forever. Whatever the case, you have magical abilities drawn from the moon, and are a beacon in the night.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">MOONTOUCHED QUIRKS</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d6</td><td>Quirk</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>You skin, hair, or fur is a pale white color.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>Your eyes are larger than normal, and have larger cornea to adjust to the night.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>You sing, pray, or speak to the moon when it is out.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>Downtime at night is best spent running amongst other nocturnal creatures.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>Owls, wolves, and bats are your favorite animals.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>You feel as though waves on lakes and oceans have a respect towards you, if that could even be.</td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOONTOUCHED_MAGIC_OF_THE_MOON" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOONTOUCHED_NOCTURNAL_CREATURE" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOONTOUCHED_PENUMBRAL_SILVER" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOONTOUCHED_LUNAR_BLESSINGS" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOONTOUCHED_MOONLIGHT_CLOAK" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOONTOUCHED_DREAD_ECLIPSE" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SORCERER_ADDITIONAL_PLAYER_OPTIONS" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SORCERER_ADDITIONAL_PLAYER_OPTIONS" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOONTOUCHED_MAGIC_OF_THE_MOON" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOONTOUCHED_NOCTURNAL_CREATURE" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOONTOUCHED_PENUMBRAL_SILVER" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOONTOUCHED_LUNAR_BLESSINGS" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOONTOUCHED_MOONLIGHT_CLOAK" level="14" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOONTOUCHED_DREAD_ECLIPSE" level="18" />
            <select type="List" name="Quirk">
                <item id="1">You skin, hair, or fur is a pale white color.</item>
                <item id="2">Your eyes are larger than normal, and have larger cornea to adjust to the night.</item>
                <item id="3">You sing, pray, or speak to the moon when it is out.</item>
                <item id="4">Downtime at night is best spent running amongst other nocturnal creatures.</item>
                <item id="5">Owls, wolves, and bats are your favorite animals.</item>
                <item id="6">You feel as though waves on lakes and oceans have a respect towards you, if that could even be.</item>
            </select>
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Magic of the Moon" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Cycles" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOONTOUCHED_MAGIC_OF_THE_MOON">
            <description>
                <p>Your connection to the moon and its cycles gives you the option to learn some additional spells that focus on sleep, tides, beasts, and lunar radiance. When your Spellcasting feature lets you learn a sorcerer spell of 1st level or higher, you gain an additional spell from the list below. These spells do not count towards the total number of spells you know, and the spells count as a sorcerer spells for you.</p>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Sorcerer Level</td><td>Spell</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1st</td><td><em>sleep</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>moonbeam</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>tidal wave</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>7th</td><td><em>conjure woodland beings</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><em>dream</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>11th</td><td><em>*sunbeam**</em></td></tr>
                </table>
                <p class="indent"><em>*The only change from this spell is that the light is moonlight instead of sunlight</em></p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SLEEP" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="1" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MOONBEAM" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_TIDAL_WAVE" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONJURE_WOODLAND_BEINGS" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="7" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DREAM" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SUNBEAM" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="11" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Nocturnal Creature" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Cycles" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOONTOUCHED_NOCTURNAL_CREATURE">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 1st level, you have darkvision with a range of 120 feet, and can see through both magical and non-magical darkness. You also no longer need to sleep can’t be forced to sleep by any means. To gain the benefits of a long rest, you can spend all 8 hours doing light activity, such as reading, writing, or keeping watch. You also learn the <em>light</em> cantrip.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can see through both magical and non-magical darkness. You also no longer need to sleep can’t be forced to sleep by any means. To gain the benefits of a long rest, you can spend all 8 hours doing light activity, such as reading, writing, or keeping watch.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_SUPERIORDARKVISION" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LIGHT" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Penumbral Silver" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Cycles" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOONTOUCHED_PENUMBRAL_SILVER">
            <description>
                <p>At 1st level, the power of the moon courses through your veins. You are immune to lycanthropy.</p>
                <p class="indent">In addition, you can use an action to touch one weapon to coat it in a magical, silver coating, making the weapon silvered for 1 hour. You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier per long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="{{charisma:modifier/Long Rest}}">
                <description>You are immune to lycanthropy. In addition, you can use an action to touch one weapon to coat it in a magical, silver coating, making the weapon silvered for 1 hour. You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier per long rest.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Lunar Blessings" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Cycles" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOONTOUCHED_LUNAR_BLESSINGS">
            <description>
                <p>By 6th level, you’ve become attuned to the light of the moon, and have learned to strike your enemies with blinding moonlight. You gain resistance to radiant damage, and whenever you are in dim light or darkness, you can spend 2 sorcery points as a bonus action to become invisible until you take an action or reaction.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, you’ve learned to halt the transformation of shapechangers and lycanthropes. Whenever a shapechanger or lycanthrope within 30 feet of you used their action to transform, you can channel rays of moonlight to surround them as a reaction, forcing the target to make a Constitution saving throw against your spell save DC. On a failure, the target is unable to transform and is blinded until the beginning of their next turn. On a successful save, the target is immune to this ability for 1 hour.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Whenever you are in dim light or darkness, you can spend 2 sorcery points as a bonus action to become invisible until you take an action or reaction. Whenever a shapechanger or lycanthrope within 30 feet of you used their action to transform, you can channel rays of moonlight to surround them as a reaction, forcing the target to make a Constitution saving throw (save DC {{spellcasting:dc}}). On a failure, the target is unable to transform and is blinded until the beginning of their next turn. On a successful save, the target is immune to this ability for 1 hour.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_RADIANT" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Moonlight Cloak" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Cycles" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOONTOUCHED_MOONLIGHT_CLOAK">
            <description>
                <p>At 14th level, you can craft a shimmering cloak of moonlight around your body. As an action, you can spend 2 sorcery points to make your moonlight cloak appear for 1 hour or until you are incapacitated. This cloak grants you resistance to cold damage, and sheds bright light out to 10 feet from you and dim light an additional 10 feet. In addition, whenever a creature ends their turn within 10 feet of you, that creature must make a Wisdom saving throw against your spell save DC. On a failure, the creature is charmed by you until the beginning of their next turn. A creature who fails this saving throw must make it again should they end their turn within 10 feet of you, and a creature who succeeds is immune to its effects. You can end this effect as a bonus action.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="2 Sorcery Points">
                <description>You can make your moonlight cloak appear for 1 hour or until you are incapacitated. This cloak grants you resistance to cold damage, and sheds bright light out to 10 feet from you and dim light an additional 10 feet. In addition, whenever a creature ends their turn within 10 feet of you, that creature must make a Wisdom saving throw (save DC {{spellcasting:dc}}). On a failure, the creature is charmed by you until the beginning of their next turn. A creature who fails this saving throw must make it again should they end their turn within 10 feet of you, and a creature who succeeds is immune to its effects. You can end this effect as a bonus action.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Dread Eclipse" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Cycles" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOONTOUCHED_DREAD_ECLIPSE">
            <description>
                <p>At 18th level, you have become the physical embodiment of the moon. By spending 6 sorcery points as an action, you can draw the power of the moon to you before channeling it towards the sky. The sky becomes dark, as if under the effects of a lunar eclipse. Creatures of your choice within a radius of 60 feet of you gain temporary hit points equal to your sorcerer level, while every other creature within this range must make a Wisdom saving throw or take radiant damage equal to your sorcerer level and become blinded, taking half as much damage and not being blinded on a successful save. Once you have used this feature, you cannot do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="6 Sorcery Points, 1/Long Rest">
                <description>Creatures of your choice within a radius of 60 feet of you gain {{level:sorcerer}} temporary hit points, while every other creature within this range must make a Wisdom saving throw or take {{level:sorcerer}} radiant damage and become blinded, taking half as much damage and not being blinded on a successful save.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    
    <element name="Wooden Soul" type="Archetype" source="Children of the Cycles" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_SORCERER_WOODEN_SOUL">
        <supports>Sorcerous Origin</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Trees have long been an incredible part of nature; they provide oxygen for the air, shelter for creatures, wood for tools and weapons, and can grow to mighty heights and strength during their life cycles.</p>
            <p class="indent">Your innate magic comes from the element of wood, from the might of ancient trees and forests. Some wielders of this rare magic often trace their lineage back to ancient druid ancestors, whereas others were exposed to some magical event within a forest or from a particular tree. Or you were blessed by a powerful fey, or born in the Feywild itself. Whatever the cause of your magic, your command over wood and trees leaves you a formidable force, both of nature and magic.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">WOODEN SOUL QUIRKS</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d6</td><td>Quirk</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>You always seem to have leaves in your hair or clothing.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>You never say anything unless it is worth taking a very long time to say.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>You prefer to sleep under a tree than in a bed.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>You often prefer to hear or read stories of druids and long to speak their language.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>You swear you feel the pain of a tree cutting down.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>You often smell like pine, cedar, oak, or some other type of tree.</td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WOODEN_SOUL_MAGIC_OF_THE_TREES" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WOODEN_SOUL_KNOWLEDGE_OF_THE_COPSE" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WOODEN_SOUL_CRAFTS_OF_THE_WEALD" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WOODEN_SOUL_STRENGTH_OF_THE_COPPICE" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WOODEN_SOUL_MOVEMENT_OF_THE_TIMBERLAND" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WOODEN_SOUL_BENEVOLENCE_OF_THE_FOREST" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SORCERER_ADDITIONAL_PLAYER_OPTIONS" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SORCERER_ADDITIONAL_PLAYER_OPTIONS" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WOODEN_SOUL_MAGIC_OF_THE_TREES" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WOODEN_SOUL_KNOWLEDGE_OF_THE_COPSE" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WOODEN_SOUL_CRAFTS_OF_THE_WEALD" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WOODEN_SOUL_STRENGTH_OF_THE_COPPICE" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WOODEN_SOUL_MOVEMENT_OF_THE_TIMBERLAND" level="14" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WOODEN_SOUL_BENEVOLENCE_OF_THE_FOREST" level="18" />
            <select type="List" name="Quirk">
                <item id="1">You always seem to have leaves in your hair or clothing.</item>
                <item id="2">You never say anything unless it is worth taking a very long time to say.</item>
                <item id="3">You prefer to sleep under a tree than in a bed.</item>
                <item id="4">You often prefer to hear or read stories of druids and long to speak their language.</item>
                <item id="5">You swear you feel the pain of a tree cutting down.</item>
                <item id="6">You often smell like pine, cedar, oak, or some other type of tree.</item>
            </select>
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Magic of the Trees" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Cycles" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WOODEN_SOUL_MAGIC_OF_THE_TREES">
            <description>
                <p>Your connection to trees and its life cycles gives you the option to learn some additional spells that focus on wood, groves, and walking amongst the trees. When your Spellcasting feature lets you learn a sorcerer spell of 1st level or higher, you gain an additional spell from the list below. These spells do not count towards the total number of spells you know, and the spells count as a sorcerer spells for you.</p>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Sorcerer Level</td><td>Spell</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1st</td><td><em>*entangle</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>barkskin</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>plant growth</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>7th</td><td><em>conjure woodland beings</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><em>tree stride</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>11th</td><td><em>druid grove</em></td></tr>
                </table>
                <p class="indent">*entangle <em>uses branches and wood instead.</em></p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENTANGLE" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="1" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BARKSKIN" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PLANT_GROWTH" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONJURE_WOODLAND_BEINGS" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="7" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TREE_STRIDE" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_DRUID_GROVE" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="11" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Knowledge of the Copse" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Cycles" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WOODEN_SOUL_KNOWLEDGE_OF_THE_COPSE">
            <description>
                <p>At 1st level, your familiarity with forests and woodlands has granted you proficiency in the Nature skill. You also can speak to trees as if under the effects of the spell <em>speak with plants</em>.</p>
                <p class="indent">In addition, you learn the <em>druidcraft</em> and <em>shillelagh</em> cantrips, which both count as a sorcerer spells for you and do not count towards the total number of cantrips you know.</p>
                <div class="reference">
                    <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_PLANTS" />
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can speak to trees as if under the effects of the spell speak with plants.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_NATURE" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_PLANTS" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DRUIDCRAFT" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHILLELAGH" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Crafts of the Weald" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Cycles" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WOODEN_SOUL_CRAFTS_OF_THE_WEALD">
            <description>
                <p>At 1st level, you are able to create small objects out of wood by growing the wood out of your body. You can use your action to create an inanimate object created out of wood in your hand or on the ground in an unoccupied space that you can see within 10 feet of you. This object can be no larger than 3 feet on a side and weigh no more than 20 pounds, and its form must be that of a nonmagical object that you have seen. The object is visibly magical, with the wood giving the appearance of perfect craftsmanship. The object disappears after 1 hour, when you use this feature again, or if it takes any damage.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>You can use your action to create an inanimate object created out of wood in your hand or on the ground in an unoccupied space that you can see within 10 feet of you. This object can be no larger than 3 feet on a side and weigh no more than 20 pounds, and its form must be that of a nonmagical object that you have seen.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Strength of the Coppice" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Cycles" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WOODEN_SOUL_STRENGTH_OF_THE_COPPICE">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 6th level, the strength of trees flows through you. As an action, you can spend 3 sorcery points to assume the strength of a tree in a ’tree form’ as your skin becomes covered in thick bark, branches, and leaves. For 1 minute, or until you are reduced to 0 hit points. While in this form, you gain the following benefits:</p>
                <p class="indent">You count as one size larger when determining your carrying capacity and the weight you can push, drag, or lift.</p>
                <p class="indent">You have advantage on checks and saving throws against being knocked prone as if rooted into the ground.</p>
                <p class="indent">Your AC increases by 2.</p>
                <p class="indent">Your reach for touch spells increases by 5 feet as your arms extend as if like branches. This increases to 10 feet at 14th level.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="3 Sorcery Points">
                <description>Your skin becomes covered in thick bark, branches, and leaves. For 1 minute, or until you are reduced to 0 hit points. You count as one size larger when determining your carrying capacity and the weight you can push, drag, or lift. You have advantage on checks and saving throws against being knocked prone as if rooted into the ground. Your AC increases by 2. Your reach for touch spells increases by {{strength-of-the-coppice:range}} feet as your arms extend as if like branches.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="strength-of-the-coppice:range" value="5" level="6" />
                <stat name="strength-of-the-coppice:range" value="5" level="14" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Movement of the Timberland" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Cycles" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WOODEN_SOUL_MOVEMENT_OF_THE_TIMBERLAND">
            <description>
                <p>By 14th level, you’ve learned to move amongst the trees. Once on each of your turns, you can use 10 feet of your movement to step magically into one living tree within 5 feet of you and emerge from a second living tree within 60 feet of you that you can see, appearing in an unoccupied space within 5 feet of the second tree. Both trees must be Large or bigger.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, you may move up trees and structures made of wood as if under the effects of the <em>spider climb</em> spell, and you ignore difficult terrain caused by roots, branches, and trees.</p>
                <div class="reference">
                    <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPIDER_CLIMB" />
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Once on each of your turns, you can use 10 feet of your movement to step magically into one living tree within 5 feet of you and emerge from a second living tree within 60 feet of you that you can see, appearing in an unoccupied space within 5 feet of the second tree. Both trees must be Large or bigger. Additionally, you may move up trees and structures made of wood as if under the effects of the spider climb spell, and you ignore difficult terrain caused by roots, branches, and trees.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPIDER_CLIMB" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Benevolence of the Forest" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Cycles" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WOODEN_SOUL_BENEVOLENCE_OF_THE_FOREST">
            <description>
                <p>At 18th level, you age similarly to a tree. For every 10 years that pass, your body ages only 1 year, and your lifespan increases by 500-600 years.</p>
                <p class="indent">In addition, your body has gained the strength of a mighty tree. You have advantage on Strength checks and saving throws. Your skin also hardens like bark, and you are always considered to be under the effects of the spell barkskin.</p>
                <div class="reference">
                    <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_BARKSKIN" />
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>For every 10 years that pass, your body ages only 1 year, and your lifespan increases by 500-600 years. You have advantage on Strength checks and saving throws. Your skin also hardens like bark, and you are always considered to be under the effects of the spell barkskin.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BARKSKIN" />
            </rules>
        </element>

  <!-- Additional Player Options for Children of the Cycles -->
  <element name="Additional Player Options" type="Archetype Feature" source="Children of the Cycles" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SORCERER_ADDITIONAL_PLAYER_OPTIONS">
      <description>
          <p>What are sorcerers without their unique qualities? From how the world reacts to them to how they wield their magic, sorcerers have rare and incredible features that make them who they are. Below are four d6 roll tables that are geared more towards the origins presented in this compendium, and as such will focus more on aspects related to the seasons, nature, etc.</p>
          <p class="indent">However they can be used for anyone building a sorcerer, particularly if someone has a specific character or backstory in mind. Feel free to use any of these roll tables for your sorcerer! And DM’s, perhaps these tables can help you in creating unique NPC’s!</p>
          <h4>Additional Arcane Origins</h4>
          <p>Use this roll table for additional options for how your sorcerer discovered or gained their powers. What was the source? What does it tie to in the world?</p>
          <table>
              <thead>
                  <tr><td>d6</td><td>Arcane Origin</td></tr>
              </thead>
              <tr><td>1</td><td>Your birth occurred during a solstice, an eclipse, or the first day of a season.</td></tr>
              <tr><td>2</td><td>A supernatural being of the seasons blessed your family with a gift. That gift was you.</td></tr>
              <tr><td>3</td><td>Your birth was part of a prophecy foretold during a culture’s significant holiday.</td></tr>
              <tr><td>4</td><td>Your family has a deep connection to a particular season or the moon, and as such, you are expected to follow in their footsteps.</td></tr>
              <tr><td>5</td><td>Raw, untamed powers in nature changed the nature of your birth, affecting you forever.</td></tr>
              <tr><td>6</td><td>You are from a bloodline filled with druids, or even a dryad.</td></tr>
          </table>
          <h4>Additional Reactions</h4>
          <p>Use this roll table for additional options on how the world and the people in it react to your sorcerer. Are they appalled and fearful, or are they in awe and full of praise for you and your abilities?</p>
          <table>
              <thead>
                  <tr><td>d6</td><td>Reaction</td></tr>
              </thead>
              <tr><td>1</td><td>Your family holds great expectations of you for returning the seasons to their glory.</td></tr>
              <tr><td>2</td><td>You are seen as a blessing from the gods, sent to help people in a time of environmental crisis.</td></tr>
              <tr><td>3</td><td>Your powers over the cycles of nature has made people wary of what your true intentions are.</td></tr>
              <tr><td>4</td><td>Your people fear you, thinking that you will offset the natural cycles of nature.</td></tr>
              <tr><td>5</td><td>You are seen as the ‘good luck charm’ of your home.</td></tr>
              <tr><td>6</td><td>Powerful fey and intelligent beasts watch over your progress, whether you are aware of it or not.</td></tr>
          </table>
          <h4>Additional Supernatural Marks</h4>
          <p>Use this roll table for additional options for the unique qualities that your sorcerer has that sets them apart from other wielders of magic. Is it source of pride and power, or a mark of shame that should remain hidden?</p>
          <table>
              <thead>
                  <tr><td>d6</td><td>Supernatural Mark</td></tr>
              </thead>
              <tr><td>1</td><td>You seem to be taller, walk with more ease, or seem louder when in the season you correlate to.</td></tr>
              <tr><td>2</td><td>Your body always has something adorned upon it that relates to a season or the moon.</td></tr>
              <tr><td>3</td><td>Your eyes are large and glowing.</td></tr>
              <tr><td>4</td><td>Your voice sounds airy when you speak, as if carried by a breeze.</td></tr>
              <tr><td>5</td><td>Your skin is adorned with tattoo-like markings of flowers, suns, leaves, ice crystals, or moons.</td></tr>
              <tr><td>6</td><td>Your hair, facial hair, or fur is constantly wild and untamed.</td></tr>
          </table>
          <h4>Additional Signs of Sorcery</h4>
          <p>Use this roll table tof additional options for the effects that wielding your magic has on either you or the surrounding environment. Is your magic a telltale signal of who you are, like a trademark? Or is it something that reveals more about who you are and where your magic originates?</p>
          <table>
              <thead>
                  <tr><td>d6</td><td>Sign of Sorcery</td></tr>
              </thead>
              <tr><td>1</td><td>Whenever you cast a spell, the terrain around you changes as if affected by a season, then briefly returns to its original state.</td></tr>
              <tr><td>2</td><td>When using material components, the components become affect by your seasonal alignment: smelling fresh and warm for spring, hot to the touch for summer, cool and decaying for autumn, cold and frosted for winter, and slightly radiating for the moon.</td></tr>
              <tr><td>3</td><td>Flowers, heatwaves, autumn leaves, particles of ice, or streaks of moonlight twirl around you when you cast a spell.</td></tr>
              <tr><td>4</td><td>After you cast a spell, the air around you becomes crisp and pure, as if cleansed.</td></tr>
              <tr><td>5</td><td>Casting spells while in an area affected by your cycle alignment causes your spells to appear larger than they normally are.</td></tr>
              <tr><td>6</td><td>You whisper the verbal components of spells, as if not wanting to disturb the nature around you.</td></tr>
          </table>
      </description>
      <sheet display="false">
          <description></description>
      </sheet>
      <rules>
          <select type="List" name="Arcane Origin">
            <item id="1">Your birth occurred during a solstice, an eclipse, or the first day of a season.</item>
            <item id="2">A supernatural being of the seasons blessed your family with a gift. That gift was you.</item>
            <item id="3">Your birth was part of a prophecy foretold during a culture’s significant holiday.</item>
            <item id="4">Your family has a deep connection to a particular season or the moon, and as such, you are expected to follow in their footsteps.</item>
            <item id="5">Raw, untamed powers in nature changed the nature of your birth, affecting you forever.</item>
            <item id="6">You are from a bloodline filled with druids, or even a dryad.</item>
          </select>
          <select type="List" name="Reaction">
            <item id="1">Your family holds great expectations of you for returning the seasons to their glory.</item>
            <item id="2">You are seen as a blessing from the gods, sent to help people in a time of environmental crisis.</item>
            <item id="3">Your powers over the cycles of nature has made people wary of what your true intentions are.</item>
            <item id="4">Your people fear you, thinking that you will offset the natural cycles of nature.</item>
            <item id="5">You are seen as the ‘good luck charm’ of your home.</item>
            <item id="6">Powerful fey and intelligent beasts watch over your progress, whether you are aware of it or not.</item>
          </select>
          <select type="List" name="Supernatural Mark">
            <item id="1">You seem to be taller, walk with more ease, or seem louder when in the season you correlate to.</item>
            <item id="2">Your body always has something adorned upon it that relates to a season or the moon.</item>
            <item id="3">Your eyes are large and glowing.</item>
            <item id="4">Your voice sounds airy when you speak, as if carried by a breeze.</item>
            <item id="5">Your skin is adorned with tattoo-like markings of flowers, suns, leaves, ice crystals, or moons.</item>
            <item id="6">Your hair, facial hair, or fur is constantly wild and untamed.</item>
          </select>
          <select type="List" name="Sign of Sorcery">
            <item id="1">Whenever you cast a spell, the terrain around you changes as if affected by a season, then briefly returns to its original state.</item>
            <item id="2">When using material components, the components become affect by your seasonal alignment: smelling fresh and warm for spring, hot to the touch for summer, cool and decaying for autumn, cold and frosted for winter, and slightly radiating for the moon.</item>
            <item id="3">Flowers, heatwaves, autumn leaves, particles of ice, or streaks of moonlight twirl around you when you cast a spell.</item>
            <item id="4">After you cast a spell, the air around you becomes crisp and pure, as if cleansed.</item>
            <item id="5">Casting spells while in an area affected by your cycle alignment causes your spells to appear larger than they normally are.</item>
            <item id="6">You whisper the verbal components of spells, as if not wanting to disturb the nature around you.</item>
          </select>
      </rules>
  </element>

  <!-- New Spells -->
    <element name="Scythe of Moonlight" type="Spell" source="Children of the Cycles" id="ID_YORVIING_COTC_SPELL_SCYTHE_OF_MOONLIGHT">
        <supports>Druid, Sorcerer, Warlock</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You whisper chants of the night to form a scythe made of radiant moonlight in your hand. This magic scythe lasts until the spell ends. It counts as a simple melee weapon with which you are proficient. It deals 2d6 radiant damage plus your Spellcasting modifier on a hit and has the two handed and reach properties. In addition, when you use the scythe to attack a target that is in dim light, or you and the target are both out in the open at night, you make the attack roll with advantage. If you drop the weapon or throw it, it dissipates at the end of the turn. Thereafter, while the spell persists, you can use a bonus action to cause the scythe to reappear in your hand.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a 3rd- or 4th-level spell slot, the damage increases to 3d6. When you cast it using a 5th- or 6th-level spell slot, the damage increases to 4d6. When you cast it using a spell slot of 7th level or higher, the damage increases to 5d6.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>


</elements>