<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Upgrades from Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox v2.2</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="upgrades.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/kibblestasty/inventor-extended-toolbox/upgrades.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>

    <!-- Gadgetsmith Upgrades -->
        <element name="Antimagical Shackle" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_GADGETSMITH_ANTIMAGICAL_SHACKLE">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Gadgetsmith,5,Level 5 Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements>[level:inventor:5]</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Level 5 Inventor</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>Prerequisite: 5th level Inventor</p>
                <p class="indent">You create an antimagical shackle. When you are adjacent to a creature, as an action you can attempt to shackle them to yourself or a nearby object using these shackles. The you make a Dexterity (Sleight of Hand) check contested by a Strength (Athletics) or Dexterity (Acrobatics) check. On failure, they are shackled to the creature or object you attempted to shackle them to, and can move only by moving it if they are able to.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, while shackled by these shackles, they cannot teleport, planeshift, polymorph, shapechange, dematerialize, or turn into an amorphous form. As an action they can make a Strength saving throw against your spell save DC to break the shackles once shackled, otherwise these shackles last until you remove them.</p>
                <p class="indent">This shackles have no effect on creatures immune to being grappled or restrained.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>You can use these to attempt to shackle an adjacent creature to yourself or an object. Sleight of Hand v. Athletics or Acrobatics.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Conductive Lightning" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_GADGETSMITH_CONDUCTIVE_LIGHTNING">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Gadgetsmith,3,Unrestricted Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements>ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_GADGETSMITH_LIGHTNING_BATON</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Lightning Baton</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>Prerequisite: Lightning Baton</p>
                <p class="indent">If you make an attack against a target wearing metal armor or wielding metal weapons, the target takes the lightning damage from your baton attack regardless if you hit or miss, and your Lightning Baton gains a special attack. If you are under the effect of <i>lightning charged</i>, missed attacks that deal lightning damage also generate an arc of lightning from the spell.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Special:</b> If your opponent is wielding a metal weapon, you can deliver a extra powerful shock to attempt to make them drop the weapon. As an attack, instead of making an attack roll, the target makes a Constitution saving throw, taking 2d4 + your Intelligence modifier lightning damage and dropping their weapon on a failed save. When you make this special attack, your Lightning Baton becomes a Club until the end of your next turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>If you make an attack against a target wearing metal armor or wielding metal weapons, the target takes the lightning damage regardless if you hit or miss. If you are under the effect of lightning charged, missed attacks that deal lightning damage also generate an arc of lightning from the spell. <b>Special:</b> target makes Constitution saving throw, or takes 2d4 + {{intelligence:modifier}} lightning damage, and drops their weapon.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Creature Container" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_GADGETSMITH_CREATURE_CONTAINER">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Gadgetsmith,5,Level 5 Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements>[level:inventor:5]</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Level 5 Inventor</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>Prerequisite: 5th level Inventor</p>
                <p class="indent">You make a small ball like gadget that contains a magical replica of a beast. As an action, you can throw this ball to conjure forth the stored creature, casting summon beast without expending a spell slot. You can expend a spell slot of a higher level to cast the spell at the level of the expended spell slot plus one level.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this gadget, you cannot use it again until you complete a long rest.</p>
                <div class="sidebar">
                    <h5 class="caption">Container Coloration</h5>
                    <p>I’m not here to tell you what color the container should be. If it’s a red and white ball, that’s up to you.</p>
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You can throw this ball and cast summon beast without expending a spell slot, or casting the spell at 1 plus the level of an expended spell slot.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_TCE_SPELL_SUMMON_BEAST" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Death Ray" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_GADGETSMITH_DEATH_RAY">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Gadgetsmith,17,Level 17 Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements>[level:inventor:17]</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Level 17 Inventor</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>Prerequisite: 17th level Inventor</p>
                <p class="indent">You build a death ray, as Inventors do. As an action, you can cast <i>finger of death</i> without expending a spell slot. Once you use this gadget, you cannot use it again until you complete a long rest.</p>
                <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_FINGER_OF_DEATH" />
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You can cast finger of death without expending a spell slot.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FINGER_OF_DEATH" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Flames and Fury" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_GADGETSMITH_FLAMES_AND_FURY">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Gadgetsmith,3,Unrestricted Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements>ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_GADGETSMITH_FIRE_SPITTER</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Fire Spitter</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>Prerequisite: Fire Spitter</p>
                <p class="indent">Sometimes the world needs more fire, and you’ve developed ways to accommodate the world on that need. Tinkering with things of a more violtile nature has given you insight into more ways to burn and explode things with your spell slots at the following levels:</p>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Inventor Level</td><td>Spell</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>burning hands, hellish rebuke</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>Aganazzar’s scorcher, pyrotechnics</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><em>fireball</em></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false" />
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BURNING_HANDS" spellcasting="Inventor" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HELLISH_REBUKE" spellcasting="Inventor" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_AGANAZZARS_SCORCHER" spellcasting="Inventor" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_PYROTECHNICS" spellcasting="Inventor" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIREBALL" spellcasting="Inventor" level="9" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Multipurpose Investigation Tool" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_GADGETSMITH_MULTIPURPOSE_INVESTIGATION_TOOL">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Gadgetsmith,3,Unrestricted Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements></requirements>
            <prerequisite></prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>You build a tool with a suite of gizmos and widgets for optimal examination. While using this device, you gain proficiency in Intelligence (Investigation) checks. If you already have proficiency in Intelligence (Investigation) you can add twice your proficiency bonus.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>While using this device, you gain proficiency in Investigation checks. If you already have proficiency in Investigation you can add twice your proficiency bonus.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Spring Action Dagger" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_GADGETSMITH_SPRING_ACTION_DAGGER">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Gadgetsmith,3,Unrestricted Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements></requirements>
            <prerequisite></prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>You create a dagger capable of being deployed with sudden and brutal efficiency. You have proficiency in this weapon, and it has the Finesse, Light, and Thrown (30/90) properties. It deals 1d4 piercing damage. This weapon can be concealed as something else; a creature searching you will only determine it a weapon by making an Intelligence (Investigation) check with a DC equal to your Spell Save modifier.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Special:</b> The first time you attack a creature with this dagger, you have advantage on the attack roll. When thrown, it’s damage die becomes a d8.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once thrown, another dagger can be equipped as your Spring Action Dagger as a bonus action.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>You create a dagger capable of being deployed with sudden and brutal efficiency. <b>Special:</b> The first time you attack a creature with this dagger, you have advantage on the attack roll. When thrown, it’s damage die becomes a d8. Once thrown, another dagger can be equipped as your Spring Action Dagger as a bonus action.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Steelweave Nets" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_GADGETSMITH_STEELWEAVE_NETS">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Gadgetsmith,3,Unrestricted Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements></requirements>
            <prerequisite></prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>You thread your nets with metal reinforcement, making them tougher and more conductive. The net gains an AC of 15 and resistance to slashing damage. Whenever a creature restrained by the net takes Lightning damage, it takes an additional 1d6 lightning damage.</p>
                <p class="indent">When a net is turned into a Steelweave Net, only you have proficiency with it. You can have a number of them equal to your Intelligence modifier, replenishing your supply over the course of a long rest by forging normal nets into Steelweave Nets.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can create up to {{intelligence:modifier}} nets during a long rest. Each net has an AC of 15 and resistance to slashing damage. Whenever a creature restrained by the net takes Lightning damage, it takes an additional 1d6 lightning damage.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Trick Shots" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_GADGETSMITH_TRICK_SHOTS">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Gadgetsmith,3,Unrestricted Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements></requirements>
            <prerequisite></prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>At the end of a short or long rest, you can add one of the following effects to a piece of ammunition or thrown weapon, turning it into a trick shot.</p>
                <ul>
                    <li><b>Special Tip:</b> You can select a different damage type for the attack from bludgeoning, piercing, slashing, acid, cold, fire, or lightning.</li>
                    <li><b>Bouncing:</b> You can attack a target out of line of sight of with it if you know their location by bouncing it off a surface. They have the benefit of half cover instead of full cover.</li>
                    <li><b>Ricochet:</b> If you hit an attack roll with it, you can make another attack roll against another target within 10 feet of the first as part of the same attack.</li>
                    <li><b>Smoke Shot:</b> You can use the shot to deploy your smoke bomb feature on impact at a point or target.</li>
                    <li><b>Arcane Trick:</b> You can imbue a cantrip or 1st level spell you know into the shot, casting it on impact where the shot lands. If the spell has a target, the target of the attack is the target.</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">You can only have one modified shot at a time, and it is expended on use.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>At the end of a short or long rest, you can add one of the following effects to a piece of ammunition or thrown weapon, turning it into a trick shot. Special Tip, Bouncing, Ricochet, Smoke Shot, or Arcane Trick. You can only have one modified shot at a time, and it is expended on use.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Transmogrifier" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_GADGETSMITH_TRANSMOGRIFIER">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Gadgetsmith,9,Level 9 Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements>[level:inventor:9]</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Level 9 Inventor</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>Prerequisite: 9th level Inventor</p>
                <p class="indent">You build a device to channel the power of transmutation. You are able to cast polymorph without expending a spell slot... unfortunately without great precision. Roll a d8 to determine what beast the spell will transform the target into and a d4 to select an additional effect, and then pick a target for the spell. If you do not pick a target, you will be the target.</p>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>d8</td><td>Beast</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1</td><td>Frog (MM p.318)</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>2</td><td>Cat (MM p.322)</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3</td><td>Ape (MM p.317)</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>4</td><td>Brown Bear (MM p.319)</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5</td><td>Giant Constrictor Snake (MM p.324)</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>6</td><td>Elephant (MM p.322)</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>7</td><td>Mammoth (MM p.332)</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>8</td><td>Tyrannosaurus Rex (MM p.80)</td></tr>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>d4</td><td>Additional Effect</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1</td><td>The creature is one size smaller. Deals half damage.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>2</td><td>The creature is missing a leg. Halved movement speed.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3</td><td>The creature has an extra head. Makes 1 extra attack.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>4</td><td>The creature is one size larger. Deals +1d4 damage.</td></tr>
                </table>
                <p class="indent">Once you use it, the Transmogrifier cannot be used again until you complete a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You are able to cast polymorph without expending a spell slot... unfortunately without great precision.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_POLYMORPH" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Wild Detonation" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_GADGETSMITH_WILD_DETONATION">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Gadgetsmith,9,Level 9 Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements>[level:inventor:9],(ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_GADGETSMITH_FIRE_SPITTER||ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_GADGETSMITH_FLASHBANG)</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Level 9 Inventor, Fire Spitter or Flashbang</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>Prerequisite: Fire Spitter or Flashbang, 9th level Inventor</p>
                <p class="indent">When you use your Fire Spitter, you can double the dimensions and damage of the spell effect. Additionally, creatures that fall the saving against your Flashbang by 5 or more are stunned as well as blinded until the end of their next turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you use your Fire Spitter, you can double the dimensions and damage of the spell effect. Additionally, creatures that fall the saving against your Flashbang by 5 or more are stunned as well as blinded until the end of their next turn.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Violent Momentum" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_GADGETSMITH_VIOLENT_MOMENTUM">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Gadgetsmith,11,Level 11 Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements>[level:inventor:11]</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Level 11 Inventor</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>Prerequisite: Impact Gauntlet, 11th level Inventor</p>
                <p class="indent">Once per turn, when you move 10 feet or more toward a target before attacking them with your Impact Gauntlet, you can use the special attack of your Impact Gauntlet without forgoing your hit bonus.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Once per turn, when you move 10 feet or more toward a target before attacking them with your Impact Gauntlet, you can use the special attack of your Impact Gauntlet without forgoing your hit bonus.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Quick Smoke Bomb" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_GADGETSMITH_QUICK_SMOKE_BOMB">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Gadgetsmith,3,Unrestricted Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements></requirements>
            <prerequisite></prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>You set aside one of your smoke bombs for rapid deployment. You can use a Smoke Bomb as a bonus action. Once you you use this smoke bomb, you most complete a short or long rest before you can use this feature again.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
                <description>You can use a Smoke Bomb as a bonus action.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>

    <!-- Golemsmith Upgrades -->
        <element name="Ether Heart" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_GOLEMSMITH_ETHER_HEART">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Golemsmith,3,Unrestricted Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements></requirements>
            <prerequisite></prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>You install a magical ether heart into your golem, because that seems like a good idea. Your golem gains 2 charges. It can use 1 charge to cast any first level spell you know. These charges are restored at the end of a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Your golem gains 2 charges. It can use 1 charge to cast any 1st level spell you know. These charges are restored at the end of a long rest.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Ever Watching Sentry" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_GOLEMSMITH_EVER_WATCHING_SENTRY">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Golemsmith,3,Unrestricted Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements></requirements>
            <prerequisite></prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>Your engineer your golem to remain constantly vigilant. It gains Proficiency in Perception and Darkvision (60 feet). While doing tasked with nothing else during a extended respite (such as during a long rest), it gains the benefits of the Alert feat.</p>
                <div element="ID_PHB_FEAT_ALERT" />
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Your golem has proficiency in Perception and Darkvision (60 feet). While doing tasked with nothing else during a extended respite, it gains the benefits of the Alert feat.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="companion:perception:proficiency" value="companion:proficiency" bonus="sentry" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Magical Construct" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_GOLEMSMITH_MAGICAL_CONSTRUCT">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Golemsmith,5,Level 5 Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements>[level:inventor:5]</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Level 5 Inventor</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>Prerequisite: 5th level Inventor</p>
                <p class="indent">Your construct’s magical nature extends to it’s natural weapons. Your construct’s weapons are considered magical for the purpose of overcoming resistance to nonmagical bludgeoning, piercing and slashing damage, and it can add +1 to it’s attack and damage rolls.</p>
                <p class="indent">This increases to a +2 at 14th level.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Your construct’s weapons are considered magical for the purpose of overcoming resistance to nonmagical bludgeoning, piercing and slashing damage, and it can add +{{magical-construct:bonus}} to it’s attack and damage rolls.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="magical-construct:bonus" value="1" level="5" />
                <stat name="magical-construct:bonus" value="1" level="14" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Reciprocity" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_GOLEMSMITH_RECIPROCITY">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Golemsmith,5,Level 5 Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements>[level:inventor:5]</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Level 5 Inventor</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>Prerequisite: 5th level Inventor</p>
                <p class="indent">If you use your bonus action to take the Help action to grant your golem advantage on attacking a creature, your golem can take the Help action as a bonus action to take the Help action to grant you advantage on attacking a creature.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>If you use your bonus action to take the Help action to grant your golem advantage on attacking a creature, your golem can take the Help action as a bonus action to take the Help action to grant you advantage on attacking a creature.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Soul Puppet" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_GOLEMSMITH_SOUL_PUPPET">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Golemsmith,3,Unrestricted Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements></requirements>
            <prerequisite></prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>You bind your soul to your golem. Your consciousness is transferred to the golem, and you gain complete control of the golem, retaining both its action and your own, but you are only able to take any action the golem could take with its action.</p>
                <p class="indent">Your golem’s mental stats are replaced by your mental stats, and your golem gains all of your spell slots, attunement slots, and class features. Your former body dies and cannot be resurrected, unless a <i>wish</i> or similar magic returns your soul to your body.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Your consciousness is transferred to the golem, and you gain complete control of the golem, retaining both its action and your own, but you are only able to take any action the golem could take with its action. </description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Razor Claws" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_GOLEMSMITH_RAZOR_CLAWS">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Golemsmith,3,Unrestricted Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements>ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GOLEMSMITH_GOLEM_CHASSIS_QUADRUPEDAL,!ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_GOLEMSMITH_WARFARE_ROUTINES</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Quadrupedal Golem, Incompatible with Warfare Routines</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>Prerequisite: Quadrupedal Golem, Incompatible with Warfare Routines</p>
                <p class="indent">Your golem’s gains two additional natural weapons that deal 1d8 slashing damage, and have the Light property. Additionally, your golem gains the Two Weapon Fighting Fighting Style from the Fighter Class (as below).</p>
                <p class="indent">Two Weapon Fighting. When you engage in two-weapon fighting, you can add your ability modifier to the damage of the second Attack.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Your golem’s gains two additional natural weapons that deal 1d8 slashing damage, and have the Light property. When your golem attacks with both weapons, you can add its ability modifier to the damage of the second Attack.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Trample" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_GOLEMSMITH_TRAMPLE">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Golemsmith,3,Unrestricted Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements>ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GOLEMSMITH_GOLEM_CHASSIS_QUADRUPEDAL</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Quadrupedal Golem</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>Prerequisite: Quadrupedal Golem</p>
                <p class="indent">When your golem moves more than 10 feet toward a target before making an attack, the target must succeed in a Strength saving throw of a DC equal to 8 + your Golems Strength modifier + your Golem’s Proficiency modifier, or be knocked prone. If the target is knocked prone, the golem can make on additional attack against the target as a bonus action.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When your golem moves more than 10 feet toward a target before making an attack, the target must succeed in a Strength saving throw (DC {{trample:save-dc}}), or be knocked prone.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="trample:save-dc" value="8" />
                <stat name="trample:save-dc" value="companion:strength:modifier" />
                <stat name="trample:save-dc" value="companion:proficiency" />
            </rules>
        </element>

    <!-- Infusionsmith Upgrades -->
        <element name="Infuse Elements" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_INFUSIONSMITH_INFUSE_ELEMENTS">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Infusionsmith,3,Unrestricted Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements></requirements>
            <prerequisite></prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>You can infuse elements with your magic temporarily, granting you limited control of them. You learn the cantrips <em>control flames</em>, <em>mold earth</em>, and <em>shape water</em>.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_CONTROL_FLAMES" spellcasting="Inventor" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_MOLD_EARTH" spellcasting="Inventor" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_SHAPE_WATER" spellcasting="Inventor" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Enchanted Garmets" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_INFUSIONSMITH_ENCHANTED_GARMETS">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Infusionsmith,3,Unrestricted Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements></requirements>
            <prerequisite></prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>You enchant your clothes, granting you several benefits over mundane not-enchanted clothes:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>You can cast prestidigitation targeting only your own clothes.</li>
                    <li>You cause them to change style or color as an action, keeping the new style or color until your take them off or enchant a new set.</li>
                    <li>They do not get wet unless you will them to, keeping you dry.</li>
                    <li>You can ignore the environmental effects of extreme heat or cold.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can cast prestidigitation targeting only your own clothes. You cause them to change style or color as an action, keeping the new style or color until your take them off or enchant a new set. They do not get wet unless you will them to, keeping you dry. You can ignore the environmental effects of extreme heat or cold.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PRESTIDIGITATION" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Investiture of Soul" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_INFUSIONSMITH_INVESTITURE_OF_SOUL">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Infusionsmith,19,Level 19 Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements>[level:inventor:19]</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Level 19 Inventor</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>Prerequisite: 19th level Inventor</p>
                <p class="indent">When you cast <i>animate object</i> spell, you can expend a hit die. If you do it no longer requires concentration, and lasts until the objects created are destroyed or you complete a long rest. If you cast <i>animate object</i> again while you still have animated objects active, the previous spell immediately ends.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you cast animate object spell, you can expend a hit die. If you do it no longer requires concentration, and lasts until the objects created are destroyed or you complete a long rest.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Spinning Blades" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_INFUSIONSMITH_SPINNING_BLADES">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Infusionsmith,3,Unrestricted Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements></requirements>
            <prerequisite></prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p></p>
                <p class="indent">As an action, instead of attacking with your Animated Weapons, you cause them to whirl through the air in place. This has the effect of cloud of daggers, but does not require concentration and ends at the start of your next turn. For each animated weapon you have you can pick a different 5 foot cube, or send them to the same spot. For each weapon sent the same spot, the spell level of the effect is increased by one.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>Instead of attacking with your Animated Weapons, they can produce the effect of cloud of daggers, but it does not require concentration and ends at the start of your next turn. For each animated weapon you have you can pick a different 5 foot cube, or send them to the same spot. For each weapon sent the same spot, the spell level of the effect is increased by one.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CLOUD_OF_DAGGERS" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Translocation Binding" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_INFUSIONSMITH_TRANSLOCATION_BINDING">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Infusionsmith,5,Level 5 Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements>[level:inventor:5]</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Level 5 Inventor</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>Prerequisite: 5th level Inventor</p>
                <p class="indent">As a bonus action while attacking with an Animated Weapon or a weapon under the effect of returning weapon, you can expend a first level spell slot and teleport to it before it returns to you. You can invoke this even if the attack misses the target.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>As a bonus action while attacking with an Animated Weapon or a weapon under the effect of returning weapon, you can expend a 1st level spell slot and teleport to it before it returns to you. You can invoke this even if the attack misses the target.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>

    <!-- Potionsmith Upgrades -->
        <element name="Collateral Damage" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_POTIONSMITH_COLLATERAL_DAMAGE">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Potionsmith,3,Unrestricted Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements></requirements>
            <prerequisite></prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>Prerequisite: Explosive Reaction Incompatible with Shaped Charges</p>
                <p class="indent">Your explosive reaction now deals half damage to creatures that pass the saving throw against it.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Your explosive reaction now deals half damage to creatures that pass the saving throw against it.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Carrier Familiar" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_POTIONSMITH_CARRIER_FAMILIAR">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Potionsmith,9,Level 9 Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements>[level:inventor:9],ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_POTIONSMITH_HOMUNCULUS_FAMILIAR</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Level 9 Inventor, Homunculus Familiar</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>Prerequisites: Homunculus Familiar, 9th level Inventor</p>
                <p class="indent">You utilize your Familiar to deliver your instant reactions. As an action, you can hand off a semi-stablized instant reaction to your familiar. Until the end of your familiar’s next turn, it can use your Instant Reaction as it’s action, targeting a point within 10 feet of it or dropping it up to 20 feet before it takes effect.</p>
                <p class="indent">You take this chance to improve your familiar’s delivery capabilities, granting it the Flyby feature of an Owl if does not have the feature, and 5 feet of increased movement speed to its fastest movement speed if it already does.</p>
                <div class="sidebar">
                    <p><b>Flyby:</b> The creature doesn’t provoke Opportunity Attacks when it flies out of an enemy’s reach.</p>
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>You can hand off a semi-stablized instant reaction to your familiar. Until the end of your familiar’s next turn, it can use your Instant Reaction as it’s action, targeting a point within 10 feet of it or dropping it up to 20 feet before it takes effect.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Dragon Draught" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_POTIONSMITH_DRAGON_DRAUGHT">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Potionsmith,3,Unrestricted Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements>ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_POTIONSSMITH_INSTANT_REACTIONS</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Instant Reactions</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>Instant Reactions</p>
                <p class="indent">As an action you quaff a vial of highly reactive liquid, allow you to immediately belch a blast of devastating elemental energy. You can select between cold, fire, acid, or lightning. Cold and fire effect a 10 foot cone. Lightning and Acid effect at 15 foot line. Creatures in that area have to make a Dexterity saving throw against your Spell Save DC, or take 1d8 damage of the elemental type chosen.</p>
                <p class="indent">The damage increases by 1d8 when you reach 5th level (2d8), 11th level (3d8), and 17th level (4d8).</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>Quaff a vial of highly reactive liquid, allow you to immediately belch a blast of devastating elemental energy. You can select between cold, fire, acid, or lightning. Dexterity saving throw or take {{dragon-draught:damage-dice}}d8 of the damage type chosen.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="dragon-draught:damage-dice" value="1" level="3" />
                <stat name="dragon-draught:damage-dice" value="1" level="5" />
                <stat name="dragon-draught:damage-dice" value="1" level="11" />
                <stat name="dragon-draught:damage-dice" value="1" level="17" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Extra Zest" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_POTIONSMITH_EXTRA_ZEST">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Potionsmith,3,Unrestricted Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements></requirements>
            <prerequisite></prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>You’ve mastered a twist for infusion. Whenever a consumed potion restores health, it restores an additional 1d4 hit points per level of the spell slot used to infuse it. Whenever a thrown potion deals damage, it deals an additional 1d4 damage of its primary damage type to creatures effected by it.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Whenever a consumed potion restores health, it restores an additional 1d4 hit points per level of the spell slot used to infuse it. Whenever a thrown potion deals damage, it deals an additional 1d4 damage of its primary damage type to creatures effected by it.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Flaming Grease" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_POTIONSMITH_FLAMING_GREASE">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Potionsmith,3,Unrestricted Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements></requirements>
            <prerequisite></prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>You tweak your grease formula to be flammable, as grease should be. When you cast grease or use it to make an Alchemical Infusion, the effect becomes flammable. If the area of effect is hit with 1 or more point of fire damage, the all creatures in the area of effect take 2d4 fire damage. The grease burns for 2 turns after being set on fire.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, you can use the grease spell or Alchemical Infusion to coat a weapon; when ignited, that weapon deals 2d4 additional fire damage until the grease burns away (2 turns).</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you cast grease or use it to make an Alchemical Infusion, the effect becomes flammable. If the area of effect is hit with 1 or more point of fire damage, the all creatures in the area of effect take 2d4 fire damage. The grease burns for 2 turns after being set on fire. You can use the grease spell or Alchemical Infusion to coat a weapon; when ignited, that weapon deals 2d4 additional fire damage until the grease burns away (2 turns).</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Mutation Mixture" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_POTIONSMITH_MUTATION_MIXTURE">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Potionsmith,13,Level 13 Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements>[level:inventor:13]</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Level 13 Inventor</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>Prerequisite: 13th level Inventor</p>
                <p class="indent">You concoct an infused potion that warps your body, rapidly and temporary mutating it in extreme ways. You gain the polymorph spell as an option for Alchemical Infusion, and when when you consume this Infused Potion, the duration of the potion is one hour, though it can be ended early by the creature that consumed it as an action.</p>
                <p class="indent">A creature cannot undergo the effect of this Infused Potion again until they complete a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You gain the polymorph spell as an option for Alchemical Infusion, and when when you consume this Infused Potion, the duration of the potion is one hour, though it can be ended early by the creature that consumed it as an action.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_POLYMORPH" spellcasting="Inventor" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Napalm" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_POTIONSMITH_NAPALM">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Potionsmith,3,Unrestricted Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements>ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_POTIONSMITH_ALCHEMICAL_FIRE</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Alchemical Fire</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>Preqrequisite: Alchemical Fire</p>
                <p class="indent">Targets that fail their saving throw against your Alchemical Fire Instant Reaction take an additional 1d4 damage at the start of their turns for one minute. They can end the effect early with an action to put it out.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Targets that fail their saving throw against your Alchemical Fire Instant Reaction take an additional 1d4 damage at the start of their turns for one minute. They can end the effect early with an action to put it out.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Stablizing Agent" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_POTIONSMITH_STABLIZING_AGENT">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Potionsmith,3,Unrestricted Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements></requirements>
            <prerequisite></prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>You introduce a new compound to your instant reactions that temporary stablizes them. When you use an Instant reaction, you can give it a timer of 0 to 3 rounds. The instant reaction is treated as a small clump of components until that point; if undisturbed (it can be moved or thrown, but any creature that touches it can intentionally deactivate it if they know what it is), it will trigger the effect of the instant reaction where it is when the number of specified rounds have passed.</p>
                <p class="indent">If set to 0 rounds, it will trigger the effect at the end of your turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you use an Instant reaction, you can give it a timer of 0 to 3 rounds. The instant reaction is treated as a small clump of components until that point; if undisturbed, it will trigger the effect of the instant reaction where it is when the number of specified rounds have passed.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Goodlent Pellets" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_POTIONSMITH_GOODLENT_PELLETS">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Potionsmith,3,Unrestricted Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements></requirements>
            <prerequisite></prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>You devise a nutritionally complete and revitalizing compound. You can use your alchemy to expend a first level spell slot to cast <i>goodberry</i>, but any berries generated taste distinctly bland.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can use your alchemy to expend a first level spell slot to cast goodberry, but any berries generated taste distinctly bland.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GOODBERRY" />
            </rules>
        </element>

    <!-- Thundersmith Upgrades -->
        <element name="Lightning Arcs" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_THUNDERSMITH_LIGHTNING_ARCS">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Thundersmith,11,Level 11 Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements>[level:inventor:11]</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Level 11 Inventor</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>Prerequisite: 11th level Inventor</p>
                <p class="indent">Once per turn, when you deal Lightning damage with your Stormforged weapon, you can arc the lightning to strike another target within 5 feet. For each die of lightning damage you dealt to the first target, deal 1d4 lightning damage to the second target.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Stormforged Weapon">
                <description>Once per turn, when you deal Lightning damage with your Stormforged weapon, you can arc the lightning to strike another target within 5 feet. For each die of lightning damage you dealt to the first target, deal 1d4 lightning damage to the second target.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Shrapnel Shot" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_THUNDERSMITH_SHRAPNEL_SHOT">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Thundersmith,3,Unrestricted Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements></requirements>
            <prerequisite>Stormforged weapon with the Ammunition property</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>Prerequisite: Stormforged weapon with the Ammunition property</p>
                <p class="indent">You build in the tolerances to load a round of shrapnel into your Stormforged weapon. As a bonus action, you swap in a special shrapnel round. This replaces the damage die the next attack you make with your stormforged weapon with a scaling effect that does more damage the closer a target is. A target within 5 feet takes 4d4 piercing damage, a target within 10 feet takes 3d4 damage a target within 20 feet takes 2d4 damage and a target’s beyond 20 feet take 1d4 damage.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="Stormforged Weapon">
                <description>You swap in a special shrapnel round. On your next attack you make with your stormforged, a target within 5 feet takes 4d4 piercing damage, a target within 10 feet takes 3d4 damage a target within 20 feet takes 2d4 damage and a target’s beyond 20 feet take 1d4 damage.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Static Aura" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_THUNDERSMITH_STATIC_AURA">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Thundersmith,9,Level 9 Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements>[level:inventor:9]</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Level 9 Inventor</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>Prerequisite: 9th level Inventor</p>
                <p class="indent">Your Thunder Cannon emits such a powerful charged aura after being fired, creatures within 5 feet must make a Dexterity saving throw. On failure they take 1d8 lightning damage and have disadvantage on their next attack made before the end of their turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Thunder Cannon">
                <description>When you fire your Thunder Cannon, creatures within 5 feet must make a Dexterity saving throw. On failure they take 1d8 lightning damage and have disadvantage on their next attack made before the end of their turn.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Railgun" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_THUNDERSMITH_RAILGUN">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Thundersmith,19,Level 19 Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements>[level:inventor:19]</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Level 19 Inventor, Thunder Cannon</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>Prerequisite: 19th level Inventor, Thunder Cannon</p>
                <p class="indent">You upgrade the penetration power of your Thunder Cannon. Your Thunder Cannon gains the Siege weapon property, dealing double damage to structures. Additionally, targets can no longer gain the benefits of cover from wooden cover less than 2 feet thick or stone cover less than 1 foot thick, and such cover is destroyed when it would otherwise impede your Thunder Cannon’s attack.</p>
                <p class="indent">If a second target is directly behind a target you attack and within 5 feet, make a second attack roll with disadvantage. If the second attack roll hits, roll Thunder Cannon weapon damage against the second target as well (but no Thundermonger damage is applied to it).</p>
                <p class="indent">The range of your Thunder Cannon increases by 20/60 feet.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Thunder Cannon">
                <description>Your Thunder Cannon gains the Siege weapon property, dealing double damage to structures. Additionally, targets can no longer gain the benefits of cover from wooden cover less than 2 feet thick or stone cover less than 1 foot thick, and such cover is destroyed when it would otherwise impede your Thunder Cannon’s attack. If a second target is directly behind a target you attack and within 5 feet, make a second attack roll with disadvantage. If the second attack roll hits, roll Thunder Cannon weapon damage against the second target as well. The range of your Thunder Cannon increases by 20/60 feet.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Lightning Saber" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_THUNDERSMITH_LIGHTNING_SABER">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Thundersmith,19,Level 19 Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements>[level:inventor:19]</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Level 19 Inventor, Charged Blade</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>Prerequisite: 19th level Inventor, Charged Blade</p>
                <p class="indent">You amplify lightning coursing through your weapon until it becomes a brilliant rod of near pure power. Your weapon casts bright light in a color of your choice for 30 feet, and dim light for additional 30 feet.</p>
                <p class="indent">If you target is wearing non-magical armor or natural armor, your attacks treat their armor class as 10 + their dexterity modifier; only magical effects can add additional AC to the target’s defenses.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Charged Blade">
                <description>Your weapon casts bright light in a color of your choice for 30 feet, and dim light for additional 30 feet. If you target is wearing non-magical armor or natural armor, your attacks treat their armor class as 10 + their dexterity modifier; only magical effects can add additional AC to the target’s defenses.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>

    <!-- Warsmith Upgrades -->
        <element name="Adaptable Armor" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_WARSMITH_ADAPTABLE_ARMOR">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Warsmith,3,Unrestricted Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements></requirements>
            <prerequisite></prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>You integrate deployable hooks and fins into your armor, augmenting its mobility. While wearing your armor you gain a climbing speed equal to your walking speed, and you can move up, down, and across vertical surfaces and upside down along ceilings, while leaving your hands free.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, you gain a swim speed equal to your walking speed.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>While wearing your armor you gain a swimming speed and climbing speed of {{speed}}, and you can move up, down, and across vertical surfaces and upside down along ceilings, while leaving your hands free.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Barrier Capacitor" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_WARSMITH_BARRIER_CAPACITOR">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Warsmith,11,Level 11 Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements>[level:inventor:11],(!ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_WARSMITH_FLASH_FREEZE_CAPACITOR,!ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_WARSMITH_POWER_SLAM_CAPACITOR)</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Level 11 Inventor, Incompatible with other Capacitors</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>Prerequisite: 11th level Inventor; Incompatible with other Capacitors</p>
                <p class="indent">You can store up arcane energy, discharging it in the form of a protective barrier. As an action you can cast wall of force without expending a spell slot or charges. You can use an action to reorient or move the wall up to your movement speed, but the movement is not strong enough to cause any damage.</p>
                <p class="indent">If a creature would be moved by the barrier it can make a Strength check against a Spellcasting ability check, stopping the wall on a successful check.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this upgrade, you cannot use it again until you complete a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You can cast wall of force without expending a spell slot or charges. You can use an action to reorient or move the wall up to your movement speed.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Hyperspace Arsenal" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_WARSMITH_HYPERSPACE_ARSENAL">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Warsmith,19,Level 19 Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements>[level:inventor:19],ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_WARSMITH_RECALL</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Level 19 Inventor, Recall</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>Prerequisite: 19th level, Recall</p>
                <p class="indent">You expand the pocket dimension to store multiple sets of Wargear, as well as up to 100 lbs of weapons or items. As a bonus action, you can conjure and equip any weapon or item stored in the pocket dimension. Additionally, you can swap out your attuned Wargear for another set of Wargear with this upgrade in the pocket dimension during this bonus action, instantly unattuning to the set you were wearing and attuning to the new set. Once you swap your Wargear using this feature, you cannot do so again until you complete a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>You expand the pocket dimension to store multiple sets of Wargear, as well as up to 100 lbs of weapons or items. As a bonus action, you can conjure and equip any weapon or item stored in the pocket dimension.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Searing Shell" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_WARSMITH_SEARING_SHELL">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Warsmith,3,Unrestricted Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements>ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_FIRE"</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Fire Resistance</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>Prerequisite: Resistance: Fire</p>
                <p class="indent">As a bonus action, you can heat your armor to searing temperatures. Anything grappling, restraining, or otherwise holding onto you within 5 feet takes Fire damage equal to your Intelligence modifier. You can end this at the start of your turn (no action required). Whenever you end your turn with this active, you take 1 fire damage that cannot be resisted.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can fully ignite your armor and cast fire shield without consuming a spell slot. When cast with this upgrade, you can only select the fire damage option. Once you cast it in this way, you cannot cast it again until you complete a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>You can heat your armor to searing temperatures. Anything grappling, restraining, or otherwise holding onto you within 5 feet takes {{intelligence:modifier}} fire damage. Whenever you end your turn with this active, you take 1 fire damage that cannot be resisted. You can cast fire shield without consuming a spell slot. When cast with this upgrade, you can only select the fire damage option. Once you cast it in this way, you cannot cast it again until you complete a long rest.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIRE_SHIELD" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Vice Grip" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_WARSMITH_VICE_GRIP">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Warsmith,3,Unrestricted Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements></requirements>
            <prerequisite></prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>You upgrade the arm that your warplate gauntlet is installed with crushing power. If a creature ends turn while grappled by your Warplate Gauntlet, it takes damage equal to your Strength modifier.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>If a creature ends turn while grappled by your Warplate Gauntlet, it takes {{strength:modifier}} damage.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Earth Projector" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_WARSMITH_EARTH_PROJECTOR">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Warsmith,3,Unrestricted Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements></requirements>
            <prerequisite></prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>You gain the ability of elemental control of earth. While wearing your Warplate Gauntlet, you can cast magic stone, and gain access to the following spells at the following levels while wearing your Warplate Gauntlet:</p>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Inventor Level</td><td>Spell</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>earth tremor</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>earthbind</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><em>erupting earth</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>13th</td><td><em>orbital stones*</em></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>While wearing your Warplate Gauntlet, you can cast certain earth elemental spells.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_MAGIC_STONE" spellcasting="Warplate Gauntlet" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_EARTH_TREMOR" spellcasting="Warplate Gauntlet" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_EARTHBIND" spellcasting="Warplate Gauntlet" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ERUPTING_EARTH" spellcasting="Warplate Gauntlet" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_KT_KIET_SPELL_ORBITAL_STONES" spellcasting="Warplate Gauntlet" level="13" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Water Projector" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_WARSMITH_WATER_PROJECTOR">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Warsmith,3,Unrestricted Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements></requirements>
            <prerequisite></prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>You gain the ability to elemental control of water. While wearing your Warplate Gauntlet, you can cast ray of frost, and gain access to the following spells at the following levels while wearing your Warplate Gauntlet:</p>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Inventor Level</td><td>Spell</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>ice knife</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>snowball storm</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><em>tidal wave</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>13th</td><td><em>watery sphere</em></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>While wearing your Warplate Gauntlet, you can cast certain cold elemental spells.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RAY_OF_FROST" spellcasting="Warplate Gauntlet" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ICE_KNIFE" spellcasting="Warplate Gauntlet" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_SNILLOCS_SNOWBALL_SWARM" spellcasting="Warplate Gauntlet" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_TIDAL_WAVE" spellcasting="Warplate Gauntlet" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_WATERY_SPHERE" spellcasting="Warplate Gauntlet" level="13" />
            </rules>
        </element>
    <!-- Suit-Specific Upgrades -->
        <element name="Piloted Golem" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARTFICER_UPGRADE_WARSMITH_PILOTED_GOLEM">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Warsmith,9,Level 9 Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements>[level:inventor:9],ID_KT_KIET_MAGIC_ITEM_WARSMITH_WARSMITHS_ARMOR_WARPLATE,!ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_WARSMITH_COLLAPSIBLE</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Level 9 Inventor, Warplate, Incompatible with Collapsible</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>Prerequisite: 9th level Inventor, Warplate, Incompatible with Collapsible</p>
                <p class="indent">You enlarge your Warplate, turning it into a piloted mechanical golem. Your size category when wearing the armor increases by one.</p>
                <p class="indent">You have advantage on Strength saving throws and Strength checks against creatures the same size as you or smaller than you, but you You have disadvantage on Dexterity savings throws and ability checks (including initiative checks). At the end of a short or long rest, your Warplate gains temporary hit points equal to your Inventor level.</p>
                <p class="indent">You are no longer a valid target for spells that require a humanoid target, but can be targeted by spells that require a construct target while wearing this armor.</p>
                <div class="sidebar">
                    <h5 class="caption">Large Suits</h5>
                    <p>Some players will want to build a larger suit, the Piloted Golem option below allows you to do that. The player and the DM should give some consideration to the consequences of being a large sized creature. It has advantages but considerably drawbacks that should not be ignored.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Large weapons are not defined in the Player’s Handbook for 5e, so what a Large weapon will be (if anything) is up to your DM.</p>
                    <p class="indent">The Dungeon Master’s Guide provides guidance for doubling a Large weapon’s damage dice on page 278 when discussing monster’s weapons, but other DMs opt for a more modest increase akin to the spell enlarge of just having large weapons deal 1d4 additional damage.</p>
                    <h5 class="caption">Large Inconvenience</h5>
                    <p>This is an optional route that can offer substantial benefits; it would generally be advisable to not pull punches on the drawbacks of being a large sized creature (inability to gain cover, difficulty in tight areas, etc). Discuss what sort of challenges you might face with this. Consider if a Piloted Golem - essentially a walking war tank - would have trouble interacting with things created for medium sized creatures - ladders, potion bottles, and more.</p>
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You enlarge your Warplate, turning it into a piloted mechanical golem. Your size category when wearing the armor increases by one.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Self-Repair Matrix" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARTFICER_UPGRADE_WARSMITH_SELF_REPAIR_MATRIX">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Warsmith,9,Level 9 Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements>ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARTFICER_UPGRADE_WARSMITH_PILOTED_GOLEM</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Piloted Golem</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>Prerequisite: Piloted Golem</p>
                <p class="indent">Your at the start of each turn you gain temporary hit points equal your proficiency modifier.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Your at the start of each turn, you gain {{proficiency}} temporary hit points.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Shield Arm" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARTFICER_UPGRADE_WARSMITH_SHIELD_ARM">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Warsmith,9,Level 9 Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements>ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARTFICER_UPGRADE_WARSMITH_PILOTED_GOLEM</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Piloted Golem</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>Prerequisite: Piloted Golem</p>
                <p class="indent">You integrate a shield into one of your armor’s arms. You have proficiency with that shield, and can deploy it as a bonus action. It requires the use of that arm while deployed.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, when you shove a medium or smaller creature while you have the shield deployed, you can shove it by slamming it with the attached shield causing it to take damage equal to your Strength modifier.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You integrate a shield into one of your armor’s arms. You have proficiency with that shield, and can deploy it as a bonus action. It requires the use of that arm while deployed. when you shove a medium or smaller creature while you have the shield deployed, you can shove it by slamming it with the attached shield causing it to take {{strength:modifier}} damage.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Iron Fortress" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARTFICER_UPGRADE_WARSMITH_IRON_FORTRESS">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Warsmith,9,Level 9 Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements>ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARTFICER_UPGRADE_WARSMITH_PILOTED_GOLEM</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Piloted Golem</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>Prerequisite: Piloted Golem</p>
                <p class="indent">You count as three quarters cover for creatures within 5 feet (so long as you are between them and the attacker). Additionally, you cannot be moved against your will while in contact with the ground.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You count as three quarters cover for creatures within 5 feet (so long as you are between them and the attacker). Additionally, you cannot be moved against your will while in contact with the ground.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Construct Constitution" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARTFICER_UPGRADE_WARSMITH_CONSTRUCT_CONSTITUTION">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Warsmith,3,Unrestricted Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements>ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_WARSMITH_INTEGRATED_ATTACK</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Integrated Armor</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>Prerequisite: Integrated Armor</p>
                <p class="indent">You gain resistance to poison damage and immunity to the poisoned condition. You have advantage on saving throws against diseases as well as spell effects that require a "humanoid" target.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You gain resistance to poison damage and immunity to the poisoned condition. You have advantage on saving throws against diseases as well as spell effects that require a "humanoid" target.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Extendable Arms" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARTFICER_UPGRADE_WARSMITH_EXTENDABLE_ARMS">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Warsmith,3,Unrestricted Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements>ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_WARSMITH_INTEGRATED_ATTACK</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Integrated Armor</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>Prerequisite: Integrated Armor</p>
                <p class="indent">When you make a melee attack on your turn, your reach for it is 5 feet greater than normal.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you make a melee attack on your turn, your reach for it is 5 feet greater than normal.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Iron Fortitude" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARTFICER_UPGRADE_WARSMITH_IRON_FORTITUDE">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Warsmith,3,Unrestricted Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements>ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_WARSMITH_INTEGRATED_ATTACK</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Integrated Armor</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>Prerequisite: Integrated Armor</p>
                <p class="indent">You gain an unnatural durability. When damage reduces you to 0 hit points, you make Constitution saving throw with a DC of 5 + the damage taken, unless the damage from a critical hit. On a success, you drop to 1 hit point instead.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When damage reduces you to 0 hit points, you make Constitution saving throw with a DC of 5 + the damage taken, unless the damage from a critical hit. On a success, you drop to 1 hit point instead.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Mechanical Overdrive" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARTFICER_UPGRADE_WARSMITH_MECHANICAL_OVERDRIVE">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Warsmith,9,Level 9 Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements>[level:inventor:9],ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_WARSMITH_INTEGRATED_ATTACK</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Level 9 Inventor, Integrated Armor</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>Prerequisite: Integrated Armor, 9th level Inventor</p>
                <p class="indent">You overload your integrated armor, driving it to superhuman speeds. You can use this upgrade to cast haste targeting yourself. When you cast haste in this way, you have advantage on concentration checks to maintain it, but at the end of each of your turns take 1d4 fire damage that cannot be resisted from overheating.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can use this upgrade to cast haste targeting yourself. When you cast haste in this way, you have advantage on concentration checks to maintain it, but at the end of each of your turns take 1d4 fire damage that cannot be resisted from overheating.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Powered Nervous System" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARTFICER_UPGRADE_WARSMITH_POWERED_NERVOUS_SYSTEM">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Warsmith,3,Unrestricted Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements>ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_WARSMITH_INTEGRATED_ATTACK, ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_LIGHTNING</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Integrated Armor, Lightning Resistance</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>Prerequisite: Integrated Armor; Resistance: Lightning</p>
                <p class="indent">Once per turn when you take or deal lightning damage, you gain a d4. You can add this d4 to your next attack roll or saving throw before the end of your next turn. You can only have one d4 from this ability at a time. If you gain another d4 while you already have one, you immediately roll it and gain temporary hit points equal to the amount rolled.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Once per turn when you take or deal lightning damage, you gain a d4. You can add this d4 to your next attack roll or saving throw before the end of your next turn. You can only have one d4 from this ability at a time. If you gain another d4 while you already have one, you immediately roll it and gain temporary hit points equal to the amount rolled.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Wire Acrobatics" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARTFICER_UPGRADE_WARSMITH_WIRE_ACROBATICS">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Warsmith,3,Unrestricted Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements>ID_KT_KIET_MAGIC_ITEM_WARSMITH_WARSMITHS_ARMOR_WARSUIT, ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_WARSMITH_GRAPPLING_REEL</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Warsuit, Grappling Reel</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>Prerequisite: Warsuit, Grappling Reel</p>
                <p class="indent">You can take your movement using your grappling reel instead of using it as an attack or action; you can only move yourself when using the grappling reel in this way.</p>
                <p class="indent">Opportunity attacks generated by movement with your grappling reel are made with disadvantage.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can take your movement using your grappling reel instead of using it as an attack or action; you can only move yourself when using the grappling reel in this way. Opportunity attacks generated by movement with your grappling reel are made with disadvantage.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Assume Control" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARTFICER_UPGRADE_WARSMITH_ASSUME_CONTROL">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Warsmith,</supports>
            <requirements>[level:inventor:9],ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_WARSMITH_SENTIENT_ARMOR,ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_WARSMITH_EMERGENCY_PROTOCOL</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Sentient Armor, Emergency Protocol, Level 9 Inventor</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>Prerequisite: Sentient Armor, Emergency Protocol, 9th level Inventor</p>
                <p class="indent">You have expanded the control available to your armor’s sentience. You can set additional conditions when your armor will take control of your movement and actions, and can maintain this control of up to a 1 minute.</p>
                <p class="indent">While acting in this mode, it can take any action you could take (including attacking), but can only cast spells granted by Upgrades. It uses your ability scores.</p>
                <p class="indent">The triggering event can by a preset condition, a verbal command, or a specified time. Your armor is immune to the charmed, blinded, frightened, paralyzed, and poisoned conditions, and does not suffer from exhaustion, ignoring these effects if you are under them.</p>
                <p class="indent">If you have Warplate, it can act in this way even when you are not wearing it (or dead). When doing so, it uses the game statistics of animated armor with the following modifications:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>It has an intelligence of 12.</li>
                    <li>It can cast any spells that come from Upgrades with a DC equal to your spell save DC.</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">This counts as a use of your Emergency Protocol, and it cannot control the armor again (in either way) until you complete a short or long rest.</p>
                <p class="indent">In non-combat situations in which you are not wearing your armor, it can exert a lesser control of the armor to move it about and perform simple tasks. During this time it has the statistics of an unseen servant, though it looks like your suit of armor. It’s ability to do this is not limited, but it takes 1 minute to assume this kind of control of your armor, and it can only do so while you are not wearing it.</p>
                <div class="sidebar">
                    <h5 class="caption">Optional Control</h5>
                    <p>With Assume Control upgrade, the armor taking control on Emergency Protocol becomes optional, though if you do not choose for it to activate, it cannot activate later unless the condition was previously specified (i.e. "take control if I fail two Death Saving throws").</p>
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can set additional conditions when your armor will take control of your movement and actions, and can maintain this control of up to a 1 minute.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Contingent Response" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARTFICER_UPGRADE_WARSMITH_CONTINGENT_RESPONSE">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Warsmith,</supports>
            <requirements>ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_WARSMITH_SENTIENT_ARMOR</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Sentient Armor</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>Prerequisite: Sentient Armor</p>
                <p class="indent">Choose a spell of 2nd level or lower spell that you can cast, that has a casting time of 1 action, and that can target you. You cast that spell, expending a spell slot, but the spell doesn’t come into effect. Instead, it takes effect when a certain circumstance occurs.</p>
                <p class="indent">The spell takes effect immediately after the circumstance is met for the first time, whether or not you want it to, and then contingency ends.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can only have one spell prepared to go off in this way. Preparing a new one immediately ends the effect of the last one.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Choose a spell of 2nd level or lower spell that you can cast, that has a casting time of 1 action, and that can target you. You cast that spell, expending a spell slot, but the spell doesn’t come into effect. Instead, it takes effect when a certain circumstance occurs.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Telepathic Uplink" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARTFICER_UPGRADE_WARSMITH_TELEPATHIC_UPLINK">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Warsmith,</supports>
            <requirements>ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_WARSMITH_SENTIENT_ARMOR</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Sentient Armor</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>Prerequisite: Sentient Armor</p>
                <p class="indent">You can communicate with your armor as long as you are attuned to it, and it is on the same plane of existence as you. As an action, you can see through your armors visor and hear what it hears until the start of your next turn. During this time, you are deaf and blind with regard to your own Senses.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>You can communicate with your armor as long as you are attuned to it, and it is on the same plane of existence as you. You can see through your armors visor and hear what it hears until the start of your next turn. During this time, you are deaf and blind with regard to your own Senses.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>

    <!-- Fleshsmith Upgrades -->
        <element name="Acid Gland" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_FLESHSMITH_ACID_GLAND">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Fleshsmith,5,Level 5 Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements>[level:inventor:5]</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Level 5 Inventor</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>Prerequisite: 5th level Inventor</p>
                <p class="indent">Realizing that putting something that oozes acid inside yourself could not possible go wrong, you do just that. You gain a pool of d4s equal to your Constitution modifier. As a bonus action, you can expend an amount of these d4s, adding them to the next damage roll you make with a natural weapon before the end of your turn. The pool of d4s recharge at the end of a short or long rest.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, you learn the <i>acid spray</i> cantrip. When casting it using this upgrade, it does not require verbal or somatic components and you can use your Constitution as your spell casting modifier for it instead of your Intelligence modifier. You can expend the d4s granted by Acid Gland on the damage roll of <i>acid spray</i>, following the same restrictions as natural weapons.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>You gain a pool of {{constitution:modifier}} d4s. You can expend an amount of these d4s, adding them to the next damage roll you make with a natural weapon before the end of your turn. The pool of d4s recharge at the end of a short or long rest. When casting it using this upgrade, it does not require verbal or somatic components and you can use your Constitution as your spell casting modifier for it instead of your Intelligence modifier. You can expend the d4s granted by Acid Gland on the damage roll of acid spray.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ACID_SPRAY" spellcasting="Inventor" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Amalgamated Form" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_FLESHSMITH_AMALGAMATED_FORM">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Fleshsmith,9,Level 9 Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements>[level:artficier:9]</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Level 9 Inventor</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>Prerequisite: 9th level Inventor</p>
                <p class="indent">You modify yourself to gain a racial ability of another race. This can be used to gain one physical trait of a playable race, both in form and function. For example, adding the lower body of centaur may give you their movement, hooves, and poor climbing ability.</p>
                <p class="indent">This can include physiology and physical traits, including natural weapons, movement speed, physical senses, or special properties relating to physical features. Select a trait from the following table:</p>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Race / Part</td><td>Features Gained</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>Centaur Lower Body</td><td>Gain 40 ft. speed, Hooves and Equine Build</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>Minotaur Horns</td><td>Gain Horns, Goring Rush, Hammering Horns</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>Tortle Shell</td><td>Natural Armor, Shell Defense</td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Amalgamated Form" supports="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_FLESHSMITH_AMALGAMATED_FORM_CENTAUR_LOWER_BODY|ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_FLESHSMITH_AMALGAMATED_FORM_MINOTAUR_HORNS|ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_FLESHSMITH_AMALGAMATED_FORM_TORTLE_SHELL" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Centaur Lower Body" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_FLESHSMITH_AMALGAMATED_FORM_CENTAUR_LOWER_BODY">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>Gain 40 ft. speed, Hooves and Equine Build</p>
                    <div element="ID_WOTC_GGTR_RACIAL_TRAIT_CENTAUR_HOOVES" />
                    <div element="ID_WOTC_GGTR_RACIAL_TRAIT_CENTAUR_EQUINE_BUILD" />
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="innate speed" value="40" bonus="base" />
                    <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_WOTC_GGTR_RACIAL_TRAIT_CENTAUR_HOOVES" />
                    <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_WOTC_GGTR_RACIAL_TRAIT_CENTAUR_EQUINE_BUILD" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Minotaur Horns" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_FLESHSMITH_AMALGAMATED_FORM_MINOTAUR_HORNS">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>Gain Horns, Goring Rush, Hammering Horns</p>
                    <div element="ID_WOTC_GGTR_RACIAL_TRAIT_MINOTAUR_HORNS" />
                    <div element="ID_WOTC_GGTR_RACIAL_TRAIT_MINOTAUR_GORING_RUSH" />
                    <div element="ID_WOTC_GGTR_RACIAL_TRAIT_MINOTAUR_HAMMERING_HORNS" />
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_WOTC_GGTR_RACIAL_TRAIT_MINOTAUR_HORNS" />
                    <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_WOTC_GGTR_RACIAL_TRAIT_MINOTAUR_GORING_RUSH" />
                    <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_WOTC_GGTR_RACIAL_TRAIT_MINOTAUR_HAMMERING_HORNS" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Tortle Shell" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_FLESHSMITH_AMALGAMATED_FORM_TORTLE_SHELL">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>Natural Armor, Shell Defense</p>
                    <div element="ID_WOTC_TOA_RACIAL_TRAIT_TORTLE_NATURAL_ARMOR" />
                    <div element="ID_WOTC_TOA_RACIAL_TRAIT_TORTLE_SHELL_DEFENSE" />
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_WOTC_TOA_RACIAL_TRAIT_TORTLE_NATURAL_ARMOR" />
                    <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_WOTC_TOA_RACIAL_TRAIT_TORTLE_SHELL_DEFENSE" />
                </rules>
            </element>
        <element name="Adaptive Response" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_FLESHSMITH_ADAPTIVE_RESPONSE">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Fleshsmith,15,Level 15 Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements>[level:inventor:15]</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Level 15 Inventor</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>Prerequisite: 15th level Inventor</p>
                <p class="indent">You attain full mastery of your body and its functionality, able to detect when it malfunctions. As a reaction to failing a saving throw against becoming paralyzed, blinded, deafened, poisoned or infected by a disease as the result of failing a constitution saving throw, you can end the effect, even if you would normally not be able to take reactions due to the effect.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you do this, you cannot do this again until you complete a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
                <description>As a reaction to failing a saving throw against becoming paralyzed, blinded, deafened, poisoned or infected by a disease as the result of failing a constitution saving throw, you can end the effect, even if you would normally not be able to take reactions due to the effect.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Brimstone Bladder" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_FLESHSMITH_BRIMSTONE_BLADDER">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Fleshsmith,5,Level 5 Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements>[level:inventor:5]</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Level 5 Inventor</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>Prerequisite: 5th level Inventor</p>
                <p class="indent">Why should dragons have all the fun? You can now exhale fire. You gain a pool of d12s equal to your Inventor level. As an action, you can exhale a cone of fire, expending d12s from this pool equal to your Proficiency modifier. Creatures in a 30 foot cone make a Dexterity saving throw, taking Fire damage equal to the d12s expended on a failure, and half as much damage on a successful saving throw.</p>
                <p class="indent">You gain resistance to fire damage.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>You have a pool of {{level:inventor}} d12s. You can exhale a cone of fire, expending up to {{proficiency}} d12s from this pool. Creatures in a 30 foot cone make a Dexterity saving throw, taking Fire damage equal to the d12s expended on a failure, and half as much damage on a successful saving throw.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_FIRE" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Devouring Maw" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_FLESHSMITH_DEVOURING_MAW">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Fleshsmith,9,Level 9 Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements>[level:inventor:9]</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Level 9 Inventor</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>Prerequisite: 9th level Inventor</p>
                <p class="indent">Due to the inefficiency of having only one intake port, you build an additional one, properly equipped with razor sharp fangs and a special property. This maw becomes a natural weapon that deals 1d10 piecing damage.</p>
                <p class="indent">If you hit with an attack with this maw, you can chose to make a Grapple check against the target as a bonus action. Targets grappled by this maw take 1d4 piercing and 1d4 acid damage at the start of their turn.</p>
                <p class="indent">Attacks with this Maw are made with advantage against targets it is Grappling, but it cannot attack other creatures while grappling a creature.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can apply a Fleshcrafted Enhancement to this Maw instead of Extra Fangs when taking that upgrade; this Maw can have a different upgrade than your Extra Fangs if you have both.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>This maw becomes a natural weapon that deals 1d10 piecing damage. If you hit with an attack with this maw, you can chose to make a Grapple check against the target as a bonus action. Targets grappled by this maw take 1d4 piercing and 1d4 acid damage at the start of their turn.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Soul Eater" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_FLESHSMITH_SOUL_EATER">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Fleshsmith,3,Unrestricted Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements>(ID_KT_KI_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_FLESHSMITH_FLESHCRAFTED_MUTATION_EXTRA_FANGS||ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_FLESHSMITH_DEVOURING_MAW)</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Extra Fangs or Devouring Maw</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>Prerequisite: Extra Fangs or Devouring Maw</p>
                <p class="indent">When you kill a creature with a CR of 1/4 or higher with your Extra Fangs or Devouring Maw, it consumes part of the soul of the creature, nourishing you with its essence. You regain an expanded spell slot equal to half the creatures CR (minimum first level spell slot).</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you’ve benefited from this nourishment, you must take a short or long rest before you can benefit from it again. If you have no spell slots remaining, you can benefit from this nourishment again even without resting.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
                <description>When you kill a creature with a CR of 1/4 or higher with your Extra Fangs or Devouring Maw, you regain an expanded spell slot equal to half the creatures CR (minimum 1st).</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Extra Quills" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_FLESHSMITH_EXTRA_QUILLS">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Fleshsmith,3,Unrestricted Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements></requirements>
            <prerequisite></prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>Do you know what monsters never eat? Hedgehogs. You become more like a hedgehog. When you are attacked by a melee attack or are the target of a grapple attempt, you can use your reaction to deal 1d6 piercing damage to the attacking creature. You can do this a number of times equal to your Constitution modifier, and regrow all expended quills (regaining all uses of the ability) after you complete a long rest.</p>
                <p class="indent">Alternatively, you as sometimes the best defense is a good offense, you can expend a use of quills as a ranged weapon attack with a range of 20/60, dealing 1d8 piercing damage on hit.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="{{constitution:modifier}}/Long Rest">
                <description>When you are attacked by a melee attack or are the target of a grapple attempt, you can use your reaction to deal 1d6 piercing damage to the attacking creature. You can expend a use of quills as a ranged weapon attack with a range of 20/60, dealing 1d8 piercing damage on hit.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Dogmatic Persistence" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_FLESHSMITH_DOGMATIC_PERSISTENCE">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Fleshsmith,3,Unrestricted Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements></requirements>
            <prerequisite></prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>Your idealogical conviction in your Thesis is such that you gain an additional 2 uses of it (for Perfection of Form) or an addition two d8s (for Perfection of Mind).</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="perfection-of-form:uses" value="2" />
                <stat name="perfection-of-mind:pool" value="2" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Prehensile Feet" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Inventor Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KIET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INVENTOR_UPGRADE_FLESHSMITH_PREHENSILE_FEET">
            <supports>Specialization Upgrade,Fleshsmith,3,Unrestricted Specialization Upgrade</supports>
            <requirements></requirements>
            <prerequisite></prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p>You tinker with your appendages, improving their flexibility and configuration. You gain a climbing speed equal to your walking speed. If you are prone or otherwise supported without your feet, your foot can count as a free hand for the purposes of grappling.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>If you are prone or otherwise supported without your feet, your foot can count as a free hand for the purposes of grappling.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="speed:climb" value="speed" bonus="base" />
            </rules>
        </element>

</elements>