<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Arcanasylph Sorcerous Origin</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="sorcerer-arcanasylph.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/subclasses/sorcerer/sorcerer-arcanasylph.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="The Arcanasylph" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_GMBINDER_SOURCE_THE_ARCANASYLPH">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation">ASO</set>
            <set name="url">https://www.gmbinder.com/share/-LjJ-HGYOXyyHkCIRDpP</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" abbreviation="NTS" url="https://www.gmbinder.com/profile/notthesmoooze">NotTheSmooze</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20200821</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Arcanasylph" type="Archetype" source="The Arcanasylph" id="ID_NTS_ASO_ARCHETYPE_SORCERER_ARCANASYLPH">
        <supports>Sorcerous Origin</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Sorcerers who reject the wild and chaotic power in their blood can tame their inner arcana, compelling it into stable structures through complex glyphs and sigils, and what might be lost in sacrificing the natural expression of their power is gained in skill, control, and masterful precision.</p>
            <p class="indent">Few sorcerers choose this path, instead embracing the magic inherent to their blood and soul. Those that do always have good reason. You might have suppressed your former origin after accidentally losing control and harming a loved one, or perhaps it was done to you against your will to limit and focus your power, or to keep the true nature of your sorcerous origin a secret.</p>
            <div element="ID_NTS_ASO_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCANASYLPH_ORIGIN_SPELLS" />
            <div element="ID_NTS_ASO_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCANASYLPH_MYSTIC_GEOMETRY" />
            <div element="ID_NTS_ASO_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCANASYLPH_STUDY_AND_REPETITION" />
            <div element="ID_NTS_ASO_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCANASYLPH_RUNEWRIGHT" />
            <div element="ID_NTS_ASO_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCANASYLPH_PRIMEVAL_RUNE" />
            <div element="ID_NTS_ASO_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCANASYLPH_IMPROVED_GLYPHS" />
            <div element="ID_NTS_ASO_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCANASYLPH_RINGED_GATEWAYS" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_NTS_ASO_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCANASYLPH_ORIGIN_SPELLS" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_NTS_ASO_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCANASYLPH_MYSTIC_GEOMETRY" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_NTS_ASO_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCANASYLPH_STUDY_AND_REPETITION" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_NTS_ASO_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCANASYLPH_RUNEWRIGHT" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_NTS_ASO_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCANASYLPH_PRIMEVAL_RUNE" level="14" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_NTS_ASO_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCANASYLPH_IMPROVED_GLYPHS" level="14" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_NTS_ASO_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCANASYLPH_RINGED_GATEWAYS" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Variant Feature: Origin Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Arcanasylph" id="ID_NTS_ASO_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCANASYLPH_ORIGIN_SPELLS">
            <description>
                <p>You learn origin spells at the sorcerer levels noted in the origin spells table. An origin spell counts as sorcerer spell for you, but doesn’t count against your number of sorcerer spells known.</p>
                <h5 class="caption">ARCANASYLPH ORIGIN SPELLS</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Sorcerer Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1st</td><td><em>identify</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>Nystul’s magic aura</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>glyph of warding</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>7th</td><td><em>banishment</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><em>teleportation circle</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>11th</td><td><em>contingency</em></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_IDENTIFY" spellcasting="Sorcerer" level="1" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_NYSTULS_MAGIC_AURA" spellcasting="Sorcerer" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GLYPH_OF_WARDING" spellcasting="Sorcerer" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BANISHMENT" spellcasting="Sorcerer" level="7" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TELEPORTATION_CIRCLE" spellcasting="Sorcerer" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONTINGENCY" spellcasting="Sorcerer" level="11" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Mystic Geometry" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Arcanasylph" id="ID_NTS_ASO_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCANASYLPH_MYSTIC_GEOMETRY">
            <description>
                <p>Starting when you choose this origin at 1st level, you can use a bonus action to summon a 5-foot diameter glyph on a surface you can see within 30 feet of you. The glyph is visibly magical, radiating dim light out to 5 feet.</p>
                <p class="indent">While within 30 feet of a glyph, you can cast sorcerer spells through it as though you were in a space in its area, though you must use your own senses. If a friendly creature is in a glyph’s area, you can make any spell you cast through the glyph that targets only you instead target that creature. You must maintain concentration on the spell as normal.</p>
                <p class="indent">A glyph disappears after 1 hour. It disappears early if you summon a new glyph, if you dismiss it (no action required), if you are knocked unconscious, or if surface the glyph is summoned on is moved.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>You summon a 5-foot diameter glyph on a surface you can see within 30 feet of you. The glyph is visibly magical, radiating dim light out to 5 feet. While within 30 feet of a glyph, you can cast sorcerer spells through it as though you were in a space in its area, though you must use your own senses.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Study and Repetition" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Arcanasylph" id="ID_NTS_ASO_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCANASYLPH_STUDY_AND_REPETITION">
            <description>
                <p>At 1st level, you gain proficiency with calligrapher’s supplies, and your proficiency bonus is doubled for any ability check you make using them. You can use your calligrapher’s supplies as a spellcasting focus.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, you can cast any sorcerer spell you know as a ritual if that spell has the ritual tag. You also learn the <i>comprehend languagues</i> spell, which counts as a sorcerer spell for you but doesn’t count against your number of sorcerer spells known.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Your proficiency bonus is doubled for any ability check you make using your calligrapher’s supplies. You can use your calligrapher’s supplies as a spellcasting focus. Additionally, you can cast any sorcerer spell you know as a ritual if that spell has the ritual tag.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_CALLIGRAPHERS_SUPPLIES" />
    			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_RITUAL_CASTING" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMPREHEND_LANGUAGES" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" allowReplace="false" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Runewright" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Arcanasylph" id="ID_NTS_ASO_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCANASYLPH_RUNEWRIGHT">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 6th level, your glyphs’ fortifying magic shields those within. When you cast a spell of 1st level or higher through a glyph, any friendly creature in the glyph’s area gains temporary hit points equal to 1 + twice the spell’s level, which last until the start of your next turn.</p>
                <p class="indent">You also learn the <i>magic circle</i> spell, which counts as a sorcerer spell for you but doesn’t count against your number of sorcerer spells known.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you cast a spell of 1st level or higher through a glyph, any friendly creature in the glyph’s area gains temporary hit points equal to 1 + twice the spell’s level, which last until the start of your next turn.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGIC_CIRCLE" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" allowReplace="false" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Primeval Rune" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Arcanasylph" id="ID_NTS_ASO_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCANASYLPH_PRIMEVAL_RUNE">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 14th level, any friendly creature in a glyph’s area has advantage on saving throws against spells. In addition, those creatures automatically succeed on saving throws against spells you cast, taking no damage if they would normally take half damage on a successful save.</p>
                <p class="indent">You also learn the symbol spell, which counts as a sorcerer spell for you but doesn’t count against your number of sorcerer spells known.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Any friendly creature in a glyph’s area has advantage on saving throws against spells. In addition, those creatures automatically succeed on saving throws against spells you cast, taking no damage if they would normally take half damage on a successful save.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SYMBOL" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" allowReplace="false" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Improved Glyphs" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Arcanasylph" id="ID_NTS_ASO_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCANASYLPH_IMPROVED_GLYPHS">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 14th level, your glyphs become more powerful. You can summon glyphs on surfaces you can see within 60 feet of you and cast spells through any glyph within the same range, and glyphs you summon can be up to 15-foot in diameter.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can summon glyphs on surfaces you can see within 60 feet of you and cast spells through any glyph within the same range, and glyphs you summon can be up to 15-foot in diameter.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Ringed Gateways" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Arcanasylph" id="ID_NTS_ASO_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCANASYLPH_RINGED_GATEWAYS">
            <description>
                <p>By 18th level, your control of your magic is perfected. When you use a bonus action to summon a glyph, you can summon three glyphs, instead of one. You can cast spells through any of your summoned glyphs within range.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, while you aren’t incapacitated, a friendly creature in the area of one of your summoned glyphs can spend 5 feet of movement to teleport to an unoccupied space in the area of one of your other glyphs (no action required).</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you use a bonus action to summon a glyph, you can summon three glyphs, instead of one. You can cast spells through any of your summoned glyphs within range. Additionally, while you aren’t incapacitated, a friendly creature in the area of one of your summoned glyphs can spend 5 feet of movement to teleport to an unoccupied space in the area of one of your other glyphs (no action required).</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>


</elements>