<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Dream Magic Sorcerous Origin</name>
        <update version="0.0.2">
            <file name="sorcerer-dream-magic.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/subclasses/sorcerer/sorcerer-dream-magic.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Sorcerous Origin: Dream Magic" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_ROBNOCTE_HOMEBREWERY_SOURCE_SORCEROUS_ORIGIN_DREAM_MAGIC">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation">SODM</set>
            <set name="url">https://homebrewery.naturalcrit.com/share/sy8JQV_BnXuG</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" abbreviation="RN" url="https://www.reddit.com/user/RobNocte/">u/RobNocte</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20200118</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Dream Magic" type="Archetype" source="Sorcerous Origin: Dream Magic" id="ID_RN_SODM_ARCHETYPE_SORCERER_DREAM_MAGIC">
        <supports>Sorcerous Origin</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Your innate magic comes from a place of dreams. This could be from a place that you only connect to while you sleep, or from a plane or realm of dreams that you have been exposed to. You may even have a connection, or have been cursed, by a creature of dreams or nightmares. However your powers came to be, the magic of dreams flows through your blood and mind.</p>
            <p class="indent">Dream sorcerers often first manifest their powers in their sleep, leading some to not realise they actually have the power at first. It is also not uncommon for those who have not started mastering their powers, to unwittingly use their magic while sleeping, in response to something they dream or as a manifestation of their subconscious.</p>
            <div element="ID_RN_SODM_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAM_MAGIC_DREAMING_MIND" />
            <div element="ID_RN_SODM_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAM_MAGIC_SLUMBERING_POWER" />
            <div element="ID_RN_SODM_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAM_MAGIC_TERRORS_OF_THE_NIGHT" />
            <div element="ID_RN_SODM_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAM_MAGIC_PROTECTIVE_STUPOR" />
            <div element="ID_RN_SODM_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAM_MAGIC_DREAM_WALKER" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RN_SODM_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAM_MAGIC_DREAMING_MIND" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RN_SODM_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAM_MAGIC_SLUMBERING_POWER" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RN_SODM_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAM_MAGIC_TERRORS_OF_THE_NIGHT" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RN_SODM_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAM_MAGIC_PROTECTIVE_STUPOR" level="14" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RN_SODM_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAM_MAGIC_DREAM_WALKER" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Dreaming Mind" type="Archetype Feature" source="Sorcerous Origin: Dream Magic" id="ID_RN_SODM_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAM_MAGIC_DREAMING_MIND">
            <description>
                <p>Starting when you choose this origin at 1st level, your dreams are protected by the magic that you gain from them. Magic can’t put you to sleep unless you want it to, and if magic is affecting your dreams you are immediately aware of it.</p>
                <p class="indent">In addition, while you are sleeping, whether naturally or by the <i>sleep</i> spell or similar spells, you can see and hear as if you were conscious in your space. All other effects of the unconscious condition still apply to you.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Magic can’t put you to sleep unless you want it to, and if magic is affecting your dreams you are immediately aware of it. While you are sleeping, you can see and hear as if you were conscious in your space. All other effects of the unconscious condition still apply to you.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Slumbering Power" type="Archetype Feature" source="Sorcerous Origin: Dream Magic" id="ID_RN_SODM_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAM_MAGIC_SLUMBERING_POWER">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 1st level, you learn the sleep spell, which doesn’t count against your number of sorcerer spells known.</p>
                <p class="indent">When you reach 2nd level in this class, when you can cast the sleep spell you can expend a number of sorcery points equal to the half the level of the spell slot used to cast the spell (rounded up). When you expend sorcery points in this way, a roll on the d8s of 4 or lower is counted as a 5.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
                <description level="2">When you can cast the sleep spell you can expend a number of sorcery points equal to the half the level of the spell slot used to cast the spell (rounded up). When you expend sorcery points in this way, a roll on the d8s of 4 or lower is counted as a 5.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SLEEP" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="1" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Terrors of the Night" type="Archetype Feature" source="Sorcerous Origin: Dream Magic" id="ID_RN_SODM_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAM_MAGIC_TERRORS_OF_THE_NIGHT">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, you gain the power to manifest fears hidden deep in the subconscious of your foes. When you hit a creature you can see with a spell attack or a creature you can see fails a saving throw against one of your spells, you can choose to create an illusory manifestation of the target’s deepest fears in an unoccupied space within 30 feet of the target.</p>
                <p class="indent">The target must make a Wisdom saving throw against your sorcerer spell save DC, becoming frightened of the illusion until it disappears on a failed save. The target can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns. The illusion lasts for 1 minute, or until you lose your concentration (as if you were casting a concentration spell). The illusion moves with the target, always staying the same distance away from it and the target is always aware of its presence. Creatures other than the target see the illusion as faint and translucent, but the target sees the illusion as realistic and cannot discern it as an illusion by sight alone.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
                <description>When you hit a creature you can see with a spell attack or a creature you can see fails a saving throw against one of your spells, you can choose to create an illusory manifestation of the target’s deepest fears in an unoccupied space within 30 feet of the target. The target must make a Wisdom saving throw (DC {{spellcasting:dc:cha}}), becoming frightened of the illusion until it disappears</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Protective Stupor" type="Archetype Feature" source="Sorcerous Origin: Dream Magic" id="ID_RN_SODM_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAM_MAGIC_PROTECTIVE_STUPOR">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 14th level, when a creature you can see attacks you or another creature you can see within 60 feet of you, you can use your reaction to cause the attacker’s mind to begin to slumber for a moment. The attacker must make a Wisdom saving throw against your sorcerer spell save DC, having disadvantage on all attack rolls until the beginning of its next turn on a failed save, or just having disadvantage on the attack it is making on a successful one.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Reaction">
                <description>When a creature you can see attacks you or another creature you can see within 60 feet of you, you cause the attacker to make a Wisdom saving throw against (DC {{spellcasting:dc:cha}}), having disadvantage on all attack rolls until the beginning of its next turn on a failed save, or just having disadvantage on the attack it is making on a successful one.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Dream walker" type="Archetype Feature" source="Sorcerous Origin: Dream Magic" id="ID_RN_SODM_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAM_MAGIC_DREAM_WALKER">
            <description>
                <p>At 18th level, not even being asleep can stop you. When something causes you to become unconscious, you can instead spend 3 sorcery points to enter a semiconscious state. While in this state you do not suffer any of the negative effects of being unconscious. If knocked unconscious by being reduced to 0 hit points, you can use this ability but must still make death saving throws and suffer the normal effects of taking damage while at 0 hit points. This state lasts for 10 minutes or until you are no longer unconscious, and when it ends as long as you are still unconscious you can spend another 3 sorcery points to keep it up for another 10 minutes.</p>
                <p class="indent">In addition, your power over dreams grows, you learn the <i>dream</i> spell, which counts as a sorcerer spell for you, but it doesn’t count against your number of sorcerer spells known. Also, your dreams can’t be affected by magic in any way unless you allow them to.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When something causes you to become unconscious, you can instead spend 3 sorcery points to enter a semiconscious state. While in this state you do not suffer any of the negative effects of being unconscious. Also, your dreams can’t be affected by magic in any way unless you allow them to.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DREAM" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="18" />
            </rules>
        </element>

</elements>