<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Variant Shadow Magic Sorcerous Origin</name>
        <update version="0.0.2">
            <file name="sorcerer-shadow-magic.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/subclasses/sorcerer/sorcerer-shadow-magic.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Variant Shadow Magic" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_RAINJUNKIE_GMBINDER_SOURCE_VARIANT_SHADOW_MAGIC">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation">VSM</set>
            <set name="url">https://www.gmbinder.com/share/-MAqz3r403CZFYbuyCUq</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" abbreviation="RJ" url="https://www.gmbinder.com/profile/rain-junkie">Rain-Junkie</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20200826</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Shadow Magic (Variant)" type="Archetype" source="Variant Shadow Magic" id="ID_RJ_VSM_ARCHETYPE_SORCERER_SHADOW_MAGIC_VARIANT">
        <supports>Sorcerous Origin</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You are a creature of shadow, for your innate magic comes from the Shadowfell itself. You might trace your lineage to an entity from that place, or perhaps you were exposed to its fell energy.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">SHADOW ORIGIN SPELLS</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Sorcerer Level</td><td>Spell</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1st</td><td><em>bane</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>darkness</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>major image</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>7th</td><td><em>greater invisibility</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>9th</td><td><em>mislead</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>11th</td><td><em>mental prison</em></td></tr>
            </table>
            <div class="sidebar">
                <h5 class="caption">VARIANT FEATURE: ORIGIN SPELLS</h5>
                <p>You gain spells at the sorcerer levels noted in the Shadow Origin Spells table. Once you gain an origin spell, you always know it, and it doesn’t count against the number of spells you know.</p>
                <p class="indent">If you have an origin spell that doesn’t appear on the sorcerer spell list, the spell is nonetheless a sorcerer spell for you.</p>
            </div>
            <div element="ID_RJ_VSM_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOW_MAGIC_BEYOND_SIGHT" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_VSM_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOW_MAGIC_EYES_OF_THE_DARK" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_VSM_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOW_MAGIC_LINGERING_OMEN" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_VSM_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOW_MAGIC_SHADOW_WALK" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_VSM_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOW_MAGIC_IN_EVERY_SHADOW" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_VSM_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOW_MAGIC_BEYOND_SIGHT" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_VSM_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOW_MAGIC_EYES_OF_THE_DARK" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_VSM_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOW_MAGIC_LINGERING_OMEN" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_VSM_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOW_MAGIC_SHADOW_WALK" level="14" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_VSM_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOW_MAGIC_IN_EVERY_SHADOW" level="18" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BANE" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="1" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DARKNESS" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="3" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAJOR_IMAGE" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="5" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GREATER_INVISIBILITY" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="7" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MISLEAD" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="9" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_MENTAL_PRISON" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="11" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Beyond Sight" type="Archetype Feature" source="Variant Shadow Magic" id="ID_RJ_VSM_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOW_MAGIC_BEYOND_SIGHT">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 1st level, you can flicker from the vision of your foes as your magic ensnares them. When you hit a creature with a spell attack from a sorcerer spell, or it fails its saving throw against a sorcerer spell, you can mark it with dark magic. Until the end of your next turn, you become invisible to that creature as long as you aren’t within 10 feet of it.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t do so again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
                <description>When you hit a creature with a spell attack from a sorcerer spell, or it fails its saving throw against a sorcerer spell, you can mark it with dark magic. Until the end of your next turn, you become invisible to that creature as long as you aren’t within 10 feet of it.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Eyes of the Dark" type="Archetype Feature" source="Variant Shadow Magic" id="ID_RJ_VSM_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOW_MAGIC_EYES_OF_THE_DARK">
            <description>
                <p>At 1st level, you can see normally in non-magical darkness out to a range of 120 feet. At 14th level, you can also see normally in magical darkness, out to a range of 120 feet.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can see normally in non-magical darkness out to a range of 120 feet.</description>
                <description level="14">You can see normally in non-magical and magical darkness out to a range of 120 feet.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Lingering Omen" type="Archetype Feature" source="Variant Shadow Magic" id="ID_RJ_VSM_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOW_MAGIC_LINGERING_OMEN">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, when you take damage, you can spend 2 sorcery points as a reaction to reduce that damage by an amount equal to 1d6 + your Charisma modifier + half your sorcerer level, as you wrap shadows around your form to block the blow.</p>
                <p class="indent">If you reduce the damage to 0 hit points this way, you vanish from your current plane of existence, teleporting to a harmless demiplane, and leave behind an omen, which is a humanoid figure made from swirling shadows remains in your original location. The omen has AC 10 + your Charisma modifier, 1 hit point, and immunity to all conditions. If it has to make a saving throw, it uses your saving throw bonus for the roll. It is the same size as you, and it occupies its space. You can see and hear through your omen using your normal senses. When the omen is reduced to 0 hit points, it’s destroyed, and you immediately re-appear at its location.</p>
                <p class="indent">If the omen isn’t destroyed before the start of your next turn, it vanishes and you return to an unoccupied space of your choice within 15 feet of the space you vanished from.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Reaction">
                <description>when you take damage, you can spend 2 sorcery points as a reaction to reduce that damage by 1d6 + {{linger-omen:bonus}}.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="linger-omen:bonus" value="charisma:modifier" />
                <stat name="linger-omen:bonus" value="level:sorcerer:half" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Shadow Walk" type="Archetype Feature" source="Variant Shadow Magic" id="ID_RJ_VSM_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOW_MAGIC_SHADOW_WALK">
            <description>
                <p>At 14th level, you gain the ability to step from one shadow into another, leaving your enemies guessing. When you are in dim light or darkness, as a bonus action, you can magically teleport up to 120 feet to an unoccupied space you can see that is also in dim light or darkness.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>When you are in dim light or darkness, you can magically teleport up to 120 feet to an unoccupied space you can see that is also in dim light or darkness.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="In Every Shadow" type="Archetype Feature" source="Variant Shadow Magic" id="ID_RJ_VSM_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOW_MAGIC_IN_EVERY_SHADOW">
            <description>
                <p>At 18th level, you can veil your foes in shadow magic. As an action on your turn, you can spend 5 sorcery points to send a wave of darkness out from you. Each creature of your choice within 60 feet of you must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or become blinded for 1 minute. While a creature is blinded this way, the shadows that cling to them turn bright light within 15 feet of them to dim light. A creature can use its action on its turn to attempt to regain its sight, repeating the save.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>You can spend 5 sorcery points to force each creature of your choice within 60 feet of you to make a Wisdom saving throw or become blinded for 1 minute. While a creature is blinded this way, the shadows that cling to them turn bright light within 15 feet of them to dim light.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
    
</elements>