<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Feytouched Sorcerous Origin</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="sorcerer-feytouched-enraric.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/subclasses/sorcerer/sorcerer-feytouched-enraric.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Enraric's Feytouched Sorcerer" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_ENRARIC_GMBINDER_SOURCE_Enraric's Feytouched Sorcerer">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation"></set>
            <set name="url">https://www.gmbinder.com/share/-LiYoaNLab1me5lIUx7t</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" url="https://www.gmbinder.com/profile/enraric">Enraric</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20200416</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Feytouched" type="Archetype" source="Enraric's Feytouched Sorcerer" id="ID_ENRARIC_FEYTOUCHED_ARCHETYPE_SORCERER_FEYTOUCHED">
        <supports>Sorcerous Origin, Tweaked Sorcerous Origin</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Feytouched sorcerers come across their powers in a variety of ways. Some have a fey somewhere in their lineage, while others inherited their magic from an ancestor who struck a deal with an archfey. Still others receive their powers through more chance means - a lucky encounter with a creature from the feywild, or an accidental trip into the feywild itself.</p>
            <p class="indent">Regardless of why, you now have the charming powers of the fey. People find you difficult to resist, and often end up bending to your will whether they wanted to or not.</p>
            <div class="reference">
                <h5 class="caption">SORCEROUS ORIGIN SPELLS</h5>
                <p>If you use a homebrew that adds spell lists to the sorcerous origins, such as the spell lists I made, then you can use the following spell list for the feytouched sorcerer:</p>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Sorcerer Level</td><td>Spell</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1st</td><td><em>animal friendship</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>enthrall</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>speak with plants</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>7th</td><td><em>compulsion</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><em>geas</em></td></tr>
                </table>
            </div>
            <div element="ID_ENRARIC_FEYTOUCHED_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FEYTOUCHED_NATURAL_CHARM" />
            <div element="ID_ENRARIC_FEYTOUCHED_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FEYTOUCHED_VANISHING_ACT" />
            <div element="ID_ENRARIC_FEYTOUCHED_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FEYTOUCHED_ILLUSORY_WILL" />
            <div element="ID_ENRARIC_FEYTOUCHED_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FEYTOUCHED_CRITTER_FORM" />
            <div element="ID_ENRARIC_FEYTOUCHED_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FEYTOUCHED_CLOAK_OF_BEGUILEMENT" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANIMAL_FRIENDSHIP" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="1" requirements="(ID_GM_BINDER_OPTION_SORCERER_ORIGIN_SPELLS||ID_SWORDMEOW_TTS_CLASS_TWEAKED_SORCERER)" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENTHRALL" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="3" requirements="(ID_GM_BINDER_OPTION_SORCERER_ORIGIN_SPELLS||ID_SWORDMEOW_TTS_CLASS_TWEAKED_SORCERER)" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_PLANTS" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="5" requirements="(ID_GM_BINDER_OPTION_SORCERER_ORIGIN_SPELLS||ID_SWORDMEOW_TTS_CLASS_TWEAKED_SORCERER)" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMPULSION" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="7" requirements="(ID_GM_BINDER_OPTION_SORCERER_ORIGIN_SPELLS||ID_SWORDMEOW_TTS_CLASS_TWEAKED_SORCERER)" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GEAS" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" level="9" requirements="(ID_GM_BINDER_OPTION_SORCERER_ORIGIN_SPELLS||ID_SWORDMEOW_TTS_CLASS_TWEAKED_SORCERER)" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ENRARIC_FEYTOUCHED_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FEYTOUCHED_NATURAL_CHARM" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ENRARIC_FEYTOUCHED_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FEYTOUCHED_VANISHING_ACT" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ENRARIC_FEYTOUCHED_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FEYTOUCHED_ILLUSORY_WILL" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ENRARIC_FEYTOUCHED_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FEYTOUCHED_CRITTER_FORM" level="14" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ENRARIC_FEYTOUCHED_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FEYTOUCHED_CLOAK_OF_BEGUILEMENT" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Natural Charm" type="Archetype Feature" source="Enraric's Feytouched Sorcerer" id="ID_ENRARIC_FEYTOUCHED_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FEYTOUCHED_NATURAL_CHARM">
            <description>
                <p>Due to the influence of fey magic, you are extraordinarily charming. You gain proficiency in the Charisma (Persuasion) skill if you don't already have it. If you already have profiency in that skill, you instead add double your proficiency modifier to checks made with that skill.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_OR_DOUBLE_PERSUASION" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Vanishing Act" type="Archetype Feature" source="Enraric's Feytouched Sorcerer" id="ID_ENRARIC_FEYTOUCHED_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FEYTOUCHED_VANISHING_ACT">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 1st level, you can disappear into thin air when in danger. As a reaction to taking damage, you can turn invisible and teleport up to 30 feet to an unoccupied space you can see. You remain invisible until the start of your next turn or until you attack or cast a spell.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can use this feature a number of times per long rest equal to your Charisma modifier. You can use this ability additional times by expending 2 Sorcery points.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Reaction" usage="{{charisma:modifier}}/Long Rest">
                <description>As a reaction to taking damage, you can turn invisible and teleport up to 30 feet to an unoccupied space you can see. You remain invisible until the start of your next turn or until you attack or cast a spell. You can use this feature {{charisma:modifier}} times per long rest or by expending 2 Sorcery points.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Illusory Will" type="Archetype Feature" source="Enraric's Feytouched Sorcerer" id="ID_ENRARIC_FEYTOUCHED_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FEYTOUCHED_ILLUSORY_WILL">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 6th level, you gain the ability to make creatures believe your enchantments are their own free will. Whenever you cast an enchantment spell of 1st level or higher targeting one or more creatures, you can spend 1 sorcery point to have one of those creatures forget that they were under the effect of the spell once the spell ends. The creature still remembers all the events that took place, but believes any actions it took were undertaken of its own free will.</p>
                <p class="indent">If the spell targets multiple creatures, you can spend additional sorcery points to cause multiple creatures to forget that they were under the effects of the spell. For each additional creature you wish to have forget, you must spend an additional sorcery point.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Whenever you cast an enchantment spell of 1st level or higher targeting one or more creatures, you can spend 1 sorcery point to have one of those creatures forget that they were under the effect of the spell once the spell ends. If the spell targets multiple creatures, you can spend 1 sorcery point per creature to forget that they were under the effects of the spell.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Critter Form" type="Archetype Feature" source="Enraric's Feytouched Sorcerer" id="ID_ENRARIC_FEYTOUCHED_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FEYTOUCHED_CRITTER_FORM">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 14th level, you learn how to take on the shapes of tiny woodland creatures. You learn the <em>polymorph</em> spell if you don't already know it, and can cast it targeting yourself by expending 2 sorcery points. When you cast polymorph using Sorcery points, you can only turn into a CR 0 creature, but you retain your mental ability scores.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can expend 2 sorcery points cast polymorph targeting yourself. You can only turn into a CR 0 creature when cast this way, but you retain your mental ability scores.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_POLYMORPH" spellcasting="Sorcerer" known="true" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Cloak of Beguilement" type="Archetype Feature" source="Enraric's Feytouched Sorcerer" id="ID_ENRARIC_FEYTOUCHED_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FEYTOUCHED_CLOAK_OF_BEGUILEMENT">
            <description>
                <p>At 18th level, the beguiling magic of the fey surrounds you like a protective cloak. Whenever a creature makes an attack roll against you, it must make a Wisdom saving throw. If it fails, the attack automatically misses and it is charmed by you for 1 minute. The effect ends early for a creature if you or your companions do anything harmful to it. If a creature succeeds on the saving throw or the effect ends, the creature is immune to being charmed in this way for the next 24 hours.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Whenever a creature makes an attack roll against you, it must make a Wisdom saving throw. If it fails, the attack automatically misses and it is charmed by you for 1 minute. The effect ends early for a creature if you or your companions do anything harmful to it. If a creature succeeds on the saving throw or the effect ends, the creature is immune to being charmed in this way for the next 24 hours.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

</elements>