<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Beyond the Stars Backgrounds</name>
        <update version="0.0.12">
            <file name="backgrounds.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/beyond-the-stars/backgrounds.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Cultist" type="Background" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_BACKGROUND_CULTIST">
        <description>
            <p>You once belonged to a cult. Perhaps it was brief, embracing the rebellious spirit of youth and curious where this path may take you. You also may have felt alone and lost, this community offering a welcome you had been subconsciously seeking. It’s possible you were raised from the beginning to pray to the gods of shadow and death. Then one day the veil was lifted and the cruel truth shook your faith, sending you running from the false promises and seeking redemption. You have been freed from the bindings of these dangerous philosophies, but few secret societies find comfort until those who abandon their way are rotting beneath the soil.</p>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Skill Proficiencies:</strong> Insight, Religion</li>
                <li><strong>Tool Proficiencies:</strong> None</li>
                <li><strong>Languages:</strong> Two of your choice</li>
                <li><strong>Equipment:</strong> A holy symbol (a gift to you when you entered the priesthood), a prayer book or prayer wheel, 5 sticks of incense, vestments, a set of common clothes, and a pouch containing 15 gp</li>
            </ul>
            <div element="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_CULTIST_WICKED_AWARENESS" />
            <h5>SUGGESTED CHARACTERISTICS</h5>
            <p>Use the tables below for your traits and motivations, modifying the entries when appropriate to match your ties to your intent as a crazed cultist or a ex-cultist now seeking redemption. Your bond is likely associated with those whom you have grown close to in your cult or who showed you the strength to flee the cult ways and begin your new life. Your ideal probably involves your wishing to further the agenda of your cults goals or if an ex-cultist to take down and destroy those who promote the dark ways you escaped, and perhaps finding new faith in a forgiving god.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="short">Insight, Religion, 2 Languages</set>
        </setters>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_RELIGION" />
            <select type="Language" name="Language (Background)" number="2" />
            <grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_CULTIST_WICKED_AWARENESS" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_OPTIONAL_BACKGROUND_FEATURE"/>
            <select type="Background Feature" name="Variant Feature" supports="Optional Background Feature" optional="true" />
            <select type="List" name="Personality Trait" number="2">
                <item id="1">I idolize a particular hero of my faith or cult group, and constantly refer to that person’s deeds and example.</item>
                <item id="2">I constantly trace symbols inn everything, the dirt, the sand, journals, strange hieroglyphs that i glimpse in my dreams.</item>
                <item id="3">I see omens in every event and action. The stars beyond try to speak to us, we just need to listen.</item>
                <item id="4">Nothing can shake my faith.</item>
                <item id="5">I quote (or misquote) sacred texts and proverbs in almost every situation.</item>
                <item id="6">I am tolerant (or intolerant) of other faiths and respect (or condemn) the worship of other gods.</item>
                <item id="7">I’ve enjoyed fine food, drink, and high society among my temple’s elite. Rough living grates on me.</item>
                <item id="8">I’ve spent so long in the cult that I have little practical experience dealing with people in the outside world.</item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="Ideal">
                <item id="1">Tradition. The ancient traditions of worship and sacrifice must be preserved and upheld. (Lawful)</item>
                <item id="2">Repentant. I cannot possibly undo the wrongs I have done, but I can still try and atone. (Good)</item>
                <item id="3">Anarchist. Lives of men should not be ruled by anyone. No gods, no masters! (Chaotic)</item>
                <item id="4">Power. I hope to one day rise to the top of my faith’s religious hierarchy. (Lawful)</item>
                <item id="5">Faithful. While our cause is righteous, the cult’s leaders are corrupt: I seek to follow my own plans. {Any)</item>
                <item id="6">Selfish. The world is doomed either way. Better make the most of it. (Evil). (Any)</item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="Bond">
                <item id="1">I would die to recover an ancient relic of my faith that was lost long ago.</item>
                <item id="2">No one must ever know about my involvement with the cult.</item>
                <item id="3">I owe my life to the acolyte who took me in when my parents died.</item>
                <item id="4">Everything I do is for the common people, even if they don’t understand or realize my intentions.</item>
                <item id="5">I must spread the teachings of my faith to the non-believers, opening their eyes to the lies of the false gods.</item>
                <item id="6">I seek to preserve a sacred text that my enemies consider heretical and seek to destroy.</item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="Flaw">
                <item id="1">I judge others harshly, and myself even more severely.</item>
                <item id="2">I frequently trance out and lose touch with reality, especially at night. I am sometimes delusional or experience delirious states.</item>
                <item id="3">I take great solace in flagellation. The road to salvation is through blood and self-inflicted pain.</item>
                <item id="4">I am inflexible in my thinking.</item>
                <item id="5">Sometimes, I hear voices in my head that command me to do terrible things. And sometimes, I give in.</item>
                <item id="6">Once I pick a goal, I become obsessed with it to the detriment of everything else in my life.</item>
                <item id="7">I keep secrets even from those closest to me.</item>
                <item id="8">I am quick to anger when my beliefs are slighted.</item>
            </select>
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Feature: Wicked Awareness" type="Background Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_CULTIST_WICKED_AWARENESS">
            <description>
                <p>Your time worshiping in secrecy and shadow at the altar of malevolent forces has left you with insight and keen awareness to those who still operate in such ways. You can often spot hidden signs, messages, and signals left in populated places. If actively seeking signs of a cult or dark following, you have an easier time locating and decoding the signs or social interactions that signify cult activity, gaining advantage on any ability checks to discover such details.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet alt="Wicked Awareness">
                <description>If actively seeking signs of a cult or dark following, you have advantage on any ability checks to discover such details.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    <element name="Insane" type="Background" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_BACKGROUND_INSANE">
        <description>
            <p>Your sanity left you long ago, whether touched by the energies of the Far-realm, or perhaps by contact with one of the Great Old Ones or the Watchers Beyond the Stars, or mayhaps just because you suffered some terrible trauma that broke you. which ever the case, it has warped your mind. Nonexistent things hunt you, real dangers pose you no threat, and the inner workings of the fabric of reality are simple concepts to you. You hear sounds, see sights, and feel presences that no one else can. Despite all of this you’ve never once questioned your sanity because the nice old man who lives in your pocket assures you everything’s alright, or maybe he doesn’t.</p>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Skill Proficiencies:</strong> Insight, Intimidation</li>
                <li><strong>Tool Proficiencies:</strong> None</li>
                <li><strong>Languages:</strong> Choose one exotic languages (Abyssal, Celestial, Deep Speech, Draconic, Infernal, Primordial, Sylvan, or Undercommon)</li>
                <li><strong>Equipment:</strong> An Entertainer’s pack and one trinket.</li>
            </ul>
            <h5>MADNESS TABLE</h5>
            <p>Losing the mind makes way for so many possibilities. You see reality through a very warped lens but at least it’s consistent, you think. Choose a manifestation of your madness or roll for one on the Madness Table.</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d4</td><td>Madness</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td><strong>Paranoia.</strong> Everything, yes everything, is hell bent on your destruction.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td><strong>Mania.</strong> Your understanding is deranged, reasoning is absent, and your always in an unnecessary state of excitement.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td><strong>Incoherence.</strong> Your emotions are mismatched, you forget things, and sometimes your judgment has wandered off.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td><strong>Split Personality.</strong> You aren’t the only tenant of your body, sometimes you have to share with the other(s).</td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_INSANE_SHATTERED_MIND" />
            <h5>SUGGESTED CHARACTERISTICS</h5>
            <p>You have learned to live with the terrors that haunt you, you’ve even named a few of them. You are a thrill seeker and get bored at the slightest hint of normalcy and peace.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="short">Insight, Intimidation, Exotic Language</set>
        </setters>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INTIMIDATION" />
            <select type="Language" name="Language (Background)" number="2" supports="Exotic" />
            <grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_INSANE_SHATTERED_MIND" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_OPTIONAL_BACKGROUND_FEATURE"/>
            <select type="Background Feature" name="Variant Feature" supports="Optional Background Feature" optional="true" />
            <select type="List" name="Personality Trait" number="2">
                <item id="1">I don’t run from evil. Evil runs from me.</item>
                <item id="2">I like to read and memorize poetry. Not only that but I’m convinced that it’s 100% true as long as it rhymes.</item>
                <item id="3">I spend money freely and mostly on useless items.</item>
                <item id="4">I live for the thrill of discovery.</item>
                <item id="5">I tell anyone and everyone about the things that torment me.</item>
                <item id="6">I expect danger around every corner.</item>
                <item id="7">I refuse to sit still, I will never reveal why.</item>
                <item id="8">I put no trust in things that are written down, letters cannot be trusted.</item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="Ideal">
                <item id="1">I try to help those in need, no matter what the personal cost. (Good)</item>
                <item id="2">I’ll stop the spirits that haunt me or die trying. (Any)</item>
                <item id="3">I kill monsters to make the world a happier place, they make the worst party guests. (Good)</item>
                <item id="4">The voices speak to me and usually they forget to tell me about the rules. (Chaotic)</item>
                <item id="5">I strive to find truth, no matter how crazy it seems. (Lawful)</item>
                <item id="6">I’m a monster that destroys other monsters, and anything else I feel like. (Evil)</item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="Bond">
                <item id="1">I recorded my memories in a journal. However I cannot read it and must find someone who can.</item>
                <item id="2">I’ve been exiled from my home and can never return.</item>
                <item id="3">My brokenness drove away the person I love. I strive to win back the love I’ve lost.</item>
                <item id="4">A terrible guilt consumes me and is the reason for my state of mind.</item>
                <item id="5">There’s evil in me, I can feel it. It must never be set free.</item>
                <item id="6">I have a single truth that is concrete. I judge the world by how it stacks up against it.</item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="Flaw">
                <item id="1">I have certain rituals that I must follow every day. I can never break them.</item>
                <item id="2">I assume the best/worst in people.</item>
                <item id="3">I say whatever comes to my mind.</item>
                <item id="4">I have an addiction, or several.</item>
                <item id="5">I am a purveyor of doom and gloom who is way too cheerful about it.</item>
                <item id="6">I talk to spirits that no one else can see.</item>
            </select>
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Feature: Shattered Mind" type="Background Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_INSANE_SHATTERED_MIND">
            <description>
                <p>Those who look into your eyes can see nothing beyond them, or quite possibly everything it’s hard to tell. Kind-hearted folk might find pity for you and offer you some scraps of food or shelter for the night, whereas more hardened folk might ignore you and try to stay clear of you, providing you ample opportunity to be ignored and roam freely so long as you do not provoke them.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet alt="Shattered Mind">
                <description>Those who look into your eyes can see nothing beyond them, or quite possibly everything it’s hard to tell. Kind-hearted folk might find pity for you and offer you some scraps of food or shelter for the night, whereas more hardened folk might ignore you and try to stay clear of you, providing you ample opportunity to be ignored and roam freely so long as you do not provoke them.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
</elements>