<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Path of the Abomination Primal Path</name>
        <update version="0.0.2">
            <file name="barbarian-path-of-the-abomination.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/beyond-the-stars/barbarian-path-of-the-abomination.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Path of the Abomination" type="Archetype" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_BARBARIAN_PATH_OF_THE_ABOMINATION">
        <supports>Primal Path</supports>
        <description>
            <p>A Barbarian of the Path of the Abomination has learned to manipulate their flesh, reshaping it to their will and making it into a living weapon. Whether shaping their arms into a jagged axe or sword, twisting their flesh into a mercurial sponge to protect against an errant explosion, or rapidly stitching itself together to mend wounds. They truly embody their name; Abomination.</p>
            <div element="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARPED_ANGER" />
            <div element="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MERCURIAL_FLESH" />
            <div element="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HARSH_ADAPTATION" />
            <div element="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VIOLENT_REGROWTH" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARPED_ANGER" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MERCURIAL_FLESH" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HARSH_ADAPTATION" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VIOLENT_REGROWTH" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Warped Anger" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARPED_ANGER">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 3rd level when you choose this Path, your anger and rage can unleash the warped magic that perverts your body, reshaping your flesh into a instrument of war. When you rage, you can choose to either grow a tentacle or mutate your arm into a monstrous appendage, your choice, this effect lasts for the duration of the rage.</p>
                <ul>
                    <li><b>Tentacle:</b> You sprout a grotesque tentacle that has a reach of 10 feet and deals 1d4 bludgeoning damage. You can use a bonus action on subsequent turns to attack with it or attempt to grapple or pull a creature 5 feet closer to you. The tentacle is considered an unarmed weapon and uses your strength for the purposes of attack and damage rolls.</li>
                    <li><b>Appendage:</b> Your arm mutates into a fleshy unnatural weapon, such as a spiked mace, a claw, or a sword or axe. Regardless of your choice ,this new appendage deals 1d8 damage of either Bludgeoning, Piercing, or Slashing (your choice) and is magical. This damage increases to 2d8 at 14th level. While mutated in this manner, you cannot use your mutated arm to use an object that requires two hands, such as a weapon with the Two-handed or Heavy property. This effect ends if the arm is severed from your body, or if you end it willingly (no action required).</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you rage, you can choose to either grow a tentacle or mutate your arm into a monstrous appendage, your choice, this effect lasts for the duration of the rage.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Mercurial Flesh" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MERCURIAL_FLESH">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 6th level, your skin can react quickly - and violently- to reform itself to better protect you from further harm. When you are subject to one of the following damage types: Acid, Cold, Fire, Lightning, Necrotic, or Radiant, you can spend your reaction and take Necrotic damage equal to your Barbarian Level to violently reform your flesh to grant resistance for 1 minute against that damage type. This form of Necrotic damage cannot be reduced or ignored in anyway.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Reaction">
                <description>When you are subject to one of the following damage types: Acid, Cold, Fire, Lightning, Necrotic, or Radiant, you can spend your reaction and take Necrotic damage equal to your Barbarian Level to violently reform your flesh to grant resistance for 1 minute against that damage type.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Harsh Adaptation" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HARSH_ADAPTATION">
            <description>
                <p>At 10th level, you gain the ability to reshape your flesh to better adapt to harsh environments you find yourself in. As an Action, you can violently reshape your flesh, taking necrotic damage equal to your Barbarian level, to grant one of the following effects below, each effect lasts for 1 hour. This form of Necrotic damage cannot be reduced or ignored in anyway. You can use this feature multiple times, but must expend hit points for every use. You can end any of the effects at any time (no action required).</p>
                <ul>
                    <li><b>Aquatic Adaptation:</b> You adapt your body to an aquatic environment, sprouting gills and growing webbing between your fingers. You can breathe underwater and gain a swimming speed equal to your walking speed.</li>
                    <li><b>Aerial Adaptation:</b> You adapt your body to the sky, sprouting monstrous wings and gaining a fly speed equal to your walking speed. You cannot be wearing heavy armor while flying from this effect.</li>
                    <li><b>Environmental Adaptation:</b> You adapt your body to better protect you from extreme heat or cold, gaining your choice of either Cold or Fire Resistance.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>You can violently reshape your flesh, taking {{level:barbarian}} points necrotic damage, to grant one of the following effects, each effect lasts for 1 hour: Aquatic Adaptation, Aerial Adaptation or Environmental Adaptation.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Violent Regrowth" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VIOLENT_REGROWTH">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 14th level, your body is under constant degradation and regrowth, reforming itself from any damage you sustain. At the start of each of your turns, you regain hit points equal to Your Constitution Modifier if you have no more than half of your hit points left. You don't gain this benefit if you have 0 hit points. In addition, if you lose a limb (such as if its severed from your body), your body will regrow that limb or even an entire new body. If a limb is severed, your body will regrow a new one over the course of a short rest. If you die - and so long as your heart remains intact and undamaged - you will regrow an entire body over the course of 24 hours. Once you have regrown an entire new body and have regenerated in this manner from death, it takes a toll on you, you cannot benefit from this portion of the feature again until after 7 days have passed.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>At the start of each of your turns, you regain {{constitution:modifier}} hit points if you have no more than half of your hit points left. You don't gain this benefit if you have 0 hit points. In addition, you can regrow a limb or a new body.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
</elements>