<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Bard College of Fate</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="bard-college-of-fate.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/beyond-the-stars/bard-college-of-fate.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="College of Fate" type="Archetype" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_BARD_COLLEGE_OF_FATE">
        <supports>Bard College</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The Bardic College of fate is comprised of fortunetellers, gypsies, and seers. Wanderers who have a gift (or a curse) for glimpsing beyond the veil of the cosmos to peer at the threads of fate; some even being able to manipulate these strands. T hey use their gifts to bring fortune to their friends and misfortune to their foes, but they must tread carefully, for fate is a fickle one, and manipulating it too much could bring great misfortune upon them.</p>
            <div element="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_FATE_CARD_READER" />
            <div element="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_FATE_THREADS_OF_FATE" />
            <div element="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_FATE_CHEAT_FATE" />
            <div element="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_FATE_CHANGE_OF_FATE" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_FATE_CARD_READER" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_FATE_THREADS_OF_FATE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_FATE_CHEAT_FATE" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_FATE_CHANGE_OF_FATE" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Card Reader" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_FATE_CARD_READER">
            <description>
                <p>When you join this college at 3rd level, you gain proficiency with two tools, the Dice Gaming Set and the Playing Card set. If you were already proficient with these tools, you can instead add double your proficiency bonus to checks made with them instead. In addition, you can use a special deck of fortunetelling Tarot cards as your spellcasting focus.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can use a special deck of fortunetelling Tarot cards as your spellcasting focus.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_GAMING_SET_PROFICIENCY_DICE_SET" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_GAMING_SET_PROFICIENCY_PLAYING_CARD_SET" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Threads of Fate" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_FATE_THREADS_OF_FATE">
            <description>
                <p>When you join this college at 3rd level, you learn to provoke and tempt the threads of fate, hoping that the fates draw in your favor. You can expend a use of your bardic inspiration and roll it, and attempt to manipulate the threads of fate. Your DM then draws a card from the Tarokka Deck, consults the Tarokka Fates list described later on, and rolls a d20, he does not reveal either results. Instead, your DM jots them both down in his notes. Fate Cards are broken down into two types; Fortune &amp; Misfortune. The former being an effect that is beneficial to the bard and his allies, and the latter being results that are detrimental to them. When the DM rolls his d20 secretly, if their die result is equal to or greater than the Bard’s bardic inspiration result, than the Fates favor Fortune upon them, if the result is lower than the Bard’s result, the fates show disfavor and show Misfortune upon them.</p>
                <p class="indent">The bard then gains 1 Fate Point, they can only ever have a maximum of 3 fate points, any fate points gained over this amount causes the oldest fate point (and the corresponding fate card and result) to be erased. As a bonus action at any point, the Bard can call out to the fates and provoke their response spending their Fate Point, the DM then reveals his result for that fate card and whether it was a Fortune or a Misfortune and triggers that effect. Alternatively, at any point the DM can activate a Fate Card of his own volition, if it is a Misfortune result. regardless if the Bard activates his effect, displaying how Fate is fickle and can show its ire at any moment.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can expend a use of your bardic inspiration and roll it, and attempt to manipulate the threads of fate. Your DM then draws a card from the Tarokka Deck, consults the Tarokka Fates list described later on, and rolls a d20, he does not reveal either results. You gain 1 Fate Point out of a maximum of 3 Fate Points. As a bonus action at any point, the Bard can call out to the fates and provoke their response spending their Fate Point, the DM then reveals his result for that fate card and whether it was a Fortune or a Misfortune and triggers that effect.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Cheat Fate" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_FATE_CHEAT_FATE">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 6th level, you have the ability to twist fate using your charm, wit, and a bit of magic. When you roll your bardic inspiration die, but before your DM rolls his own secret die and draws his Tarokka Card, you can Cheat Fate, allowing you to add your Charisma Modifier to the bardic die result. Once you use this feature, you cannot do so again until after a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>When you roll your bardic inspiration die, but before your DM rolls his own secret die and draws his Tarokka Card, you can Cheat Fate, allowing you to add your Charisma Modifier to the bardic die result.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Change of Fate" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_FATE_CHANGE_OF_FATE">
            <description>
                <p>At 14th level, you have a long history with the Fates above, one riddled with manipulation, and give and take. When Fate rears its misfortune and ire upon you, you know just the right trick and a little bit of magic to turn that terrible misfortune into a favorable outcome. When your DM reveals a Misfortune Fate card, you can use your reaction and expend another use of your Bardic Inspiration and use the new die result, but must still use the corresponding Tarokka Fate Card. Your DM then rolls a new d20 to determine if this new changed fate is Fortune or Misfortune. Once you use this feature in this manner, you cannot do so again until after a long rest.</p>
                <div class="sidebar">
                    <h5 class="caption">Playing without a Tarokka Deck</h5>
                    <p>Playing this sub-class, it is heavily suggested to play with a Tarokka Deck, a 54-card deck produced by Gale Force Nine and central to the Curse of Strahd adventure module.</p>
                    <p class="indent">If you do not own a Tarokka Deck, below there are alternative suggestions for use of a standard playing card deck, or for simply using percentile dice.</p>
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Reaction">
                <description>When your DM reveals a Misfortune Fate card, you can expend another use of your Bardic Inspiration and use the new die result, but must still use the corresponding Tarokka Fate Card. Your DM then rolls a new d20 to determine if this new changed fate is Fortune or Misfortune.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
</elements>