<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Madness Divine Domain</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="cleric-madness-domain.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/beyond-the-stars/cleric-madness-domain.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Madness Domain" type="Archetype" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_CLERIC_MADNESS_DOMAIN">
        <supports>Divine Domain</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The Madness domain is home to lunatics, sycophants and fanatical zealots, those who adopt this domain are often already touched in some form by madness already. The gods and goddesses that offer this domain to their followers are often time devious, malevolent and manipulative, draining the sanity of mortals to increase their power. Other see themselves as liberators. They promise their followers that by offering their devotion to them, they will break the shackles of reason and reality that is holding their mind down, opening their mind to a whole new world of possibility. Cleric choosing this domain can sometimes find themselves lost in thoughts with themselves, rambling incoherently or debating the most outlandish subjects. Deities of this domain include Cyric, Ghaunadaur, and Tharizdun.</p>
            <div element="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MADNESS_DOMAIN_SPELLS" />
            <div element="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MADNESS_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" />
            <div element="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MADNESS_THE_TOUCHED_MIND" />
            <div element="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MADNESS_CD_SOW_MADNESS" />
            <div element="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MADNESS_CD_TOUCH_OF_INSANITY" />
            <div element="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MADNESS_WHISPERS_OF_LUNACY" />
            <div element="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MADNESS_PSYCHOTIC_BREAK" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MADNESS_DOMAIN_SPELLS" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MADNESS_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MADNESS_THE_TOUCHED_MIND" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MADNESS_CD_SOW_MADNESS" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MADNESS_CD_TOUCH_OF_INSANITY" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MADNESS_WHISPERS_OF_LUNACY" level="8" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MADNESS_PSYCHOTIC_BREAK" level="17" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Domain Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MADNESS_DOMAIN_SPELLS">
            <description>
                <p>At 3rd level, a Cleric gains the Divine Domain feature. The following option is available to a Cleric, in addition to those offered in the Player’s Handbook: Madness Domain.</p>
                <h5 class="caption">Madness Domain Spells</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Cleric level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1st</td><td><i>dissonant whispers, Tasha’s hideous laughter</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td><i>crown of madness, phantasmal force</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><i>fear, hunger of Hadar</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>7th</td><td><i>confusion, phantasmal killer</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><i>dream, modify memory</i></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISSONANT_WHISPERS" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="1" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TASHAS_HIDEOUS_LAUGHTER" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="1" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CROWN_OF_MADNESS" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PHANTASMAL_FORCE" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FEAR" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HUNGER_OF_HADAR" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONFUSION" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="7" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PHANTASMAL_KILLER" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="7" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DREAM" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MODIFY_MEMORY" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="9" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Bonus Proficiencies" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MADNESS_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES">
            <description>
                <p>At 1st level, You know the Vicious Mockery cantrip, which counts as a cleric cantrip for you, and does not count against the number of cantrips you can have known.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_VICIOUS_MOCKERY" spellcasting="Cleric" know="true" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="The Touched Mind" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MADNESS_THE_TOUCHED_MIND">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 1st level, your mind suffers the glorious truth of insanity, as your gods whispers begin to seep into your mind. The turmoil and conflicted nature of your mind grants you advantage on saving throws against being charmed or frightened, and on saving throws against effects that would read your mind or thoughts. In addition, you must roll a d100 and gain an indefinite madness flaw as per pg.260 of the <em>Dungeon Master’s Guide</em>. This indefinite madness can be cured by nothing short of a <em>wish</em> spell or magic of comparable power.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You have advantage on saving throws against being charmed or frightened, and on saving throws against effects that would read your mind or thoughts. You gain an indefinite madess.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Channel Divinity: Sow Madness" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MADNESS_CD_SOW_MADNESS">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to shatter the minds of other creatures. As an action, choose a creature that you can see within 60 feet of you, and they must make a Intelligence Saving Throw. On a failure, the creature takes 3d10 + your Cleric level psychic damage and must roll for a random affliction of madness from the Short-Term Madness on pg.259 of the <em>Dungeon Master’s Guide</em>. This form of madness lasts for 1d10 minutes, which they must roll for when the madness effect takes hold.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet alt="Sow Madness" usage="Channel Divinity" action="Action">
                <description>Choose a creature that you can see within 60 feet of you, and they must make a Intelligence Saving Throw. On a failure, the creature takes 3d10 + {{level:cleric}} psychic damage and must roll for a random affliction of madness from the Short-Term Madness on pg.259 of the DMG. This form of madness lasts for 1d10 minutes, which they must roll for when the madness effect takes hold.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Channel Divinity: Touch of Insanity" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MADNESS_CD_TOUCH_OF_INSANITY">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 6th level, you can use your Channel Divinity to afflict prolonged debilitating madness upon a foe. As an action, choose one creature that you can see within 60 feet of you, that creature must make an Intelligence Saving Throw. On a failure, you touch their mind with whispers of madness, causing them to roll for a random affliction from a long-term madness effect as per the long-term madness table on pg.260 of the <em>Dungeon Master’s Guide</em>. This effect lasts for 1d10 x 10 hours, which they must roll for when the madness effect takes hold.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Channel Divinity" alt="Touch of Insanity" action="Action">
                <description>choose one creature that you can see within 60 feet of you, that creature must make an Intelligence Saving Throw. On a failure, you touch their mind with whispers of madness, causing them to roll for a random affliction from a long-term madness effect as per the long-term madness table on pg.260 of the DMG. This effect lasts for 1d10 x 10 hours, which they must roll for when the madness effect takes hold.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Whispers of Lunacy" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MADNESS_WHISPERS_OF_LUNACY">
            <description>
                <p>At 8th level, you can add your Wisdom Modifier to the damage you deal with any cleric cantrip.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You add {{wisdom:modifier}} to the damage you deal with any cleric cantrip.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Psychotic Break" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MADNESS_PSYCHOTIC_BREAK">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 17th level, your mind has shattered under the strain of the wisdom granted by your god, while it has rendered you irrevocably insane, it also makes your mind a impenetrable fortress of knowledge. You gain another indefinite madness, as per the <em>Dungeon Master’s Guide</em>. In exchange, you gain immunity to the Charmed and Frightened Condition, and your thoughts cannot be read nor detected by telepathy or other means, unless you allow it, nor can you be detected by divination magic or scrying. In addition, you gain resistance to psychic damage, and whenever a creature deals psychic damage to you, that creature takes the same amount of psychic damage that was dealt to you, and that creature must make a Intelligence Saving Throw against your Spell Save DC. On a failure, the creature is struck by a backlash of insanity, and must roll for a short-term madness effect as on pg.259 of the <em>Dungeon Master’s Guide</em>, this form of madness lasts for 1d10 minutes which they must roll for when the madness effect takes hold.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You gain another indefinite madness, as per the DMG. You are immune to the charmed and frightened conditions and your thoughts cannot be read nor detected by any means. Whenever a creature deals psychic damage to you, that creature takes the same amount of psychic damage that was dealt to you, and that creature must make a Intelligence Saving Throw against your Spell Save DC. On a failure, the creature is struck by a backlash of insanity, and must roll for a short-term madness effect as on pg.259 of the DMG, this form of madness lasts for 1d10 minutes which they must roll for when the madness effect takes hold.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_PSYCHIC" />
            </rules>
        </element>
    
</elements>