<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Druid Circle of the Stars</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="druid-circle-of-the-stars.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/beyond-the-stars/druid-circle-of-the-stars.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Circle of the Stars" type="Archetype" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_DRUID_CIRCLE_OF_THE_STARS">
        <supports>Druid Circle</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The druids of this circle have a deep understanding of the natural cycle of life, realizing that the great cycle extends beyond the meager land beneath their feet, and into the celestial heavens themselves; the cosmos, the stars. Druids of the circle have a deep connection to the stars and the constellations, drawing power from the celestial energies that permeate the cosmos and the effects that the constellations have upon the natural world.</p>
            <div element="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_STARS_CIRCLE_OF_THE_STARS_SPELLS" />
            <div element="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_STARS_BLINDING_STARLIGHT" />
            <div element="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_STARS_ASTRAL_FORM" />
            <div element="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_STARS_ASTRAL_MENDING" />
            <div element="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_STARS_ASK_THE_STARS" />
            <div element="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_STARS_SHOOTING_STAR" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_STARS_CIRCLE_OF_THE_STARS_SPELLS" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_STARS_BLINDING_STARLIGHT" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_STARS_ASTRAL_FORM" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_STARS_ASTRAL_MENDING" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_STARS_ASK_THE_STARS" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_STARS_SHOOTING_STAR" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Circle of the Stars Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_STARS_CIRCLE_OF_THE_STARS_SPELLS">
            <description>
                <p>When you choose this druidic circle at 2nd level, you gain the ability to harness the energy of the cosmos, granting you access to certain spells. You learn the <em>dancing lights</em> cantrip. and at 3rd, 5th, 7th, and 9th level you gain access to the spells listed for that level in the Circle of the Stars spells table. Once you gain access to one of these spells, you always have it prepared and it doesn’t count against the number of spells you can prepare each day. If you gain access to a spell that doesn’t appear on the druid spell list, the spell is nonetheless a druid spell for you.</p>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Druid Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td><i></i>healing spirit, moonbeam</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><i></i>blink, hunger of Hadar</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>7th</td><td><i></i>Evard’s black tentacles, sickening radiance</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><i></i>scrying, wall of light</td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DANCING_LIGHTS" spellcasting="Druid" known="true" level="2" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_HEALING_SPIRIT" spellcasting="Druid" prepared="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MOONBEAM" spellcasting="Druid" prepared="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLINK" spellcasting="Druid" prepared="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HUNGER_OF_HADAR" spellcasting="Druid" prepared="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_EVARDS_BLACK_TENTACLES" spellcasting="Druid" prepared="true" level="7" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_SICKENING_RADIANCE" spellcasting="Druid" prepared="true" level="7" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SCRYING" spellcasting="Druid" prepared="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_WALL_OF_LIGHT" spellcasting="Druid" prepared="true" level="9" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Blinding Starlight" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_STARS_BLINDING_STARLIGHT">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 2nd level, you can call upon the brilliant light of the stars to shine down upon you in your darkest hour, to shield you from harm. As a reaction when a creature makes an attack against you, you can cause starlight to emanate forth from you, shedding bright light out to 10 feet, and dim light for an additional 10 feet beyond that, this light lasts either for 1 minute, until you are knocked unconscious or until you end it (no action required). The attack immediately has disadvantage and the attacker must make a Constitution Saving Throw against your spell save DC, on a failure they take 1d4 radiant damage and are blinded for 1 minute. They can repeat this save at the end of each of their turns, ending the effect on a successful save. The radiant damage increases to 1d6 at 6th level, 1d8 at 10th level, and 1d10 at 14th level. You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom Modifier (minimum of once), regaining expended uses of it after a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Reaction">
                <description>When a creature makes an attack against you, you can cause starlight to emanate forth from you, shedding bright light out to 10 feet, and dim light for an additional 10 feet beyond that, this light lasts either for 1 minute, until you are knocked unconscious or until you end it (no action required). The attack immediately has disadvantage and the attacker must make a Constitution Saving Throw against your spell save DC, on a failure they take 1d4 radiant damage and are blinded for 1 minute.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Astral Form" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_STARS_ASTRAL_FORM">
            <description>
                <p>At 2nd level, you gain the ability to channel the light of the stars into your primal druidic magic. As an Action, you can expend one use of your Wild Shape and infuse your primal transformation with the magic of the stars. Rather than transform into a beast, you transform into a being of Starlight, and gain 3 temporary hit points for each Druid level you have. While this feature is active, you gain the following benefits:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>You radiate an aura of bright starlight in a 5 - to 20-foot radius and dim light for an additional number of feet equal to the chosen radius. You can alter the radius as a bonus action. While radiating this starlight, you, and each ally that starts their turn in the aura or enters it for the first time, gain hit points equal to your Wisdom Modifier (minimum of 1). Any enemy creature that enters the aura for the first time or starts their turn within it, takes Radiant damage equal to your Wisdom Modifier (minimum of 1). Lastly, no creature can benefit from being invisible while within the starlight,</li>
                    <li>While radiating starlight, you gain resistance to radiant damage.</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">These benefits last for 10 minutes, until you lose all these temporary hit points, or until you use your Wild Shape again</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>You can expend one use of your Wild Shape and infuse your primal transformation with the magic of the stars. Rather than transform into a beast, you transform into a being of Starlight, and gain 3 temporary hit points for each Druid level you have. While this feature is active, you gain several benefits: you radiate starlight which can heal allies and damage enemies; you gain resistance to radian damage.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="astral-form:temp-hp" value="level:druid" />
                <stat name="astral-form:temp-hp" value="level:druid" />
                <stat name="astral-form:temp-hp" value="level:druid" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Astral Mending" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_STARS_ASTRAL_MENDING">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 6th level, You learn to harness fragments of the magic you channel from the stars, and use it to replenish yourself and mend your wounds. Whenever you cast a spell of 1st level or higher that deals radiant damage, you regain hit points equal to 2 + the level of the spell slot expended.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Whenever you cast a spell of 1st level or higher that deals radiant damage, you regain hit points equal to 2 + the level of the spell slot expended.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Ask the Stars" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_STARS_ASK_THE_STARS">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 10th level, You know the <em>contact other plane</em> spell and have it always prepared. In addition, you can cast it once without expending a spell slot, when you do so in this manner, you can ask the Stars above for guidance, making a DC:15 Wisdom Saving Throw, instead of the normal Intelligence Saving Throw associated with the spell. However, once you use this feature in this manner, you cannot use this feature again until after a long rest, though you can cast the spell normally by expending a spell slot of appropriate spell level.</p>
                <div class="reference">
                    <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONTACT_OTHER_PLANE" />
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can cast contact other plane once without expending a spell slot, when you do so in this manner, you can ask the Stars above for guidance, making a DC:15 Wisdom Saving Throw, instead of the normal Intelligence Saving Throw associated with the spell.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONTACT_OTHER_PLANE" prepared="true" spellcasting="Druid" level="10" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Shooting Star" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_STARS_SHOOTING_STAR">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 14th level, you learn to transcend your limits to this mortal coil and take up to the night sky as an ethereal star. While in your Astral Form, you gain a fly speed of 60 ft and your physical form partially shifts into the ethereal, allowing you to see into the Ethereal Plane up to 60 feet. In addition, you gain resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage from non-magical weapons, and you can spend an Action to traverse into the Ethereal Plane or back into the Material Plane, you are still visible while on the Border Ethereal, and vice versa, yet you can’t affect or be affected by anything on the other plane. Lastly, while in your Astral Form, you can move through other creatures and objects as if they were difficult terrain. However, you takes 1d10 force damage if you end your turn inside an object.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>While in your Astral Form, you gain a fly speed of 60 ft and your physical form partially shifts into the ethereal, allowing you to see into the Ethereal Plane up to 60 feet. In addition, you gain resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage from non-magical weapons, and you can spend an Action to traverse into the Ethereal Plane or back into the Material Plane, you are still visible while on the Border Ethereal, and vice versa, yet you can’t affect or be affected by anything on the other plane. Lastly, while in your Astral Form, you can move through other creatures and objects as if they were difficult terrain. However, you takes 1d10 force damage if you end your turn inside an object.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
    
</elements>