<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>The Pactsworn Martial Archetype</name>
        <update version="0.0.2">
            <file name="fighter-the-pactsworn.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/beyond-the-stars/fighter-the-pactsworn.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="The Pactsworn" type="Archetype" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FIGHTER_THE_PACTSWORN">
        <supports>Martial Archetype</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Warriors who have entered a pact to obtain profane knowledge and mastery over dark magicks, with which to amplify their combat prowess and obtain an edge over their foes.</p>
            <div element="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTSWORN_PACT_MAGIC" />
            <div element="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTSWORN_PACTBLADE" />
            <div element="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTSWORN_GREATER_PACT" />
            <div element="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTSWORN_ELDRITCH_RENEWAL" />
            <div element="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTSWORN_PROFANE_REAPING" />
            <div element="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTSWORN_BANE_AND_BLADE" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTSWORN_PACT_MAGIC" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTSWORN_PACTBLADE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTSWORN_GREATER_PACT" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTSWORN_ELDRITCH_RENEWAL" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTSWORN_PROFANE_REAPING" level="15" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTSWORN_BANE_AND_BLADE" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Pact Magic" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTSWORN_PACT_MAGIC">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 3rd level, you can augment your combat techniques with the ability to cast Warlock spells. you enter into a pact with a Warlock Patron in exchange for the ability to cast spells, however unlike the Warlock, you do not receive Warlock Patron features, merely the ability to cast spells. </p>
                <h5>CANTRIPS</h5>
                <p>You learn two cantrips of your choice from the warlock spell list. You learn an additional warlock cantrip of your choice at 10th level.</p>
                <h5>SPELL SLOTS</h5>
                <p>The Pactsworn Spellcasting Table shows how many spell slots you have. The table also shows what the level of those slots is; all of your spell slots are the same level. To cast one of your warlock spells of 1st level or higher, you must expend a spell slot. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a short or long rest. For example, when you are 8th level, you have two 2nd-level spell slots. To cast the 1st-level spell Thunderwave, you must spend one of those slots and you cast it as a 2nd-level spell.</p>
                <h5>SPELLS KNOWN OF 1ST LEVEL AND HIGHER</h5>
                <p>At 3rd level, you know two 1st-level spells of your choice from the Warlock spell list. The Spells Known Column of the Pactsworn table shows when you learn more Warlock spells of your choice of 1st level and higher. A spell you choose must be of a level no higher than what’s shown in the table’s Slot Level column for your level. When you reach 11th level, for example, you learn a new warlock spell, which can be 1st, 2nd, or 3rd level. Additionally, when you gain a level in this Class and Order, you can choose one for the warlock spells you know and replace it with another spell from the Warlock spell list, which also must be of a level for which you have spell slots.</p>
                <h5>SPELLCASTING ABILITY</h5>
                <p>Charisma is your Spellcasting ability for your Warlock spells.</p>
                <center>
                    <p><strong>Spell Save DC</strong> = 8 + Your Proficiency Bonus + Your Charisma Modifier. </p>
                    <p><strong>Spell Attack Modifier</strong> = Your Proficiency Bonus + Your Charisma Modifier.</p>
                </center>
                <h5 class="caption">ARCANE TRICKSTER SPELLCASTING</h5>
                <table class="class-features">
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td class="col-10">Level</td><td class="col-10">Cantrips Known</td><td class="col-10">Spells Known</td><td>Spell Slots</td><td>Slot Level</td><td></td><td></td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td> 3rd</td><td>2</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>1st</td></tr>
                    <tr><td> 4th</td><td>2</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>1st</td></tr>
                    <tr><td> 5th</td><td>2</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>1st</td></tr>
                    <tr><td> 6th</td><td>2</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>1st</td></tr>
                    <tr><td> 7th</td><td>2</td><td>4</td><td>2</td><td>2nd</td></tr>
                    <tr><td> 8th</td><td>2</td><td>4</td><td>2</td><td>2nd</td></tr>
                    <tr><td> 9th</td><td>2</td><td>5</td><td>2</td><td>2nd</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>10th</td><td>3</td><td>5</td><td>2</td><td>2nd</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>11th</td><td>3</td><td>6</td><td>2</td><td>2nd</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>12th</td><td>3</td><td>6</td><td>2</td><td>2nd</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>13th</td><td>3</td><td>7</td><td>2</td><td>3rd</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>14th</td><td>3</td><td>7</td><td>2</td><td>3rd</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>15th</td><td>3</td><td>8</td><td>2</td><td>3rd</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>16th</td><td>3</td><td>8</td><td>2</td><td>3rd</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>17th</td><td>3</td><td>9</td><td>2</td><td>3rd</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>18th</td><td>3</td><td>9</td><td>2</td><td>3rd</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>19th</td><td>3</td><td>10</td><td>2</td><td>4th</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>20th</td><td>3</td><td>11</td><td>2</td><td>4th</td></tr>
                </table>				
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <spellcasting name="Pactsworn" ability="Charisma" prepare="false">
                <list>Warlock</list>
            </spellcasting>
            <setters>
                <set name="spellcaster">true</set>
                <set name="spellcastingAbility">Charisma</set>
            </setters>
            <rules>
                <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Pact Magic Patron" supports="Pactsworn Patron" level="3" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Pactsworn)" number="2" spellcasting="Pactsworn" known="true" supports="Warlock,0" level="3" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Pactsworn)" number="1" spellcasting="Pactsworn" known="true" supports="Warlock,0" level="10" />

                <stat name="pactsworn:spellcasting:slots:count" value="1" level="3"/>
                <stat name="pactsworn:spellcasting:slots:count" value="1" level="5"/>

                <stat name="pactsworn:spellcasting:slot" value="1" level="1" />
                <stat name="pactsworn:spellcasting:slot" value="1" level="7" />
                <stat name="pactsworn:spellcasting:slot" value="1" level="13" />
                <stat name="pactsworn:spellcasting:slot" value="1" level="19" />

                <!-- negative count to remove slots -->
                <stat name="pactsworn:spellcasting:slots:1" value="pactsworn:spellcasting:slots:count" level="1" />
                <stat name="pactsworn:spellcasting:slots:1" value="-pactsworn:spellcasting:slots:count" level="7" />
                <stat name="pactsworn:spellcasting:slots:2" value="pactsworn:spellcasting:slots:count" level="7" />
                <stat name="pactsworn:spellcasting:slots:2" value="-pactsworn:spellcasting:slots:count" level="13" />
                <stat name="pactsworn:spellcasting:slots:3" value="pactsworn:spellcasting:slots:count" level="13" />
                <stat name="pactsworn:spellcasting:slots:3" value="-pactsworn:spellcasting:slots:count" level="19" />
                <stat name="pactsworn:spellcasting:slots:4" value="pactsworn:spellcasting:slots:count" level="19" />

                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Pactsworn)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="3" number="2" spellcasting="Pactsworn"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Pactsworn)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="5" spellcasting="Pactsworn"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Pactsworn)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="7" spellcasting="Pactsworn"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Pactsworn)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="9" spellcasting="Pactsworn"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Pactsworn)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="11" spellcasting="Pactsworn"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Pactsworn)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="13" spellcasting="Pactsworn"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Pactsworn)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="15" spellcasting="Pactsworn"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Pactsworn)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="17" spellcasting="Pactsworn"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Pactsworn)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="19" spellcasting="Pactsworn"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Pactsworn)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="20" spellcasting="Pactsworn"/>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Pactblade" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTSWORN_PACTBLADE">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 3rd level, you have gained a gift from your patron, a weapon given to seal the contract of the pact. Your patron required a warrior, and granted you the tools to be one. You can use your action to create a pact weapon in your empty hand. You can choose the form that this melee weapon takes each time you create it (see chapter 5 for weapon options). It acts as a warlock spellcasting focus. Your pact weapon disappears if it is more than 5 feet away from you for 1 minute or more. It also disappears if you use this feature again, if you dismiss the weapon (no action required), or if you die. You can transform a magic weapon into your pact weapon by performing the ritual over the course of 1 hour, which can be done during a short rest. you can have a maximum of one transformed magic weapon, if you attempt to transform a second, the oldest magical pact weapon loses its bond to you. You can then dismiss the weapon, shunting it into an extradimensional space, and it appears whenever you create your pact weapon thereafter. The weapon ceases being your pact weapon if you die, if you perform the 1-hour ritual on a different weapon, or if you use a 1-hour ritual to break your bond to it. The weapon appears at your feet if it is in the extradimensional space when the bond breaks.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>You can use your action to create a pact weapon in your empty hand. You can choose the form that this melee weapon takes each time you create it. It acts as a warlock spellcasting focus.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Greater Pact" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTSWORN_GREATER_PACT">
            <description>
                <p>At 7th level, Your eldritch magic has grown further, shaped by the origin of your patron, you gain the benefits of one of the following choices described below, dependent on the entity your patron is:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li><strong>Archfey:</strong> You know the <em>suggestion</em> spell and can cast it once without expending a spell slot, regaining said use after a long rest.</li>
                    <li><strong>Celestial:</strong> You know the <em>lesser restoration</em> spell and can cast it once without expending a spell slot, regaining said use after a long rest.</li>
                    <li><strong>Fiend:</strong> You know the <em>scorching ray</em> spell and can cast it once without expending a spell slot, regaining said use after a long rest.</li>
                    <li><strong>Great Old One:</strong> You know the <em>detect thoughts</em> spell and can cast it once without expending a spell slot, regaining said use after a long rest.</li>
                    <li><strong>Hexblade:</strong> You know the <em>spiritual weapon</em> spell and can cast it once without expending a spell slot, regaining said use after a long rest.</li>
                    <li><strong>Undying:</strong> You know the <em>gentle repose</em> spell and can cast it once without expending a spell slot, regaining said use after a long rest.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Eldritch Renewal" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTSWORN_ELDRITCH_RENEWAL">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 10th level, when you use your <em>Second Wind</em> feature, you also regain one expended warlock spell slot.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you use your Second Wind feature, you also regain one expended warlock spell slot.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Profane Reaping" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTSWORN_PROFANE_REAPING">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 15th level, Your pactblade is a conduit to your patron, and the more blood you shed with it, the further you fuel your pact. You gain one of the following benefits dependent on the type of patron you have:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li><strong>Archfey:</strong> When you score a critical hit with your pactblade, you can temporarily shift into the feywild and reappear elsewhere, distorted by fey magic. You can teleport up to 30 feet and become ethereal, causing attack rolls against you to have disadvantage until the start of your next turn.</li>
                    <li><strong>Celestial:</strong> Once per turn, when you deal damage to a creature with a spell or your pactblade, you can cause residual radiant energy to mend the wounds of one ally creature within 15 feet of you that you can see, causing them to regain hit points equal to 1 + Your Charisma Modifier.</li>
                    <li><strong>Fiend:</strong> When you take damage from a melee attack, your attacker is struck by a backlash of hellish energy, taking fire damage equal to your Charisma Modifier (minimum of 1).</li>
                    <li><strong>Great Old One:</strong> When you score a critical hit, you deal additional psychic damage equal to half your warlock level, and the creature must make an Intelligence Saving Throw or be frightened of you until the end of your next turn.</li>
                    <li><strong>Hexblade:</strong> You can score a critical hit on a roll of 19-20 with your pactblade.</li>
                    <li><strong>Undying:</strong> When you deal damage with your pactblade, you deal an additional amount of necrotic damage equal to your Charisma Modifier (minimum of 1). You gain Temporary Hit Points equal to the necrotic damage dealt.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Bane and Blade" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTSWORN_BANE_AND_BLADE">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 18th level, You learn to weave magic and blade together in perfect harmony. When you take the Attack action, you can also quickly cast a spell, allowing you to cast a spell with a cast time of 1 action as a bonus action instead. Once you use this feature, you cannot do so again until after a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    <!-- Pactsworn Patron -->
        <element name="Archefey" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTSWORN_PATRON_ARCHFEY">
            <supports>Pactsworn Patron</supports>
            <description>
                <p>Your patron is a lord or lady of the fey, a creature of legend who holds secrets that were forgotten before the mortal races were born. This being’s motivations are often inscrutable, and sometimes whimsical, and might involve a striving for greater magical power or the settling of age-old grudges. Beings of this sort include the Prince of Frost; the Queen of Air and Darkness, ruler of the Gloaming Court; Titania of the Summer Court; her consort Oberon, the Green Lord; Hyrsam, the Prince of Fools; and ancient hags.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet alt="Patron: Archfey">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTSWORN_PATRON_ARCHFEY_GREATER_PACT" level="7" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTSWORN_PATRON_ARCHFEY_PROFANE_REAPING" level="15" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Celestial" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTSWORN_PATRON_CELESTIAL">
            <supports>Pactsworn Patron</supports>
            <description>
                <p>Your patron is a powerful being of the Upper Planes. You have bound yourself to an ancient empyrean, solar, ki-rin, or unicorn or to another entity that resides in the planes of everlasting bliss. Your pact with that being allows you to experience the barest touch of the holy light that illuminates the multiverse.</p>
                <p class="indent">Being connected to such power can cause changes in your behavior and beliefs. You might find yourself driven to annihilate the undead, to defeat fiends, and to protect the innocent. At times, your heart might also be filled with a longing for the celestial realm of your patron, a desire to wander that paradise for the rest of your days. But you know that your mission is among mortals for now and that your pact binds you to bring light to the dark places of the world.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet alt="Patron: Celestial">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTSWORN_PATRON_CELESTIAL_GREATER_PACT" level="7" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTSWORN_PATRON_CELESTIAL_PROFANE_REAPING" level="15" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Fiend" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTSWORN_PATRON_FIEND">
            <supports>Pactsworn Patron</supports>
            <description>
                <p>You have made a pact with a fiend from the lower planes of existence, a being whose aims are evil, even if you strive against those aims. Such beings desire the corruption or destruction of all things, ultimately including you. Fiends powerful enough to forge a pact include demon lords such as Demogorgon, Orcus, Fraz’Urb-luu, and Baphomet; archdevils such as Asmodeus, Dispater, Mephistopheles, and Belial; pit fiends and balors that are especially mighty; and ultroloths and other lords of the yugoloths.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet alt="Patron: Fiend">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTSWORN_PATRON_FIEND_GREATER_PACT" level="7" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTSWORN_PATRON_FIEND_PROFANE_REAPING" level="15" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Great Old One" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTSWORN_PATRON_GREAT_OLD_ONE">
            <supports>Pactsworn Patron</supports>
            <description>
                <p>Your patron is a mysterious entity whose nature is utterly foreign to the fabric of reality. It might come from the Far Realm, the space beyond reality, or it could be one of the elder gods known only in legends. Its motives are incomprehensible to mortals, and its knowledge so immense and ancient that even the greatest libraries pale in comparison to the vast secrets it holds. The Great Old One might be unaware of your existence or entirely indifferent to you, but the secrets you have learned allow you to draw your magic from it.</p>
                <p class="indent">Entities of this type include Ghaunadar, called That Which Lurks; Tharizdun, the Chained God; Dendar, the Night Serpent; Zargon, the Returner; Great Cthulhu; and other unfathomable beings.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet alt="Patron: Great Old One">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTSWORN_PATRON_GREAT_OLD_ONE_GREATER_PACT" level="7" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTSWORN_PATRON_GREAT_OLD_ONE_PROFANE_REAPING" level="15" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Hexblade" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTSWORN_PATRON_HEXBLADE">
            <supports>Pactsworn Patron</supports>
            <description>
                <p>You have made your pact with a mysterious entity from the Shadowfell—a force that manifests in sentient magic weapons carved from the stuff of shadow. The mighty sword Blackrazor is the most notable of these weapons, which have been spread across the multiverse over the ages. The shadowy force behind these weapons can offer power to warlocks who form pacts with it. Many hexblade warlocks create weapons that emulate those formed in the Shadowfell. Others forgo such arms, content to weave the dark magic of that plane into their spellcasting.</p>
                <p class="indent">Because the Raven Queen is known to have forged the first of these weapons, many sages speculate that she and the force are one and that the weapons, along with hexblade warlocks, are tools she uses to manipulate events on the Material Plane to her inscrutable ends. </p>
            </description>
            <sheet alt="Patron: Hexblade">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTSWORN_PATRON_HEXBLADE_GREATER_PACT" level="7" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTSWORN_PATRON_HEXBLADE_PROFANE_REAPING" level="15" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Undying" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTSWORN_PATRON_UNDYING">
            <supports>Pactsworn Patron</supports>
            <description>
                <p>Death holds no sway over your patron, who has unlocked the secrets of everlasting life, although such a prize- like all power- comes at a price. Once mortal, the Undying has seen mortal lifetimes pass like the seasons, like the flicker of endless days and nights. It has the secrets of the ages to share, secrets of life and death. Beings of this sort include Vecna, Lord of the Hand and the Eye; the dread Iuz; the lich-queen Vol; the Undying Court of Aerenal; Vlaakith, lich-queen of the githyanki; and the deathless wizard Fistandantalus.</p>
                <p class="indent">In the Realms, Undying patrons include Larloch the Shadow King, legendary master of Warlock’s Crypt, and Gilgeam, the God-King of Unther.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet alt="Patron: Undying">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTSWORN_PATRON_UNDYING_GREATER_PACT" level="7" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTSWORN_PATRON_UNDYING_PROFANE_REAPING" level="15" />
            </rules>
        </element>

    <!-- Greater Pact Features -->
        <element name="Greater Pact: Archfey" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTSWORN_PATRON_ARCHFEY_GREATER_PACT">
            <description>
                <p>You know the <em>suggestion</em> spell and can cast it once without expending a spell slot, regaining said use after a long rest.</p>
                <div class="reference">
                    <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_SUGGESTION" />
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet alt="Greater Pact" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You know the spell and can cast it once without expending a spell slot.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SUGGESTION" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Greater Pact: Celestial" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTSWORN_PATRON_CELESTIAL_GREATER_PACT">
            <description>
                <p>You know the <em>lesser restoration</em> spell and can cast it once without expending a spell slot, regaining said use after a long rest.</p>
                <div class="reference">
                    <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_LESSER_RESTORATION" />
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet alt="Greater Pact" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You know the lesser restoration spell and can cast it once without expending a spell slot.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LESSER_RESTORATION" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Greater Pact: Fiend" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTSWORN_PATRON_FIEND_GREATER_PACT">
            <description>
                <p>You know the <em>scorching ray</em> spell and can cast it once without expending a spell slot, regaining said use after a long rest.</p>
                <div class="reference">
                    <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_SCORCHING_RAY" />
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet alt="Greater Pact" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You know the scorching ray spell and can cast it once without expending a spell slot.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SCORCHING_RAY" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Greater Pact: Great Old One" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTSWORN_PATRON_GREAT_OLD_ONE_GREATER_PACT">
            <description>
                <p>You know the <em>detect thoughts</em> spell and can cast it once without expending a spell slot, regaining said use after a long rest.</p>
                <div class="reference">
                    <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_THOUGHTS" />
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet alt="Greater Pact" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You know the detect thoughts spell and can cast it once without expending a spell slot.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_THOUGHTS" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Greater Pact: Hexblade" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTSWORN_PATRON_HEXBLADE_GREATER_PACT">
            <description>
                <p>You know the <em>spiritual weapon</em> spell and can cast it once without expending a spell slot, regaining said use after a long rest.</p>
                <div class="reference">
                    <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPIRITUAL_WEAPON" />
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet alt="Greater Pact" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You know the spiritual weapon spell and can cast it once without expending a spell slot.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPIRITUAL_WEAPON" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Greater Pact: Undying" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTSWORN_PATRON_UNDYING_GREATER_PACT">
            <description>
                <p>You know the <em>gentle repose</em> spell and can cast it once without expending a spell slot, regaining said use after a long rest.</p>
                <div class="reference">
                    <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_GENTLE_REPOSE" />
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet alt="Greater Pact" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You know the gentle repose spell and can cast it once without expending a spell slot.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GENTLE_REPOSE" />
            </rules>
        </element>

    <!-- Profane Reaping Features -->
        <element name="Profane Reaping: Archfey" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTSWORN_PATRON_ARCHFEY_PROFANE_REAPING">
            <description>
                <p>When you score a critical hit with your pactblade, you can temporarily shift into the feywild and reappear elsewhere, distorted by fey magic. You can teleport up to 30 feet and become ethereal, causing attack rolls against you to have disadvantage until the start of your next turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet alt="Profane Reaping">
                <description>When you score a critical hit with your pactblade, you can temporarily shift into the feywild and reappear elsewhere, distorted by fey magic. You can teleport up to 30 feet and become ethereal, causing attack rolls against you to have disadvantage until the start of your next turn.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Profane Reaping: Celestial" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTSWORN_PATRON_CELESTIAL_PROFANE_REAPING">
            <description>
                <p>Once per turn, when you deal damage to a creature with a spell or your pactblade, you can cause residual radiant energy to mend the wounds of one ally creature within 15 feet of you that you can see, causing them to regain hit points equal to 1 + Your Charisma Modifier</p>
            </description>
            <sheet alt="Profane Reaping">
                <description>Once per turn, when you deal damage to a creature with a spell or your pactblade, you can cause residual radiant energy to mend the wounds of one ally creature within 15 feet of you that you can see, causing them to regain {{profane-reaping:healing}} hit points.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="profane-reaping:healing" value="1" />
                <stat name="profane-reaping:healing" value="charisma:modifier" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Profane Reaping: Fiend" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTSWORN_PATRON_FIEND_PROFANE_REAPING">
            <description>
                <p>When you take damage from a melee attack, your attacker is struck by a backlash of hellish energy, taking fire damage equal to your Charisma Modifier (minimum of 1).</p>
            </description>
            <sheet alt="Profane Reaping">
                <description>When you take damage from a melee attack, your attacker is struck by a backlash of hellish energy, taking {{profane-reaping:damage}} fire damage.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="profane-reaping:damage" value="1" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="profane-reaping:damage" value="charisma:modifier" bonus="base" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Profane Reaping: Great Old One" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTSWORN_PATRON_GREAT_OLD_ONE_PROFANE_REAPING">
            <description>
                <p>When you score a critical hit, you deal additional psychic damage equal to half your warlock level, and the creature must make an Intelligence Saving Throw or be frightened of you until the end of your next turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet alt="Profane Reaping">
                <description>When you score a critical hit, you deal additional {{level:warlock:half}} psychic damage, and the creature must make an Intelligence Saving Throw or be frightened of you until the end of your next turn.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Profane Reaping: Hexblade" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTSWORN_PATRON_HEXBLADE_PROFANE_REAPING">
            <description>
                <p>You can score a critical hit on a roll of 19-20 with your pactblade.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet alt="Profane Reaping">
                <description>You can score a critical hit on a roll of 19-20 with your pactblade.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Profane Reaping: Undying" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PACTSWORN_PATRON_UNDYING_PROFANE_REAPING">
            <description>
                <p>When you deal damage with your pactblade, you deal an additional amount of necrotic damage equal to your Charisma Modifier (minimum of 1). You gain Temporary Hit Points equal to the necrotic damage dealt.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet alt="Profane Reaping">
                <description>When you deal damage with your pactblade, you deal an additional {{profane-reaping:damage}} necrotic damage. You gain {{profane-reaping:damage}} temporary hit points.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="profane-reaping:damage" value="1" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="profane-reaping:damage" value="charisma:modifier" bonus="base" />
            </rules>
        </element>

</elements>