<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Beyond the Stars Magic Items</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="magic-items.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/beyond-the-stars/magic-items.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Eye of the Beholder" type="Magic Item" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_MAGIC_ITEM_EYE_OF_THE_BEHOLDER">
        <description>
            <p>A golden chain connected to a large petrified blood amber crystal, within the crystal is a large petrified eyestalk. Staring into the crystal, one might swear that the eye-stalk just blinked! A creature wearing the amulet has advantage on saving throws against spells and other magical effects. In addition, the crystal has 3 charges. A creature wearing the necklace can use an Action and make a DC:14 Arcana check to attempt to invoke the magic of the amulet. If the check is successful, choose one creature you can see within 120 feet of you, and roll on the Eye of the Beholder table as seen on the following page. On a failure, you become the target of the effect as the magic of the amulet backlashes upon you. The eye regains 1d3 expended charges at dawn.</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d10</td><td>Ray Beam</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td><strong>Charm Ray</strong> The targeted creature must succeed on a DC:14 Wisdom saving throw or be charmed by you for 1 hour, or until you harm the creature. If the amulet backlashed, you become charmed by the first creature you lay your eyes on for 1 hour or until it harms you.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td><strong>Paralyzing Ray</strong> The targeted creature must succeed on a DC:14 Constitution saving throw or be paralyzed for 1 minute. The target can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td><strong>Fear Ray</strong> The targeted creature must succeed on a DC:14 Wisdom saving throw or be frightened for 1 minute. The target can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success. If the amulet backlashed, you become the target of the effect instead, becoming frightened of the first hostile creature you see.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td><strong>Slowing Ray</strong> The targeted creature must succeed on a DC:14 Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, the target's speed is halved for 1 minute. In addition, the creature can't take reactions, and it can take either an action or a bonus action on its turn, not both. The creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td><strong>Enervation Ray</strong> The targeted creature must make a DC:14 Constitution saving throw, taking 30 (6d8) necrotic damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td><strong>Telekinetic Ray</strong> If the target is a creature, it must succeed on a DC:14 Strength saving throw or you move it up to 30 feet in any direction. It is restrained by the ray's telekinetic grip until the start of your next turn or until you are incapacitated. If the target is an object weighing 300 pounds or less that isn't being worn or carried, it is moved up to 30 feet in any direction. You can also exert fine control on objects with this ray, such as manipulating a simple tool or opening a door or a container. If the amulet backlashed, you are forcibly thrown by the amulets telekinetic power 30 feet in a direction of the DM's choice.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>7</td><td><strong>Sleep Ray</strong> The targeted creature must succeed on a DC:14 Wisdom saving throw or fall asleep and remain unconscious for 1 minute. The target awakens if it takes damage or another creature takes an action to wake it. This ray has no effect on constructs and undead.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>8</td><td><strong>Petrification Ray</strong> The targeted creature must make a DC:14 Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, the creature begins to turn to stone and is restrained. It must repeat the saving throw at the end of its next turn. On a success, the effect ends. On a failure, the creature is petrified until freed by the greater restoration spell or other magic.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>9</td><td><strong>Disintegration Ray</strong> If the target is a creature, it must succeed on a DC:14 Dexterity saving throw or take 36 (8d8) force damage. If this damage reduces the creature to 0 hit points, its body becomes a pile of fine gray dust. If the target is a Large or smaller nonmagical object or creation of magical force, it is disintegrated without a saving throw. If the target is a Huge or larger object or creation of magical force, this ray disintegrates a 10-foot cube of it.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>10</td><td><strong>Death Ray</strong> The targeted creature must succeed on a DC:14 Dexterity saving throw or take 55 (10d10) necrotic damage. The target dies if the ray reduces it to 0 hit points.</td></tr>
            </table>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Melech's Traveling Telescope" type="Magic Item" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_MAGIC_ITEM_MELECHS_TRAVELING_TELESCOPE">
        <description>
            <p>A small figurine depicting a miniature telescope, remarkably well detailed. As an action, you can speak its command word, causing it to expand and grow in size to a large life-sized telescope fit with a tripod pedestal, a mobile device for you to gaze at the stars. This large telescope can be returned back to its miniature form again by speaking its command word. This telescope is enhanced by magic and is incredibly potent and perceiving vast distances. In addition, you can utter the name of a known constellation or star and the telescope will magically fix itself to the position of where that star is in the sky. This effect might not always work, such as the case if its a star that is difficult to see, a star that moves constantly, or is a star that you do not know any information about. (DM's Discretion).</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Shard of Sight" type="Magic Item" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_MAGIC_ITEM_SHARD_OF_SIGHT">
        <description>
            <p>A small shard of stained glass that seems to shimmer the colors of the rainbow when it catches light. As an action, you can peer through the glass shard, the glass shard enables you to see magical auras or see through illusions or other magical enchantments. Peering through the shard in this manner, you can see magic in this way, able to visibly see the faintest aura of magic around any visible creature or object and discerning its school of magic via color, if any. The shard is even able to discern if a creature or object is under a curse or a magical enchantment (such as if it is under the effect of Mage Armor or affected by a Glyph of Warding). Lastly, peering through the shard in this way, you have truesight, effectively able to see invisible creatures and objects, perceiving the true form of a shapechanger or a creature that is transformed by magic, or even see into the ethereal plane.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="The Eye" type="Magic Item" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_MAGIC_ITEM_THE_EYE">
        <description>
            <p>A blackish-red crystal orb roughly 6 inches in diameter, a quick glance one would see past the red mist inside and see the night sky. Peering deeper into it causes one to see vast stars and constellations, galaxies and distant planets of the outer cosmos, they feel their gaze cast out beyond the stars and being pulled towards somewhere, towards something.</p>
            <p class="indent">A creature peering into the orb must make an Intelligence Saving Throw (DC:15), They see a vast cinder-red planet-shaped star with waves of energy rippling out from it like arms, though it has no eyes, the creature feels the star acknowledge it as its tendrils stretch toward them. If they fail their saving throw, The creature is struck insane and gains one long-term madness effect as per the Long-Term madness table of the DMG.259, this insanity lasts until their next long rest. While insane, you can't take actions, can't understand what other creatures say, can't read, and speak only in gibberish. A greater restoration spell cast on you ends this effect. If they succeed, they can ask the entity questions, as per the Contact Other Plane spell.</p>
            <p class="indent">A creature that attempts to use the orb for the first time is immediately cursed by its magic, struck with a permanent madness that cannot be cured save for a 9th-level wish spell or magic of comparable power. This madness effect is: " This orb is mine! it speaks to me, it shows me the answers of the cosmos, i see the looks others give me, they want it, i won't let them have it! I feel an intense hunger that is only temporarily satiated by killing." The entity is "Hadar, the Dark Hunger", and wishes to be freed from its prison, to devour all life to ignite its dying spark.</p>
            <p class="indent">The orb radiates an alien energy, that seems to affect the bodies of the once living. Any corpse or creature that died within 30 feet of the orb will raise 1d4 minutes later as a zombie or skeleton depending on its decomposition state. This creature remains permanently animate even after they leave this radius, and are hostile to all creatures, excluding the holder of the orb, which they see as friendly unless attacked.</p>
            <p class="indent">A creature that is killed within the presence of this orb secretly has its spark consumed by the orb, once the orb has consumed a number of creatures whose total hit dice equal 500, Hadar is able to be released from its prison and emerges in the atmosphere over the world, ready to devour all life in the cosmos and usher in the end of days. A creature who has its spark consumed in this manner cannot be resurrected by anything save for a Wish spell or a spell of comparable power. lastly, a creature that successfully communicates for the first time with the entity connected to this orb is permanently marked in some way. They gain the ability to cast the "Arms of Hadar" spell once per short or long rest, using Charisma as their spellcasting ability for this, and perhaps might be given more gifts in the future. (DM's discretion to use as narrative explanation for warlock levels).</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
            <set name="cursed">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
</elements>