<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Way of the Dancing Star Monastic Tradition</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="monk-way-of-the-dancing-star.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/beyond-the-stars/monk-way-of-the-dancing-star.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Way of the Dancing Star" type="Archetype" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_MONK_WAY_OF_THE_DANCING_STAR">
        <supports>Monastic Tradition</supports>
        <description>
            <p>This monk order follows an ancient tradition, one that reveres the reverie of the night sky and all its beauty and splendor. They hone their martial prowess after a particular star, one that is known as the elusive "Dancing Star" which is constantly moving night to night and never in the same place in the sky. Monks of this order seek to transcend their physical limitations and reach enlightenment, they emulate this star by forming their techniques around swiftly maneuvering through battle unhindered, shining like a star when they must, but quickly flickering away to be unseen in the next fleeting moment. Many monks of this order are regal dancers and entertainers, regaling others with flashy moves and entrancing displays of magical light to catch peoples attention, only to disappear the next moment and leave them perplexed.</p>
            <div element="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DANCING_STAR_INNER_LIGHT" />
            <div element="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DANCING_STAR_THE_DANCING_STAR" />
            <div element="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DANCING_STAR_FLICKER_AND_DISAPPEAR" />
            <div element="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DANCING_STAR_SHOOTING_STAR" />
            <div element="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DANCING_STAR_ASCENSION" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DANCING_STAR_INNER_LIGHT" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DANCING_STAR_THE_DANCING_STAR" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DANCING_STAR_FLICKER_AND_DISAPPEAR" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DANCING_STAR_SHOOTING_STAR" level="11" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DANCING_STAR_ASCENSION" level="17" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Inner Light" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DANCING_STAR_INNER_LIGHT">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 3rd level, you know the <em>dancing lights</em> cantrip, Wisdom is your spellcasting modifier for this ability.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You know the dancing lights cantrip, Wisdom is your spellcasting modifier for this ability.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DANCING_LIGHTS" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="The Dancing Star" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DANCING_STAR_THE_DANCING_STAR">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 3rd level when you choose this monastic tradition, you can begin the Dance of the Dancing Star, this dance lasts for 1 minute, until you are knocked unconscious or knocked prone, or until you end it willingly (no action required). While in this stance, you gain the following benefits:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Your movement speed increases by 5 feet.</li>
                    <li>Your body is charged with traces of illuminating star energy as you build traction with your movement. Whenever you move 5 or more feet in a turn, you build up radiant energy, causing any damage you deal with your unarmed strikes or monk weapons to deal an additional 1d6 Radiant Damage.</li>
                    <li>When you deal radiant damage to a creature, the flash of starlight temporarily dazes it, causing it to hesitate in its retaliation. You do not provoke opportunity attacks from that creature for the rest of the turn, whether you hit or not.</li>
                    <li>You can use your "Step of the Wind" feature without expending a ki point.</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">You can enter this dance a number of times equal to 1 + Your Wisdom Modifier, regaining expended uses of this feature after a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can begin the Dance of the Dancing Star, this dance lasts for 1 minute, until you are knocked unconscious or knocked prone, or until you end it willingly (no action required). While in this stance, you gain the several benefits (see full description).</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Flicker and Disappear" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DANCING_STAR_FLICKER_AND_DISAPPEAR">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 6th level, the elusive nature of the star is difficult to capture and follow with the naked eye, yet you have learned how to capture the essence of this ability and perform it yourself when in danger. While you are performing the dance of the Dancing Star, you can spend 1 Ki Point and use your reaction when a creature makes an attack roll against you to disappear in a flash of starlight, teleporting up to 10 feet away and becoming invisible until the end of your next turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>While you are performing the dance of the Dancing Star, you can spend 1 Ki Point and use your reaction when a creature makes an attack roll against you to disappear in a flash of starlight, teleporting up to 10 feet away and becoming invisible until the end of your next turn.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Shooting Star" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DANCING_STAR_SHOOTING_STAR">
            <description>
                <p>Upon reaching 11th level, your inner light has begun to swell within you, ascending beyond your physical limitations to lift you up to the night sky. You gain a fly speed of 30 feet. If you are engaged in the dance of the Dancing Star, this fly speed is increased to 60 feet instead, and you can choose to radiates bright light in a 5- to 20-foot radius and dim light for an additional number of feet equal to the chosen radius. The monk can alter the radius as a Bonus Action.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>If you are engaged in the dance of the Dancing Star, your fly speed is increased to 60 feet instead, and you can choose to radiates bright light in a 5- to 20-foot radius and dim light for an additional number of feet equal to the chosen radius. You can alter the radius as a Bonus Action.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="speed:fly" value="30" bonus="base" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Ascension" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DANCING_STAR_ASCENSION">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 17th level, you have reached the pinnacle of your teachings, and reached enlightenment, and learn how to ascend beyond your mortal shell. You can spend 5 Ki Points to cast the <em>etherealness</em> spell on yourself. In addition, if you spend 10 minutes meditating in quiet contemplation, you can cast the <em>astral projection</em> spell without the requirement of material components, however you can only target yourself and cannot bring other creatures with you. Once you use the latter portion of this feature, you cannot do so again until after a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can spend 5 Ki Points to cast the etherealness spell on yourself. In addition, if you spend 10 minutes meditating in quiet contemplation, you can cast the astral projection spell without the requirement of material components, however you can only target yourself and cannot bring other creatures with you. Once you use the latter portion of this feature, you cannot do so again until after a long rest.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ETHEREALNESS" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ASTRAL_PROJECTION" />
            </rules>
        </element>
    
</elements>