<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Beyond the Stars Spells</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="spells.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/beyond-the-stars/spells.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Dread" type="Spell" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_SPELL_DREAD">
        <supports>Cleric, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You attempt to instill dread in the heart and mind of one creature you can see within range. A construct or an undead is immune to this effect. The target must succeed on a Wisdom Saving Throw or take 1d6 psychic damage and become frightened of you until the end of its next turn. </p>
            <p class="indent">The spell's damage increases by 1d6 when you reach 5th level (2d6), 11th level (3d6), and 17th level (4d6).</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">0</set>
            <set name="school">Necromancy</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Pain" type="Spell" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_SPELL_PAIN">
        <supports>Cleric, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>you utter a single word that tears at the back of your foes' mind, wracking them with terrible pain. Choose one creature that you can see within range. That creature must make a Constitution Saving Throw, on a failure it takes 1d12 psychic damage.</p>
            <p class="indent">The spell's damage increases by 1d10 when you reach 5th level (2d10), 11th level (3d10), and 17th level (4d10).</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">0</set>
            <set name="school">Necromancy</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">30 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Astral Seal" type="Spell" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_SPELL_ASTRAL_SEAL">
        <supports>Cleric, Druid, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>A flash of silver starlight streaks toward a creature of your choice you can see within range. Make a ranged spell attack against the target. On a hit, the target suffers 1d6 radiant damage, and you outline your enemy with the silver glow of the starry night sky, exuding an energizing light that guides an ally's strike. The next attack roll an ally makes against the target before the end of your next turn, gains a bonus to the attack roll equal to half your spellcasting ability modifier, rounded down to a minimum of 1. </p>
            <p class="indent">The spell's damage increases by 1d6 when you reach 5th level (2d6), 11th level (3d6), and 17th level (4d6).</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">0</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">30 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Fleshcurdle" type="Spell" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_SPELL_FLESHCURDLE">
        <supports>Cleric, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Choose one creature within 30 feet that you can see. That creature must make a Constitution Saving Throw, on a failure, it takes 1d6 necrotic damage and has its flesh twisted and warped, discoloring it and causing it to become misshapen and impairing its function. The creature has its movement speed halved and has disadvantage on attack rolls until the end of it's next turn. This spell has no effect on incorporeal creatures, oozes, constructs, or any undead creature that lacks flesh or aren't organic in some form.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">30 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Disperse" type="Spell" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_SPELL_DISPERSE">
        <supports>Druid, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Until the start of your next turn, your body disperses into hundreds of small motes of stars and scatter, only to reappear later in full form. When you are struck by an attack roll or targeted by a spell or effect that causes you to make a saving throw, you can disperse into stars and vanish from sight, causing you to vanish from your current plane of existence. At the start of your next turn, and when the spell ends, you return to an unoccupied space of your choice that you can see within 30 feet of the space you vanished from. If no unoccupied space is available within that range, you appear in the nearest unoccupied space (chosen at random if more than one space is equally near).</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 Reaction</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">1 Round</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Twisted Innards" type="Spell" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_SPELL_TWISTED_INNARDS">
        <supports>Druid, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>For the duration of the spell, your vital organs writhe, shift, and move about. Making it difficult to strike you in a vulnerable area. Even your bones shift their density to lessen the damage of a blow. While this spell is in effect, when you take bludgeoning, piercing, or slashing damage from non-magical weapons, you reduce said damage by 3, In addition, if you are the target of a critical hit, that creature must roll percentile dice. there is a 50% chance that the critical hit becomes a normal hit instead.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 Action</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, Up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Withering Touch" type="Spell" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_SPELL_WHITHERING_TOUCH">
        <supports>Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You wreathe your hand in the consuming energy of the negative plane, the simplest touch sapping the strength of your foe. One creature you touch must make a Constitution saving throw, If the saving throw fails, the creature takes 5d10 necrotic damage and its Strength Score is reduced by 1d6+1 as its muscles wither substantially. On a successful save, it takes half damage with no other effects. A creatures strength score cannot be reduced below 1 with this spell. If a creature is reduced to 0 hit points with this spell, they are turned into a withering husk of bones and sinew and collapse. </p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels:</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a slot spell of 6th level or higher, the spell does an additional 1d10 necrotic damage for each spell slot beyond 5th.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">5</set>
            <set name="school">Necromancy</set>
            <set name="time">1 Action</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">flesh from a corpse</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Wall of Flesh" type="Spell" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_SPELL_WALL_OF_FLESH">
        <supports>Warlock, Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>A disgusting wall made of churning flesh springs into existence at a point you choose within range. The wall is 6 inches thick and is composed of ten 10-foot-by-10-foot panels. Each panel must be contiguous with at least one other panel. If the wall cuts through a creature's space when it appears, the creature is pushed to one side of the wall (your choice). If a creature would be surrounded on all sides by the wall (or the wall and another solid surface), that creature can make a Dexterity saving throw. On a success, it can use its reaction to move up to its speed so that it is no longer enclosed by the wall. This wall can be used to seal off a passage or close a breach, for the wall inserts itself into any surrounding nonliving material if its area is sufficient to do so. Eyeballs, ears, noses and mouths spring to the surface of the wall. Arms and legs may sprout as well. The five senses of the wall – except for touch (and pain) – are immediately transmitted to the caster. Each 10-foot section of the wall has 25 HP per inch of thickness and AC 12 (normally 150 HP). A section of wall brought to 0 hit points is breached. </p>
            <p class="indent">Any creature which makes physical interaction with the wall (including melee weapons and touch magic) takes 1d6 points of necrotic damage from the corrosive nature of the rotting flesh and the haunting moans. Only the surrounding material that the wall initially is conjured to touch, such as the floor or an adjoining wall, is immune to this damage. </p>
            <p class="indent">Furthermore, organic material (such as creatures) that directly touch the wall must succeed at a Constitution saving throw or be paralyzed for 1 minute.. The wall then consumes the creature in 3 rounds, digesting it and adding the creature’s hit point total to its own. The paralyzed creature can repeat the Constitution saving throw at the end of each of their turns to escape this.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">6</set>
            <set name="school">Conjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 Action</set>
            <set name="range">90 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 hour</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a lead weight</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
</elements>