<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Patron from Beyond the Stars Otherworldly Patron</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="warlock-patron-from-beyond-the-stars.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/beyond-the-stars/warlock-patron-from-beyond-the-stars.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Patron from Beyond the Stars" type="Archetype" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_WARLOCK_PATRON_FROM_BEYOND_THE_STARS">
        <supports>Otherworldly Patron</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The study of divination and fortune-telling is as old as time itself. There are augurs who watch the flight paths of birds; there are oracles who burn offal and throw bones. Others devote their entire lives to the steady examination of fate and the future, space and time, and other metaphysical inquiries. However, there are those who do not waste their time and forge a pact with the stars themselves. These warlocks - whether brave or foolish - tread a razor-thin line between limitless truths and blinding madness. It is not understood why the stars grant some astrologers a fraction of their powers and curse others with madness. Few have posed this question, and fewer still have sought to answer it and possibly draw the stars’ ire. Some of the dying stars might bestow their gifts so that they may continue to live on in records; the brighter, malicious stars may do it remind the mortal races of their near-limitless powers. Warlocks whose patron gleams in the midnight sky may draw their power from just one star, or they may draw from a host of stars. While there exist countless stars in the realm above, some of the names of stars have been recorded in an ancient text known as the Revelations of Melech. They are as follows: Acamar, the Great Devourer; Caiphon, the Dream Whisperer; Delban, the Boreal Watcher; Gibbeth, the Formless Terror; Hadar, the Dying Ember; Ihbar, the Silent Void; Khirad, the Radiant King; Nihal, the Serpent Star; lban, the Wicked Lord; Zhudun, the Fallen One; and Allabar, the Opener of the Way.</p>
            <p class="indent"></p>
            <div element="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATRON_BEYOND_THE_STARS_EXPANDED_SPELL_LIST" />
            <div element="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATRON_BEYOND_THE_STARS_BONUS_CANTRIPS" />
            <div element="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATRON_BEYOND_THE_STARS_MAW_OF_ACAMAR" />
            <div element="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATRON_BEYOND_THE_STARS_GUIDANCE_OF_CAIPHON" />
            <div element="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATRON_BEYOND_THE_STARS_WATCER_OF_THE_STARS" />
            <div element="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATRON_BEYOND_THE_STARS_THE_REVELATIONS_OF_MELECH" />
            <div element="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATRON_BEYOND_THE_STARS_REVALATIONS_OF_MELECH_CHART" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATRON_BEYOND_THE_STARS_EXPANDED_SPELL_LIST" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATRON_BEYOND_THE_STARS_BONUS_CANTRIPS" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATRON_BEYOND_THE_STARS_MAW_OF_ACAMAR" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATRON_BEYOND_THE_STARS_GUIDANCE_OF_CAIPHON" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATRON_BEYOND_THE_STARS_WATCER_OF_THE_STARS" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATRON_BEYOND_THE_STARS_THE_REVELATIONS_OF_MELECH" level="14" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATRON_BEYOND_THE_STARS_REVALATIONS_OF_MELECH_CHART" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Expanded Spell List" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATRON_BEYOND_THE_STARS_EXPANDED_SPELL_LIST">
            <description>
                <p>The Patron of Stars lets you choose from an expanded list of spells when you learn a warlock spell, the following spells are added to the warlock list for you.</p>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Spell Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1st</td><td><i>faerie fire, sleep</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>2nd</td><td><i>augury, moonbeam</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td><i>clairvoyance, Melf’s minute meteors</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>4th</td><td><i>divination, Evard’s black tentacles</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><i>dominate person, planar binding</i></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <spellcasting name="Warlock" extend="true">
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_FAERIE_FIRE</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_SLEEP</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_AUGURY</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_MOONBEAM</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_CLAIRVOYANCE</extend>
                <extend>ID_XGTE_SPELL_MELFS_MINUTE_METEORS</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_DIVINATION</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_EVARDS_BLACK_TENTACLES</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_DOMINATE_PERSON</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_PLANAR_BINDING</extend>
            </spellcasting>
        </element>
        <element name="Bonus Cantrips" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATRON_BEYOND_THE_STARS_BONUS_CANTRIPS">
            <description>
                <p>At 1st level, you learn the <em>guidance</em> and <em>dancing lights</em> cantrips. They count as warlock cantrips for you, and they don’t count against your number of cantrips known.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GUIDANCE" spellcasting="Warlock" known="true" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DANCING_LIGHTS" spellcasting="Warlock" known="true" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Maw of Acamar" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATRON_BEYOND_THE_STARS_MAW_OF_ACAMAR">
            <description>
                <p>Stars, as ancient and long-lived as they may be, eventually succumb to death’s cold and inevitable grasp. The revelation of entropy has been granted to you in your study of the stars, revealing hidden lore in the transition of expiration. Starting at 1st level when you reduce a creature to 0 hit points, you can use your Bonus Action to grant yourself Advantage on the next attack roll, ability check, or saving throw you make. If this boon has not been used before your next short or long rest, you lose the boon. You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Charisma Modifier (minimum of 1), regaining expended uses of it on a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="{{maw-of-acamar:uses}}/Short Rest">
                <description>When you reduce a creature to 0 hit points, you can grant yourself advantage on the next attack roll, ability check, or saving throw you make. If this boon has not been used before your next short or long rest, you lose the boon.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="maw-of-acamar:uses" value="1" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="maw-of-acamar:uses" value="charisma:modifier" bonus="base" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Guidance of Caiphon" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATRON_BEYOND_THE_STARS_GUIDANCE_OF_CAIPHON">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 6th level, you beseech the stellar guide above to intervene on your behalf. When a hostile creature that you can see rolls a natural 20 on an attack roll, ability check, or saving throw, as a reaction you can force them to reroll again with disadvantage. Afterwhich, The next attack roll, ability check, or saving throw that you make is made with advantage. Alternatively, when a friendly creature that you can see rolls a natural 1 on an attack roll, ability check, or saving throw, as a reaction you can let them reroll with advantage. The next attack roll, ability check, or saving throw you make is made with disadvantage. You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Charisma Modifier (minimum of 1), regaining expended uses of it on a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Reaction" usage="{{maw-of-acamar:uses}}/Short Rest">
                <description>When a hostile creature that you can see rolls a natural 20 or a friendly creature rolls a natural 1 on an attack roll, ability check, or saving throw, you can force them to reroll again with disadvantage. Afterwhich, The next attack roll, ability check, or saving throw that you make is made with advantage.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Watcher of the Stars" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATRON_BEYOND_THE_STARS_WATCER_OF_THE_STARS">
            <description>
                <p>At 10th level, your mind has been scarred by the unblinking eyes of the great star; Allabar. You instinctively know which way is north, and can never get lost while you are outside or at least in site of the constellations and the starry night sky, even by magical means. Additionally, when you can see the stars - such as when you are outside after the sun has set - you always know the fastest direction or path will take you to your current goal or intended destination and you have a clear, mental image of the surroundings of the area you see, and can perfectly recall any path you have traveled.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You instinctively know which way is north, and can never get lost while you are outside or at least in site of the starry night sky, even by magical means. Additionally, you always know the fastest direction or path will take you to your current goal or intended destination and you have a clear, mental image of the surroundings of the area you see, and can perfectly recall any path you have traveled.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="The Revelations of Melech" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATRON_BEYOND_THE_STARS_THE_REVELATIONS_OF_MELECH">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 14th level, you unravel the complex and mysterious Revelations of Melech, a great - yet increddibly mad - scholar and prophet of the stars. You dream each night of the stars who have aligned themselves in the sky to bathe the world in their light. You have a number of Star Petitions equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum 1), and you regain all spent Petitions when you finish a long rest. As an Action, you may expend one or more Petitions. The number of Petitions expended determines the number of times you roll a d12 on the Revelations of Melech table. The result determines which of the petitions’ boons will be granted to you. The Stars then hear your plea and grant you their Boon. Activating a boon requires no action, however it must be done on your turn. Upon activating it, you are immediately granted the benefit from it. If a boon has not been activated within 8 hours after you obtain it, it expires and you lose the Boon. If you expend a petition and roll on a boon you already have, you may reroll for a different result.</p>
                <h5 class="caption">Revelations of Melech</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>d12</td><td>Star</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1</td><td>Entropy</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>2</td><td>Acamar, the Great Devourer</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3</td><td>Caiphon, the Dream Whisperer</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>4</td><td>Delban, the Boreal Watcher</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5</td><td>Gibbeth, the Formless Terror</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>6</td><td>Hadar, the Dying Ember</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>7</td><td>Ihbar, the Silent Void</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>8</td><td>Khirad, the Radiant King</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9</td><td>Nihal, the Serpent Star</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>10</td><td>Ulban, the Wicked Lord</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>11</td><td>Zhudun, the Fallen One</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>12</td><td>Allabar, the Opener of the Way</td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="{{maw-of-acamar:uses}} Star Petitions/Long Rest" action="Action">
                <description>You may expend one or more Star Petitions, rolling a d12 for each and consulting the Revelations of Melech chart for the boon(s) granted. Activating a boon requires no action and disappears if not used in 8 hours.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Revelations of Melech Chart" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATRON_BEYOND_THE_STARS_REVALATIONS_OF_MELECH_CHART">
            <description>
                <ul>
                    <li><strong></strong>Entropy: Your mind is overcome by chilling darkness and maddening images of the starry void, as they voice their displeasure with you, causing you to lose the petition and gain no boon, and you take Psychic Damage equal to your Charisma Modifier (minimum of 1). If you get this result more than once per long rest, you may ignore it and roll again.</li>
                    <li><strong></strong>Acamar: You may reroll a Failed Death Saving Throw, but must take the second roll regardless of the result.</li>
                    <li><strong></strong>Caiphon: You gain advantage on Saving Throws against being Charmed or Frightened, and gain advantage on Charisma-Ability Checks for 1 hour.</li>
                    <li><strong></strong>Delban: You gain Resistance to Cold Damage for 1 hour.</li>
                    <li><strong></strong>Gibbeth: You ward your mind so that it cannot be read nor detected by magic, nor can you be located upon by divination or scrying magic, In addition, you gain resistance to psychic damage for 1 hour.</li>
                    <li><strong></strong>Hadar: You gain Resistance to Fire Damage for 1 hour.</li>
                    <li><strong></strong>Ihbar: For the next minute, any spell you cast, ignores the requirement of Verbal or Somatic Components, as well as any Material Components so long as it does not have a Gold Cost. In addition, you regain an Expended Warlock Spell Slot. You can only benefit from the latter portion of this boon once per long rest.</li>
                    <li><strong></strong>Khirad: You gain the ability to read, write, and speak any language, and gain advantage on all intelligence ability checks. In addition, you gain the ability to cast "Detect Thoughts" at-will, and have Telepathy out to 60 feet. This boon lasts for 1 hour.</li>
                    <li><strong></strong>Nihal: Your Movement speed increases by an additional 15 feet and you ignore difficult terrain, this boon lasts for 1 hour.</li>
                    <li><strong></strong>Ulban As an action, you can turn invisible for up to 1 hour. If you attack, deal damage, or force a creature to make a saving throw, you become visible at the end of the current turn, though you can return to invisibility As an action on your turn. This boon lasts for 1 hour.</li>
                    <li><strong></strong>Zhudun: Within the next minute upon activating this Boon, The next Damage roll you make as part of a Spell or Cantrip deals maximum damage, instead of rolling.</li>
                    <li><strong></strong>Allabar: Your mind is temporarily granted insight into the cosmos and its revelation fills you with untold power. You may choose any Boon of your choice from the list. In addition, you regain an Expended Warlock Spell Slot. You can only benefit from this boon once per long rest, if you get this result again ignore it and roll again. feature, you cannot do so again until after a short or long rest.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
    
</elements>