<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>School of Astronomy Arcane Tradition</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="wizard-school-of-astronomy.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/beyond-the-stars/wizard-school-of-astronomy.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="School of Astronomy" type="Archetype" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_WIZARD_SCHOOL_OF_ASTRONOMY">
        <supports>Arcane Tradition</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Your long delving into the constellations, of the stars themselves, have granted you arcane secrets to shape your spells.</p>
            <div element="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SCHOOL_OF_ASTRONOMY_CELESTIAL_ALIGNMENT" />
            <div element="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SCHOOL_OF_ASTRONOMY_ASTRONOMERS_INSIGHT" />
            <div element="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SCHOOL_OF_ASTRONOMY_STAR_CONFLUX" />
            <div element="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SCHOOL_OF_ASTRONOMY_DUALITY_OF_THE_STARS" />
            <div element="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SCHOOL_OF_ASTRONOMY_CELESTIAL_ENLIGHTENMENT" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SCHOOL_OF_ASTRONOMY_CELESTIAL_ALIGNMENT" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SCHOOL_OF_ASTRONOMY_ASTRONOMERS_INSIGHT" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SCHOOL_OF_ASTRONOMY_STAR_CONFLUX" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SCHOOL_OF_ASTRONOMY_DUALITY_OF_THE_STARS" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SCHOOL_OF_ASTRONOMY_CELESTIAL_ENLIGHTENMENT" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Celestial Alignment" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SCHOOL_OF_ASTRONOMY_CELESTIAL_ALIGNMENT">
            <description>
                <p>At 2nd level when you choose this tradition, you have long studied the stars and the celestial bodies of the various constellations, and your research has granted a great revelation into the arcane arts. You have learned how to channnel magic from these constellations to influence your arcane power. You can attune yourself to one of these constellations during a short rest, gaining a minor boon during the day when the constellation is barely visible and at its weakest, but evolves into a mighty boon at night when it is most visible and at its strongest. When at night, you gain the benefits of both the day and night effect, whereas in the morning you only gain the benefits of the day effect. Certain constellations provide access to spells depending on your alignment, these spells count as wizard spells for you even if they aren’t, but you only have access to them while aligned with that respective constellation. You can change alignments during another short rest, or cease channeling your current celeestial alignment entirely and sever the connection (no action required). See the Celestial Constellations Chart later for details.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can attune yourself to a constellation during a short rest, gaining a minor boon during the day when the constellation is barely visible and at its weakest, but evolves into a mighty boon at night when it is most visible and at its strongest. Consult the Celestial Constellations Chart in <em>Beyond the Stars</em> for the different boons. You can maintain connection and benefit from one celestial alignment.</description>
                <description level="10">You can attune yourself to a constellation during a short rest, gaining a minor boon during the day when the constellation is barely visible and at its weakest, but evolves into a mighty boon at night when it is most visible and at its strongest. Consult the Celestial Constellations Chart in <em>Beyond the Stars</em> for the different boons. You can maintain connection and benefit from two celestial alignments.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Astronomer’s Insight" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SCHOOL_OF_ASTRONOMY_ASTRONOMERS_INSIGHT">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 2nd level when you choose this tradition, your knowledge of the night sky has granted you the following:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>You always know which way is north so long as you are outside or can visibly see the stars or the night sky.</li>
                    <li>You have advantage on ability checks pertaining to space, stars and constellations or the field of astronomy.</li>
                    <li>You know the <em>dancing lights</em> cantrip, and it does not count against the number of cantrips you can have known.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You always know which way is north so long as you are outside or can visibly see the stars or the night sky. You have advantage on ability checks pertaining to space, stars and constellations or the field of astronomy.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DANCING_LIGHTS" spellcasting="Wizard" known="true" level="2" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Star Conflux" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SCHOOL_OF_ASTRONOMY_STAR_CONFLUX">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 6th level level, when you cast a spell gained by your Celestial Alignment feature and that spell targets a single creature, you can target an additional creature but it must also be within range of the spell.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you cast a spell gained by your Celestial Alignment feature and that spell targets a single creature, you can target an additional creature but it must also be within range of the spell.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Duality of the Stars" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SCHOOL_OF_ASTRONOMY_DUALITY_OF_THE_STARS">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 10th level, you can maintain connection and benefit from two celestial alignments, instead of one.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Celestial Enlightenment" type="Archetype Feature" source="Beyond the Stars" id="ID_DMMALUS_BTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SCHOOL_OF_ASTRONOMY_CELESTIAL_ENLIGHTENMENT">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 14th level, you have reached the pinnacle of your studies and discovered an enlightened revelationn, one that invokes a grand discovery in your arcane studies. You can choose one Celestial Constellation and gain that constellation’s effects permanently, and it does not count against the number of celestial alingmennts you can maintain connection to. You can change this choice during a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can choose one Celestial Constellation and gain that constellation’s effects permanently, and it does not count against the number of celestial alingmennts you can maintain connection to. You can change this choice during a long rest.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
    
</elements>