<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Mashiro’s Manual of Monstrous Magic Magic Items</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="magic-items.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/mashiros-manual-of-monstrous-magic/magic-items.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Coven Eye" type="Magic Item" source="Mashiro’s Manual of Monstrous Magic" id="ID_AEYANA_MMOMM_MAGIC_ITEM_COVEN_EYE">
        <description>
            <p>Up to three different creatures can attune to this item at the same time. Each creature must have at least one spell slot of 1st level or higher.</p>
            <p class="indent">Each creature attuned to the eye can take an action to see what the eye sees if it is on the same plane of existence as the eye until the start of its next turn. While a creature is looking through the eye, it is blind with regard to its own senses.</p>
            <p class="indent">The eye has AC 10, 1 hit point, and darkvision with a radius of 60 feet. If it is destroyed, each attuned creature takes 3d10 psychic damage and is blinded for 24 hours.</p>
            <p class="indent">The eye has 7 charges. While all three creatures attuned to the eye are within 30 feet of each other, and the eye is on the same plane of existence as all three creatures, an attuned creature can expend 1 or more of the eye’s charges to cast one of the following spells from it, using the creature’s spell save DC and spell attack bonus: identify (1 charge), ray of sickness (1 charge), hold person (2 charges), locate object (2 charges), bestow curse (3 charges), counterspell (3 charges), lightning bolt (3 charges), phantasmal killer (4 charges), polymorph (4 charges), contact other plane (5 charges), scrying (5 charges), eyebite (6 charges). The creature can increase the level of one of these spells by one for each additional charge expended. The creature must cast the spells as though it were in the eye’s space, using the eye’s senses, and can only target things that are visible to the eye.</p>
            <p class="indent">The eye regains 1d6+1 expended charges daily at midnight. If you expend the last charge, roll a d20. On a 1, the eye bursts and is destroyed. A creature attuned to the eye can expend a spell slot as bonus action on its turn. The eye regains a number of expended charges equal to the level of the spell slot expended.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
            <set name="attunement" addition="by three spellcasters">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Darkmantle Hide" type="Magic Item" source="Mashiro’s Manual of Monstrous Magic" id="ID_AEYANA_MMOMM_MAGIC_ITEM_DARKMANTLE_HIDE">
        <description>
            <p>This waist-length hooded cloak is made from the hide of a darkmantle, and provides its wearer a perfect camouflage against stone. While wearing the cloak with its hood up, you have advantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks made to hide amid natural stone surfaces.</p>
            <p class="indent">As an action, you can make the cloak produce a 15-foot-radius sphere of magical darkness, which moves with you and spreads around corners. This darkness lasts for 10 minutes. A creature with darkvision cannot see through this darkness, and nonmagical light cannot illuminate it. If any of the effects area overlaps with an area of light created by an area of 2nd level or lower, the spell that created that area is dispelled. Once you use this ability, you can’t use it again until the next dawn.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Manual of Monstrous Magic" type="Magic Item" source="Mashiro’s Manual of Monstrous Magic" id="ID_AEYANA_MMOMM_MAGIC_ITEM_MANUAL_OF_MONSTROUS_MAGIC">
        <description>
            <p>This tome contains information and incantations relating to magic of many creatures. While attuned to the tome, you can perform a 1 hour ritual to form a contract with another creature. Choose a willing creature within 30 feet of you. The creature must remain within 30 feet of you and must not be under any magical effects during the duration of this ritual. At the end of the ritual, both you and the creature must sign your names in the tome.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you complete this contract, the creature grants you certain spells or magic items relating to its own abilities, as determined by the DM. A contract can grant you a number of spells up to the creature’s proficiency bonus, and one magic item. For example, a mimic could grant you the chameleon and alter self (adhesive only) spells, and allow you to summon a bag of devouring or a mimic hide armor. A shield guardian could grant you the regenerate, shield, and warding bond spells, and allow you to summon an amulet of the shield guardian (uncommon).</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Spells.</em></strong> You can cast spells granted by a contract by expending your own spell slots, using your spell save DC and spell attack bonus.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Magic Items.</em></strong> You can use a bonus action to expend a spell slot to summon an item granted by a contract. The level of the spell slot required depends on the rarity of the item: a 2nd-level slot for an uncommon item, a 4th-level slot for a rare item, a 6th-level slot for a very rare item, and a 8th-level slot for a legendary item. You can choose for the item to appear donned or in your empty hand. If the item requires attunement, it counts as attuned, sharing an attunement slot with this tome. The item lasts for 1 hour, or until you dismiss it as a bonus action.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Summons.</em></strong> You can use an action to expend a spell slot to summon a creature bound by a contract. The level of the spell slot requires is equal 2 + the CR of the creature (creatures of CR 1/2 or lower require a 2nd-level spell slot). The creature appears in an unoccupied space within 30 feet of you, and disappears if it is reduced to less than half of its maximum hit points, or after 1 hour. If the summoned creature can cast spells, you must provide the spell slots for those spells.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can form a number of contracts up to your proficiency bonus. If you attempt to form a contract beyond this, you must choose one of your existing contracts to end. All contracts also end if you become unattuned to the tome.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
            <set name="attunement" addition="by a spellcaster">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Mimic Hide Armor" type="Magic Item" source="Mashiro’s Manual of Monstrous Magic" id="ID_AEYANA_MMOMM_MAGIC_ITEM_MIMIC_HIDE_ARMOR">
        <description>
            <p>This armor is crafted from the corpse of a freshly slain mimic, and allows its wearer to transform into objects like a mimic. While wearing this armor, you gain a +1 bonus to AC. You can also use a bonus action to transform into a Small or Medium sized object. Your gear melds into the new form, and you can’t activate, use, wield, or otherwise benefit from any of your equipment while transformed.</p>
            <p class="indent">While transformed this way, your speed is reduced to 10 feet, and you can use your action to make one unarmed strike, which deals bludgeoning damage equal to 1d8 + your Strength modifier. Otherwise, the only actions you can take are the Dash, Dodge, Disengage, or Hide actions.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can end the transformation as an action. The transformation also ends if you take damage or are knocked unconscious.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="slot">body</set>
			<set name="type" addition="leather or hide">Armor</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="armor">ID_WOTC_ARMOR_LIGHT_LEATHER|ID_WOTC_ARMOR_MEDIUM_HIDE_ARMOR</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Pocket Boulder" type="Magic Item" source="Mashiro’s Manual of Monstrous Magic" id="ID_AEYANA_MMOMM_MAGIC_ITEM_POCKET_BOULDER">
        <description>
            <p>This magic pebble is marked with a rune, written in Giant. As an action, you can throw the pebble at a point within 60 feet of you, or launch it from a sling. As it flies through the air, the pebble transforms into a Large boulder, which comes crashing down at the point. Each creature within 5 feet of the point must make a DC 12 Dexterity saving throw. A target takes 4d10 bludgeoning damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. Items within this area that are not worn or carried are crushed, taking twice as much damage from this effect.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once a pebble has been used this way, it becomes a nonmagical boulder, weighing 100,000 lbs.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
			<set name="keywords">arrow</set>
			<set name="category">Ammunition</set>
			<set name="type" addition="sling bullet">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Robe of Incorporeal Form" type="Magic Item" source="Mashiro’s Manual of Monstrous Magic" id="ID_AEYANA_MMOMM_MAGIC_ITEM_ROBE_OF_INCORPOREAL_FORM">
        <description>
            <p>This gossamer robe is made of ethereal fabric, extracted from a ghost or specter. It has 3 charges, and regains 1d3 expended charges daily at dawn. While you wear it, you can use an action and expend 1 charge to become incorporeal until the end of your next turn. During this time, you have resistance to all damage except force, and can move through other creatures and objects as if they were difficult terrain. If this effect ends while you are inside an object, you are shunted to the nearest unoccupied space and take 1d10 force damage for every 5 feet you are shunted.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Satyr’s Panpipes" type="Magic Item" source="Mashiro’s Manual of Monstrous Magic" id="ID_AEYANA_MMOMM_MAGIC_ITEM_SATYRS_PANPIPES">
        <description>
            <p>This musical instrument has 3 charges, and it regains 1d3 expended charges daily at dawn. While you are playing it, you can use an action to expend 1 or more charges from the instrument and to cast one of the following spells (save DC 13): charm person (1 charge), sleep (1 charge), fear (3 charges). You can increase the level of one of these spells by one for each additional charge you expend.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Shield of the Androsphinx" type="Magic Item" source="Mashiro’s Manual of Monstrous Magic" id="ID_AEYANA_MMOMM_MAGIC_ITEM_SHIELD_OF_THE_ANDROSPHINX">
        <description>
            <p>This round bronze shield bears the iconography of an androsphinx with an open maw.</p>
            <p class="indent">The shield has 3 charges. While holding it, you can use an action to expend 1 of its charges to emit a magical roar. Each time you use this roar, it is louder and has a different effect.</p>
            <p class="indent">The first time you use this roar, each creature within 500 feet of you that can hear the roar must succeed on a DC 18 Wisdom saving throw or be frightened of you for 1 minute. A frightened creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.</p>
            <p class="indent">The second time you use this roar, each creature within 500 feet of you that can hear the roar must succeed on a DC 18 Wisdom saving throw or be frightened of you and deafened for 1 minute. A frightened creature is paralyzed and can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.</p>
            <p class="indent">The third time you use this roar, each creature within 500 feet of you that can hear the roar must make a DC 18 Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes 8d10 thunder damage and is knocked prone. On a successful save, the creature takes half as much damage and isn’t knocked prone.</p>
            <p class="indent">The shield regains all expended charges daily at dawn, and the effect of the roar resets to that of the first roar.</p>
            <p class="indent">If you are also attuned to the Sword of the Gynosphinx, this shield grants an additional +1 bonus to AC.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
			<set name="category">Armor</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">10</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="6">6 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand,secondary</set>
			<set name="type">Shield</set>
			<set name="armor">Shield</set>
			<set name="proficiency">ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_SHIELD</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Sword of the Gynosphinx" type="Magic Item" source="Mashiro’s Manual of Monstrous Magic" id="ID_AEYANA_MMOMM_MAGIC_ITEM_SWORD_OF_THE_GYNOSPHINX">
        <description>
            <p>This magical bronze sword bears the iconography of a gynosphinx, claws raised and ready to strike. While attuned to the sword, you no longer age.</p>
            <p class="indent">The sword has 3 charges. While holding it, you can use a bonus action to expend 1 of its charges to twist the flow of time. Each creature within 500 feet of you must reroll initiative. You can choose not to reroll. The sword regains all expended charges daily at dawn.</p>
            <p class="indent">If you are also attuned to the Shield of the Androsphinx, this sword has a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="shortsword or longsword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_WOTC_PHB_WEAPON_SHORTSWORD|ID_WOTC_PHB_WEAPON_LONGSWORD</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
</elements>