<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Witchguard Class</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="class-witchguard.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/classes/class-witchguard.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="The Witchguard" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_SE_WG_SOURCE_THE_WITCHGUARD">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation">WG</set>
            <set name="url">https://homebrewery.naturalcrit.com/share/Bkvp4_gSE</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" abbreviation="SE" url="https://www.reddit.com/u/StygianEmperor">Stygian Emporer</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20200627</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Witchguard" type="Class" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_WITCHGUARD">
        <description>
            <p>A black knight’s raised sword casts out a dozen screaming skulls wreathed in hellfire to crash and explode on a line of templars, sending those that aren’t in pieces fleeing for their lives. Behind his horned barbute, he smiles and mutters thanks to a dark benefactor outcast by greater society.</p>
            <p class="indent">Madly clutching his helmeted head, an elf with blazing fire for eyes mentally struggles against the fell whispers from within his own armor, his other hand reflexively grasping for the black book chained to his back. Retrieving the grimoire, he opens it to a blood-scrawled page and begins drawing a chalk circle upon the ground from which he will call forth abyssal creatures onto this plane.</p>
            <p class="indent">Her flesh still horrifically marred by burns inflicted by a self-righteous hunter, a forsaken woman returns to her childhood village now armed with the very curses of which she was falsely accused so long ago. Those few that survive this night only do so by her will, and they shall remember how the temple held no sanctuary for their guilty priesthood.</p>
            <p class="indent">Almost universally scorned, witchguards are united only by their willingness to embrace the forbidden and the taboo. Whether by means of a pact with an ostracized deity, or through simple research into illicit secrets of the arcane, they combine ruinous spells and skill with martial combat to serve their own ungodly ends. </p>
            <h4>THE POWER OF SIN</h4>
            <p>Witchguards’ flagrant disregard of societal norms and religious precepts lead them down rarely-trekked paths, and though they may not intend it or ever even realize it, most end up adopting a particular sin that shapes and directs their abilities. Not necessarily vices or flaws in their ethics, sins nonetheless are frowned upon by the general public whether deserved or not. For is he who angrily rails against injustice truly wrathful, or could he be righteously indignant? Regardless, most witchguards find their sin a deeply personal (or at the least very useful) weapon with which they combat their foes, whether they take the form of overzealous inquisitors or simple bandits. </p>
            <h4>DRAWN TO THE FORBIDDEN</h4>
            <p>A witchguard has no use for the sacred or the traditional, so they are natural outcasts and often make for able adventurers. While a few do find themselves literally guarding witch covens - often just women exiled from society for seeking alternative means for their own betterment - most do not settle for such a dormant life.</p>
            <p class="indent">Instead, most witchguards seek to ever improve their arts, either by pursuing more forbidden texts in forgotten tombs or testing their mettle in combat against the sanctimonious servants of the celestial megalomaniacs that call themselves gods. Adventuring is usually just a means to gain more power for their sort, though no two witchguards are alike and some genuinely enjoy the allure of exploration and the thrill of danger.</p>
            <h4>CREATING A WITCHGUARD</h4>
            <p>While you create your witchguard, try to relate his or her personality traits to one of the sins described at the end of the class. Are they ill-tempered, or very impassioned, as many are who embrace the sin of Wrath? Or are they the opposite - apathetic or just generally laid-back, as would befit the sin of Sloth? Or they could be arrogant, or perhaps justly self-satisfied, as would describe one delighting in the sin of Pride?</p>
            <p class="indent">What drove them away from societal norms and expectations? Were they wronged by an authority figure or system, religious or otherwise? Or did they simply see through the facade that authority put on, and were driven to put that lie to its rightful demise? Or maybe they were even raised by outcasts, exiles that taught them the value of autonomy and discouraged blind faith.</p>
            <p class="indent">Being natural rebels, witchguards are seldom of lawful alignment. Most see only arbitrary rules that are made to be shattered, but if a doctrine is ever found that truly measures up to their ideal of justice, a witchguard could become its staunchest defender. Matters of good and evil are subjective at best, and witchguards should rarely fall neatly into anyone’s concept of either - though the temptation to make an evil witchguard may be strong.</p>
            <h5>QUICK BUILD</h5>
            <p>You can make a witchguard quickly by following these suggestions. First, Strength should be your highest ability score, followed by Intelligence. Second, choose the hermit background.</p>
            <h4>MULTICLASSING</h4>
            <p>The prerequisites for multiclassing into or from a witchguard are a Strength and Intelligence score of 13. When you multiclass into witchguard, you gain proficiency in light armor, medium armor, shields, simple weapons, and martial weapons. Add half your levels (rounded up) in the witchguard class to the appropriate levels from other classes to determine your available spell slots.</p>
            <h2>CLASS FEATURES</h2>
            <p>As a witchguard, you gain the following class features.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">HIT POINTS</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Hit Dice:</strong> 1d10 per witchguard level</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at 1st Level:</strong> 10 + your Constitution modifier</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at Higher Levels:</strong> 1d10 (or 6) + your Constitution modifier per witchguard level after 1st</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">PROFICIENCIES</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled mb">
                <li><strong>Armor:</strong> All armor, shields</li>
                <li><strong>Weapons:</strong> Simple weapons, martial weapons</li>
                <li><strong>Tools:</strong> None</li>
            </ul>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Saving Throws:</strong> Constitution, Intelligence</li>
                <li><strong>Skills:</strong> Choose two from Arcana, Athletics, Deception, Insight, Intimidation, and Persuasion</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">EQUIPMENT</h5>
            <p>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>(a) a martial weapon and a shield or (b) two martial weapons</li>
                <li>(a) a component pouch or (b) an arcane focus</li>
                <li>(a) a scholar’s pack or (b) an explorer’s pack</li>
                <li>Chain mail</li>
            </ul>
        <!-- class table here -->
            <h5 class="caption">THE WITCHGUARD</h5>
            <table class="class-features">
                <thead>
                    <tr><td class="col-5">Level</td><td class="col-10">Proficiency Bonus</td><td class="left">Features</td><td>1st</td><td>2nd</td><td>3rd</td><td>4th</td><td>5th</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td> 1st</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Devil’s Tongue, Doom Bolt</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 2nd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Fighting Style, Spellcasting, Possessed Artefact</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 3rd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Corruption, Mortal Sin</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 4th</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 5th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Mortal Sin Feature</td><td>4</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 6th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Aura of Aggression</td><td>4</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 7th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Mortal Sin Feature</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 8th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 9th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">—</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>10th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Aura of Cowardice</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>11th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Improved Artefact</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>12th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">—</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>1</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>14th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Lay Curse</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>1</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>15th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Mortal Sin Feature</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>16th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>17th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">—</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>1</td></tr>
                <tr><td>18th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Aura Improvements</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>1</td></tr>
                <tr><td>19th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td></tr>
                <tr><td>20th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Mortal Sin Feature</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCHGUARD_DEVILS_TONGUE" />
            <div element="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCHGUARD_DOOM_BOLT" />
            <div element="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCHGUARD_FIGHTING_STYLE" />
            <div element="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCHGUARD_SPELLCASTING" />
            <div element="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCHGUARD_POSSESSED_ARTEFACT" />
            <div element="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCHGUARD_CORRUPTION" />
            <div element="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCHGUARD_MORTAL_SIN" />
            <div element="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCHGUARD_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" />
            <div element="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCHGUARD_AURA_OF_AGGRESSION" />
            <div element="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCHGUARD_AURA_OF_COWARDICE" />
            <div element="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCHGUARD_IMPROVED_ARTEFACT" />
            <div element="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCHGUARD_LAY_CURSE" />
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="hd">d10</set>
            <set name="short">A sinful inversion of the Paladin.</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_MEDIUM_ARMOR" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_HEAVY_ARMOR" requirements="!ID_SE_WG_MULTICLASS_WITCHGUARD" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_SHIELDS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_MARTIAL_WEAPONS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CONSTITUTION" requirements="!ID_SE_WG_MULTICLASS_WITCHGUARD" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_INTELLIGENCE" requirements="!ID_SE_WG_MULTICLASS_WITCHGUARD" />
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency, Witchguard" number="2" supports="Skill,Witchguard" requirements="!ID_SE_WG_MULTICLASS_WITCHGUARD" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCHGUARD_DEVILS_TONGUE" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCHGUARD_DOOM_BOLT" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCHGUARD_FIGHTING_STYLE" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCHGUARD_SPELLCASTING" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCHGUARD_POSSESSED_ARTEFACT" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCHGUARD_CORRUPTION" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCHGUARD_MORTAL_SIN" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCHGUARD_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" level="4" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCHGUARD_AURA_OF_AGGRESSION" level="6" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCHGUARD_AURA_OF_COWARDICE" level="10" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCHGUARD_IMPROVED_ARTEFACT" level="11" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCHGUARD_LAY_CURSE" level="14" />
        </rules>
        <multiclass id="ID_SE_WG_MULTICLASS_WITCHGUARD">
            <prerequisite>Strength 13, Intelligence 13</prerequisite>
            <requirements>[str:13],[int:13]</requirements>
            <setters>
                <set name="multiclass proficiencies">Light armor, medium armor, shields, simple weapons, martial weapons</set>
            </setters>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS" />
            </rules>
        </multiclass>
    </element>
        <element name="Devil’s Tongue" type="Class Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCHGUARD_DEVILS_TONGUE">
            <description>
                <p>Your ability to coerce others into doing what you want is like that of an insidious fiend. You gain proficiency in either Deception, Intimidation, or Persuasion. If you are already proficient in this skill, your proficiency bonus is doubled for any ability check you make that uses this skill. You also learn your choice of Abyssal or Infernal.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Language" name="Devil’s Tongue" supports="ID_LANGUAGE_ABYSSAL|ID_LANGUAGE_INFERNAL" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Deception Proficiency" type="Class Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCHGUARD_DEVILS_TONGUE_">
                <supports>Witchguard Devils Tongue</supports>
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p></p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_OR_DOUBLE_DECEPTION" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Intimidation Proficiency" type="Class Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCHGUARD_DEVILS_TONGUE_">
                <supports>Witchguard Devils Tongue</supports>
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p></p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_OR_DOUBLE_INTIMIDATION" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Persuasion Proficiency" type="Class Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCHGUARD_DEVILS_TONGUE_">
                <supports>Witchguard Devils Tongue</supports>
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p></p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_OR_DOUBLE_PERSUASION" />
                </rules>
            </element>
        <element name="Doom Bolt" type="Class Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCHGUARD_DOOM_BOLT">
            <description>
                <p>You can summon screaming lost souls from the lower planes to crash into your enemies and explode. You have a pool of summoning power that replenishes when you take a long rest. With that pool, you can cause a total number of psychic damage equal to your witchguard level x 5.</p>
                <p class="indent">As an action, you send lost souls flying out towards a creature or group of creatures within a 20-foot-radius sphere, centered up to 120 feet away from you, splitting the damage between them, up to the maximum amount remaining in your pool. Each creature targeted must make a Wisdom saving throw equal to your spell saving throw DC. A target takes full damage on a failed save, or half damage on a successful one. Even if the target takes half damage, the full amount is spent.</p>
                <p class="indent">Instead of causing damage, you can spend 5 points from your pool to cause a target who failed their Wisdom save to become frightened of you for one minute. The frightened target can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect early on a success. You may affect more than one creature at a time with this ability, spending 5 points from your pool to affect each target. You cannot frighten undead or constructs with Doom Bolt, unless they are under the effects of Aura of Cowardice.</p>
                <p class="indent">However, using too much of this power at once can be dangerous to the wielder. After 1st level, if you use more than 3 times your witchguard level in damage points from your pool in one casting of Doom Bolt, roll a d4. A roll of 1 causes some of the lost souls to disobey you, turning the damage in excess of 3 times your witchguard level against you instead of an intended target. This self-damage does not allow for a saving throw, but it can be reduced by psychic damage reduction as normal.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="{{doom-bolt:summoning-power}} Points/Long Rest" action="Action">
                <description>You send lost souls flying out in a 20-foot-radius sphere, centered up to 120 feet away from you, splitting the damage between them, up to the maximum amount remaining in your pool. Wisdom save versus spell DC. Half damage if successful. Instead of causing damage, you can spend 5 points from your pool to cause a target who failed their Wisdom save to become frightened of you for one minute. After 1st level, spending more than {{doom-bolt:limit}} points in one casting of Doom Bolt, roll a d4 for a random effect.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="doom-bolt:summoning-power" value="level:witchguard" />
                <stat name="doom-bolt:summoning-power" value="level:witchguard" />
                <stat name="doom-bolt:summoning-power" value="level:witchguard" />
                <stat name="doom-bolt:summoning-power" value="level:witchguard" />
                <stat name="doom-bolt:summoning-power" value="level:witchguard" />
                <stat name="doom-bolt:limit" value="level:witchguard" />
                <stat name="doom-bolt:limit" value="level:witchguard" />
                <stat name="doom-bolt:limit" value="level:witchguard" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Fighting Style" type="Class Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCHGUARD_FIGHTING_STYLE">
            <description>
                <p>At 2nd level, you adopt a style of fighting as your specialty. Choose one of the following options. You can’t choose the same Fighting Style option more than once, even if you later get to choose again.</p>
                <h5>ARCHERY</h5>
                <p>You gain a +2 bonus to attack rolls you make with ranged weapons.</p>
                <h5>DEFENSE</h5>
                <p>While you are wearing armor, you gain a +1 bonus to AC.</p>
                <h5>DUELING</h5>
                <p>When you are wielding a melee weapon in one hand and no other weapons, you gain a +2 bonus to damage rolls with that weapon.</p>
                <h5>GREAT WEAPON FIGHTING</h5>
                <p>When you roll a 1 or 2 on a damage die for an attack you make with a melee weapon that you are wielding with two hands, you can reroll the die and must use the new roll, even if the new roll is a 1 or a 2. The weapon must have the two-handed or versatile property for you to gain this benefit.</p>
                <h5>PROTECTION</h5>
                <p>When a creature you can see attacks a target other than you that is within 5 feet of you, you can use your reaction to impose disadvantage on the attack roll. You must be wielding a shield.</p>
                <h5>TWO-WEAPON FIGHTING</h5>
                <p>When you engage in two-weapon fighting, you can add your ability modifier to the damage of the second attack.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Fighting Style, Witchguard" supports="Fighting Style, Witchguard" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Spellcasting" type="Class Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCHGUARD_SPELLCASTING">
            <description>
                <p>By 2nd level, you begin to gain an understanding of the malevolent texts you carry in your grimoire, and can cast spells much as a wizard does. You have a grimoire containing three 1st-level witchguard spells of your choice.</p>
                <h5>PREPARING AND CASTING SPELLS</h5>
                <p>The Witchguard table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your witchguard spells of 1st level and higher. To cast one of these spells. you must expend a slot of the spell’s level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.</p>
                <p class="indent">You prepare the list of witchguard spells that are available for you to cast. To do so, choose a number of witchguard spells from your grimoire equal to your Intelligence modifier + half your witchguard level, rounded down (minimum of one spell). The spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can change your list of prepared spells when you finish a long rest.</p>
                <h5>SPELLCASTING ABILITY</h5>
                <p>Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for your witchguard spells. You use your Intelligence whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Intelligence modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a witchguard spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.</p>
                <p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Spell save DC</strong> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier </p>
                <p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Spell attack modifier</strong> = your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier</p>
                <h5>SPELLCASTING FOCUS</h5>
                <p>You can use an arcane focus as a spellcasting focus for your witchguard spells.</p>
                <h5>LEARNING SPELLS OF 1ST LEVEL AND HIGHER</h5>
                <p>Each time you gain a witchguard level, you can add one witchguard spell of your choice to your grimoire. Each of these spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots. as shown on the Witchguard table. On your adventures. you might find other spells that you can add to your grimoire.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <spellcasting name="Witchguard" ability="Intelligence" prepare="true">
                <list known="true">Witchguard</list>
            </spellcasting>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS_SPELLCASTING_SLOTS_HALF" requirements="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS"/>
                <stat name="witchguard:spellcasting:slots:1" value="2" level="2" />
                <stat name="witchguard:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="3" />
                <stat name="witchguard:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="5" />
                <stat name="witchguard:spellcasting:slots:2" value="2" level="5" />
                <stat name="witchguard:spellcasting:slots:2" value="1" level="7" />
                <stat name="witchguard:spellcasting:slots:3" value="2" level="9" />
                <stat name="witchguard:spellcasting:slots:3" value="1" level="11" />
                <stat name="witchguard:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="13" />
                <stat name="witchguard:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="15" />
                <stat name="witchguard:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="17" />
                <stat name="witchguard:spellcasting:slots:5" value="1" level="17" />
                <stat name="witchguard:spellcasting:slots:5" value="1" level="19" />
                <stat name="witchguard:spellcasting:prepare" value="intelligence:modifier" />
                <stat name="witchguard:spellcasting:prepare" value="level:witchguard:half" />
    			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_INTERNAL_PROFICIENCY_SPELLFOCUS_GROUP_ARCANE_FOCUS" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Possessed Artefact" type="Class Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCHGUARD_POSSESSED_ARTEFACT">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 2nd level, astral fiends begin to inhabit an item of your choice. Whenever you finish a long rest, you can touch up to two weapons, a shield, or a suit of armor that you are proficient with. While wielding the weapons or shield, or wearing the armor, you gain a benefit depending on its type.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Weapon.</em></strong> When you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can expend one spell slot to deal psychic damage to the target, in addition to the weapon’s damage. The extra damage is 2d8 for a 1st-level spell slot, plus 1d8 for each spell-level higher than 1st, to a maximum of 5d8. The damage increases by 1d8 if the target is a celestial or a fiend, to a maximum of 6d8. These dice become d6s when using a ranged weapon.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Armor or Shield.</em></strong> When a creature misses you with an attack, you can expend one spell slot to deal psychic damage to the creature. The damage is 2d8 for a 1st-level spell slot, plus 1d8 for each spell-level higher than 1st, to a maximum of 5d8. The damage increases by 1d8 if the target is a celestial or a fiend, to a maximum of 6d8. These dice become d6s if the triggering attack is ranged.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, this item becomes sentient, being able to communicate telepathically with its wielder or wearer, and has hearing and normal vision out to 30 feet. The player and the DM should work together to determine the item’s alignment and any other characteristics it may have.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Whenever you finish a long rest, you can touch up to two weapons, a shield, or a suit of armor that you are proficient with, making them your Possessed Artefact. Weapon: When you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can expend one spell slot to deal psychic damage to the target. Armor or Shield: When a creature misses you with an attack, you can expend one spell slot to deal psychic damage to the creature. Additionally, this item becomes sentient, being able to communicate telepathically with its wielder or wearer, and has hearing and normal vision out to 30 feet.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Corruption" type="Class Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCHGUARD_CORRUPTION">
            <description>
                <p>At 3rd level, your exposure to dark forces grants you resistance to psychic damage and advantage on saves against being possessed.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You have advantage on saving throws against being possessed.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_PSYCHIC" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Mortal Sin" type="Class Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCHGUARD_MORTAL_SIN">
            <description>
                <p>Various faiths across the realm conclude that certain character traits should be suppressed if one is to be good to others, or even to attain salvation and reward in the afterlife. Witchguards dispense with this common wisdom, realizing that to deny the mortal self is to damn one in an entirely different way, and so embrace their darker attributes gaining new and fitting powers in the process. The following Sins come with certain values, though as a witchguard should be beholden to no master save themselves, unlike a paladin’s tenets, they should be seen more as descriptive, rather than prescriptive.</p>
                <p>When you reach 3rd level, your darkest traits are teased out into the light by the fiends you work with so closely, setting you on a particular path to damnation. Choose the Sin of Wrath, Pride, Sloth, Greed, Lust, Envy, or Gluttony, each of which are detailed at the end of the class description.</p>
                <p class="indent">Your choice grants you features at 3rd level and again at 5th, 7th, 15th, and 20th level.</p>
                <h5>SIN SPELLS</h5>
                <p>Each sin has a list of associated spells. You gain access to these spells at the levels specified in the sin description. Once you gain access to a sin spell, you always have it prepared. Sin spells don’t count against the number of spells you can prepare each day.</p>
                <p class="indent">If you gain a sin spell that doesn’t appear on the witchguard spell list, the spell is nonetheless a witchguard spell for you.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Archetype" name="Mortal Sin" supports="Witchguard Mortal Sin" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Ability Score Improvement" type="Class Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCHGUARD_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Witchguard 4)" supports="Improvement Option,Witchguard,4" level="4" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Witchguard 8)" supports="Improvement Option,Witchguard,8" level="8" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Witchguard 12)" supports="Improvement Option,Witchguard,12" level="12" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Witchguard 16)" supports="Improvement Option,Witchguard,16" level="16" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Witchguard 19)" supports="Improvement Option,Witchguard,19" level="19" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Aura of Aggression" type="Class Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCHGUARD_AURA_OF_AGGRESSION">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 6th level, you and friendly creatures within 10 feet of you gain a bonus to the first damage rolls you make each round equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of +1). You must be conscious to grant this bonus.</p>
                <p class="indent">At 18th level, the range of this aura increases to 30 feet.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You and friendly creatures within {{aura-of-aggression:range}} feet of you gain a +{{aura-of-aggression:bonus}} bonus to the first damage rolls you make each round, as long as your a conscious.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="aura-of-aggression:bonus" value="1" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="aura-of-aggression:bonus" value="intelligence:modifier" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="aura-of-aggression:range" value="10" level="6" />
                <stat name="aura-of-aggression:range" value="20" level="18" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Aura of Cowardice" type="Class Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCHGUARD_AURA_OF_COWARDICE">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 10th level, all enemy creatures within 10 feet of you have disadvantage on saving throws made to resist being frightened, as well as on Wisdom saving throws against your Doom Bolt ability while you are conscious. Creatures that are normally immune to being frightened, such as undead and constructs, lose that immunity while within your aura, but do not suffer disadvantage.</p>
                <p class="indent">At 18th level, the range of this aura increases to 30 feet.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>All enemy creatures within {{aura-of-aggression:range}} feet of you have disadvantage on saving throws made to resist being frightened, as well as on Wisdom saving throws against your Doom Bolt ability while you are conscious. Creatures that are normally immune to being frightened, such as undead and constructs, lose that immunity while within your aura, but do not suffer disadvantage.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Improved Artefact" type="Class Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCHGUARD_IMPROVED_ARTEFACT">
            <description>
                <p>By 11th level, the fiendish spirits taking up residence in your arms and armor are so attuned to your items that they retaliate against your enemies by themselves.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Weapon.</em></strong> Whenever you hit a creature with a possessed weapon, the creature takes an additional 1d8 psychic damage. If you choose to expend a spell slot with an attack, you add this damage to the extra damage added with the spell slot. This die becomes a d6 when using a ranged weapon.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Armor or Shield.</em></strong> The creatures that miss you the first two times in a round take 1d8 psychic damage each time. If you choose to expend a spell slot with your reaction, you add this damage to the extra damage added with the spell slot. These dice become d6s if the triggering attacks are ranged.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Weapon: Whenever you hit a creature with a possessed weapon, the creature takes an additional 1d8 psychic damage. If you choose to expend a spell slot with an attack, you add this damage to the extra damage added with the spell slot.  This die becomes a d6 when using a ranged weapon. Armor or Shield: The creatures that miss you the first two times in a round take 1d8 psychic damage each time. If you choose to expend a spell slot with your reaction, you add this damage to the extra damage added with the spell slot. These dice become d6s if the triggering attacks are ranged.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Lay Curse" type="Class Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCHGUARD_LAY_CURSE">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 14th level, you can cast the spell <em>bestow curse</em> as a 4th level spell without using a spell slot and without requiring concentration. You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier (a minimum of once). You regain expended uses when you finish a long rest.</p>
                <p class="indent">Alternatively, you can spend multiple uses of this feature to raise the spell level of <em>bestow curse</em>, one use per spell level above 4th, up to a maximum of 5 uses to cast it as a 9th-level spell.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="{{aura-of-aggression:bonus}}/Long Rest">
                <description>You can cast bestow curse as a 4th level spell without using a spell slot and without requiring concentration. You can spend multiple uses of this feature to raise the spell level, one use per spell level above 4th, up to a maximum of 5 uses to cast it as a 9th-level spell.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BESTOW_CURSE" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" />
            </rules>
        </element>


	<element name="Sin of Wrath" type="Archetype" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_WITCHGUARD_WRATH">
		<supports>Witchguard Mortal Sin</supports>
		<description>
			<p>The Sin of Wrath is perhaps the most obvious, and most destructive. Devotees of Wrath are often simply called Furies after the fabled women of myth whose desire for vengeance was never slaked. Amongst witchguards, none are more terrifying in martial combat.</p>
			<div element="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WRATH_VALUES_OF_WRATH" />
			<div element="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WRATH_SIN_SPELLS" />
			<div element="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WRATH_FURY" />
			<div element="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WRATH_EXTRA_ATTACK" />
			<div element="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WRATH_IMPATIENCE" />
			<div element="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WRATH_HATED_ENEMY" />
			<div element="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WRATH_ASCENSCION" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WRATH_VALUES_OF_WRATH" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WRATH_SIN_SPELLS" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WRATH_FURY" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WRATH_EXTRA_ATTACK" level="5" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WRATH_IMPATIENCE" level="7" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WRATH_HATED_ENEMY" level="15" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WRATH_ASCENSCION" level="20" />
		</rules>
	</element>
		<element name="Values of Wrath" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WRATH_VALUES_OF_WRATH">
			<description>
				<p>Wrath is quite simple at its core. It is an inversion of the idea that one must remain satisfied with events no matter how unjust.</p>
				<p class="indent"><strong><em>Impatience.</em></strong> Do not wait your turn. Take matters into your own hands or you will be left behind.</p>
				<p class="indent"><strong><em>Anger.</em></strong> Anger is a wonderful motivator. To be otherwise is to remain passive.</p>
				<p class="indent"><strong><em>Vengeance.</em></strong> Never allow wrongs to go unpunished, lest they repeat themselves.</p>
				<p class="indent"><strong><em>Hatred.</em></strong> Know who your enemies are, and keep their misdeeds fresh in your mind.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description></description>
			</sheet>
		</element>
		<element name="Sin Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WRATH_SIN_SPELLS">
			<description>
				<p>You gain Sin spells at the witchguard levels listed.</p>
				<h5 class="caption">SIN OF WRATH SPELLS</h5>
				<table>
					<thead>
						<tr><td>Witchguard Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
					</thead>
					<tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>burning hands, earth tremor</em></td></tr>
					<tr><td>5th</td><td><em>scorching ray, shatter</em></td></tr>
					<tr><td>9th</td><td><em>erupting earth, fireball</em></td></tr>
					<tr><td>13th</td><td><em>fire shield, freedom of movement</em></td></tr>
					<tr><td>17th</td><td><em>destructive wave, flame strike</em></td></tr>
				</table>
			</description>
			<sheet display="false">
				<description></description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BURNING_HANDS" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_EARTH_TREMOR" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SCORCHING_RAY" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHATTER" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ERUPTING_EARTH" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIREBALL" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIRE_SHIELD" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="13" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FREEDOM_OF_MOVEMENT" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="13" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DESTRUCTIVE_WAVE" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="17" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FLAME_STRIKE" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="17" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Fury" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WRATH_FURY">
			<description>
				<p>When you choose this Sin at 3rd level, your anger is always bubbling just below the surface. As a bonus action, you can let it loose, gaining the following features.</p>
				<ul>
					<li>You have advantage on Strength checks and Strength saving throws.</li>
					<li>When you make a melee weapon attack using Strength, your attacks deal an extra 2 Acid, Cold, Fire, Lightning, Poison, or Thunder damage, chosen at the beginning of your fury. This bonus damage increases to 3 at 9th level, and 4 at 16th level.</li>
				</ul>
				<p class="indent">You can cast spells while infuriated as long as the spell’s casting time is no more than 1 action and the spell does not require concentration.</p>
				<p class="indent">Your fury lasts for 1 minute. It ends early if you are knocked unconscious. You can also end your fury on your turn as a bonus action.</p>
				<p class="indent">Once your fury ends, you must finish a long rest before you can enter your fury again.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
				<description>You let loose your fury. You have advantage on Strength checks and Strength saving throws. When you make a melee weapon attack using Strength, your attacks deal an extra {{fury:bonus-damage}} Acid, Cold, Fire, Lightning, Poison, or Thunder damage, chosen at the beginning of your fury. Your fury lasts for 1 minute. It ends early if you are knocked unconscious. You can also end your fury on your turn as a bonus action.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <stat name="fury:bonus-damage" value="2" level="3" />
                <stat name="fury:bonus-damage" value="1" level="9" />
                <stat name="fury:bonus-damage" value="1" level="16" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Extra Attack" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WRATH_EXTRA_ATTACK">
			<description>
				<p>Beginning at 5th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description>You can attack twice whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <stat name="extra attack:count" value="2" level="5" bonus="extra attack" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Impatience" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WRATH_IMPATIENCE">
			<description>
				<p>At 7th level, you gain advantage on initiative rolls.</p>
				<p class="indent">Additionally, as a reaction, you may choose to take an action at any time during the round. Once you use this feature, you must finish a long rest before you can use it again. Starting at 17th level, you can use it twice before a rest, but only once during the same round.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet usage="1/Long Rest" action="Reaction">
				<description>You have advantage on initiative rolls. Additionally, as a reaction, you may choose to take an action at any time during the round. Once you use this feature, you must finish a long rest before you can use it again.</description>
				<description level="17" usage="2/Long Rest">You have advantage on initiative rolls. Additionally, as a reaction, you may choose to take an action at any time during the round. You can use it twice before a long rest, but only once during the same round.</description>
			</sheet>
		</element>
		<element name="Hated Enemy" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WRATH_HATED_ENEMY">
			<description>
				<p>At 15th level, you can designate a foe to be your hated enemy. When you attack a creature, you can choose the target of the attack as your hated enemy. You can use this ability once during your turn. The target remains your hated enemy until you use this ability again.</p>
				<p class="indent">You gain a bonus to your attack rolls against your hated enemy equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of +1). Additionally, your hated enemy has disadvantage against your spells, abilities, and effects.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description>When you attack a creature, you can choose the target of the attack as your hated enemy. You can use this ability once during your turn. The target remains your hated enemy until you use this ability again. You have a +{{aura-of-aggression:bonus}} on attack rolls against your hated enemy. Your hated enemy has disadvantage against your spells, abilities, and effects.</description>
			</sheet>
		</element>
		<element name="Ascenscion" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WRATH_ASCENSCION">
			<description>
				<p>At 20th level, you reach the epitome of Wrath, transforming into a fiend yourself.</p>
				<p class="indent">Your creature type changes to fiend for the purposes of game effects, and as an action you may choose to become one size category larger or return to your regular size. You become permanently under the effects of Fury, though you can cast spells as normal. You can change the damage type dealt by the bonus damage from your fury at the end of a long rest.</p>
				<p class="indent">Additionally, you can take two traits from the list below.</p>
				<p class="indent"><strong><em>Elemental Infusion.</em></strong> You gain resistance to the damage type chosen for your fury. Additionally, once per short rest, as an action, you may vomit up this elemental energy. When you use your breath weapon, each creature in a 15-foot cone or a 5 by 30-foot line (Your choice when the breath weapon is used) must make a saving throw - Dexterity for Acid, Fire, and Lightning; or Constitution for Cold, Poison, or Thunder. The DC for this saving throw equals 8 + your Intelligence modifier + your proficiency bonus. A creature takes 6d6 damage on a failed save, and half as much damage on a successful one.</p>
				<p class="indent"><strong><em>Extra Grasping Limbs.</em></strong> You have more than two arms (or tentacles, pedipalps, etc.). You can only gain the benefit of items held by two of your grasping limbs at any given time, and at the beginning of your turn you can switch which arms you are benefiting from (no action required). When you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack on your turn, you can use a bonus action to attempt to grapple the target. While you have at least 3 arms free, you have a climbing speed equal to your walking speed.</p>
				<p class="indent"><strong><em>Extra Walking Limbs.</em></strong> You have more than two legs, or instead you have a slithering, snakelike tail. Your walking speed increases by 10 feet, you can add 10 feet to your long jump distance and 5 feet to your high jump distance. You also have advantage on all saving throws to resist being knocked prone or restrained.</p>
				<p class="indent"><strong><em>Wings.</em></strong> You sprout leathery wings large enough to fly. You gain a 40-foot fly speed.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet action="Action">
				<description>You can become one size larger as an action. You become permanently under the effects of Fury, though you can cast spells as normal. You can change the damage type dealt by the bonus damage from your fury at the end of a long rest.</description>
			</sheet>
            <setters>
                <set name="type">Fiend</set>
            </setters>
			<rules>
                <select type="Racial Trait" name="Fiend Features" supports="ID_SE_WG_RACIAL_TRAIT_WITCHGUARD_FURY_ELEMENTAL_INFUSION|ID_SE_WG_RACIAL_TRAIT_WITCHGUARD_FURY_EXTRA_GRASPING_LIMBS|ID_SE_WG_RACIAL_TRAIT_WITCHGUARD_FURY_EXTRA_WALKING_LIMBS|ID_SE_WG_RACIAL_TRAIT_WITCHGUARD_FURY_WINGS" number="2" />
                <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_SE_WG_RACIAL_TRAIT_WITCHGUARD_FURY_WITCHGUARD_ASCENSION" />
			</rules>
		</element>
            <element name="Witchguard Ascension" type="Racial Trait" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_RACIAL_TRAIT_WITCHGUARD_FURY_WITCHGUARD_ASCENSION">
                <description>
                    <p>You are now considered a fiend.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>You are now considered a fiend.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Elemental Infusion" type="Racial Trait" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_RACIAL_TRAIT_WITCHGUARD_FURY_ELEMENTAL_INFUSION">
                <description>
                    <p>You gain resistance to the damage type chosen for your fury. Additionally, once per short rest, as an action, you may vomit up this elemental energy. When you use your breath weapon, each creature in a 15-foot cone or a 5 by 30-foot line (Your choice when the breath weapon is used) must make a saving throw - Dexterity for Acid, Fire, and Lightning; or Constitution for Cold, Poison, or Thunder. The DC for this saving throw equals 8 + your Intelligence modifier + your proficiency bonus. A creature takes 6d6 damage on a failed save, and half as much damage on a successful one.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Short Rest">
                    <description>You gain resistance to the damage type chosen for your fury. Once per short rest, as an action, you may vomit up this elemental energy. When you use your breath weapon, each creature in a 15-foot cone or a 5 by 30-foot line. Save DC {{spellcasting:dc}}. A creature takes 6d6 damage on a failed save, and half as much damage on a successful one.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Extra Grasping Limbs" type="Racial Trait" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_RACIAL_TRAIT_WITCHGUARD_FURY_EXTRA_GRASPING_LIMBS">
                <description>
                    <p>You have more than two arms (or tentacles, pedipalps, etc.). You can only gain the benefit of items held by two of your grasping limbs at any given time, and at the beginning of your turn you can switch which arms you are benefiting from (no action required). When you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack on your turn, you can use a bonus action to attempt to grapple the target. While you have at least 3 arms free, you have a climbing speed equal to your walking speed.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>You have more than two arms. You can only gain the benefit of items held by two of your grasping limbs at any given time, and at the beginning of your turn you can switch which arms you are benefiting from (no action required). When you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack on your turn, you can use a bonus action to attempt to grapple the target. While you have at least 3 arms free, you have a climbing speed equal to your walking speed.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Extra Walking Limbs" type="Racial Trait" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_RACIAL_TRAIT_WITCHGUARD_FURY_EXTRA_WALKING_LIMBS">
                <description>
                    <p>You have more than two legs, or instead you have a slithering, snakelike tail. Your walking speed increases by 10 feet, you can add 10 feet to your long jump distance and 5 feet to your high jump distance. You also have advantage on all saving throws to resist being knocked prone or restrained.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>You have more than two legs, or instead you have a slithering, snakelike tail. Your walking speed increases by 10 feet, you can add 10 feet to your long jump distance and 5 feet to your high jump distance. You also have advantage on all saving throws to resist being knocked prone or restrained.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="speed:misc" value="10" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Wings" type="Racial Trait" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_RACIAL_TRAIT_WITCHGUARD_FURY_WINGS">
                <description>
                    <p>You sprout leathery wings large enough to fly. You gain a 40-foot fly speed.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>You have leathery wings large enough to fly.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="speed:fly" value="40" bonus="base" />
                </rules>
            </element>


	<element name="Sin of Pride" type="Archetype" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_WITCHGUARD_PRIDE">
		<supports>Witchguard Mortal Sin</supports>
		<description>
			<p>The Sin of Pride is considered one of the oldest and most serious of sins, for the danger proud mortals pose to the gods’ precarious positions on their heavenly thrones is greater than many would like to admit. Known as Contemptors, disciples of Pride are untouchable to most, both in terms of status and also in combat.</p>
			<div element="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PRIDE_VALUES_OF_PRIDE" />
			<div element="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PRIDE_SIN_SPELLS" />
			<div element="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PRIDE_UNTOUCHABLE" />
			<div element="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PRIDE_EXTRA_ATTACK" />
			<div element="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PRIDE_ARROGANCE" />
			<div element="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PRIDE_CONTEMPT" />
			<div element="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PRIDE_UNSTOPPABLE" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PRIDE_VALUES_OF_PRIDE" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PRIDE_SIN_SPELLS" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PRIDE_UNTOUCHABLE" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PRIDE_EXTRA_ATTACK" level="5" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PRIDE_ARROGANCE" level="7" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PRIDE_CONTEMPT" level="15" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PRIDE_UNSTOPPABLE" level="20" />
		</rules>
	</element>
		<element name="Values of Pride" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PRIDE_VALUES_OF_PRIDE">
			<description>
				<p>Pride is about self-esteem more than anything, whether earned or not.</p>
				<p class="indent"><strong><em>Confidence.</em></strong> Your prowess is such that you can face any challenge. Let the others run in fear; all the more glory for you when the dragon falls.</p>
				<p class="indent"><strong><em>Disdain.</em></strong> Other people are only there to give you the praise you deserve. Do not dignify them as anything better.</p>
				<p class="indent"><strong><em>Bravado.</em></strong> Others need to know of your accomplishments. Recount them at every opportunity.</p>
				<p class="indent"><strong><em>Perfection.</em></strong> Your weaknesses and insecurities cannot be known. If they are discovered, all is lost.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description></description>
			</sheet>
		</element>
		<element name="Sin Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PRIDE_SIN_SPELLS">
			<description>
				<p>You gain Sin spells at the witchguard levels listed.</p>
				<h5 class="caption">SIN OF PRIDE SPELLS</h5>
				<table>
					<thead>
						<tr><td>Witchguard Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
					</thead>
					<tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>heroism, shield</em></td></tr>
					<tr><td>5th</td><td><em>blur, mirror image</em></td></tr>
					<tr><td>9th</td><td><em>magic circle, protection from energy</em></td></tr>
					<tr><td>13th</td><td><em>death ward, stoneskin</em></td></tr>
					<tr><td>17th</td><td><em>dispel evil and good, wall of force</em></td></tr>
				</table>
			</description>
			<sheet display="false">
				<description></description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HEROISM" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHIELD" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLUR" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MIRROR_IMAGE" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGIC_CIRCLE" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PROTECTION_FROM_ENERGY" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DEATH_WARD" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="13" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_STONESKIN" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="13" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISPEL_EVIL_AND_GOOD" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="17" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WALL_OF_FORCE" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="17" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Untouchable" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PRIDE_UNTOUCHABLE">
			<description>
				<p>When you choose this Sin at 3rd level, the damage you take from bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing is reduced by an amount equal to your proficiency bonus.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description>The damage you take from bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing is reduced by {{proficiency}} points.</description>
			</sheet>
		</element>
		<element name="Extra Attack" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PRIDE_EXTRA_ATTACK">
			<description>
				<p>Beginning at 5th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description>You can attack twice whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <stat name="extra attack:count" value="2" level="5" bonus="extra attack" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Arrogance" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PRIDE_ARROGANCE">
			<description>
				<p>At 7th level, you can no longer be frightened.</p>
				<p class="indent">Additionally, as a bonus action you can challenge a number of creatures equal to your Intelligence modifier (a minimum of 1) that can see or hear you to engage you at the same time. Each creature so challenged must make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, they have disadvantage on attack rolls against creatures other than you, and must make Wisdom saving throws each time they attempt to move to a space that is more than 30 feet away from you; if they succeed on this saving throw, this ability doesn’t restrict the target’s movement for that turn.</p>
				<p class="indent">The ability ends after one minute, or if you move more than 30 feet away from any of the targets. After using this ability, you must complete a long rest before you can use it again.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
				<description>You can no longer be frightened. Additionally, as a bonus action you can challenge a up to {{aura-of-aggression:bonus}} creatures that can see or hear you to engage you at the same time. Each creature so challenged must make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, they have disadvantage on attack rolls against creatures other than you, and must make Wisdom saving throws each time they attempt to move to a space that is more than 30 feet away from you; if they succeed on this saving throw, this ability doesn’t restrict the target’s movement for that turn. The ability ends after one minute, or if you move more than 30 feet away from any of the targets.</description>
			</sheet>
		</element>
		<element name="Contempt" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PRIDE_CONTEMPT">
			<description>
				<p>At 15th level, when a creature attacks you, casts a spell, or uses an ability targeting you, you may use your reaction to hold them in contempt. The target remains held in contempt until you use this ability again.</p>
				<p class="indent">You gain a bonus to your AC equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of +1) against the attacks of a creature held in contempt, and you have advantage on all your saving throws against their spells, abilites and effects. This bonus to AC and saving throws includes the triggering attack, spell, ability, or effect.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet action="Reaction">
				<description>When a creature attacks you, casts a spell, or uses an ability targeting you, you may use your reaction to hold them in contempt. The target remains held in contempt until you use this ability again. You gain a +{{aura-of-aggression:bonus}} bonus to your AC against the attacks of a creature held in contempt, and you have advantage on all your saving throws against their spells, abilites and effects. This bonus to AC and saving throws includes the triggering attack, spell, ability, or effect.</description>
			</sheet>
		</element>
		<element name="Unstoppable" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PRIDE_UNSTOPPABLE">
			<description>
				<p>At 20th level, all damage you take other than that from bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing is reduced by 6. Additionally, any critical hit against you becomes a normal hit.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description>All damage you take other than that from bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing is reduced by 6. Additionally, any critical hit against you becomes a normal hit.</description>
			</sheet>
		</element>


	<element name="Sin of Sloth" type="Archetype" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_WITCHGUARD_SLOTH">
		<supports>Witchguard Mortal Sin</supports>
		<description>
			<p>The Sin of Sloth asks "Why should I do something difficult when someone or something else can do it for me?" Sometimes called Diabolists, wallowers in the Sin of Sloth summon fiends from the lower planes to fight on their behalf, always searching for more and more potent demons and devils to fulfill their own ever-multiplying obligations.</p>
			<div element="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLOTH_VALUES_OF_SLOTH" />
			<div element="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLOTH_SIN_SPELLS" />
			<div element="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLOTH_FIENDISH_SERVANT" />
			<div element="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLOTH_COORDINATED_ATTACK" />
			<div element="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLOTH_FIENDS_DEFENSE" />
			<div element="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLOTH_SUPERIOR_FIENDS_DEFENSE" />
			<div element="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLOTH_CONSUME" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLOTH_VALUES_OF_SLOTH" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLOTH_SIN_SPELLS" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLOTH_FIENDISH_SERVANT" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLOTH_COORDINATED_ATTACK" level="5" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLOTH_FIENDS_DEFENSE" level="7" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLOTH_SUPERIOR_FIENDS_DEFENSE" level="15" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLOTH_CONSUME" level="20" />
		</rules>
	</element>
		<element name="Values of Sloth" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLOTH_VALUES_OF_SLOTH">
			<description>
				<p>Though the very nature of Sloth is to ignore conviction and duty, these values tend to define witchguards who partake the most of this Sin.</p>
				<p class="indent"><strong><em>Apathy.</em></strong> Caring too much is only likely to make you upset. Let things be as they will be; you will be that much happier for it.</p>
				<p class="indent"><strong><em>Idleness.</em></strong> "Idle hands are a devil’s playthings," or so the saying goes. Make plenty of free time for yourself, that you might become inadvertently invested in something others might think you shouldn’t.</p>
				<p class="indent"><strong><em>Avoidance.</em></strong> Don’t do anything too difficult; if someone else doesn’t eventually do it for you, it must not be that important.</p>
				<p class="indent"><strong><em>Ease.</em></strong> If something must be done by you yourself, the simplest solution is best. A job half-done is better than none at all, supposedly.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description></description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Sin Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLOTH_SIN_SPELLS">
			<description>
				<p>You gain Sin spells at the witchguard levels listed.</p>
				<h5 class="caption">SIN OF SLOTH SPELLS</h5>
				<table>
					<thead>
						<tr><td>Witchguard Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
					</thead>
					<tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>sleep, unseen servant</em></td></tr>
					<tr><td>5th</td><td><em>calm emotions, find steed</em></td></tr>
					<tr><td>9th</td><td><em>catnap, summon lesser demons</em></td></tr>
					<tr><td>13th</td><td><em>find greater steed, summon greater demon</em></td></tr>
					<tr><td>17th</td><td><em>dream, infernal calling</em></td></tr>
				</table>
			</description>
			<sheet display="false">
				<description></description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SLEEP" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_UNSEEN_SERVANT" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CALM_EMOTIONS" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIND_STEED" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_CATNAP" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_SUMMON_LESSER_DEMONS" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_FIND_GREATER_STEED" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="13" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_SUMMON_GREATER_DEMON" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="13" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DREAM" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="17" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_INFERNAL_CALLING" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="17" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Fiendish Servant" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLOTH_FIENDISH_SERVANT">
			<description>
				<p>When you choose this Sin at 3rd level, you learn a ritual to summon a minor entity from the lower planes to serve you. With 8 hours of preparation and the expendature of 50 gp worth of rare blood and fine candles, you call forth a fiend that is magically bound to follow your every command. Choose a fiendish archetype, which is detailed at the end of this Sin. At the end of 8 hours, your fiendish servant appears and gains all the abilities of your Servant’s Binding ability. You can only have one fiendish servant at a time.</p>
				<p class="indent">If your fiendish servant is ever slain in or banished from any plane other than its native one, you can resummon it. With 8 hours of work and the expenditure of 25 gp worth of rare blood and fine candles, you call forth your servant as if it had never left your service. If, however, it is slain in its native plane, its soul must form a new body from the stuff of the lower planes over the course of 1d4 weeks, during which time you will need to summon a different entity or make do without.</p>
				<p class="indent">If you use this ability to return a former fiendish servant to life while you have a current fiendish servant, your current servant is no longer bound to your will and you lose control of it. Unless you’ve managed to form an improbable bond of trust with it, it will most likely attack you or anyone nearby, causing as much havoc as it can before it can be banished once more.</p>
                <h5>SERVANT’S BINDING</h5>
                <p>Your fiendish servant gains a variety of benefits while it is bound to your will.</p>
                <ul>
                <li>The servant obeys your commands as best it can. It acts on your turn, and you determine its actions, decisions, attitudes, and so on. If you are incapacitated or absent, your servant acts on its own. It cannot attack you during this time, but it may otherwise attempt to work against your better interests, unless you manage to form a bond of trust with it.</li>
                <li>Your servant’s level equals your witchguard level, and for each witchguard level you gain after 3rd, it gains an additional hit die and increases its hit points accordingly.</li>
                <li>Your servant has the proficiency bonus of a player character of the same level.</li>
                <li>Whenever you gain the Ability Score Improvement class feature, your servant’s abilities also improve. Your servant can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or it can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, your servant can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature unless its description specifies otherwise.</li>
                    <ul>
                    <li>Alternatively, whenever you gain the Ability Score Improvement class feature, you can wreathe new spells into your servant to force them to evolve new features that improve its potency instead of having the servant gain the regular Ability Score Improvement. You can choose one of these traits from the Fiendish Evolutions list below.</li>
                    </ul>
                <li>You may use the Possessed Artefact feature through your servant as if they were wielding or wearing your artefact, and your Improved Artefact feature through your servant when you gain that feature at 11th level, using your spell slots for those features.</li>
                </ul>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description>With 8 hours of preparation and the expendature of 50 gp worth of rare blood and fine candles, you call forth a fiend that is magically bound to follow your every command.</description>
			</sheet>
		</element>
		<element name="Coordinated Attack" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLOTH_COORDINATED_ATTACK">
			<description>
				<p>Beginning at 5th level, you and your fiendish servant form a more potent fighting team. When you use the Attack action on your turn, if your servant can see you, it can use its reaction to make a weapon attack or cast a cantrip that requires a spell attack check or a saving throw.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description>When you use the Attack action on your turn, if your servant can see you, it can use its reaction to make a weapon attack or cast a cantrip that requires a spell attack check or a saving throw.</description>
			</sheet>
		</element>
		<element name="Fiend’s Defense" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLOTH_FIENDS_DEFENSE">
			<description>
				<p>At 7th level, while your servant can see you, it has advantage on all saving throws.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description>While your servant can see you, it has advantage on all saving throws.</description>
			</sheet>
		</element>
		<element name="Superior Fiend’s Defense" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLOTH_SUPERIOR_FIENDS_DEFENSE">
			<description>
				<p>At 15th level, whenever an attacker that your servant can see hits it with an attack, it can use its reaction to halve the attack’s damage against it.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description>Whenever an attacker that your servant can see hits it with an attack, it can use its reaction to halve the attack’s damage against it.</description>
			</sheet>
		</element>
		<element name="Consume" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLOTH_CONSUME">
			<description>
				<p>At 20th level, you learn how to consume the essence of your fiendish servant when the need is great. As long as your fiendish servant is within 30 feet of you, you can consume it as an action, killing it and gaining the following benefits until you take a long rest:</p>
				<ul>
					<li>You gain temporary hit points equal to its remaining hit points.</li>
					<li>You regain any spent spell slots that the fiendish servant had unspent.</li>
					<li>When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can make one additional attack as part of that action.</li>
					<li>Your attacks and damaging spells deal an additional 1d8 psychic damage.</li>
					<li>You have advantage on all saving throws.</li>
					<li>Whenever an attacker that you can see hits you with an attack, you can use your reaction to halve the attack’s damage against you.</li>
				</ul>
			</description>
			<sheet action="Action">
				<description>As long as your fiendish servant is within 30 feet of you, you can consume it, killing it and gaining the following benefits until you take a long rest:
                You gain temporary hit points equal to its remaining hit points.
                You regain any spent spell slots that the fiendish servant had unspent.
                When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can make one additional attack as part of that action.
                Your attacks and damaging spells deal an additional 1d8 psychic damage.
                You have advantage on all saving throws.
                Whenever an attacker that you can see hits you with an attack, you can use your reaction to halve the attack’s damage against you.</description>
			</sheet>
		</element>


	<element name="Sin of Greed" type="Archetype" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_WITCHGUARD_GREED">
		<supports>Witchguard Mortal Sin</supports>
		<description>
			<p>The Sin of Greed embodies desire for things temporal, most often wealth or power, rather than those supposed eternal things pious folk believe should be striven for. However, for the witchguard adherents to Greed, known as Death Knights, life itself is their object of desire, and life everlasting their ultimate aspiration. They wield necromantic power to grow closer to this ambitious objective, raising the dead to serve them as they weaken the living who stand in their way.</p>
			<div element="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GREED_VALUES_OF_GREED" />
			<div element="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GREED_SIN_SPELLS" />
			<div element="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GREED_COMMAND_UNDEAD" />
			<div element="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GREED_DEATH_BOLT" />
			<div element="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GREED_EXTRA_ATTACK" />
			<div element="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GREED_EXPLOIT_BONE" />
			<div element="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GREED_AUGMENT_UNDEAD" />
			<div element="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GREED_IMMORTALITY" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GREED_VALUES_OF_GREED" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GREED_SIN_SPELLS" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GREED_COMMAND_UNDEAD" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GREED_DEATH_BOLT" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GREED_EXTRA_ATTACK" level="5" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GREED_EXPLOIT_BONE" level="7" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GREED_AUGMENT_UNDEAD" level="15" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GREED_IMMORTALITY" level="20" />
		</rules>
	</element>
		<element name="Values of Greed" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GREED_VALUES_OF_GREED">
			<description>
				<p>Greed is wanting more than you have, either material or intangible.</p>
				<p class="indent"><strong><em>Want.</em></strong> Never allow your ambitions to end or you will grow stagnant and die.</p>
				<p class="indent"><strong><em>Worldliness.</em></strong> This current existence is what matters; embrace it.</p>
				<p class="indent"><strong><em>Possessions.</em></strong> The things you have define you as much as the things you do.</p>
				<p class="indent"><strong><em>Selfishness.</em></strong> Life is a zero-sum game. To give something is to lose something.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description></description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Sin Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GREED_SIN_SPELLS">
			<description>
				<p>You gain Sin spells at the witchguard levels listed.</p>
				<h5 class="caption">SIN OF GREED SPELLS</h5>
				<table>
					<thead>
						<tr><td>Witchguard Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
					</thead>
					<tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>false life, inflict wounds</em></td></tr>
					<tr><td>5th</td><td><em>blindness/deafness, ray of enfeeblement</em></td></tr>
					<tr><td>9th</td><td><em>animate dead, speak with dead</em></td></tr>
					<tr><td>13th</td><td><em>blight, death ward</em></td></tr>
					<tr><td>17th</td><td><em>danse macabre, negative energy flood</em></td></tr>
				</table>
			</description>
			<sheet display="false">
				<description></description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FALSE_LIFE" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INFLICT_WOUNDS" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLINDNESS_DEAFNESS" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RAY_OF_ENFEEBLEMENT" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANIMATE_DEAD" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_DEAD" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLIGHT" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="13" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DEATH_WARD" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="13" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_DANSE_MACABRE" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="17" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_NEGATIVE_ENERGY_FLOOD" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="17" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Command Undead" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GREED_COMMAND_UNDEAD">
			<description>
				<p>When you choose this Sin at 3rd level, you learn to steal control over undead creatures. Once per short or long rest, as an action, you target one undead creature you can see within 30 feet. The target must make a Wisdom saving throw against your witchguard spell save DC. On a failed saving throw, the creature must obey your commands for the next 24 hours, or until you use this feature again. An undead whose challenge rating is equal to or greater than your witchguard level is immune to this effect.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet action="Action" usage="1/Short Rest">
				<description>You target one undead creature you can see within 30 feet. The target must make a Wisdom saving throw against your witchguard spell save DC. On a failed saving throw, the creature must obey your commands for the next 24 hours, or until you use this feature again. An undead whose challenge rating is equal to or greater than your witchguard level is immune to this effect.</description>
				<description level="15">You target two undead creatures you can see within 30 feet. The target must make a Wisdom saving throw against your witchguard spell save DC. On a failed saving throw, the creature must obey your commands for the next 24 hours, or until you use this feature again. An undead whose challenge rating is equal to or greater than your witchguard level is immune to this effect.</description>
			</sheet>
		</element>
		<element name="Death Bolt" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GREED_DEATH_BOLT">
			<description>
				<p>Also at 3rd level, you gain resistance to necrotic damage. Additionally, you may choose to change the damage type of your Doom Bolt feature from psychic to necrotic whenever you use it.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description>You may choose to change the damage type of your Doom Bolt feature from psychic to necrotic whenever you use it.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_NECROTIC" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Extra Attack" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GREED_EXTRA_ATTACK">
			<description>
				<p>Beginning at 5th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description>You can attack twice whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <stat name="extra attack:count" value="2" level="5" bonus="extra attack" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Exploit Bone" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GREED_EXPLOIT_BONE">
			<description>
				<p>At 7th level, you have learned several innovative magical uses for a creature’s skeleton. A pile of bones, a corpse of a Small or larger creature, or an undead creature under your control within 30 feet of you are all viable targets for the following effects.</p>
				<p class="indent"><strong><em>Bone Armor.</em></strong> As an action, you may call the bones from the target to cling to you in a protective manner, reinforcing your armor. For one hour, you gain temporary hit points equal to your witchguard level + your Intelligence modifier.</p>
				<p class="indent"><strong><em>Bone Shield.</em></strong> As a reaction, you can summon the bones from the target to fuse together and form a shield on your arm to block an incoming blow. Until the beginning of your next turn, your AC increases by an amount equal to your Intelligence modifier (a minimum of 1), ranged attacks (including spell attacks) have disadvantage against you, and you have advantage on Dexterity saving throws. If you have a weapon already in this hand, you are forced to put it away as part of this reaction.</p>
				<p class="indent"><strong><em>Bone Spear.</em></strong> As an action, you can form the bones of the target into a long spike, which you can throw in an attempt to impale several foes in a line. All creatures in a line 100 feet long and 5 feet wide starting from you in a direction you choose must make a Dexterity saving throw against your spell save DC. On a failed save, a creature takes 3d6 piercing and 3d6 necrotic damage, or half as much on a success. The damage dice increase to d8s at 11th level, d10s at 15th level, and d12s at 19th level.</p>
				<p class="indent"><strong><em>Bone Wall.</em></strong> As an action, you can turn the bones of the target into a barricade, blocking both movement and potentially the attacks of your enemies. You designate a line on a solid surface that is 5 feet thick and 10 feet high that begins and ends within 60 feet of you to become a bone wall. The corpse of a Small creature can make a wall 25-feet long; and for each size category above Small the wall can be an additional 10 feet long.</p>
				<p class="indent">When the wall appears, each hostile creature within its area must make a Dexterity saving throw against your spell save DC as they are shoved to a side of the wall that you designate. On a failed save, a creature takes 1d6 piercing and 1d6 necrotic damage, or half as much damage on a successful save. The wall parts to allow you, your attacks, and any creature you designate, as well as their attacks through, closing together again as they pass.</p>
				<p class="indent">The wall is an object made of bone that can be damaged and thus breached. The wall has an AC of 15 and hit points equal to your witchguard level x 3. Reducing the wall to 0 hit points destroys it. The damage dice increase to d8s at 11th level, d10s at 15th level, and d12s at 19th level.</p>
				<p class="indent">You may use Exploit Bone a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier (a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you complete a long rest.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet usage="{{aura-of-aggression:bonus}}/Long Rest">
				<description>A pile of bones, a corpse of a Small or larger creature, or an undead creature under your control within 30 feet of you are all viable targets for the following effects. Bone Armor (action). Bone Shield (reaction). Bone Spear (action). Bone Wall (action).</description>
			</sheet>
		</element>
		<element name="Augment Undead" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GREED_AUGMENT_UNDEAD">
			<description>
				<p>At 15th level, when you cast animate dead, you can target one additional corpse or pile of bones, creating another zombie or skeleton. Similarly, when you use your Command Undead feature, you may target up to two undead creatures within 30 feet of you.</p>
				<p class="indent">Whenever you create an undead using a necromancy spell or take control of an undead using your Command Undead feature, it has additional benefits:</p>
				<ul>
					<li>The creature’s hit point maximum is increased by an amount equal to your witchguard level.</li>
					<li>The creature adds your proficiency bonus to its weapon damage rolls.</li>
				</ul>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description>When you cast animate dead, you can target one additional corpse or pile of bones, creating another zombie or skeleton. Whenever you create an undead using a necromancy spell or take control of an undead using your Command Undead feature, it has additional benefits: The creature’s hit point maximum is increased by {{level:witchguard}}. The creature adds {{proficiency}} to its weapon damage rolls.</description>
			</sheet>
		</element>
		<element name="Immortality" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GREED_IMMORTALITY">
			<description>
				<p>By 20th level, you have learned a ritual to attain immortality in undeath. The next time you die, you can choose to rise again, regaining all hit points. When you do this, your creature type changes to undead, and two of your Strength, Constitution, or Intelligence scores (your choice) increase by 2. Your maximum for those scores increases by 2.</p>
				<p class="indent">Additionally, you become immune to necrotic and poison damage, the frightened and poisoned conditions, and exhaustion. You gain darkvision out to 120 feet, and unless you are incapacitated, you and undead creatures under your control within 60 feet of you have advantage on saving throws against features that turn undead.</p>
				<p class="indent">This effect is permanent. Once you have used this ability, you cannot use it again.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet usage="Once">
				<description></description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Immortality" supports="Witchguard Rise as Undead" optional="true" />
			</rules>
		</element>
            <element name="Rise as Undead" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GREED_IMMORTALITY_RISE_AS_UNDEAD">
                <supports>Witchguard Rise as Undead</supports>
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p></p>
                </description>
                <setters>
                    <set name="type">Undead</set>
                </setters>
                <sheet>
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_SUPERIORDARKVISION" />
                    <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_IMMUNITY_NECROTIC" />
                    <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_IMMUNITY_POISON" />
                    <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_SE_WG_RACIAL_TRAIT_WITCHGUARD_GREED_RISEN_AS_UNDEAD" />
                    <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Undead Ability Score Improvement" supports="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GREED_IMMORTALITY_RISE_AS_UNDEAD_STRENGTH|ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GREED_IMMORTALITY_RISE_AS_UNDEAD_CONSTITUTION|ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GREED_IMMORTALITY_RISE_AS_UNDEAD_INTELLIGENCE" number="2" />
                </rules>
            </element>
                <element name="Strength" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GREED_IMMORTALITY_RISE_AS_UNDEAD_STRENGTH">
                    <compendium display="false" />
                    <description>
                        <p></p>
                    </description>
                    <sheet display="false">
                        <description></description>
                    </sheet>
                    <rules>
                        <stat name="strength" value="2" />
                        <stat name="strength:max" value="2" />
                    </rules>
                </element>
                <element name="Constitution" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GREED_IMMORTALITY_RISE_AS_UNDEAD_CONSTITUTION">
                    <compendium display="false" />
                    <description>
                        <p></p>
                    </description>
                    <sheet display="false">
                        <description></description>
                    </sheet>
                    <rules>
                        <stat name="constitution" value="2" />
                        <stat name="constitution:max" value="2" />
                    </rules>
                </element>
                <element name="Intelligence" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GREED_IMMORTALITY_RISE_AS_UNDEAD_INTELLIGENCE">
                    <compendium display="false" />
                    <description>
                        <p></p>
                    </description>
                    <sheet display="false">
                        <description></description>
                    </sheet>
                    <rules>
                        <stat name="intelligence" value="2" />
                        <stat name="intelligence:max" value="2" />
                    </rules>
                </element>
                <element name="Risen as Undead" type="Racial Trait" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_RACIAL_TRAIT_WITCHGUARD_GREED_RISEN_AS_UNDEAD">
                    <compendium display="false" />
                    <description>
                        <p>You are considered undead. You are immune to the poisoned and frightened conditions. Unless you are incapacitated, you and undead creatures under your control within 60 feet of you have advantage on saving throws against features that turn undead.</p>
                    </description>
                    <sheet>
                        <description>You are considered undead. You are immune to the poisoned and frightened conditions. Unless you are incapacitated, you and undead creatures under your control within 60 feet of you have advantage on saving throws against features that turn undead.</description>
                    </sheet>
                </element>


	<element name="Sin of Lust" type="Archetype" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_WITCHGUARD_LUST">
		<supports>Witchguard Mortal Sin</supports>
		<description>
			<p>The Sin of Lust is desire unchecked for those things carnal and giving in to passion rather than resisting temptation. Some prudish gods-botherers believe this to be a great evil, but what is Lust other than unfiltered love? Apostles of Lust, also known as Tempters and Temptresses, are usually thought to be the least threatening of all witchguards, but that would be a grave mistake: Using their natural charm backed by powerful enchantments, they almost always get their way.</p>
			<div element="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LUST_VALUES_OF_LUST" />
			<div element="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LUST_SIN_SPELLS" />
			<div element="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LUST_SHARP_WIT" />
			<div element="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LUST_SAVVY_DEFENSE" />
			<div element="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LUST_BEWITCHING_BOLT" />
			<div element="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LUST_EXTRA_ATTACK" />
			<div element="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LUST_HEARTBREAKER" />
			<div element="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LUST_AURA_OF_YEARNING" />
			<div element="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LUST_OBJECT_OF_DESIRE" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LUST_VALUES_OF_LUST" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LUST_SIN_SPELLS" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LUST_SHARP_WIT" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LUST_SAVVY_DEFENSE" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LUST_BEWITCHING_BOLT" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LUST_EXTRA_ATTACK" level="5" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LUST_HEARTBREAKER" level="7" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LUST_AURA_OF_YEARNING" level="15" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LUST_OBJECT_OF_DESIRE" level="20" />
		</rules>
	</element>
		<element name="Values of Lust" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LUST_VALUES_OF_LUST">
			<description>
				<p>Lust is excessive craving for the senses to be gratified, and sharing that desire with those around you.</p>
				<p class="indent"><strong><em>Desire.</em></strong> Crave others and make them crave you in turn.</p>
				<p class="indent"><strong><em>Satisfaction.</em></strong> Indulge your longings as they arise; to do otherwise leads to repression.</p>
				<p class="indent"><strong><em>Shamelessness.</em></strong> Care not what others may think. Yours is the true path.</p>
				<p class="indent"><strong><em>Passion.</em></strong> Do not supress your emotions. Passion is not a weakness, but your greatest strength.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description></description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Sin Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LUST_SIN_SPELLS">
			<description>
				<p>You gain Sin spells at the witchguard levels listed.</p>
				<h5 class="caption">SIN OF LUST SPELLS</h5>
				<table>
					<thead>
						<tr><td>Witchguard Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
					</thead>
					<tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>charm person, disguise self</em></td></tr>
					<tr><td>5th</td><td><em>enthrall, suggestion</em></td></tr>
					<tr><td>9th</td><td><em>hypnotic pattern, major image</em></td></tr>
					<tr><td>13th</td><td><em>charm monster, compulsion</em></td></tr>
					<tr><td>17th</td><td><em>dominate person, modify memory</em></td></tr>
				</table>
			</description>
			<sheet display="false">
				<description></description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CHARM_PERSON" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISGUISE_SELF" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENTHRALL" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SUGGESTION" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HYPNOTIC_PATTERN" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAJOR_IMAGE" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_CHARM_MONSTER" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="13" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMPULSION" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="13" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DOMINATE_PERSON" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="17" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MODIFY_MEMORY" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="17" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Sharp Wit" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LUST_SHARP_WIT">
			<description>
				<p>When you choose this Sin at 3rd level, you gain proficiency in either the Deception or Persuasion skills.</p>
				<p class="indent">Additionally, whenever you make a Charisma check or saving throw, you gain a bonus to the check equal to your Intelligence modifier.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description>Whenever you make a Charisma check or saving throw, you gain a +{{intelligence:modifier}} bonus to the check.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency, Sharp Wit" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_DECEPTION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERSUASION" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Savvy Defense" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LUST_SAVVY_DEFENSE">
			<description>
				<p>Also at 3rd level, while you are not wearing any armor, your AC equals 10 + your Dexterity modifier + your Intelligence modifier. You can use a shield and still gain this benefit. You may also gain the benefits of the Defense Fighting Style while wearing no armor.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description>While you aren’t wearing armor, your AC equals {{ac:savvy defense witchguard}}. You can use a shield and still gain this benefit.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <stat name="ac:savvy defense witchguard:base" value="10" />
                <stat name="ac:savvy defense witchguard:dexterity" value="dexterity:modifier" />
                <stat name="ac:savvy defense witchguard:intelligence" value="intelligence:modifier" />
                <stat name="ac:savvy defense witchguard" value="ac:savvy defense witchguard:base" />
                <stat name="ac:savvy defense witchguard" value="ac:savvy defense witchguard:dexterity" />
                <stat name="ac:savvy defense witchguard" value="ac:savvy defense witchguard:intelligence" />
                <stat name="ac:calculation" value="ac:savvy defense witchguard" bonus="calculation" equipped="[armor:none]" alt="Savvy Defense (Witchguard)" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Bewitching Bolt" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LUST_BEWITCHING_BOLT">
			<description>
				<p>Finally at 3rd level, whenever a target fails its Wisdom save against your Doom Bolt feature, you can spend 5 points from your pool to cause the creature to become charmed by you for one minute. The charmed target can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect early on a success. When the effect ends, the creature knows it was charmed by you.</p>
				<p class="indent">You cannot charm a creature this way if it also took damage or became frightened of you from Doom Bolt.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description>Whenever a target fails its Wisdom save against your Doom Bolt feature, you can spend 5 points from your pool to cause the creature to become charmed by you for one minute. The charmed target can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect early on a success. When the effect ends, the creature knows it was charmed by you. You cannot charm a creature this way if it also took damage or became frightened of you from Doom Bolt.</description>
			</sheet>
		</element>
		<element name="Extra Attack" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LUST_EXTRA_ATTACK">
			<description>
				<p>Beginning at 5th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description>You can attack twice whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <stat name="extra attack:count" value="2" level="5" bonus="extra attack" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Heartbreaker" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LUST_HEARTBREAKER">
			<description>
				<p>At 7th level, creatures charmed by you will attack their own allies if you so desire. As a bonus action on your turn, you can force a creature charmed by you to make a Wisdom save against your Spell Save DC. On a failure, you may command it to spend its turn moving up to its speed and making one attack against any target that it can see. This movement does not provoke opportunity attacks.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet action="Bonus Action">
				<description>As a bonus action on your turn, you can force a creature charmed by you to make a Wisdom save against your Spell Save DC. On a failure, you may command it to spend its turn moving up to its speed and making one attack against any target that it can see. This movement does not provoke opportunity attacks.</description>
			</sheet>
		</element>
		<element name="Aura of Yearning" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LUST_AURA_OF_YEARNING">
			<description>
				<p>At 15th level, your appearance permanently gains a fiendish aspect that makes you darkly alluring.</p>
				<p class="indent">In addition, all enemy creatures within 10 feet of you have disadvantage on saving throws made to resist being charmed while you are conscious. Creatures that are normally immune to being charmed, such as undead and constructs, lose that immunity while within your aura, but do not suffer disadvantage.</p>
				<p class="indent">At 18th level, the range of this aura increases to 30 feet.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description>All enemy creatures within {{aura-of-aggression:range}} feet of you have disadvantage on saving throws made to resist being charmed while you are conscious. Creatures that are normally immune to being charmed, such as undead and constructs, lose that immunity while within your aura, but do not suffer disadvantage.</description>
			</sheet>
		</element>
		<element name="Object of Desire" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LUST_OBJECT_OF_DESIRE">
			<description>
				<p>At 20th level, you can change your form to that of any humanoid within sight’s interpersonal ideal. Using your action, you undergo the transformation. Until you choose to dismiss this effect as another action, you gain the following benefits:</p>
				<ul>
					<li>You have resistance to all damage dealt by the creature (their attacks, spells, and other effects).</li>
					<li>Whenever the creature hits you with an attack, it takes psychic damage equal to half the damage you take from the attack.</li>
					<li>You have advantage on any ability check to interact socially with the creature.</li>
					<li>If the creature is charmed by you, you automatically succeed on any ability check to interact socially with it.</li>
				</ul>
				<p class="indent">You can do this a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier (a minimum of once). You regain all uses of this feature when you finish a long rest.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet action="Action" usage="{{aura-of-aggression:bonus}}/Long Rest">
				<description>You transform to that of any humanoid within sight’s interpersonal ideal. Until you choose to dismiss this effect as another action, you gain the following benefits: You have resistance to all damage dealt by the creature (their attacks, spells, and other effects). Whenever the creature hits you with an attack, it takes psychic damage equal to half the damage you take from the attack. You have advantage on any ability check to interact socially with the creature. If the creature is charmed by you, you automatically succeed on any ability check to interact socially with it.</description>
			</sheet>
		</element>


	<element name="Sin of Envy" type="Archetype" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_WITCHGUARD_ENVY">
		<supports>Witchguard Mortal Sin</supports>
		<description>
			<p>The sadness or resentment one feels when confronted with the prosperity or qualities of another, the Sin of Envy is said to drive a man against his neighbors as he tries to outdo them at every turn. In truth, however, Envy is one of the greatest motivators to better oneself, as wanting more than you have is the only way to avoid listlessness and stagnation. So it is that proponents of Envy, known as Despoilers, are amongst the most decorated of witchguards; if not by their own deeds, than at least by the failings and decrepitude of those that once rivaled them.</p>
			<div element="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ENVY_VALUES_OF_ENVY" />
			<div element="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ENVY_SIN_SPELLS" />
			<div element="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ENVY_MALEDICTION" />
			<div element="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ENVY_EXTRA_ATTACK" />
			<div element="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ENVY_AURA_OF_RESENTMENT" />
			<div element="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ENVY_SPITEFUL_REVELRY" />
			<div element="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ENVY_BRING_LOW_THE_MIGHTY" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ENVY_VALUES_OF_ENVY" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ENVY_SIN_SPELLS" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ENVY_MALEDICTION" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ENVY_EXTRA_ATTACK" level="5" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ENVY_AURA_OF_RESENTMENT" level="7" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ENVY_SPITEFUL_REVELRY" level="15" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ENVY_BRING_LOW_THE_MIGHTY" level="20" />
		</rules>
	</element>
		<element name="Values of Envy" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ENVY_VALUES_OF_ENVY">
			<description>
				<p>Wanting that which belongs to another is the core of Envy.</p>
				<p class="indent"><strong><em>Discontent.</em></strong> It is never enough. Continue to achieve; if you lose your inertia, others shall pass you by.</p>
				<p class="indent"><strong><em>Covetousness.</em></strong> No matter how high you have risen, someone, somewhere has something you do not.</p>
				<p class="indent"><strong><em>Resentment.</em></strong> Do not just desire another’s success; hate them for having it.</p>
				<p class="indent"><strong><em>Schadenfreude.</em></strong> When another fails, you have succeeded by comparison.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description></description>
			</sheet>
		</element>
		<element name="Sin Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ENVY_SIN_SPELLS">
			<description>
				<p>You gain Sin spells at the witchguard levels listed.</p>
				<h5 class="caption">SIN OF ENVY SPELLS</h5>
				<table>
					<thead>
						<tr><td>Witchguard Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
					</thead>
					<tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>bane, hex</em></td></tr>
					<tr><td>5th</td><td><em>earthbind, heat metal</em></td></tr>
					<tr><td>9th</td><td><em>bestow curse, slow</em></td></tr>
					<tr><td>13th</td><td><em>elemental bane, sickening radiance</em></td></tr>
					<tr><td>17th</td><td><em>contagion, synaptic static</em></td></tr>
				</table>
			</description>
			<sheet display="false">
				<description></description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BANE" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HEX" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_EARTHBIND" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HEAT_METAL" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BESTOW_CURSE" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SLOW" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ELEMENTAL_BANE" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="13" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_SICKENING_RADIANCE" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="13" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONTAGION" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="17" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_SYNAPTIC_STATIC" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="17" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Malediction" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ENVY_MALEDICTION">
			<description>
				<p>When you choose this Sin at 3rd level, you gain the ability to place accumulating adversities on your enemies, multiplying their misfortunes. You gain a die called a Malediction die, which begins as a d4 but increases in size by one step (d6, d8, d10, up to d12) with each application of Malediction upon the same target.</p>
				<p class="indent">As a bonus action on your turn, you can glare at a creature within 60 feet of you that you can see. Afterwards, once per round when an attack roll is made against the target, you may roll your Malediction die, adding the number rolled to that attack roll. You can do this before or after the roll is made, but must decide before the DM says whether the roll succeeds or fails.</p>
				<p class="indent">This effect lasts until and is reset upon you being incapacitated, you or the target being killed, or you taking a short or long rest. A remove curse spell also ends and resets this effect. You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier (a minimum of once). You regain any expended uses when you finish a long rest.</p>
				<p class="indent">At 7th level, you regain any expended uses when you finish a short or long rest.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="{{malediction:uses}}/Long Rest">
				<description>You gain a die called a Malediction die, which begins as a d4 but increases in size by one step (d6, d8, d10, up to d12) with each application of Malediction upon the same target. You choose a creature within 60 feet of you that you can see. Afterwards, once per round when an attack roll is made against the target, you may roll your Malediction die, adding the number rolled to that attack roll.</description>
				<description level="7" usage="{{malediction:uses}}/Short Rest">You gain a die called a Malediction die, which begins as a d4 but increases in size by one step (d6, d8, d10, up to d12) with each application of Malediction upon the same target. You choose a creature within 60 feet of you that you can see. Afterwards, once per round when an attack roll is made against the target, you may roll your Malediction die, adding the number rolled to that attack roll.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <stat name="malediction:uses" value="1" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="malediction:uses" value="intelligence:modifier" bonus="base" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Extra Attack" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ENVY_EXTRA_ATTACK">
			<description>
				<p>Beginning at 5th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description>You can attack twice whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <stat name="extra attack:count" value="2" level="5" bonus="extra attack" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Aura of Resentment" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ENVY_AURA_OF_RESENTMENT">
			<description>
				<p>Starting at 7th level, hostile creatures within 10 feet of you have a penalty to the first damage rolls they make each round equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of 1) while you are conscious.</p>
				<p class="indent">At 18th level, the range of this aura increases to 30 feet.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description>Hostile creatures within {{aura-of-aggression:range}} feet of you have -{{aura-of-aggression:bonus}} a penalty to the first damage rolls they make each round while you are conscious.</description>
			</sheet>
		</element>
		<element name="Spiteful Revelry" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ENVY_SPITEFUL_REVELRY">
			<description>
				<p>At 15th level, the failure of others incites you to greater heights of prowess. If a hostile creature you can see is reduced to 0 hitpoints within 60 feet of you, at the beginning of your next turn your weapon attacks deal an additional 1d4 psychic damage for one minute.</p>
				<p class="indent">For every subsequent hostile creature that is reduced to 0 hitpoints within 60 feet of you, at the beginning of your next turn the size of the psychic damage die increases by one step (d6, d8, d10, up to d12). This effect cannot trigger more than once per turn.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description>If a hostile creature you can see is reduced to 0 hitpoints within 60 feet of you, at the beginning of your next turn your weapon attacks deal an additional 1d4 psychic damage for one minute. For every subsequent hostile creature that is reduced to 0 hitpoints within 60 feet of you, at the beginning of your next turn the size of the psychic damage die increases by one step (d6, d8, d10, up to d12). This effect cannot trigger more than once per turn.</description>
			</sheet>
		</element>
		<element name="Bring Low the Mighty" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ENVY_BRING_LOW_THE_MIGHTY">
			<description>
				<p>At 20th level, you have learned a curse so heinous that the gods themselves dare not speak it.</p>
				<p class="indent">As an action, you utter the words and designate a creature you can see. The target and all hostile creatures within 30 feet of it lose resistance and reduction to psychic damage if they have it, and become vulnerable to psychic damage. If a target is immune to psychic damage, it instead merely loses that immunity. If a target is already vulnerable to psychic damage, it instead takes 5d8 psychic damage.</p>
				<p class="indent">This effect lasts for one minute. Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a long rest.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet action="Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
				<description>You designate a creature you can see. The target and all hostile creatures within 30 feet of it lose resistance and reduction to psychic damage if they have it, and become vulnerable to psychic damage. If a target is immune to psychic damage, it instead merely loses that immunity. If a target is already vulnerable to psychic damage, it instead takes 5d8 psychic damage.</description>
			</sheet>
		</element>


	<element name="Sin of Gluttony" type="Archetype" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_WITCHGUARD_GLUTTONY">
		<supports>Witchguard Mortal Sin</supports>
		<description>
			<p>One of the greatest instincts we have is that of hunger. But of course, to the pious, taking pleasure in consuming sustenance is yet another sin. The self-righteous would deny one the simple joy of overindulgence, whether from food, drink, or other substances. Because, as they say, the greatest pleasures are in the life yet to come. Devourers, however, as practitioners of Gluttony are known, pay them no heed. They know that great euphoria and power can come from feasting on whatever nourishment is at hand - even if it is the very life force of others.</p>
			<div element="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GLUTTONY_VALUES_OF_GLUTTONY" />
			<div element="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GLUTTONY_SIN_SPELLS" />
			<div element="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GLUTTONY_WELL_FED" />
			<div element="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GLUTTONY_EXTRA_ATTACK" />
			<div element="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GLUTTONY_FEASTING_BLADES" />
			<div element="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GLUTTONY_VORACIOUS_ARTEFACT" />
			<div element="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GLUTTONY_DEVOURER" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GLUTTONY_VALUES_OF_GLUTTONY" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GLUTTONY_SIN_SPELLS" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GLUTTONY_WELL_FED" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GLUTTONY_EXTRA_ATTACK" level="5" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GLUTTONY_FEASTING_BLADES" level="7" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GLUTTONY_VORACIOUS_ARTEFACT" level="15" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GLUTTONY_DEVOURER" level="20" />
		</rules>
	</element>
		<element name="Values of Gluttony" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GLUTTONY_VALUES_OF_GLUTTONY">
			<description>
				<p>Gluttony is, put simply, taking into one’s body more than one needs.</p>
				<p class="indent"><strong><em>Hunger.</em></strong> Be grateful for every morsel; after all, there are children starving in the slums.</p>
				<p class="indent"><strong><em>Consumption.</em></strong> Waste not, want not.</p>
				<p class="indent"><strong><em>Extravagance.</em></strong> Why have beef when you could have venison?</p>
				<p class="indent"><strong><em>Overindulgence.</em></strong> Satisfaction is a lie. There is always room for more.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description></description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Sin Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GLUTTONY_SIN_SPELLS">
			<description>
				<p>You gain Sin spells at the witchguard levels listed.</p>
				<h5 class="caption">SIN OF GLUTTONY SPELLS</h5>
				<table>
					<thead>
						<tr><td>Witchguard Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
					</thead>
					<tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>goodberry, purify food and drink</em></td></tr>
					<tr><td>5th</td><td><em>aid, lesser restoration</em></td></tr>
					<tr><td>9th</td><td><em>create food and water, vampiric touch</em></td></tr>
					<tr><td>13th</td><td><em>aura of life, aura of purity</em></td></tr>
					<tr><td>17th</td><td><em>enervation, greater restoration</em></td></tr>
				</table>
			</description>
			<sheet display="false">
				<description></description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GOODBERRY" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PURIFY_FOOD_AND_DRINK" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AID" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LESSER_RESTORATION" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CREATE_FOOD_AND_WATER" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_VAMPIRIC_TOUCH" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AURA_OF_LIFE" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="13" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AURA_OF_PURITY" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="13" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ENERVATION" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="17" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GREATER_RESTORATION" spellcasting="Witchguard" prepared="true" level="17" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Well-Fed" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GLUTTONY_WELL_FED">
			<description>
				<p>When you choose this Sin at 3rd level, your hit point maximum increases by 3, and increases by 1 every time you gain a level in this class.</p>
				<p class="indent">Additionally, any hit dice gained from this class become d12s.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description>Any hit dice gained from this class become d12s.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <stat name="hp" value="level:witchguard" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Extra Attack" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GLUTTONY_EXTRA_ATTACK">
			<description>
				<p>Beginning at 5th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description>You can attack twice whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <stat name="extra attack:count" value="2" level="5" bonus="extra attack" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Feasting Blades" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GLUTTONY_FEASTING_BLADES">
			<description>
				<p>Starting at 7th level, your attacks steal a portion of your opponents’ life force.</p>
				<p class="indent">The first time you deal damage to a creature on your turn each round, you regain a number of hit points equal to your Intelligence modifier (a minimum of 1). You can surpass your maximum hit points this way; if you are already at full hit points, you instead gain the same number of temporary hit points. These temporary hit points can add to each other up to twice your witchguard level, but they can not add to temporary hit points gained in any other manner.</p>
				<p class="indent">Temporary hit points gained in this manner expire after one hour.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description>The first time you deal damage to a creature on your turn each round, you regain {{aura-of-aggression:bonus}} hit points. You can surpass your maximum hit points this way; if you are already at full hit points, you instead gain the same number of temporary hit points, up to {{feasting-blades:limit}} temporary hit points. Temporary hit points gained in this manner expire after one hour.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <stat name="feasting-blades:limit" value="level:witchguard" />
                <stat name="feasting-blades:limit" value="level:witchguard" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Voracious Artefact" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GLUTTONY_VORACIOUS_ARTEFACT">
			<description>
				<p>At 15th level, the fiends within your artefact cry out in hunger. Whenever you expend a spell slot to deal damage with your Possessed Artefact, you regain a number of hit points equal to three times the level of the spell slot expended. This healing can surpass your maximum hit points and add to temporary hit points the same as with your Feasting Blades feature.</p>
				<p class="indent">Additionally, the maximum temporary hit points you can have at once from these features increases to three times your witchguard level.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description>Whenever you expend a spell slot to deal damage with your Possessed Artefact, you regain a number of hit points equal to three times the level of the spell slot expended. This healing can surpass your maximum hit points and add to temporary hit points the same as with your Feasting Blades feature, up to {{feasting-blades:limit}} temporary hit points.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <stat name="feasting-blades:limit" value="level:witchguard" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Devourer" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GLUTTONY_DEVOURER">
			<description>
				<p>By 20th level, you have become a walking black hole. Your Constitution score increases by 4, and your maximum for that score increases by 4.</p>
				<p class="indent">Additionally, as an action, you can force a creature your size or smaller to make a Dexterity saving throw against your spell save DC. On a failure, you swallow the creature whole. A swallowed creature is blinded and restrained, has total cover from attacks and effects from outside of you, and takes 6d6 acid damage at the beginning of each of your turns. This damage counts as damage dealt by you for the purposes of your Feasting Blades feature.</p>
				<p class="indent">If you take 30 damage or more on a single turn from the creature inside you, you must succeed on a DC 15 Constitution saving throw or regurgitate the creature, which falls prone in a space within 5 feet of you. If you die, the swallowed creature is no longer restrained and can escape from your corpse by using 5 feet of movement, exiting prone.</p>
				<p class="indent">Once a creature has failed the initial Dexterity saving throw to this feature, you must take a long rest before you may use it again.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet action="Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
				<description>You can force a creature your size or smaller to make a Dexterity saving throw against your spell save DC. On a failure, you swallow the creature whole. A swallowed creature is blinded and restrained, has total cover from attacks and effects from outside of you, and takes 6d6 acid damage at the beginning of each of your turns. This damage counts as damage dealt by you for the purposes of your Feasting Blades feature.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <stat name="constitution:max" value="4" />
                <stat name="constitution" value="4" />
			</rules>
		</element>



  <!-- Witchguard skills -->
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ARCANA">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ATHLETICS">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_DECEPTION">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INTIMIDATION">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERSUASION">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>

  <!-- Witchguard fighting styles -->
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_ARCHERY">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_DEFENSE">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_DUELING">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_GREAT_WEAPON_FIGHTING">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_PROTECTION">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_TWOWEAPON_FIGHTING">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_UA2015_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_CLOSE_QUARTERS_SHOOTER">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_UA2015_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_TUNNEL_FIGHTER">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_RSQUARED_BLACKGUARD_CLASS_FEATURE_BLACKGUARD_FIGHTINGSTYLE_REPRISAL">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTING_STYLE_BLIND_FIGHTING">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTING_STYLE_INTERCEPTION">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTING_STYLE_THROWN_WEAPON_FIGHTING">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTING_STYLE_UNARMED_FIGHTING">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTING_STYLE_SUPERIOR_TECHNIQUE">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>

  <!-- Witchguard spells -->
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ARMOR_OF_AGATHYS">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ARMS_OF_HADAR">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BANISHING_SMITE">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BANISHMENT">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BESTOW_CURSE">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLIGHT">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLINDING_SMITE">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BRANDING_SMITE">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMMAND">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMPELLED_DUEL">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CROWN_OF_MADNESS">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DARKNESS">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DESTRUCTIVE_WAVE">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_EVIL_AND_GOOD">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_MAGIC">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_POISON_AND_DISEASE">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISPEL_EVIL_AND_GOOD">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISPEL_MAGIC">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ELEMENTAL_WEAPON">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ENERVATION">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FEAR">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_FIND_GREATER_STEED">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIND_STEED">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GEAS">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HELLISH_REBUKE">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HEX">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HUNGER_OF_HADAR">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_INFERNAL_CALLING">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INFLICT_WOUNDS">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LOCATE_CREATURE">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LOCATE_OBJECT">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGIC_CIRCLE">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGIC_WEAPON">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_MIND_SPIKE">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PROTECTION_FROM_EVIL_AND_GOOD">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PROTECTION_FROM_POISON">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_REMOVE_CURSE">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SEARING_SMITE">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHADOW_OF_MOIL">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHIELD_OF_FAITH">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_STAGGERING_SMITE">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_SUMMON_GREATER_DEMON">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_SUMMON_LESSER_DEMONS">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_SYNAPTIC_STATIC">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_THUNDEROUS_SMITE">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_VAMPIRIC_TOUCH">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WRATHFUL_SMITE">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_CAUSE_FEAR">
        <supports>Witchguard</supports>
    </append>


  <!-- Fiendish Servant Generation -->
    <element name="Fiendish Servant" type="Race" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_RACE_WITCHGUARD_FIENDISH_SERVANT">
        <description>
            <p>Choosing your fiendish servant should not be taken lightly. While a brute may be an easily-manipulated wall of demon-flesh between you and your foes, a stalker makes for a much more subtle killer, and a dominator can outwit most foes with ease.</p>
            <h4>Fiendish Servant Features</h4>
            <p>All fiendish servants share the following features.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Size.</em></strong> A fiendish servant is size Medium.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Speed.</em></strong> A fiendish servant’s base walking speed is 30 feet.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Languages.</em></strong> A fiendish servant can speak, read, and write Common and the language you chose for your Devil’s Tongue feature.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Natural Weapons.</em></strong> A fiendish servant’s claws, teeth, and/or horns are natural weapons which they can use to make unarmed strikes. If they hit with them, they deal piercing or slashing damage equal to 1d6 + their strength or dexterity modifier, instead of the bludgeoning damage normal for an unarmed strike.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Psychic Resistance.</em></strong> Fiendish servants are resistant to psychic damage.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Senses.</em></strong> A fiendish servant can see in dim light within 60 feet of themselves as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. They can’t discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Type.</em></strong> A fiendish servant is considered a fiend for the purposes of game effects.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_MEDIUM" />
            <stat name="innate speed" value="30" bonus="base" />
            <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON" />
            <select type="Language" name="Devil’s Tongue" supports="ID_LANGUAGE_ABYSSAL|ID_LANGUAGE_INFERNAL" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_SE_WG_RACIAL_TRAIT_WITCHGUARD_FIENDISH_SERVANT_NATURAL_WEAPONS" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_SE_WG_RACIAL_TRAIT_WITCHGUARD_FIENDISH_SERVANT_PSYCHIC_RESISTANCE" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_SE_WG_RACIAL_TRAIT_WITCHGUARD_FIENDISH_SERVANT_SENSES" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_SE_WG_RACIAL_TRAIT_WITCHGUARD_FIENDISH_SERVANT_TYPE" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Natural Weapons" type="Racial Trait" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_RACIAL_TRAIT_WITCHGUARD_FIENDISH_SERVANT_NATURAL_WEAPONS">
            <description>
                <p>A fiendish servant’s claws, teeth, and/or horns are natural weapons which they can use to make unarmed strikes. If they hit with them, they deal piercing or slashing damage equal to 1d6 + their Strength or Dexterity modifier, instead of the bludgeoning damage normal for an unarmed strike.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>A fiendish servant’s claws, teeth, and/or horns are natural weapons which they can use to make unarmed strikes, that deal piercing or slashing damage equal to 1d6 + {{natural-weapons:bonus}}, instead of the bludgeoning damage normal for an unarmed strike.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="natural-weapons:bonus" value="strength:modifier" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="natural-weapons:bonus" value="dexterity:modifier" bonus="base" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Psychic Resistance" type="Racial Trait" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_RACIAL_TRAIT_WITCHGUARD_FIENDISH_SERVANT_PSYCHIC_RESISTANCE">
            <description>
                <p>Fiendish servants are resistant to psychic damage.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_PSYCHIC" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Senses" type="Racial Trait" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_RACIAL_TRAIT_WITCHGUARD_FIENDISH_SERVANT_SENSES">
            <description>
                <p>A fiendish servant can see in dim light within 60 feet of themselves as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. They can’t discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>A fiendish servant can see in dim light within 60 feet of themselves as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. They can’t discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Type" type="Racial Trait" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_RACIAL_TRAIT_WITCHGUARD_FIENDISH_SERVANT_TYPE">
            <description>
                <p>A fiendish servant is considered a fiend for the purposes of game effects.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>A fiendish servant is considered a fiend for the purposes of game effects.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

      <!-- Fiendish Evolutions -->
        <element name="Elemental Infusion" type="Racial Trait" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_RACIAL_TRAIT_WITCHGUARD_FIENDISH_EVOLUTION_ELEMENTAL_INFUSION">
            <supports>Witchguard Fiendish Evolution</supports>
            <description>
                <p>Choose Acid, Cold, Fire, Lightning, Poison, or Thunder. Your servant gains resistance to the chosen damage type. Additionally, once per short rest, as an action, your servant may vomit up this elemental energy. When it uses its breath weapon, each creature in a 15-foot cone or a 5 by 30-foot line (Your choice when the breath weapon is used) must make a saving throw - Dexterity for Acid, Fire, and Lightning; or Constitution for Cold, Poison, or Thunder. The DC for this saving throw equals 8 + your servant’s Constitution modifier + its proficiency bonus. A creature takes 3d6 damage on a failed save, and half as much damage on a successful one. The damage increases to 4d6 at 11th level, and 5d6 at 16th level.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Short Rest" action="Action">
                <description>Your servant may vomit up elemental energy, each creature in a 15-foot cone or a 5 by 30-foot line must make a {{elemental-infusion:saving-throw}} saving throw (save DC {{elemental-infusion:save-dc}} or take {{elemental-infusion:damage-dice}}d6 {{elemental-infusion:damage-type}} damage (half on success).</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="elemental-infusion:save-dc" value="8" />
                <stat name="elemental-infusion:save-dc" value="proficiency" />
                <stat name="elemental-infusion:save-dc" value="constitution:modifier" />
                <stat name="elemental-infusion:damage-dice" value="3" level="3" />
                <stat name="elemental-infusion:damage-dice" value="1" level="11" />
                <stat name="elemental-infusion:damage-dice" value="1" level="16" />
                <select type="Racial Trait" name="Elemental Infusion Element" supports="Fiendish Servant Elemental Infusion" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Acid" type="Racial Trait" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_RACIAL_TRAIT_WITCHGUARD_FIENDISH_EVOLUTION_ELEMENTAL_INFUSION_ACID">
                <supports>Fiendish Servant Elemental Infusion</supports>
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p></p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="elemental-infusion:damage-type" inline="true" value="acid" />
                    <stat name="elemental-infusion:saving-throw" inline="true" value="Dexterity" />
                    <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_ACID" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Cold" type="Racial Trait" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_RACIAL_TRAIT_WITCHGUARD_FIENDISH_EVOLUTION_ELEMENTAL_INFUSION_COLD">
                <supports>Fiendish Servant Elemental Infusion</supports>
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p></p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="elemental-infusion:damage-type" inline="true" value="cold" />
                    <stat name="elemental-infusion:saving-throw" inline="true" value="Constitution" />
                        <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_COLD" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Fire" type="Racial Trait" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_RACIAL_TRAIT_WITCHGUARD_FIENDISH_EVOLUTION_ELEMENTAL_INFUSION_FIRE">
                <supports>Fiendish Servant Elemental Infusion</supports>
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p></p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="elemental-infusion:damage-type" inline="true" value="fire" />
                    <stat name="elemental-infusion:saving-throw" inline="true" value="Dexterity" />
                    <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_FIRE" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Lightning" type="Racial Trait" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_RACIAL_TRAIT_WITCHGUARD_FIENDISH_EVOLUTION_ELEMENTAL_INFUSION_LIGHTNING">
                <supports>Fiendish Servant Elemental Infusion</supports>
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p></p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="elemental-infusion:damage-type" inline="true" value="lightning" />
                    <stat name="elemental-infusion:saving-throw" inline="true" value="Dexterity" />
                    <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_LIGHTNING" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Poison" type="Racial Trait" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_RACIAL_TRAIT_WITCHGUARD_FIENDISH_EVOLUTION_ELEMENTAL_INFUSION_POISON">
                <supports>Fiendish Servant Elemental Infusion</supports>
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p></p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="elemental-infusion:damage-type" inline="true" value="poison" />
                    <stat name="elemental-infusion:saving-throw" inline="true" value="Constitution" />
                    <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_POISON" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Thunder" type="Racial Trait" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_RACIAL_TRAIT_WITCHGUARD_FIENDISH_EVOLUTION_ELEMENTAL_INFUSION_THUNDER">
                <supports>Fiendish Servant Elemental Infusion</supports>
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p></p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="elemental-infusion:damage-type" inline="true" value="thunder" />
                    <stat name="elemental-infusion:saving-throw" inline="true" value="Constitution" />
                    <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_THUNDER" />
                </rules>
            </element>
        <element name="Extra Grasping Limbs" type="Racial Trait" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_RACIAL_TRAIT_WITCHGUARD_FIENDISH_EVOLUTION_EXTRA_GRASPING_LIMBS">
            <supports>Witchguard Fiendish Evolution</supports>
            <description>
                <p>Your servant has more than two arms (or tentacles, pedipalps, etc.). Your servant can only gain the benefit of items held by two of its arms at any given time, and at the beginning of its turn your servant can switch which arms it is benefiting from (no action required). When your servant hits a creature with a melee weapon attack on its turn, it can use a bonus action to attempt to grapple the target. While your servant has at least 3 arms free, it has a climbing speed equal to its walking speed.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Your servant has more than two arms. Your servant can only gain the benefit of items held by two of its arms at any given time, and at the beginning of its turn your servant can switch which arms it is benefiting from (no action required). When your servant hits a creature with a melee weapon attack on its turn, it can use a bonus action to attempt to grapple the target. While your servant has at least 3 arms free, it has a climbing speed of {{speed}} feet.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Extra Walking Limbs" type="Racial Trait" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_RACIAL_TRAIT_WITCHGUARD_FIENDISH_EVOLUTION_EXTRA_WALKING_LIMBS">
            <supports>Witchguard Fiendish Evolution</supports>
            <description>
                <p>Your servant has more than two legs, or instead it has a slithering, snakelike tail. Its walking speed increases by 10 feet, it can add 10 feet to its long jump distance and 5 feet to its high jump distance. It also has advantage on all saving throws to resist being knocked prone.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Your servant has more than two legs, or instead it has a slithering, snakelike tail. It can add 10 feet to its long jump distance and 5 feet to its high jump distance. It also has advantage on all saving throws to resist being knocked prone.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="speed:misc" value="10" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Wings" type="Racial Trait" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_RACIAL_TRAIT_WITCHGUARD_FIENDISH_EVOLUTION_WINGS">
            <supports>Witchguard Fiendish Evolution</supports>
            <description>
                <p>Your servant sprouts leathery wings large enough for it to fly. It gains a 30-foot fly speed.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="speed:fly" value="30" bonus="base" />
            </rules>
        </element>

    <element name="Brute" type="Class" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_WITCHGUARD_FIENDISH_SERVANT_BRUTE">
        <requirements>ID_SE_WG_RACE_WITCHGUARD_FIENDISH_SERVANT</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>Towering slabs of muscle, brutes are equally good at taking damage as they are dishing it out.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">HIT POINTS</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Hit Dice:</strong> 1d10 per brute level</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at 1st Level:</strong> 10 + your Constitution modifier</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at Higher Levels:</strong> 1d10 (or 6) + your Constitution modifier per brute level after 1st</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">PROFICIENCIES</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled mb">
                <li><strong>Armor:</strong> All armor, shields</li>
                <li><strong>Weapons:</strong> Simple weapons, martial weapons</li>
                <li><strong>Tools:</strong> None</li>
            </ul>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Saving Throws:</strong> Strength, Constitution</li>
                <li><strong>Skills:</strong> Two of your choice</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">ABILITY SCORES</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled mb">
                <li><strong>Strength:</strong> 16</li>
                <li><strong>Dexterity:</strong> 10</li>
                <li><strong>Constitution:</strong> 16</li>
                <li><strong>Intelligence:</strong> 8</li>
                <li><strong>Wisdom:</strong> 12</li>
                <li><strong>Charisma:</strong> 10</li>
            </ul>
            <div element="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_WITCHGUARD_FIENDISH_SERVANT_BRUTE_FIGHTING_STYLE" />
            <div element="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_FIENDISH_SERVANT_POSSESSED_ARTEFACT" />
            <div element="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_FIENDISH_SERVANT_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" />
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="hd">d10</set>
            <set name="short">Class option for fiendish servant.</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_MEDIUM_ARMOR" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_HEAVY_ARMOR" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_SHIELDS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_MARTIAL_MELEE_WEAPONS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_STRENGTH" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CONSTITUTION" />
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency, Fiendish Servant" supports="Skill" number="2" />
            <!--<stat name="strength:score:set" value="16" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="dexterity:score:set" value="10" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="constitution:score:set" value="16" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="intelligence:score:set" value="8" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="wisdom:score:set" value="12" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="charisma:score:set" value="10" bonus="base" />-->
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_WITCHGUARD_FIENDISH_SERVANT_BRUTE_FIGHTING_STYLE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_FIENDISH_SERVANT_POSSESSED_ARTEFACT" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_FIENDISH_SERVANT_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" level="4" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Fighting Style" type="Class Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_WITCHGUARD_FIENDISH_SERVANT_BRUTE_FIGHTING_STYLE">
            <description>
                <p>Brutes gain the fighting style feature of fighters.</p>
                <div class="reference">
                    <div element="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE" />
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
    			<select type="Class Feature" name="Fighting Style" supports="Fighting Style" level="1"/>
            </rules>
        </element>


    <element name="Dominator" type="Class" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_WITCHGUARD_FIENDISH_SERVANT_DOMINATOR">
        <requirements>ID_SE_WG_RACE_WITCHGUARD_FIENDISH_SERVANT</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>Among the more darkly attractive of fiends, dominators’ softer features belie a malevolent intellect.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">HIT POINTS</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Hit Dice:</strong> 1d6 per brute level</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at 1st Level:</strong> 6 + your Constitution modifier</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at Higher Levels:</strong> 1d6 (or 4) + your Constitution modifier per brute level after 1st</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">PROFICIENCIES</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled mb">
                <li><strong>Armor:</strong> None</li>
                <li><strong>Weapons:</strong> Daggers, darts, slings, quarterstaffs, light crossbows</li>
                <li><strong>Tools:</strong> None</li>
            </ul>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Saving Throws:</strong> Intelligence, Wisdom</li>
                <li><strong>Skills:</strong> Two of your choice</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">ABILITY SCORES</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled mb">
                <li><strong>Strength:</strong> 8</li>
                <li><strong>Dexterity:</strong> 12</li>
                <li><strong>Constitution:</strong> 10</li>
                <li><strong>Intelligence:</strong> 16</li>
                <li><strong>Wisdom:</strong> 12</li>
                <li><strong>Charisma:</strong> 16</li>
            </ul>
            <div element="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_WITCHGUARD_FIENDISH_SERVANT_DOMINATOR_SPELLCASTING" />
            <div element="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_FIENDISH_SERVANT_POSSESSED_ARTEFACT" />
            <div element="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_FIENDISH_SERVANT_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" />
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="hd">d6</set>
            <set name="short">Class option for fiendish servant.</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_DAGGER" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_DART" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SLING" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_QUARTERSTAFF" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_CROSSBOW_LIGHT" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_INTELLIGENCE" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_WISDOM" />
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency, Fiendish Servant" supports="Skill" number="2" />
            <!--<stat name="strength:score:set" value="8" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="dexterity:score:set" value="12" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="constitution:score:set" value="10" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="intelligence:score:set" value="16" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="wisdom:score:set" value="12" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="charisma:score:set" value="16" bonus="base" />-->
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_WITCHGUARD_FIENDISH_SERVANT_DOMINATOR_SPELLCASTING" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_FIENDISH_SERVANT_POSSESSED_ARTEFACT" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_FIENDISH_SERVANT_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" level="4" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Spellcasting" type="Class Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_WITCHGUARD_FIENDISH_SERVANT_DOMINATOR_SPELLCASTING">
            <description>
                <p>Dominators are capable of casting spells. They learn spells and cantrips at the same rate as Dominators, using the Wizard Spell List. Intelligence or Charisma is their spellcasting ability (player’s choice when the servant is created).</p>
                <div class="reference">
                    <div element="ID_WOTC_PHB_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_KNIGHT_SPELLCASTING" />
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Spellcasting Ability" supports="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_WITCHGUARD_FIENDISH_SERVANT_DOMINATOR_SPELLCASTING_INTELLIGENCE|ID_SE_WG_CLASS_WITCHGUARD_FIENDISH_SERVANT_DOMINATOR_SPELLCASTING_CHARISMA" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Intelligence" type="Class Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_WITCHGUARD_FIENDISH_SERVANT_DOMINATOR_SPELLCASTING_INTELLIGENCE">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p></p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false" />
                <spellcasting name="Dominator" ability="Intelligence" prepare="false" allowReplace="true">
                    <list>Wizard</list>
                </spellcasting>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="dominator:spellcasting:slots:1" value="2" level="3" />
                    <stat name="dominator:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="4" />
                    <stat name="dominator:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="7" />
                    <stat name="dominator:spellcasting:slots:2" value="2" level="7" />
                    <stat name="dominator:spellcasting:slots:2" value="1" level="10" />
                    <stat name="dominator:spellcasting:slots:3" value="2" level="13" />
                    <stat name="dominator:spellcasting:slots:3" value="1" level="16" />
                    <stat name="dominator:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="19" />
                    <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Dominator)" supports="Wizard, 0" level="3" number="2" spellcasting="Dominator" />
                    <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Dominator)" supports="Wizard, 0" level="10" number="1" spellcasting="Dominator" />
                    <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Dominator)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), 1" level="3" number="1" spellcasting="Dominator" />
                    <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Dominator)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), 1" level="3" number="2" spellcasting="Dominator" />
                    <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Dominator)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="4" spellcasting="Dominator"/>
                    <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Dominator)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="7" spellcasting="Dominator"/>
                    <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Dominator)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="8" spellcasting="Dominator"/>
                    <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Dominator)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="10" spellcasting="Dominator"/>
                    <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Dominator)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="11" spellcasting="Dominator"/>
                    <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Dominator)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="13" spellcasting="Dominator"/>
                    <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Dominator)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="14" spellcasting="Dominator"/>
                    <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Dominator)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="16" spellcasting="Dominator"/>
                    <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Dominator)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="19" spellcasting="Dominator"/>
                    <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Dominator)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="20" spellcasting="Dominator"/>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Charisma" type="Class Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_WITCHGUARD_FIENDISH_SERVANT_DOMINATOR_SPELLCASTING_CHARISMA">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p></p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false" />
                <spellcasting name="Dominator" ability="Charisma" prepare="false" allowReplace="true">
                    <list>Wizard</list>
                </spellcasting>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="dominator:spellcasting:slots:1" value="2" level="3" />
                    <stat name="dominator:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="4" />
                    <stat name="dominator:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="7" />
                    <stat name="dominator:spellcasting:slots:2" value="2" level="7" />
                    <stat name="dominator:spellcasting:slots:2" value="1" level="10" />
                    <stat name="dominator:spellcasting:slots:3" value="2" level="13" />
                    <stat name="dominator:spellcasting:slots:3" value="1" level="16" />
                    <stat name="dominator:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="19" />
                    <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Dominator)" supports="Wizard, 0" level="3" number="2" spellcasting="Dominator" />
                    <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Dominator)" supports="Wizard, 0" level="10" number="1" spellcasting="Dominator" />
                    <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Dominator)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), 1" level="3" number="1" spellcasting="Dominator" />
                    <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Dominator)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), 1" level="3" number="2" spellcasting="Dominator" />
                    <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Dominator)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="4" spellcasting="Dominator"/>
                    <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Dominator)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="7" spellcasting="Dominator"/>
                    <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Dominator)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="8" spellcasting="Dominator"/>
                    <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Dominator)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="10" spellcasting="Dominator"/>
                    <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Dominator)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="11" spellcasting="Dominator"/>
                    <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Dominator)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="13" spellcasting="Dominator"/>
                    <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Dominator)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="14" spellcasting="Dominator"/>
                    <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Dominator)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="16" spellcasting="Dominator"/>
                    <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Dominator)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="19" spellcasting="Dominator"/>
                    <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Dominator)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="20" spellcasting="Dominator"/>
                </rules>
            </element>


    <element name="Stalker" type="Class" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_WITCHGUARD_FIENDISH_SERVANT_STALKER">
        <requirements>ID_SE_WG_RACE_WITCHGUARD_FIENDISH_SERVANT</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>These fiends tend to be difficult to describe; always darting around, translucent and shadowy as they are.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">HIT POINTS</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Hit Dice:</strong> 1d8 per brute level</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at 1st Level:</strong> 8 + your Constitution modifier</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at Higher Levels:</strong> 1d8 (or 5) + your Constitution modifier per brute level after 1st</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">PROFICIENCIES</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled mb">
                <li><strong>Armor:</strong> Light armor</li>
                <li><strong>Weapons:</strong> Simple weapons, hand crossbows, longswords, rapiers, shortswords</li>
                <li><strong>Tools:</strong> None</li>
            </ul>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Saving Throws:</strong> Throws: Dexterity, Intelligence</li>
                <li><strong>Skills:</strong> Three of your choice</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">ABILITY SCORES</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled mb">
                <li><strong>Strength:</strong> 10</li>
                <li><strong>Dexterity:</strong> 16</li>
                <li><strong>Constitution:</strong> 14</li>
                <li><strong>Intelligence:</strong> 12</li>
                <li><strong>Wisdom:</strong> 14</li>
                <li><strong>Charisma:</strong> 8</li>
            </ul>
            <div element="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_WITCHGUARD_FIENDISH_SERVANT_STALKER_SNEAK_ATTACK" />
            <div element="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_FIENDISH_SERVANT_POSSESSED_ARTEFACT" />
            <div element="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_FIENDISH_SERVANT_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" />
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="hd">d8</set>
            <set name="short">Class option for fiendish servant.</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_CROSSBOW_HAND" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_LONGSWORD" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_RAPIER" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SHORTSWORD" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_DEXTERITY" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_INTELLIGENCE" />
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency, Fiendish Servant" supports="Skill" number="3" />
            <!--<stat name="strength:score:set" value="10" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="dexterity:score:set" value="16" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="constitution:score:set" value="14" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="intelligence:score:set" value="12" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="wisdom:score:set" value="14" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="charisma:score:set" value="8" bonus="base" />-->
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_WITCHGUARD_FIENDISH_SERVANT_STALKER_SNEAK_ATTACK" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_FIENDISH_SERVANT_POSSESSED_ARTEFACT" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_FIENDISH_SERVANT_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" level="4" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Sneak Attack" type="Class Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_WITCHGUARD_FIENDISH_SERVANT_STALKER_SNEAK_ATTACK">
            <description>
                <p>Stalkers gain the Sneak Attack feature of rogues, starting at 1d6 damage at level 3, and increasing to 2d6 at level 6, 3d6 at level 9, 4d6 at level 12, 5d6 at level 15, and 6d6 at level 18.</p>
                <div class="reference">
                    <div element="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_ROGUE_SNEAKATTACK" />
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_ROGUE_SNEAKATTACK" level="3" />
            </rules>
        </element>

    <element name="Possessed Artefact" type="Class Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_FIENDISH_SERVANT_POSSESSED_ARTEFACT">
        <description>
            <p>You may use the Possessed Artefact feature through your servant as if they were wielding or wearing your artefact, and your Improved Artefact feature through your servant when you gain that feature at 11th level, using your spell slots for those features.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You may use the Possessed Artefact feature through your servant as if they were wielding or wearing your artefact, using your spell slots for those features.</description>
            <description level="11">You may use the Possessed Artefact and Improved Artefact features through your servant as if they were wielding or wearing your artefact, using your spell slots for those features.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="Ability Score Improvement" type="Class Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_FIENDISH_SERVANT_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT">
        <description>
            <p>Whenever you gain the Ability Score Improvement class feature, your servant’s abilities also improve. Your servant can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or it can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, your servant can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature unless its description specifies otherwise.</p>
            <p class="indent">Alternatively, whenever you gain the Ability Score Improvement class feature, you can wreathe new spells into your servant to force them to evolve new features that improve its potency instead of having the servant gain the regular Ability Score Improvement. You can choose one of these traits from the Fiendish Evolutions list below.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Ability Score Improvement" supports="Improvement Option,Fiendish Servant,4" level="4" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Ability Score Improvement" supports="Improvement Option,Fiendish Servant,8" level="8" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Ability Score Improvement" supports="Improvement Option,Fiendish Servant,12" level="12" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Ability Score Improvement" supports="Improvement Option,Fiendish Servant,16" level="16" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Ability Score Improvement" supports="Improvement Option,Fiendish Servant,19" level="19" />
        </rules>
    </element>

	<element name="Ability Score Improvement" type="Class Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_ABILITY_4">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<supports>Improvement Option, Fiendish Servant, 4</supports>
		<requirements>ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_FIENDISH_SERVANT_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Ability Score Increase (Level 4)" supports="Ability Score Improvement,Class" number="2" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Fiendish Evolution" type="Class Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_FEAT_4">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<supports>Improvement Option, Fiendish Servant, 4</supports>
		<requirements>ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_FIENDISH_SERVANT_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>Select a fiendish evolution of your choice.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<setters>
			<set name="allow duplicate">true</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<select name="Fiendish Evolution (Level 4)" type="Racial Trait" supports="Witchguard Fiendish Evolution" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Ability Score Improvement" type="Class Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_ABILITY_8">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<supports>Improvement Option, Fiendish Servant, 8</supports>
		<requirements>ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_FIENDISH_SERVANT_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Ability Score Increase (Level 8)" supports="Ability Score Improvement,Class" number="2" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Fiendish Evolution" type="Class Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_FEAT_8">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<supports>Improvement Option, Fiendish Servant, 8</supports>
		<requirements>ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_FIENDISH_SERVANT_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>Select a fiendish evolution of your choice.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<setters>
			<set name="allow duplicate">true</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<select name="Fiendish Evolution (Level 8)" type="Racial Trait" supports="Witchguard Fiendish Evolution" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Ability Score Improvement" type="Class Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_ABILITY_12">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<supports>Improvement Option, Fiendish Servant, 12</supports>
		<requirements>ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_FIENDISH_SERVANT_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Ability Score Increase (Level 12)" supports="Ability Score Improvement,Class" number="2" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Fiendish Evolution" type="Class Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_FEAT_12">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<supports>Improvement Option, Fiendish Servant, 12</supports>
		<requirements>ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_FIENDISH_SERVANT_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>Select a fiendish evolution of your choice.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<setters>
			<set name="allow duplicate">true</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<select name="Fiendish Evolution (Level 12)" type="Racial Trait" supports="Witchguard Fiendish Evolution" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Ability Score Improvement" type="Class Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_ABILITY_16">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<supports>Improvement Option, Fiendish Servant, 16</supports>
		<requirements>ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_FIENDISH_SERVANT_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Ability Score Increase (Level 16)" supports="Ability Score Improvement,Class" number="2" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Fiendish Evolution" type="Class Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_FEAT_16">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<supports>Improvement Option, Fiendish Servant, 16</supports>
		<requirements>ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_FIENDISH_SERVANT_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>Select a fiendish evolution of your choice.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<setters>
			<set name="allow duplicate">true</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<select name="Fiendish Evolution (Level 16)" type="Racial Trait" supports="Witchguard Fiendish Evolution" />
		</rules>
	</element> 
	<element name="Ability Score Improvement" type="Class Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_ABILITY_19">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<supports>Improvement Option, Fiendish Servant, 19</supports>
		<requirements>ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_FIENDISH_SERVANT_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Ability Score Increase (Level 19)" supports="Ability Score Improvement,Class" number="2" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Fiendish Evolution" type="Class Feature" source="The Witchguard" id="ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_FEAT_19">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<supports>Improvement Option, Fiendish Servant, 19</supports>
		<requirements>ID_SE_WG_CLASS_FEATURE_FIENDISH_SERVANT_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>Select a fiendish evolution of your choice.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<setters>
			<set name="allow duplicate">true</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<select name="Fiendish Evolution (Level 19)" type="Racial Trait" supports="Witchguard Fiendish Evolution" />
		</rules>
	</element>


</elements>