<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Oracle Class</name>
        <author url="https://www.gmbinder.com/share/-LgquVbFUzWQUoLysaB">Zekarath</author>
        <update version="0.0.2">
            <file name="class-oracle.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/user/class-oracle.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Oracle" type="Class" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_ORACLE">
        <description>
            <p>A cowled man stumbles through the streets. He has seen it. The End. Will you stop to listen? Those that do find their fortunes turn from dreadful paths, while those that instead spit on his prophecy soon learn of their foolish ways. He calls out after one such soul, "Your path is blackened by the sickness of your own heart!" A twist of the fates, and a merchant cart loses control. That rude young man finds himself unable to evade, and is crushed by the overturned wagon. "Such is the way of those who walk in darkness..." the cowled man mutters as he walks past the scene, knowing full well the paths that fate might have taken that day.</p>
            <p class="indent">A woman walks through dreams. She seeks the one from her own visions — she has an important message to bring. When she finds the magistrate in her dreams, she whispers the portentous message and is pulled back to wakefulness. A rush of divine ecstasy enfolds her and she feels her own stresses melt away. She rises to a new day, seeking other calamities and misfortune she might prevent.</p>
            <h4>READING DESTINY</h4>
            <p>Deities and other powers have ways of seeing into the future, and those that can sit outside of time hold greater influence on its flow. Some of these beings choose mortals to act as messengers to stir against the events that may come... or grant even greater powers to sway the destiny to change what might be.</p>
            <p class="indent">Oracles have the powers of sight. They are able to see through the timestream into possible futures, and oftentimes provide prophecies and omens for those who would listen.</p>
            <p class="indent">For some, this is a gift. For others, a curse. Much depends on the source of their powers... and how it is received in their communities.</p>
            <h4>BINDING FATES</h4>
            <p>Many who bear the powers of sight are content to keep a quiet, hidden life, or perhaps simply serve in a comfortable position as an advisor to a dignitary. Some seek to serve a greater power. In service of various gods or supernatural beings, they act as prophets to their lands.</p>
            <p class="indent">Others, however, find the idea of fate disconcerting, and reach out to change their own destiny. They make their own path by weaving the threads of fate to their own desgin, by forcing the hand of fate, or by doing everything in their power to see the destiny they’ve foreseen never comes.</p>
            <p class="indent">These Oracles may be sought out or feared for their powers, but no one denies that their abilities can be dangerous. They can be powerful allies, able to turn events in your favor... or deadly enemies anticipating and countering your every move.</p>
            <h4>CREATING AN ORACLE</h4>
            <p>The power of sight is considered a blessing by some, and a bane by others. How do you view your abilities? How were you treated by others for your difference?</p>
            <p class="indent">You may want to explore how you first discovered your abilities, and if you have an idea of the source of the power — is it divine, infernal, or something else? Check with your DM to learn which deities or powers are in your campaign. If you know the origin of your powers, did you enter this service willingly? Did the power choose you, implanting this skillset within you without regard for your wishes? Or perhaps you sought this ability for yourself, hoping to control your own fate?</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you discovered your abilities, how did you learn to harness them? Did anyone help you along the way? Or were you driven away the superstitions of others, and forced to rely on your powers to make your way through the world?</p>
            <p class="indent">Do you live a hidden life, letting others seek you for council and fortune-telling, or are you one who yells prophecies in the streets to any willing listeners?</p>
            <h5>QUICK BUILD</h5>
            <p>You can make an Oracle quickly by following these suggestions. First, Wisdom should be your highest ability score. Make Charisma your next-highest if you wish to influence others with your words, or Constitution if you prefer to stand close to the action. Second choose the hermit or sage background. Third choose the cantrips <em>anticipation</em> and <em>sacred slame</em>.</p>
            <h2>CLASS FEATURES</h2>
            <p>As an class, you gain the following class features.</p>
            <h5>HIT POINTS</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Hit Dice:</strong> 1d6 per oracle level</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at 1st Level:</strong> 6 + your Constitution modifier</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at Higher Levels:</strong> 1d6 (or 4) + your Constitution modifier per class level after 1st</li>
            </ul>
            <h5>PROFICIENCIES</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Armor:</strong> None</li>
                <li><strong>Weapons:</strong> Daggers, darts, slings, quarterstaffs, light crossbows</li>
                <li><strong>Tools:</strong> Herbalism kit (or Fortune Teller’s kit<sup>*</sup>)</li>
            </ul>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Saving Throws:</strong>  Wisdom, Intelligence</li>
                <li><strong>Skills:</strong> Choose two from History, Insight, Investigation, Medicine, Perception and Religion</li>
            </ul>
            <h5>EQUIPMENT</h5>
            <p>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><em>(a)</em> a quarterstaff or <em>(b)</em> a sling and 20 bullets</li>
                <li><em>(a)</em> a component pouch <em>(b)</em> an oracle tools (see Appendix A for descriptions)</li>
                <li><em>(a)</em> a Diplomat’s Pack or <em>(b)</em> a Priest’s Pack</li>
            </ul>
            <p>Alternatively, you may ignore the equipment from your class and background, and buy 5d4 × 10 gp worth of equipment from chapter 5 in the Player’s Handbook instead.</p>
            <h5><i>Standing Out or Blending In</i></h5>
            <p class="flavor">Oracles can be reclusive, choosing common cloaks of drab coloring to conceal their often unique appearance. Or they may embrace their quirks and choose to attract attention to their gifts with bright robes and apparel - especially if they hope to make some coin with their fortune telling talents!</p>
            <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_FORETOLD_FATE" />
            <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_PORTENT_MAGIC" />
            <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_GUIDE_DESTINY" />
            <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_GUIDE_DESTINY_PREDICTION" />
            <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_PROPHETIC_INFLUENCE" />
            <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" />
            <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SEERS_RENEWAL" />
            <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHARED_VISION" />
            <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_EMPOWERED_DESTINY" />
            <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_EYES_OF_THE_VISIONARY" />
            <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_OVERWHELMING_GAZE" />
            <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_PORTENT_RECOVERY" />
            <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COUNTER_DIVINATION" />
            <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_PRECOGNITION" />
            <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_ORACLE_FIRST_VISION" />
            <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_ORACLE_FATETOUCHED_MARK" requirements="!ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_ORACLE_FATEBREAKER"/>
            <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_RECENT_REVELATION" />
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="short">A mysterious seer that can peer into the future.</set>
            <set name="hd">d6</set>
            <set name="spellcaster">true</set>
            <set name="spellcastingAbility">Wisdom</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description>description</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_WISDOM" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_INTELLIGENCE" />

            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_DAGGER" requirements="!ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_MULTICLASS_ORACLE"/>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_DART" requirements="!ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_MULTICLASS_ORACLE"/>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_QUARTERSTAFF" requirements="!ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_MULTICLASS_ORACLE"/>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SLING" requirements="!ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_MULTICLASS_ORACLE"/>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_CROSSBOW_LIGHT" requirements="!ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_MULTICLASS_ORACLE"/>

            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_HERBALISM_KIT" />

            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_FORETOLD_FATE" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_PORTENT_MAGIC" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_GUIDE_DESTINY" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_GUIDE_DESTINY_PREDICTION" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_PROPHETIC_INFLUENCE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" level="4" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SEERS_RENEWAL" level="5" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHARED_VISION" level="10" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_EMPOWERED_DESTINY" level="11" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_EYES_OF_THE_VISIONARY" level="13" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_OVERWHELMING_GAZE" level="14" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_PORTENT_RECOVERY" level="14" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COUNTER_DIVINATION" level="17" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_PRECOGNITION" level="20" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_ORACLE_FIRST_VISION" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_ORACLE_FATETOUCHED_MARK" level="1" requirements="!ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_ORACLE_FATEBREAKER" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_RECENT_REVELATION" level="1" />
        </rules>
        <multiclass id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_MULTICLASS_ORACLE">
            <prerequisite>Wisdom 13</prerequisite>
            <requirements>[wis:13]</requirements>
            <setters>
                <set name="multiclass proficiencies">Herbalism Kit</set>
            </setters>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_HERBALISM_KIT" />
            </rules>
        </multiclass>
    </element>

    <element name="Foretold Fate" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_FORETOLD_FATE">
        <description>
              <p>At 1st level you are given the illusion of choice to choose your Foretold Fate, enhancing your ability to manipulate or be manipulated by destiny.</p>
              <p class="indent">Your choice grants you fate spells and other features when you choose it at 1st level. It also grants you additional ways to use Guide Destiny when you gain that feature at 2nd level, and additional benefits at 6th, 10th, 15th, and 18th.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Archetype" name="Foretold Fate" level="1" supports="Foretold Fate" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Portent Magic" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_PORTENT_MAGIC">
        <description>
            <p>Whether you are cursed by premonitions, touched by the gods, or just destined for your vocation, your abilities as an oracle open magical possibilities. You are able to harness divine, natural, and supernatural magics to forecast the future of those around you.</p>
            <p class="indent">As a conduit for mystic power, you can cast oracle Spells. See PHB chapter 10 for the general rules of spellcasting, and Appendix B of this document for the Oracle Spell List.</p>
            <h5>NATURAL DIVINER</h5>
            <p>You are given a special clarity when you cast Divination spells. If a spell would incur a chance at random results after multiple castings, there is only a cumulative 10 percent chance after each casting.</p>
            <p class="indent">Strangely, your petitions and the answers you seek regarding your own future are always slightly muddled, thanks to your ability to change the Destiny that surround you.</p>
            <h5>CANTRIPS</h5>
            <p>You choose two cantrips from the oracle spell list. You learn additional oracle cantrips of your choice, as shown in the table above.</p>
            <h5>SPELL SLOTS, PREPARING AND CASTING SPELLS</h5>
            <p>The Oracle table shows how many spell slots you have. The table also shows what the level of those slots is; your spell slots are all the same level. To cast one of your Oracle spells of 1st level or higher, you must expend a spell slot. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            <p class="indent">You prepare the list of oracle Spells that are available for you to cast, choosing from the oracle spell list. When you do so, choose a number of oracle Spells equal to your Wisdom modifier + half your oracle level, rounded up (minimum of one spell). The Spells must be of a level for which you have Spell Slots.</p>
            <p class="indent">For example, if you are a 5th-level oracle, you have two 3rd-level Spell Slots. With a Wisdom of 16, your list of prepared Spells can include 6 Spells of 1st, 2nd or 3rd level, in any combination. If you prepare the 2nd-level spell Mind Spike<sup>XGtE</sup>, to cast it you must spend one of those slots, and you cast it as a 3rd-level spell. Casting the spell doesn’t remove it from your list of prepared Spells.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can change your list of prepared Spells when you finish a Long Rest. Preparing a new list of oracle Spells requires time spent in meditation and study of Destiny with your oracle tools: at least 1 minute per Spell Level for each spell on your list.</p>
            <h5>SPELLCASTING ABILITY</h5>
            <p>Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for your spells, and you use it whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Wisdom modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Spell save DC</strong> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Spell attack modifier</strong> = your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier</p>
            <h5>RITUAL CASTING</h5>
            <p>You can cast any oracle spell as a ritual if that spell has the ritual tag and have it prepared.</p>
            <h5>SPELLCASTING FOCUS</h5>
            <p>You can use an oracle tool as a spellcasting focus for your oracle Spells. See Appendix A for descriptions of these mystic devices.</p>
            <h5><i>SPEAKING TO GODS... OR GAME MASTERS?</i></h5>
            <p class="flavor">Oracles add great flavor to a group, but your DM will want to be aware of the increase in direct interaction that may be asked of them. Similar to other classes, such as Clerics or Warlocks, your Oracle has drawn the attention of higher powers.</p>
            <p class="indent flavor">As a class that uses many of its spells to reveal secrets and truths, a DM will want to be comfortable with their expanded range of divining abilities before welcoming Oracles to the table.</p>
            <p class="indent flavor">In games where hidden items or mysterious events drive the plot, in order to preserve some of the thrill, DMs may wish to prepare responses for an inquisitive Oracle character or create some mystical obstacles to overcome, such as a nondetection spell, before their abilities are able to discover all of the answers.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <setters>
            <set name="spellcastingClass">Oracle</set>
            <set name="spellcastingAbility">Wisdom</set>
        </setters>
        <spellcasting name="Oracle" ability="Wisdom" prepare="true">
            <list known="true">Oracle</list>
        </spellcasting>
        <rules>
            <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Oracle)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),0" spellcasting="Oracle" number="2" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Oracle)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),0" spellcasting="Oracle" number="1" level="4" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Oracle)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),0" spellcasting="Oracle" number="1" level="9" />

            <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS_SPELLCASTING_SLOTS_SOLO" requirements="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS"/>
            <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_RITUAL_CASTING" />

            <stat name="oracle:spellcasting:slots:count" value="1" level="1"/>
            <stat name="oracle:spellcasting:slots:count" value="1" level="2"/>
            <stat name="oracle:spellcasting:slots:count" value="1" level="11"/>
            <stat name="oracle:spellcasting:slots:count" value="1" level="17"/>

            <stat name="oracle:spellcasting:slot" value="1" level="1" />
            <stat name="oracle:spellcasting:slot" value="1" level="3" />
            <stat name="oracle:spellcasting:slot" value="1" level="5" />
            <stat name="oracle:spellcasting:slot" value="1" level="7" />
            <stat name="oracle:spellcasting:slot" value="1" level="9" />

            <!-- negative count to remove slots -->
            <stat name="oracle:spellcasting:slots:1" value="oracle:spellcasting:slots:count" level="1" />
            <stat name="oracle:spellcasting:slots:1" value="-oracle:spellcasting:slots:count" level="3" />
            <stat name="oracle:spellcasting:slots:2" value="oracle:spellcasting:slots:count" level="3" />
            <stat name="oracle:spellcasting:slots:2" value="-oracle:spellcasting:slots:count" level="5" />
            <stat name="oracle:spellcasting:slots:3" value="oracle:spellcasting:slots:count" level="5" />
            <stat name="oracle:spellcasting:slots:3" value="-oracle:spellcasting:slots:count" level="7" />
            <stat name="oracle:spellcasting:slots:4" value="oracle:spellcasting:slots:count" level="7" />
            <stat name="oracle:spellcasting:slots:4" value="-oracle:spellcasting:slots:count" level="9" />
            <stat name="oracle:spellcasting:slots:5" value="oracle:spellcasting:slots:count" level="9" />

            <stat name="oracle:spellcasting:prepare" value="wisdom:modifier" />
            <stat name="oracle:spellcasting:prepare" value="level:oracle:half:up" />

        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Guide Destiny" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_GUIDE_DESTINY">
        <description>
            <p>At 2nd level you gain exceptional intuition about Destiny that influences all events around you, and are able to channel it to alter the fates of those you encounter. You are granted the ability to guide forces that determine destiny, using the mystical energy to create magical effects. You start with three such effects listed below.</p>
            <p>You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom Modifier (minimum 1) plus half your Oracle Level (rounded up). When you expend a use of this feature, roll your destiny die and apply the result as directed. The destiny die starts as d6, and it changes as you gain oracle levels, as shown in the Destiny Die column of the Oracle table.</p>
            <p>You must have a free hand or oracle spellcasting focus in your hand to use this feature. If Guide Destiny changes any outcome and the target creature has a Wisdom score greater than 10, it can make an immediate Wisdom (Insight) check against your Spellcasting DC. A success reveals that you somehow interfered.</p>
            <p>You regain all expended uses of this feature after a long rest. You must have a free hand or oracle spellcasting focus in your hand to use this feature. If Guide Destiny changes any outcome and the target creature has a Wisdom score greater than 10, it can make an immediate Wisdom (Insight) check against your Spellcasting DC. A success reveals that you somehow interfered.</p>
            <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_GUIDE_DESTINY_PROPHETIC_SITE" />
            <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_GUIDE_DESTINY_EXPECTED_INJURY" />
            <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_GUIDE_DESTINY_ONE_STEP_AHEAD" />
        </description>
        <sheet usage="{{guide-destiny:uses}}d{{guide-destiny:dice}}s/Long Rest">
            <description>When you expend a use of this feature, roll your destiny die and apply the result as directed. </description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="guide-destiny:wis" value="1" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="guide-destiny:wis" value="wisdom:modifier" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="guide-destiny:uses" value="guide-destiny:wis" />
            <stat name="guide-destiny:uses" value="level:oracle:half" />
            <stat name="guide-destiny:dice" value="6" level="2" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="guide-destiny:dice" value="8" level="5" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="guide-destiny:dice" value="10" level="10" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="guide-destiny:dice" value="12" level="15" bonus="base" />

            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_GUIDE_DESTINY_PROPHETIC_SITE" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_GUIDE_DESTINY_EXPECTED_INJURY" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_GUIDE_DESTINY_ONE_STEP_AHEAD" level="2" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Guide Destiny: Prophetic Sight" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_GUIDE_DESTINY_PROPHETIC_SITE">
            <description>
                <p>You can influence the actions of other creatures by manipulating the direction the Destiny is taking. When another creature you can see makes an attack roll or an ability check, you can use your reaction to expend one destiny die and apply the result as a bonus or penalty (your choice) to the creature’s roll. You can do so after the creature rolls but before any effects of the roll occur. If a creature rolls a critical hit and your destiny die reduces the total below the target AC, it does not hit.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Guide Destiny" alt="Prophetic Sight" action="Reaction">
                <description>When another creature you can see makes an attack roll or an ability check, you can use your reaction to expend one destiny die and apply the result as a bonus or penalty (your choice) to the creature’s roll. You can do so after the creature rolls but before any effects of the roll occur. If a creature rolls a critical hit and your destiny die reduces the total below the target AC, it does not hit.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Guide Destiny: Expected Injury" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_GUIDE_DESTINY_EXPECTED_INJURY">
            <description>
                <p>Some attacks are unavoidable even if they are foreseen, but by bending the fate you are able to change the destined trajectory just enough to avoid some of the damage you would receive — sometimes even redirecting it. When an enemy hits you with an attack roll, as a reaction you may roll your destiny die and the damage you take from the attack is reduced by your destiny die result.</p>
                <p class="indent">If the attack was made with a melee weapon within 5 feet of you, and your die result reduces the damage to 0, you can choose to redirect the attack to a creature of your choice within 5 feet of the attacker. That creature takes the full damage from the attack. If no other target is available, the attack hits you but deals no damage.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Guide Destiny" alt="Expected Injury" action="Reaction">
                <description>When an enemy hits you with an attack roll, as a reaction you may roll your destiny die and the damage you take from the attack is reduced by your destiny die result. If the attack was made with a melee weapon within 5 feet of you, and your die result reduces the damage to 0, you can choose to redirect the attack to a creature of your choice within 5 feet of the attacker. That creature takes the full damage from the attack. If no other target is available, the attack hits you but deals no damage.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Guide Destiny: One Step Ahead" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_GUIDE_DESTINY_ONE_STEP_AHEAD">
            <description>
                <p>Your keen intuition allows you to step away from harms way just in time. If an enemy comes within 5 feet of you, as a reaction you may expend a destiny die to move half your movement to any direction without prompting an attack of opportunity from the moving creature. You also gain temporary hit points equal to half your Destiny die roll.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Guide Destiny" alt="One Step Ahead" action="Reaction">
                <description>If an enemy comes within 5 feet of you, as a reaction you may expend a destiny die to move half your movement to any direction without prompting an attack of opportunity from the moving creature. You also gain temporary hit points equal to half your Destiny die roll.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
    <element name="Guide Destiny: Prediction" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_GUIDE_DESTINY_PREDICTION">
        <description>
            <p>When you reach 3rd level, you find that you are able to channel Destiny in a new way. You can now twist the fate around yourself, immersing in the currents of possibility to better predict the actions of your enemies.</p>
            <p>As an action you may expend a destiny die, and while concentrating (as on a spell) for 1 minute, you gain extra-sensory abilities. Roll your destiny die and add half the result (rounded down) to your AC.</p>
            <p>You lose this benefit if you stop concentrating, are Incapacitated, or if your speed drops to 0. Once you use this ability, you can’t do so again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Short Rest" action="Action">
            <description>You may expend a destiny die, and while concentrating (as on a spell) for 1 minute, you gain extra-sensory abilities. Roll your destiny die and add half the result (rounded down) to your AC. You lose this benefit if you stop concentrating, are Incapacitated, or if your speed drops to 0.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Prophetic Influence" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_PROPHETIC_INFLUENCE">
        <description>
            <p>Also at 3rd level, your words hold greater weight than they otherwise would. Whenever you roll a Charisma (Deception, Intimidation, or Persuasion) ability check to speak of future events, you may do so with advantage.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Whenever you roll a Charisma (Deception, Intimidation, or Persuasion) ability check to speak of future events, you may do so with advantage.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Ability Score Improvement" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT">
        <description>
            <p>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two Ability Scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Oracle 4)" supports="Improvement Option,Oracle,4" level="4" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Oracle 8)" supports="Improvement Option,Oracle,8" level="8" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Oracle 12)" supports="Improvement Option,Oracle,12" level="12" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Oracle 16)" supports="Improvement Option,Oracle,16" level="16" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Oracle 19)" supports="Improvement Option,Oracle,19" level="19" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Seer’s Renewal" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SEERS_RENEWAL">
        <description>
            <p>Beginning when you reach 5th level, when you cast a spell from the divination school using a spell slot, you regain one use of Guide Destiny.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you cast a spell from the divination school using a spell slot, you regain one use of Guide Destiny.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Shared Vision" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHARED_VISION">
        <description>
            <p>When you reach 10th level, when you cast a Divination school spell or use an Oracle feature that allows you to view other events, places, or futures, you may touch one other creature to allow them to share in your vision. If the target is unwilling, it must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or become subject to the vision.</p>
            <p>A creature affected by this ability is blind and deaf to all except the shared vision and is paralyzed for the duration. At the end of each of its turns the target can make another Wisdom saving throw. On a success, the effect ends for it.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you use this ability, you can’t do so again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
            <description>When you cast a Divination school spell or use an Oracle feature that allows you to view other events, places, or futures, you may touch one other creature to allow them to share in your vision. If the target is unwilling, it must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw (save DC {{spellcasting:dc}}) or become subject to the vision.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Empowered Destiny" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_EMPOWERED_DESTINY">
        <description>
            <p>At 11th level, you are able to pull additional mystical energy when you bend destiny. When using Guide Destiny feature, the ability is empowered if your destiny die roll is 10 or greater:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong>Prophetic Sight</strong>: If used as a bonus, your target has advantage on next attack roll or ability check. If used as a penalty, your target has disadvantage on next attack roll or ability check. This ability must successfully change the outcome of the roll for these effects to ably.</li>
                <li><strong>Expected Injury</strong>: You are healed for an amount equal to your Proficiency Bonus.</li>
                <li><strong>One Step Ahead</strong>: You regain the reaction you used to spend on this ability.</li>
                <li><strong>Prediction</strong>: The resulting bonus applies to both your AC and your Dexterity saving throws.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="Guide Destiny">
            <description>When using Guide Destiny feature, the ability is empowered if your destiny die roll is 10 or greater.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Eyes of the Visionary" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_EYES_OF_THE_VISIONARY">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 13th level, you may cast the spell <i>True Seeing</i> once without expending a spell slot or material components. You must finish a long rest before you can do so again.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>You may cast the spell True Seeing once without expending a spell slot or material components.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TRUE_SEEING" prepared="false" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Overwhelming Gaze" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_OVERWHELMING_GAZE">
        <description>
            <p>At level 14, if you attempt to magically seek a creature that is hidden from divination by a nondetection spell or similar affect, your mystic abilities give you a chance at success. You may make a disadvantaged spellcasting ability check to pierce the protections and cast your spell as normal. Once you use this feature, you can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>If you attempt to magically seek a creature that is hidden from divination by a nondetection spell or similar affect, your mystic abilities give you a chance at success. You may make a disadvantaged spellcasting ability check to pierce the protections and cast your spell as normal.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Portent Recovery" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_PORTENT_RECOVERY">
        <description>
            <p>Also at 14th level, whenever you expend an oracle spell slot, you may choose to recover a spell slot. Unless the spell was from Divination school, the new spell slot is one level lower than the spell slot expended.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
            <description>Whenever you expend an oracle spell slot, you may choose to recover a spell slot. Unless the spell was from the Divination school, the new spell slot is one level lower than the spell slot expended.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Counter Divination" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COUNTER_DIVINATION">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 17th level, your understanding of divination magic has hardened your mind and body against many effects. You permanently experience the benefits of the spell <i>mind blank</i> while conscious. You are also aware if any effect that <i>mind blank</i> makes you immune to is triggered on any creature or object within 10 feet of you.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You permanently experience the benefits of the spell mind blank while conscious. You are also aware if any effect that mind blank makes you immune to is triggered on any creature or object within 10 feet of you.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Precognition" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_PRECOGNITION">
        <description>
            <p>At 20th level, your mind has permanently melded with your mystic vision, granting you a supernatural sense. You permanently experience the benefits of the spell <i>foresight</i> while you are conscious. You may extend this ability to one additional creature once per long rest, however the effect ends early on your target after it completes a short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You permanently experience the benefits of the spell foresight while you are conscious. You may extend this ability to one additional creature once per long rest, however the effect ends early on your target after it completes a short or long rest.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

  <!-- Oracle Traits -->
    <element name="First Vision" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_ORACLE_FIRST_VISION">
        <description>
            <p>Every oracle recalls the first moment their mind witnessed the expansive potential of a possible future. If you haven’t explored that aspect of your character’s history yet, try to determine what it was and what effect it may have had you.</p>
            <p class="indent">Was the moment traumatic or mundane? Did you choose to act to prevent it? Did you tell others, and how did they react when they learned of your ability? How has that colored your perception of reality, fate, and free will?</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="List" name="First Vision">
                <item id="1">You foresaw the accidental death of a close family member. When you disclosed it ahead of time you were assured it was nothing, but it came about exactly as you predicted.</item>
                <item id="2">You predicted a murder and tried to warn the victim. In response, the would-be-victim killed his potential murderer.</item>
                <item id="3">You were granted a vision that allowed you to find a local child that was lost.</item>
                <item id="4">You correctly anticipated a local insect plague that wiped out most of the harvest. Only through your warnings did the community survive</item>
                <item id="5">You were gifted the vision of a close friend being joyfully welcomed to the afterlife. You still keep this vision a closely guarded secret.</item>
                <item id="6">You have always known little things, such as the number of apples in a basket or when the first snowfall would be.</item>
            </select>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Fate-touched Mark" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_ORACLE_FATETOUCHED_MARK">
        <description>
            <p>Those who tamper with destiny may find their physical reality changed. These might be small visual indicators or invisible mental scars. Your mark might be something that only those closest to you are able to determine.</p>
            <p>How has your mark manifested? Is it a feeling? A physical change? An ever present fragrance that fills the room? Are you proud of it, or does it make you self conscious? See the following table for some possible marks, or come up with your own unique idea.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="List" name="Fate-touched Mark">
                <item id="1">You always appear either very old or very young (your choice) for your race.</item>
                <item id="2">You have mysterious markings on your face and arms.</item>
                <item id="3">Your eyes are permanently clouded white (this does not negatively affect your vision).</item>
                <item id="4">You are haunted by images of a life you didn’t live.</item>
                <item id="5">In times of stress you speak in tongues uncontrollably (roll a d8 on the exotic languages table each time you are stressed).</item>
                <item id="6">Regardless of your environment, the air within 5 feet of you feels chilly to any except you.</item>
            </select>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Recent Revelation" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_RECENT_REVELATION">
        <description>
            <p>Oracles may be chosen at random or for a specific purpose, but once a mortal is given the gift of sight it may continue issuing glimpses of the future for their own purposes and designs.</p>
            <p>These visions are often the impetus that leads oracles to a life of adventure, as they are shown a future that demands action. Discuss with your DM to determine what you have learned and to what end that might compel you.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="List" name="Recent Revelation">
                <item id="1">You glimpse a rare vision of your own future. It is uncertain whether you are doomed to meet it or can change your fate.</item>
                <item id="2">You are shown a potential future event, and are compelled to announce this when in public places, either exhorting others to stay on the path or warning them of the foreboding future.</item>
                <item id="3">You witness an omen of either fortune or folly and are compelled to deliver it to a specific person.</item>
                <item id="4">A long lost truth has been revealed to you, and everyone else has forgotten or mistaken it.</item>
                <item id="5">The deity or power behind your abilities seems to have left you alone... for now.</item>
                <item id="6">You have seen the end of the world, and it is terrifying. However, you are not certain how soon it will occur.</item>
            </select>
        </rules>
    </element>

  <!-- Foretold Fates for Oracle Class -->
      <!-- Fate of the Doomsayer-->
        <element name="Fate of the Doomsayer" type="Archetype" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_ORACLE_FATE_OF_THE_DOOMSAYER">
            <supports>Foretold Fate</supports>
            <description>
                <p>Because the omens spread by Doomsayer Oracles often bring tidings of death, they are frequently looked upon with mistrust. However, those who do not heed the warnings of Doomsayers may find their ruin sooner rather than later.</p>
                <h5>Doomsayer Expanded Spell List</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Level</td><td>Spell Names</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>Cantrip</td><td><i>message, toll the dead<sup>XGtE</sup></i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>1st</td><td><i>command, dissonant whispers</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>2nd</td><td><i>ray of enfeeblement, suggestion</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td><i>enemies abound<sup>XGtE</sup>, slow</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>4th</td><td><i>blight, confusion</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><i>dominate person, synaptic static<sup>XGtE</sup></i></td></tr>
                </table>
                <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DOOMSAYER_HARBINGER_OF_DOOM" />
                <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DOOMSAYER_GUIDE_DESTINY_ILL_OMEN" />
                <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DOOMSAYER_WHISPERS_OF_DREAD" />
                <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DOOMSAYER_THE_END_IS_NIGH" />
                <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DOOMSAYER_MARK_MY_WORDS" />
                <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DOOMSAYER_FATAL_PRONOUNCEMENT" />
                <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DOOMSAYER_QUIRK" />
            </description>
            <spellcasting name="Oracle" extend="true">
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_MESSAGE</extend>
                <extend>ID_XGTE_SPELL_TOLL_THE_DEAD</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_COMMAND</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_DISSONANT_WHISPERS</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_RAY_OF_ENFEEBLEMENT</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_SUGGESTION</extend>
                <extend>ID_XGTE_SPELL_ENEMIES_ABOUND</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_SLOW</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_BLIGHT</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_CONFUSION</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_DOMINATE_PERSON</extend>
                <extend>ID_XGTE_SPELL_SYNAPTIC_STATIC</extend>
            </spellcasting>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DOOMSAYER_HARBINGER_OF_DOOM" level="1" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DOOMSAYER_GUIDE_DESTINY_ILL_OMEN" level="2" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DOOMSAYER_WHISPERS_OF_DREAD" level="6" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DOOMSAYER_THE_END_IS_NIGH" level="10" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DOOMSAYER_MARK_MY_WORDS" level="15" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DOOMSAYER_FATAL_PRONOUNCEMENT" level="18" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DOOMSAYER_QUIRK" level="1" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Harbinger of Doom" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DOOMSAYER_HARBINGER_OF_DOOM">
                <description>
                    <p>When you choose this Foretold Fate at level 1, you become proficient in Intimidation.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Additionally, as an action, you make a proclamation of doom in attempt to demoralize one creature that you see within 30 feet of you that can hear and understand you. Make a Charisma (Intimidation) check contested by target’s Wisdom (Insight) check. If your check succeeds, the target is frightened until the end of your next turn. If your check fails, the target can’t be frightened by you in this way for 1 hour. At 3rd level, you gain benefit of Prophetic Influence in these checks.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet action="Action">
                    <description>you make a proclamation of doom in attempt to demoralize one creature that you see within 30 feet of you that can hear and understand you. Make a Charisma (Intimidation) check contested by target’s Wisdom (Insight) check. If your check succeeds, the target is frightened until the end of your next turn. If your check fails, the target can’t be frightened by you in this way for 1 hour.</description>
                    <description level="3">you make a proclamation of doom in attempt to demoralize one creature that you see within 30 feet of you that can hear and understand you. Make a Charisma (Intimidation) check, with advantage, contested by target’s Wisdom (Insight) check. If your check succeeds, the target is frightened until the end of your next turn. If your check fails, the target can’t be frightened by you in this way for 1 hour.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INTIMIDATION" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Guide Destiny: Ill Omen" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DOOMSAYER_GUIDE_DESTINY_ILL_OMEN">
                <description>
                    <p>At 2nd level, you foresee ruin and destruction of your foes. When you see a creature take damage, you may as a reaction expend a Destiny die and add the result to the damage dealt.</p>
                    <p class="indent">At 11th level, if the Destiny die roll for this feature is 10 or greater, the creature has vulnerability to next instance of damage it takes.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet alt="Ill Omen" usage="Guide Destiny" action="Reaction">
                    <description>When you see a creature  take damage, you may as a reaction expend a Destiny die and add the result to the damage dealt.</description>
                    <description level="11">When you see a creature take damage, you may as a reaction expend a Destiny die and add the result to the damage dealt. If the Destiny die roll for this feature is 10 or greater, the creature has vulnerability to the next instance of damage it takes.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Whispers of Dread" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DOOMSAYER_WHISPERS_OF_DREAD">
                <description>
                    <p>When you reach 6th level, your close dealings with negative aspects of destiny grant you keener insight on negative aspects of people.</p>
                    <p class="indent">If you spend at least 1 minute observing or interacting with another creature outside combat, you can learn certain information about its capabilities. The DM tells you one of the following characteristics of your choice:</p>
                    <ul>
                      <li>The creature’s lowest attribute score</li>
                      <li>A vulnerability</li>
                      <li>A fear</li>
                    </ul>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>If you spend at least 1 minute observing or interacting with another creature outside combat, you can learn certain information about its capabilities. The DM tells you one of the following characteristics of your choice: lowest attribute score, a vulnerability, or a fear.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="The End is Nigh" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DOOMSAYER_THE_END_IS_NIGH">
                <description>
                    <p>At 10th level, when you cast an oracle spell that deals damage, instead of rolling you can choose to deal maximum damage with that spell. Only one instance of damage from a spell can be affected by this feature.</p>
                    <p class="indent">After you’ve used this feature twice, you can’t use it again until you finish a long rest.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="2/Long Rest">
                    <description>When you cast an oracle spell that deals damage, instead of rolling you can choose to deal maximum damage with that spell. Only one instance of damage from a spell can be affected by this feature.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Mark My Words" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DOOMSAYER_MARK_MY_WORDS">
                <description>
                    <p>At 15th level, your reputation carries, and your words and simple motions carry heavy weight on others. You may cast the <em>Mass Suggestion</em> or <em>Power Word Pain (XGE)</em> spell without using a spell slot. If you’ve used Whispers of Dread ability on a creature, you know whenever that creature is an eligible target for <em>Power Word Pain (XGE)</em>. Additionally, the spell’s hit point threshold on a target is increased by the amount of the destiny die roll results from Ill Omen and Prophetic Sight abilities you have used against that creature within last minute.</p>
                    <p>After you cast either spell in this way, you can’t use this feature again until you finish a long rest.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                    <description>You may cast the Mass Suggestion or Power Word Pain spell without using a spell slot. If you’ve used Whispers of Dread ability on a creature, you know whenever that creature is an eligible target for Power Word Pain. Additionally, the spell’s hit point threshold on a target is increased by the amount of the destiny die roll results from Ill Omen and Prophetic Sight abilities you have used against that creature within last minute.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MASS_SUGGESTION" known="false" prepared="false" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_POWER_WORD_PAIN" known="false" prepared="false" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Fatal Pronouncement" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DOOMSAYER_FATAL_PRONOUNCEMENT">
                <description>
                    <p>A 18th level, your mystic powers can twist reality to provide additional vitality for those who heed your prophetic words. As a bonus action, you may choose a single creature you can see and foretell it’s demise. It becomes marked for 1 minute, and all the damage you deal against the target during that time is increased by your Wisdom modifier (minimum of 1). If the creature dies while marked, all allies within 90 feet of you gain temporary hit points equal to your Oracle level.</p>
                    <p>Once you use this feature, you can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="1/Long Rest" action="Bonus Action">
                    <description>you may choose a single creature you can see and foretell it’s demise. It becomes marked for 1 minute, and all the damage you deal against the target during that time is increased by {{fatal-pronouncement:damage}} hit points. If the creature dies while marked, all allies within 90 feet of you gain {{level:oracle}} temporary hit points.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="fatal-pronouncement:damage" value="1" bonus="base" />
                    <stat name="fatal-pronouncement:damage" value="wisdom:modifier" bonus="base" />
                </rules>
            </element>

            <element name="Doomsayer Quirk" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DOOMSAYER_QUIRK">
                <description>
                    <p>Quirks are personality traits or habits that your oracle might possess, giving them an unique edge. These quirks might be something your character has always had, or are the result or side effect of their oracle powers. While the tables here are arranged by subclasses and some of them are very subclass specific, there is nothing stopping you grabbing a quirk from a table that is not your oracle’s foretold fate if you feel it could fit your character.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <select type="List" name="Doomsayer Quirk">
                        <item id="1">You expect the worst to come, and see the worst in people.</item>
                        <item id="2">Nothing and no one is going to last forever, everything will fade eventually. Why should you care about anything?</item>
                        <item id="3">You enjoy the misery of others.</item>
                        <item id="4">You love to have power over others, be it by words or by magic, and there is no such thing as too much power.</item>
                        <item id="5">You grieve for every creature whose doom you foresee and foretell, and feel responsible for their imminent demise.</item>
                        <item id="6">You are eager to proclaim doom upon everyone and everything, whether true or not.</item>
                    </select>
                </rules>
            </element>

      <!-- Fate of the Dreamwalker-->
        <element name="Fate of the Dreamwalker" type="Archetype" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_ORACLE_FATE_OF_THE_DREAMWALKER">
            <supports>Foretold Fate</supports>
            <description>
                <p>Dreamwalkers are Oracles that are attuned to the world of dreams, gaining visions in their sleep and trances. The most powerful of Dreamwalkers can even travel into the sleeping thoughts of other creatures.</p>
                <h5>Dreamwalker Expanded Spell List</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Level</td><td>Spell Names</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>Cantrip</td><td><i>darkest dream<sup>*</sup>, minor illusion</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>1st</td><td><i>bless, sleep</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>2nd</td><td><i>calm emotions, silence (R)</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td><i>catnap<sup>XGtE</sup>, hypnotic pattern</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>4th</td><td><i>hallucinatory terrain, phantasmal killer</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><i>dream, modify memory</i></td></tr>
                </table>
                <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAMWALKER_WARDING_VISIONS" />
                <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAMWALKER_DREAMS_OF_TOMORROW" />
                <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAMWALKER_DREAM_WALK" />
                <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAMWALKER_ECSTATIC_VISIONS" />
                <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAMWALKER_DREAM_STEP" />
                <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAMWALKER_EXPANDED_VISIONS" />
                <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAMWALKER_QUIRK" />
            </description>
            <spellcasting name="Oracle" extend="true">
                <extend>ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_SPELL_DARKEST_DREAM</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_MINOR_ILLUSION</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_BLESS</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_SLEEP</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_CALM_EMOTIONS</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_SILENCE</extend>
                <extend>ID_XGTE_SPELL_CATNAP</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_HYPNOTIC_PATTERN</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_HALLUCINATORY_TERRAIN</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_PHANTASMAL_KILLER</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_DREAM</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_MODIFY_MEMORY</extend>
            </spellcasting>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAMWALKER_WARDING_VISIONS" level="1" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAMWALKER_DREAMS_OF_TOMORROW" level="2" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAMWALKER_DREAM_WALK" level="6" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAMWALKER_ECSTATIC_VISIONS" level="10" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAMWALKER_DREAM_STEP" level="15" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAMWALKER_EXPANDED_VISIONS" level="18" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAMWALKER_QUIRK" level="1" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Warding Visions" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAMWALKER_WARDING_VISIONS">
                <description>
                    <p>After you choose this Foretold Fate at level 1, whenever you expend an oracle spell slot, you gain temporary hit points equal to half your oracle level, rounded up.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>Whenever you expend an oracle spell slot, you gain {{level:oracle:half:up}} temporary hit points.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Dreams of Tomorrow" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAMWALKER_DREAMS_OF_TOMORROW">
                <description>
                    <p>At 2nd level, your ability to tap into your dreams enables you to create a fount of more mystical energy than most oracles. You gain a number of additional uses of Guide Destiny equal to your proficiency bonus.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="guide-destiny:uses" value="proficiency" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Dream Walk" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAMWALKER_DREAM_WALK">
                <description>
                    <p>When you reach 6th level, the time you need to sleep to gain the benefit of a long rest is halved, and you can also half the time needed to spend in short rest by taking a short nap for the duration of the short rest. For the duration of the long rest, you enter a lucid dream-state. While in this state, you may Dream Walk into the mind of any other dreaming or meditating creatures within 1000 feet. You may visit an number of creatures creatures up to the number of destiny dice you had remaining before the long rest.</p>
                    <p class="indent">While Dream Walking, you may attempt to speak a message of up to 10 words to each creature you visit. Once during the next 8 hours, the creatures you spoke to can roll a die equal to your Destiny die and add the result to one ability check or saving throw it makes. The creature can wait until after it rolls the d20 before deciding to use the Destiny die, but must decide before the DM says whether the roll succeeds or fails.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Once the Destiny die is rolled, it is lost. A creature can have only one Destiny die at a time. You do not need to share a language with the creatures you speak to, but creatures with an Intelligence of 3 or lower do not receive this benefit.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>The time you need to sleep to gain the benefit of a long rest is halved, and you can also half the time needed to spend in short rest by taking a short nap for the duration of the short rest. For the duration of the long rest, you enter a lucid dream-state and you may Dream Walk into the mind of any other dreaming or meditating creatures within 1000 feet. You may visit an number of creatures creatures up to the number of destiny dice you had remaining before the long rest. You can then give the creature gets a single Destiny die.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Ecstatic Visions" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAMWALKER_ECSTATIC_VISIONS">
                <description>
                    <p>Starting at level 10, you are blessed by a rush of soothing energy that results from averting a negative future. When your Prophetic Sight ability successfully changes an outcome, you gain a glimpse of the avoided fate and regain hit points equal to your Wisdom modifier.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>When your Prophetic Sight ability successfully changes an outcome, you gain a glimpse of the avoided fate and regain {{wisdom:modifier}} hit points.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Dream Step" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAMWALKER_DREAM_STEP">
                <description>
                    <p>At 15th level, Dreamwalkers learn how to better manifest their enemies’ nightmares, or visit other places in their deep trance. You may cast the <em>Eyebite</em> or <em>Project Image</em> spell without using a spell slot. With this use of <em>Project Image</em>, for the duration of the spell, you may swap places with your illusory copy as a bonus action. Doing so ends the spell early.</p>
                    <p>After you’ve cast either spell in this way, you can’t use this feature again until you finish a long rest.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                    <description>You may cast the Eyebite or Project Image spell without using a spell slot. With this use of Project Image, for the duration of the spell, you may swap places with your illusory copy as a bonus action. Doing so ends the spell early.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_EYEBITE" known="false" prepared="false" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PROJECT_IMAGE" known="false" prepared="false" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Expanded Visions" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAMWALKER_EXPANDED_VISIONS">
                <description>
                    <p>At 18th level, you learn how to give others glimpses of the visions you receive, sharing their positive energies. Whenever you gain temporary hit points from Warding Visions or regain hit points from Ecstatic Visions, you can choose one other creature you see to receive these benefits as well.</p>
                    <p>Additionally, when you use Shared Vision ability, you may share your visions up to two other creatures.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>Whenever you gain temporary hit points from Warding Visions or regain hit points from Ecstatic Visions, you can choose one other creature you see to receive these benefits as well. Additionally, when you use Shared Vision ability, you may share your visions up to two other creatures.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>

            <element name="Dreamwalker Quirk" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAMWALKER_QUIRK">
                <description>
                    <p>Quirks are personality traits or habits that your oracle might possess, giving them an unique edge. These quirks might be something your character has always had, or are the result or side effect of their oracle powers. While the tables here are arranged by subclasses and some of them are very subclass specific, there is nothing stopping you grabbing a quirk from a table that is not your oracle’s foretold fate if you feel it could fit your character.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <select type="List" name="Dreamwalker Quirk">
                        <item id="1">You have a tendency to sleepwalk or sleep-talk.</item>
                        <item id="2">You easily fall asleep if you’re not actively doing anything, or while listening someone.</item>
                        <item id="3">You have wild imagination, and eagerly share your ideas and thoughts with everyone whenever possible.</item>
                        <item id="4">You can never remember the dreams you’ve had, or suffer night terrors and prefer to stay up late.</item>
                        <item id="5">You keep a dream journal. Sometimes the journal seems to have pages filled but you don’t remember writing them.</item>
                        <item id="6">You easily forget trivial information about events and people.</item>
                    </select>
                </rules>
            </element>

      <!-- Fate of the Portentmender-->
        <element name="Fate of the Portentmender" type="Archetype" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_ORACLE_FATE_OF_THE_PORTENTMENDER">
            <supports>Foretold Fate</supports>
            <description>
                <p>Sometimes, even in the presence of an oracle, not everything goes according to plan. Portentmenders are oracles who specialize in healing people after such disaster, and guiding them back towards their intended destiny.</p>
                <h5>Portentmender Expanded Spell List</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Level</td><td>Spell Names</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>Cantrip</td><td><i>mending, spare the dying</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>1st</td><td><i>cure wounds, heroism</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>2nd</td><td><i>lesser restoration, prayer of healing</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td><i>beacon of hope, revivify</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>4th</td><td><i>aura of life, Otiluke’s resilient sphere</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><i>greater restoration, mass cure wounds</i></td></tr>
                </table>
                <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PORTENTMENDER_MENDERS_URGENCY" />
                <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PORTENTMENDER_GUIDE_DESTINY_BORROWED_FUTURE" />
                <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PORTENTMENDER_PORTENT_PACE" />
                <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PORTENTMENDER_SHIELD_OF_FATE" />
                <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PORTENTMENDER_FATE_CALLS_UPON" />
                <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PORTENTMENDER_DESTINYS_WARD" />
                <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PORTENTMENDER_QUIRK" />
            </description>
            <spellcasting name="Oracle" extend="true">
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_MENDING</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_SPARE_THE_DYING</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_CURE_WOUNDS</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_HEROISM</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_LESSER_RESTORATION</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_PRAYER_OF_HEALING</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_BEACON_OF_HOPE</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_REVIVIFY</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_AURA_OF_LIFE</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_OTILUKES_RESILIENT_SPHERE</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_GREATER_RESTORATION</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_MASS_CURE_WOUNDS</extend>
            </spellcasting>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PORTENTMENDER_MENDERS_URGENCY" level="1" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PORTENTMENDER_GUIDE_DESTINY_BORROWED_FUTURE" level="2" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PORTENTMENDER_PORTENT_PACE" level="6" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PORTENTMENDER_SHIELD_OF_FATE" level="10" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PORTENTMENDER_FATE_CALLS_UPON" level="15" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PORTENTMENDER_DESTINYS_WARD" level="18" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PORTENTMENDER_QUIRK" level="1" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Mender’s Urgency" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PORTENTMENDER_MENDERS_URGENCY">
                <description>
                    <p>When you choose this Foretold Fate at level 1, you may as a bonus action move up to half your speed toward an ally of your choice that you can see or hear. You must end this move closer to the ally than you started.</p>
                    <p class="indent">If the ally is unconscious, you may move up to your full speed instead.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                    <description>You may as a bonus action move up to half your speed toward an ally of your choice that you can see or hear. You must end this move closer to the ally than you started. If the ally is unconscious, you may move up to your full speed instead.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Guide Destiny: Borrowed Future" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PORTENTMENDER_GUIDE_DESTINY_BORROWED_FUTURE">
                <description>
                    <p>At 2nd level, you can use your abilities to reach into your future period of rest and draw from that rejuvenation in the time of need. As an action, touch one creature other than yourself and expend a destiny die and a number of Hit Dice up to half your oracle level. The creature regains hit points equal to the total of the dice. Hit dice expended this way are regained as normal via a long rest.</p>
                    <p class="indent">At 11th level, if the Destiny die roll for this feature is 10 or greater, you can reroll the Hit Dice expended by this feature once, and must use the new result.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet action="Action" usage="Guide Destiny" alt="Borrowed Future">
                    <description>Touch one creature other than yourself and expend a destiny die and a number of Hit Dice up to {{level:oracle:half}}. The creature regains hit points equal to the total of the dice. Hit dice expended this way are regained as normal via a long rest.</description>
                    <description level="11">Touch one creature other than yourself and expend a destiny die and a number of Hit Dice up to {{level:oracle:half}}. The creature regains hit points equal to the total of the dice. Hit dice expended this way are regained as normal via a long rest. If the Destiny die roll for this feature is 10 or greater, you can reroll the Hit Dice expended by this feature once, and must use the new result.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Portent Pace" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PORTENTMENDER_PORTENT_PACE">
                <description>
                    <p>At 6th level, the aid you have given to others is reflected back by being granted more time to fulfill your destiny as well as greater vitality. For every 10 years that pass, your body ages only 1 year. You also gain immunity against non-magical diseases.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>For every 10 years that pass, your body ages only 1 year. You also gain immunity against non-magical diseases.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Shield of Fate" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PORTENTMENDER_SHIELD_OF_FATE">
                <description>
                    <p>At 10th level, you are able to bolster yourself and your allies. Whenever you cast a spell or use an ability that heals a creature above its maximum hit points, that creature gains temporary hit points for 1 minute equal to half the amount healed above that creature’s maximum hit points.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>Whenever you cast a spell or use an ability that heals a creature above its maximum hit points, that creature gains temporary hit points for 1 minute equal to half the amount healed above that creature’s maximum hit points.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Fate Calls Upon" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PORTENTMENDER_FATE_CALLS_UPON">
                <description>
                    <p>At 15th level, Fatemenders gain additional power over life and death, for the fate of the world hinges on the survival of its saviors. You may cast the <em>Heal</em> or <em>Resurrection</em> spell without using a spell slot. With this use of <em>Resurrection</em>, the target of the spell does not receive penalty to attack rolls, saving throws and ability checks.</p>
                    <p>After you’ve cast either spell in this way, you can’t use this feature again until you finish a long rest.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                    <description>You may cast the Heal or Resurrection spell without using a spell slot. With this use of Resurrection, the target of the spell does not receive penalty to attack rolls, saving throws and ability checks.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HEAL" known="false" prepared="false" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RESURRECTION" known="false" prepared="false" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Destiny’s Ward" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PORTENTMENDER_DESTINYS_WARD">
                <description>
                    <p>At 18th level, you are always under the effect of <em>Sanctuary</em> spell. If you end the effect via normal means, or if you use Guide Destiny against a creature and they make a successful Wisdom (Insight) check to notice it, the creature is immune to the effect for 24 hours.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>You are always under the effect of Sanctuary spell. If you end the effect via normal means, or if you use Guide Destiny against a creature and they make a successful Wisdom (Insight) check to notice it, the creature is immune to the effect for 24 hours.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SANCTUARY" known="false" prepared="false" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Portentmender Quirk" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PORTENTMENDER_QUIRK">
                <description>
                    <p>Quirks are personality traits or habits that your oracle might possess, giving them an unique edge. These quirks might be something your character has always had, or are the result or side effect of their oracle powers. While the tables here are arranged by subclasses and some of them are very subclass specific, there is nothing stopping you grabbing a quirk from a table that is not your oracle’s foretold fate if you feel it could fit your character.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <select type="List" name="Portentmender Quirk">
                        <item id="1">You are uncomfortable around open wounds or sick people. Dead creatures horrify you.</item>
                        <item id="2">You often loose the track of time and arrive late to scheduled events.</item>
                        <item id="3">You have low pain tolerance.</item>
                        <item id="4">You feel that your work is more important than anything, and often overlook your own personal needs to get the job done.</item>
                        <item id="5">You have only ever used magic to heal people. You have no idea how humanoid body works or how to treat even the simplest of ailments without magical aid.</item>
                        <item id="6">You put your own needs over the needs of others.</item>
                    </select>
                </rules>
            </element>

      <!-- Fate of the Signreader-->
        <element name="Fate of the Signreader" type="Archetype" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_ORACLE_FATE_OF_THE_SIGNREADER">
            <supports>Foretold Fate</supports>
            <description>
                <p>There are numerous old, forgotten prophesies scattered throughout the lands. Oracles who dedicate themselves finding and cataloging these omens are known as Signreaders. Once an oracle has gathered sufficient amount of prophesies, they tend to start seeing signs of great disaster or fortune even in the smallest of things. To a farmer, a dark cloud foretells rain, to a signreader, a cloud could be a sign of the end of the world. Of all the oracles, they are most well prepared for the unexpected, for they know to expect it.</p>
                <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SIGNREADER_TOME_OF_SIGNS" />
                <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SIGNREADER_GUIDE_DESTINY_READ_THE_SIGNS" />
                <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SIGNREADER_RITUAL_MASTERY" />
                <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SIGNREADER_AS_IT_IS_WRITTEN" />
                <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SIGNREADER_ESOTERIC_WAY" />
                <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SIGNREADER_FOREWARNED" />
                <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SIGNREADER_QUIRK" />
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SIGNREADER_TOME_OF_SIGNS" level="1" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SIGNREADER_GUIDE_DESTINY_READ_THE_SIGNS" level="2" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SIGNREADER_RITUAL_MASTERY" level="6" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SIGNREADER_AS_IT_IS_WRITTEN" level="10" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SIGNREADER_ESOTERIC_WAY" level="15" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SIGNREADER_FOREWARNED" level="18" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SIGNREADER_QUIRK" level="1" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Tome of Signs" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SIGNREADER_TOME_OF_SIGNS">
                <description>
                    <p>When you choose this Foretold Fate at 1st level, instead of gaining an expanded spell list, you gain a Tome of Signs, which serves both as a spellbook and a catalog for your collected prophesies. Choose two wizard cantrips and one 1st-level wizard spell of your choice. While the tome is on your person, you can cast the cantrips at will, and they don’t count against the number of cantrips you know. If they don’t appear in the oracle spell list, they are nonetheless oracle spells for you. Furthermore, the spells contained in it are added to your oracle spell list.</p>
                    <h5>LEARNING SPELLS OF 1ST LEVEL AND HIGHER</h5>
                    <p>On every Oracle level, you can add one wizard spell of your choice to your Tome of Signs for free. The spells must be of a level for which you have Spell Slots, as shown on the Oracle table. On your adventures, you might find other spells that you can add to your Tome of Omens. For each level of the spell, the process takes 2 hours and costs 50 gold pieces.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>While the tome is on your person, you can cast the cantrips at will, and they don’t count against the number of cantrips you know.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Tome of Signs)" number="2" supports="Wizard,0" spellcasting="Oracle" />
                    <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Tome of Signs)" number="1" supports="Wizard,$(spellcasting:slots)" spellcasting="Oracle" known="true" />
                    <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Tome of Signs)" number="2" supports="Wizard,$(spellcasting:slots)" spellcasting="Oracle" known="true" />
                    <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Tome of Signs)" number="3" supports="Wizard,$(spellcasting:slots)" spellcasting="Oracle" known="true" />
                    <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Tome of Signs)" number="4" supports="Wizard,$(spellcasting:slots)" spellcasting="Oracle" known="true" />
                    <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Tome of Signs)" number="5" supports="Wizard,$(spellcasting:slots)" spellcasting="Oracle" known="true" />
                    <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Tome of Signs)" number="6" supports="Wizard,$(spellcasting:slots)" spellcasting="Oracle" known="true" />
                    <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Tome of Signs)" number="7" supports="Wizard,$(spellcasting:slots)" spellcasting="Oracle" known="true" />
                    <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Tome of Signs)" number="8" supports="Wizard,$(spellcasting:slots)" spellcasting="Oracle" known="true" />
                    <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Tome of Signs)" number="9" supports="Wizard,$(spellcasting:slots)" spellcasting="Oracle" known="true" />
                    <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Tome of Signs)" number="10" supports="Wizard,$(spellcasting:slots)" spellcasting="Oracle" known="true" />
                    <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Tome of Signs)" number="11" supports="Wizard,$(spellcasting:slots)" spellcasting="Oracle" known="true" />
                    <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Tome of Signs)" number="12" supports="Wizard,$(spellcasting:slots)" spellcasting="Oracle" known="true" />
                    <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Tome of Signs)" number="13" supports="Wizard,$(spellcasting:slots)" spellcasting="Oracle" known="true" />
                    <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Tome of Signs)" number="14" supports="Wizard,$(spellcasting:slots)" spellcasting="Oracle" known="true" />
                    <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Tome of Signs)" number="15" supports="Wizard,$(spellcasting:slots)" spellcasting="Oracle" known="true" />
                    <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Tome of Signs)" number="16" supports="Wizard,$(spellcasting:slots)" spellcasting="Oracle" known="true" />
                    <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Tome of Signs)" number="17" supports="Wizard,$(spellcasting:slots)" spellcasting="Oracle" known="true" />
                    <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Tome of Signs)" number="18" supports="Wizard,$(spellcasting:slots)" spellcasting="Oracle" known="true" />
                    <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Tome of Signs)" number="19" supports="Wizard,$(spellcasting:slots)" spellcasting="Oracle" known="true" />
                    <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Tome of Signs)" number="20" supports="Wizard,$(spellcasting:slots)" spellcasting="Oracle" known="true" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Guide Destiny: Read the Signs" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SIGNREADER_GUIDE_DESTINY_READ_THE_SIGNS">
                <description>
                    <p>At 2nd level, you can tap into the knowledge hidden within your Tome of Signs to alter the battle before it even truly begins. Whenever you see a creature roll for initiative, you may as a reaction expend a Destiny die and apply the result as a bonus or penalty (your choice) to the creature’s roll. You can do so after the creature rolls but before first turn begins.</p>
                    <p class="indent">At 11th level, if the Destiny die roll for this feature is 10 or greater, you can target one additional creature with this ability.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet alt="Read the Signs" usage="Guide Destiny" action="Reaction">
                    <description>Whenever you see a creature roll for initiative, you may as a reaction expend a Destiny die and apply the result as a bonus or penalty (your choice) to the creature’s roll. You can do so after the creature rolls but before first turn begins.</description>
                    <description level="11">Whenever you see a creature roll for initiative, you may as a reaction expend a Destiny die and apply the result as a bonus or penalty (your choice) to the creature’s roll. You can do so after the creature rolls but before first turn begins. If the Destiny die roll for this feature is 10 or greater, you can target one additional creature with this ability.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Ritual Mastery" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SIGNREADER_RITUAL_MASTERY">
                <description>
                    <p>At 6th, all signs lead to quicker spell casting, for destiny waits no one. The additional time needed to cast a ritual spell is shortened from 10 minutes to 5 minutes for you.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>The additional time needed to cast a ritual spell is shortened from 10 minutes to 5 minutes for you.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="As It Is Written" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SIGNREADER_AS_IT_IS_WRITTEN">
                <description>
                    <p>At 10th level, your ability to see the warning signs of each situation allows you to react in best way to each danger. You may as a bonus action replace one spell you have prepared with another from your Tome of Signs.</p>
                    <p>You can’t use this feature again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="1/Short Rest">
                    <description>You may one spell you have prepared with another from your Tome of Signs.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Esoteric Way" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SIGNREADER_ESOTERIC_WAY">
                <description>
                    <p>At 15th level, you gain new ways to prepare for whats to come, and to arrive at the location of destiny’s calling at right moment. You may cast the <em>Contingency</em> or <em>Teleport</em> spell without using a spell slot. With this use of <em>Teleport</em>, you are always considered to be very familiar with your destination as long as you have been there at least once. If you’ve only seen the place once through a spell, you can instead regard the location as something you have seen casually.</p>
                    <p>Once you’ve cast either spell in this way, you can’t use this feature again until you finish a long rest.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                    <description>You may cast the Contingency or Teleport spell without using a spell slot. With this use of Teleport, you are always considered to be very familiar with your destination as long as you have been there at least once. If you’ve only seen the place once through a spell, you can instead regard the location as something you have seen casually.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONTINGENCY" spellcasting="Oracle" known="false" prepared="false" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TELEPORT" spellcasting="Oracle" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Forewarned" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SIGNREADER_FOREWARNED">
                <description>
                    <p>At 18th level, you have collected enough omens, signs and prophecies in your Tome of Signs so that little fazes you anymore, and you are always ready to clear the path to destiny. When you roll initiative and have no uses of Guide Destiny left, you gain 2 uses of it.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>When you roll initiative and have no uses of Guide Destiny left, you gain 2 uses of it.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Signreader Quirk" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SIGNREADER_QUIRK">
                <description>
                    <p>Quirks are personality traits or habits that your oracle might possess, giving them an unique edge. These quirks might be something your character has always had, or are the result or side effect of their oracle powers. While the tables here are arranged by subclasses and some of them are very subclass specific, there is nothing stopping you grabbing a quirk from a table that is not your oracle’s foretold fate if you feel it could fit your character.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <select type="List" name="Signreader Quirk">
                        <item id="1">Even simple and mundane events seem like signs of impending doom to you.</item>
                        <item id="2">You record everything that might be a sign, but you do it out of habit more than actually believing they amount to anything.</item>
                        <item id="3">You tend to speak in matter of fact and humdrum way.</item>
                        <item id="4">You often present yourself more knowledgeable than you truly are.</item>
                        <item id="5">You prefer your own company or reading your books over the company of others.</item>
                        <item id="6">You value your Tome of Signs more than anything, even your own life.</item>
                    </select>
                </rules>
            </element>

      <!-- Fate of the Spiritseer-->
        <element name="Fate of the Spiritseer" type="Archetype" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_ORACLE_FATE_OF_THE_SPIRITSEER">
            <supports>Foretold Fate</supports>
            <description>
                <p>It is said that history repeats itself. To know the future, one must first know the past. These are the words oracles known as Spiritseers adhere to. They consult the spirits of the dead, drawing upon their knowledge and gaining hints of foretold prophesies.</p>
                <h5>Spiritseer Expanded Spell List</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Level</td><td>Spell Names</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>Cantrip</td><td><i>chill touch, mage hand</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>1st</td><td><i>armor of Agathys, unseen servant (R)</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>2nd</td><td><i>levitate, spiritual weapon</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td><i>fear, spirit guardians</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>4th</td><td><i>death ward, sickening radiance<sup>XGtE</sup></i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><i>antilife shell, dispel evil and good</i></td></tr>
                </table>
                <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRITSEER_SPECTRAL_GUIDANCE" />
                <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRITSEER_GUIDE_DESTINY_GRAVE_WARNING" />
                <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRITSEER_DEAD_MEN_TELL_NO_LIES" />
                <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRITSEER_BODY_AND_SOUL" />
                <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRITSEER_CROSS_THE_LINE" />
                <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRITSEER_GUIDE_DESTINY_BEYOND_THE_VEIL" />
                <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRITSEER_QUIRK" />
            </description>
            <spellcasting name="Oracle" extend="true">
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_CHILL_TOUCH</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGE_HAND</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_ARMOR_OF_AGATHYS</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_UNSEEN_SERVANT</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_LEVITATE</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_SPIRITUAL_WEAPON</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_FEAR</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_SPIRIT_GUARDIANS</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_DEATH_WARD</extend>
                <extend>ID_XGTE_SPELL_SICKENING_RADIANCE</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_ANTILIFE_SHELL</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_DISPEL_EVIL_AND_GOOD</extend>
            </spellcasting>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRITSEER_SPECTRAL_GUIDANCE" level="1" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRITSEER_GUIDE_DESTINY_GRAVE_WARNING" level="2" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRITSEER_DEAD_MEN_TELL_NO_LIES" level="6" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRITSEER_BODY_AND_SOUL" level="10" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRITSEER_CROSS_THE_LINE" level="15" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRITSEER_GUIDE_DESTINY_BEYOND_THE_VEIL" level="18" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRITSEER_QUIRK" level="1" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Spectral Guidance" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRITSEER_SPECTRAL_GUIDANCE">
                <description>
                    <p>When you choose this Foretold Fate at level 1, the spirits begin to guide your spellcasting. Spells with range of touch have a range of 30 feet for you, and spells with a range of 5 feet or greater have their range increased by 30 feet.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>Spells with range of touch have a range of 30 feet for you, and spells with a range of 5 feet or greater have their range increased by 30 feet.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Guide Destiny: Grave Warning" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRITSEER_GUIDE_DESTINY_GRAVE_WARNING">
                <description>
                    <p>The spirits whisper warnings about impending doom that they themselves have faced when they were still living. At 2nd level, when an ally you can see makes a saving throw, you may as a reaction expend a Destiny die and apply the result to their saving throw. Death saving throws and spells that subject a creature to saving throw cannot be influenced.</p>
                    <p class="indent">At 11th level, this ability increases. If the Destiny die roll for this feature is 10 or greater, the target can make the next saving throw with advantage.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet alt="Grave Warning" usage="Guide Destiny" action="Reaction">
                    <description>When an ally you can see makes a saving throw, you may as a reaction expend a Destiny die and apply the result to their saving throw. Death saving throws and spells that subject a creature to saving throw cannot be influenced.</description>
                    <description level="11">When an ally you can see makes a saving throw, you may as a reaction expend a Destiny die and apply the result to their saving throw. Death saving throws and spells that subject a creature to saving throw cannot be influenced. If the Destiny die roll for this feature is 10 or greater, the target can make the next saving throw with advantage.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Dead Men Tell No Lies" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRITSEER_DEAD_MEN_TELL_NO_LIES">
                <description>
                    <p>Starting at 6th level, you can cast <em>Speak with Dead</em> once without expending a spell slot. When you cast the spell this way, the target can’t speak a deliberate lie, as if affected by <em>Zone of Truth</em> spell. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
                    <p>Additionally, you can see into the Ethereal Plane up to 15 feet.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                    <description>You can cast Speak with Dead once without expending a spell slot. When you cast the spell this way, the target can’t speak a deliberate lie, as if affected by Zone of Truth spell. Additionally, you can see into the Ethereal Plane up to 15 feet.</description>
                </sheet>
                    <grant id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_DEAD" type="Spell" spellcasting="Oracle" known="false" prepared="false" />
                    <grant id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ZONE_OF_TRUTH" type="Spell" spellcasting="Oracle" known="false" prepared="false" />                    
            </element>
            <element name="Body and Soul" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRITSEER_BODY_AND_SOUL">
                <description>
                    <p>At 10th level, you gain greater mastery over your own life through your connection and understanding of death. You gain proficiency in Constitution saving throws. You also make death saving throws with advantage.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>You make death saving throws with advantage.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CONSTITUTION" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Cross the Line" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRITSEER_CROSS_THE_LINE">
                <description>
                    <p>At 15th level, Spiritseer’s mastery over spirits and Ethereal Plane strengthens. You may cast the <em>Etherealness</em> or <em>Soul Cage</em> spell without using a spell slot. When you cast <em>Etherealness</em> this way, you may touch one other willing creature to target them with the spell as well. You must keep touching the other creature for the duration or the spell ends early for them. You can also end the spell early as an action.</p>
                    <p>After you’ve cast either spell in this way, you can’t use this feature again until you finish a long rest.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                    <description>You may cast the Etherealness or Soul Cage spell without using a spell slot. When you cast Etherealness this way, you may touch one other willing creature to target them with the spell as well. You must keep touching the other creature for the duration or the spell ends early for them. You can also end the spell early as an action.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ETHEREALNESS" spellcasting="Oracle" known="false" prepared="false" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_SOUL_CAGE" spellcasting="Oracle" known="false" prepared="false" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Guide Destiny: Beyond the Veil" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRITSEER_GUIDE_DESTINY_BEYOND_THE_VEIL">
                <description>
                    <p>At 18th level, you can pull back the ethereal curtain and a hazy fog obscures you while you slip between worlds. As an action, you may spend a destiny die to blink in and out of the Ethereal Plane for 1 minute (as the Blink spell). You can dismiss this ability as an action.</p>
                    <p class="indent">While on the Ethereal Plane, you can see and hear the plane you originated from, which is cast in shades of gray, and you can’t see anything there more than 120 feet away.</p>
                    <p class="indent">During any round while you are hidden on the Ethereal Plane, you may use your Prophetic Sight or Grave Warning abilities without spending a use of Guide Destiny to affect creatures on your original plane of existence. Other than these two of your abilities, you can only affect and be affected by other creatures on the Ethereal Plane. Creatures that aren’t there can’t perceive you or interact with you, unless they have the ability to do so.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet alt="Beyond the Veil" action="Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
                    <description>You may spend a destiny die to blink in and out of the Ethereal Plane for 1 minute (as the Blink spell). You can dismiss this ability as an action. While on the Ethereal Plane, you can see and hear the plane you originated from, which is cast in shades of gray, and you can’t see anything there more than 120 feet away. During any round while you are hidden on the Ethereal Plane, you may use your Prophetic Sight or Grave Warning abilities without spending a use of Guide Destiny to affect creatures on your original plane of existence. Other than these two of your abilities, you can only affect and be affected by other creatures on the Ethereal Plane. Creatures that aren’t there can’t perceive you or interact with you, unless they have the ability to do so.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Spiritseer Quirk" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRITSEER_QUIRK">
                <description>
                    <p>Quirks are personality traits or habits that your oracle might possess, giving them an unique edge. These quirks might be something your character has always had, or are the result or side effect of their oracle powers. While the tables here are arranged by subclasses and some of them are very subclass specific, there is nothing stopping you grabbing a quirk from a table that is not your oracle’s foretold fate if you feel it could fit your character.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <select type="List" name="Spiritseer Quirk">
                        <item id="1">You are pestered by the spirits of your past that keep whispering into your ears.</item>
                        <item id="2">You’ve lost a very important person to you. You wish to one day to speak or reunite with them.</item>
                        <item id="3">You have grim sense of humor.</item>
                        <item id="4">The dead have to earn your respect just like the living. Few do.</item>
                        <item id="5">You treat all the dead and undead in same manner as you would a living person.</item>
                        <item id="6">You are distant or tend to ignore others.</item>
                    </select>
                </rules>
            </element>
      <!-- Fate of the Stargazer-->
        <element name="Fate of the Stargazer" type="Archetype" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_ORACLE_FATE_OF_THE_STARGAZER">
            <supports>Foretold Fate</supports>
            <description>
                <p>Stargazers are oracles who look for answers to the future written in the stars, and act as beacons of light and hope in the darkness. And while the starry night sky may seem serene and peaceful, one should not be fooled by this appearance. Indeed, Stargazers do not hesitate to unleash cosmic destruction upon those who might seek to undermine destiny laid out by the stars.</p>
                <h5>Stargazer Expanded Spell List</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Level</td><td>Spell Names</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>Cantrip</td><td><i>dancing lights, word of radiance<sup>XGtE</sup></i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>1st</td><td><i>guiding bolt, longstrider</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>2nd</td><td><i>blur, moonbeam</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td><i>fly, Melf’s minute meteors</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>4th</td><td><i>dimension door, freedom of movement</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><i>dawn<sup>XGtE</sup>, flamestrike</i></td></tr>
                </table>
                <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STARGAZER_STELLAR_GUIDANCE" />
                <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STARGAZER_GUIDE_DESTINY_LIGHTYEAR_AHEAD" />
                <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STARGAZER_AIM_FOR_THE_STARS" />
                <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STARGAZER_STARCROSSED" />
                <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STARGAZER_COSMIC_CORONATION" />
                <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STARGAZER_REWRITE_THE_STARS" />
                <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STARGAZER_QUIRK" />
            </description>
            <spellcasting name="Oracle" extend="true">
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_DANCING_LIGHTS</extend>
                <extend>ID_XGTE_SPELL_WORD_OF_RADIANCE</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_GUIDING_BOLT</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_LONGSTRIDER</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_BLUR</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_MOONBEAM</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_FLY</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_MELFS_MINUTE_METEORS</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_DIMENSION_DOOR</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_FREEDOM_OF_MOVEMENT</extend>
                <extend>ID_XGTE_SPELL_DAWN</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_FLAMESTRIKE</extend>
            </spellcasting>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STARGAZER_STELLAR_GUIDANCE" level="1" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STARGAZER_GUIDE_DESTINY_LIGHTYEAR_AHEAD" level="2" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STARGAZER_AIM_FOR_THE_STARS" level="6" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STARGAZER_STARCROSSED" level="10" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STARGAZER_COSMIC_CORONATION" level="15" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STARGAZER_REWRITE_THE_STARS" level="18" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STARGAZER_QUIRK" level="1" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Stellar Guidance" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STARGAZER_STELLAR_GUIDANCE">
                <description>
                    <p>Though you may wander under the starry sky, you are never truly lost. When you choose this Foretold Fate at level 1, you gain proficiency with Survival skill and cartographer’s tools.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Additionally, while you can see the night sky, you gain advantage on Wisdom (Survival) checks to navigate, and you always know which way is north. You also can’t be surprised while you are under the night sky.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>While you can see the night sky, you gain advantage on Wisdom (Survival) checks to navigate, and you always know which way is north. You also can’t be surprised while you are under the night sky.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SURVIVAL" />
                    <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_CARTOGRAPHERS_TOOLS" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Guide Destiny: Light-year Ahead" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STARGAZER_GUIDE_DESTINY_LIGHTYEAR_AHEAD">
                <description>
                    <p>At 2nd level, lucky stars keep you from harm’s way. Your One Step Ahead ability is replaced by Lightyear Ahead:</p>
                    <p class="indent">As a reaction when an enemy comes within 5 feet of you, you can fly up to half your movement speed without prompting an attack of opportunity from that enemy. The enemy must succeed a Dexterity saving throw against your spell save DC or take radiant damage to the enemy equal to half the destiny die roll.</p>
                    <p class="indent">At 11th level, if the Destiny die roll for this feature is 10 or greater, you regain the reaction you used to spend on this ability.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet alt="Light-year Ahead" usage="Guide Destiny" action="Reaction">
                    <description>When an enemy comes within 5 feet of you, you can fly up to half your movement speed without prompting an attack of opportunity from that enemy. The enemy must succeed a Dexterity saving throw against your spell save DC or take radiant damage to the enemy equal to half the destiny die roll.</description>
                    <description level="11">When an enemy comes within 5 feet of you, you can fly up to half your movement speed without prompting an attack of opportunity from that enemy. The enemy must succeed a Dexterity saving throw against your spell save DC or take radiant damage to the enemy equal to half the destiny die roll. If the Destiny die roll for this feature is 10 or greater, you regain the reaction you used to spend on this ability.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Aim for the Stars" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STARGAZER_AIM_FOR_THE_STARS">
                <description>
                    <p>Your mystic powers are inspired by shooting stars in the night sky. At 6th level, whenever you expend an oracle spell slot, your speed increases by 5 feet. This benefit lasts until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>Whenever you expend an oracle spell slot, your speed increases by 5 feet. This benefit lasts until you finish a short or long rest.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Star-crossed" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STARGAZER_STARCROSSED">
                <description>
                    <p>Starting at 10th level, as a bonus action, you can choose one creature that you can see and swap places with them. An unwilling creature can make a Charisma saving throw and on a successful save, they do not swap places with you.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t do so again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="1/Short Rest">
                    <description>You can choose one creature that you can see and swap places with them. An unwilling creature can make a Charisma saving throw and on a successful save, they do not swap places with you.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Cosmic Coronation" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STARGAZER_COSMIC_CORONATION">
                <description>
                    <p>At 15th level, the stars you have gazed upon for so long bestow upon you a gift. You may cast the <em>Crown of Stars (XGE)</em> or <em>Scatter (XGE)</em> spell without using a spell slot. This use of <em>Crown of Stars</em> lasts until your next short or long rest, or until all motes have been expended.</p>
                    <p class="indent">After you’ve cast either spell in this way, you can’t use this feature again until you finish a long rest.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                    <description>You may cast the Crown of Stars or Scatter spell without using a spell slot. This use of Crown of Stars lasts until your next short or long rest, or until all motes have been expended.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_CROWN_OF_STARS" spellcasting="Oracle" known="false" prepared="false" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_SCATTER" spellcasting="Oracle" known="false" prepared="false" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Rewrite the Stars" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STARGAZER_REWRITE_THE_STARS">
                <description>
                    <p>At 18th level, your power over cosmos grows, and you can make fine tuned adjustments to keep the destiny flowing to intended direction. Whenever you roll a Destiny die, you can choose to reroll that die once, and use either roll. You can choose to do so after the initial roll.</p>
                    <p class="indent">You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier (minimum of one), and regain its uses after a long rest.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="{{rewrite-the-stars:uses}}/Long Rest">
                    <description>Whenever you roll a Destiny die, you can choose to reroll that die once, and use either roll. You can choose to do so after the initial roll.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="rewrite-the-stars:uses" value="1" bonus="base" />
                    <stat name="rewrite-the-stars:uses" value="wisdom:modifier" bonus="base" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Stargazer Quirk" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STARGAZER_QUIRK">
                <description>
                    <p>Quirks are personality traits or habits that your oracle might possess, giving them an unique edge. These quirks might be something your character has always had, or are the result or side effect of their oracle powers. While the tables here are arranged by subclasses and some of them are very subclass specific, there is nothing stopping you grabbing a quirk from a table that is not your oracle’s foretold fate if you feel it could fit your character.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <select type="List" name="Stargazer Quirk">
                        <item id="1">You often daydream, and let your mind wander a lot if not focused on a task.</item>
                        <item id="2">You prefer the outdoors, and sleep best under the starry sky. Closed spaces feel uncomfortable to you.</item>
                        <item id="3">You have a hard time to make up your mind on anything, and often resort to seeking guidance from the stars on any decision making.</item>
                        <item id="4">You are swift to spring to action, and get anxious when you have to wait for someone or something.</item>
                        <item id="5">You treat constellations and other heavenly bodies as your friends, and speak to them even though they are awfully silent.</item>
                        <item id="6">The whole world revolves around you: You love attention. You’re willing to go great lengths to attain it.</item>
                    </select>
                </rules>
            </element>

      <!-- Fate of the Truthseeker-->
        <element name="Fate of the Truthseeker" type="Archetype" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_ORACLE_FATE_OF_THE_TRUTHSEEKER">
            <supports>Foretold Fate</supports>
            <description>
                <p>Oracles who use their powers to root out lies and reveal the truth, be they mundane or otherwise, are aptly named Truthseekers. These oracles are well versed in tides of destiny, perhaps thanks to knowing some hidden truth about the future that others do not.</p>
                <h5>Truthseeker Expanded Spell List</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Level</td><td>Spell Names</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>Cantrip</td><td><i>blade ward, light</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>1st</td><td><i>faerie fire, magic missile</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>2nd</td><td><i>enhance ability, zone of truth</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td><i>dispel magic, remove curse</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>4th</td><td><i>banishment, fabricate</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><i>geas, skill empowerment<sup>XGtE</sup></i></td></tr>
                </table>
                <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRUTHSEEKER_ANTICIPATED_TRUTH" />
                <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRUTHSEEKER_PIERCING_SIGHT" />
                <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRUTHSEEKER_SILENT_TRUTH" />
                <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRUTHSEEKER_CLARITY_OF_SIGHT" />
                <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRUTHSEEKER_DISPEL_FALSEHOOD" />
                <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRUTHSEEKER_TRUTH_HURTS" />
                <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRUTHSEEKER_QUIRK" />
            </description>
            <spellcasting name="Oracle" extend="true">
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_BLADE_WARD</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_LIGHT</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_FAERIE_FIRE</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGIC_MISSILE</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_ENHANCE_ABILITY</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_ZONE_OF_TRUTH</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_DISPEL_MAGIC</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_REMOVE_CURSE</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_BANISHMENT</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_FABRICATE</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_GEAS</extend>
                <extend>ID_XGTE_SPELL_SKILL_EMPOWERMENT</extend>
            </spellcasting>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRUTHSEEKER_ANTICIPATED_TRUTH" level="1" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRUTHSEEKER_PIERCING_SIGHT" level="2" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRUTHSEEKER_SILENT_TRUTH" level="6" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRUTHSEEKER_CLARITY_OF_SIGHT" level="10" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRUTHSEEKER_DISPEL_FALSEHOOD" level="15" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRUTHSEEKER_TRUTH_HURTS" level="18" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRUTHSEEKER_QUIRK" level="1" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Anticipated Truth" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRUTHSEEKER_ANTICIPATED_TRUTH">
                <description>
                    <p>When you choose this Foretold Fate at level 1, you do not hesitate to see destiny fulfilled even at the face of danger. You learn the <em>Anticipation</em> cantrip. The cantrip doesn’t count against your number of cantrips known.</p>
                    <p> For you, <em>Anticipation</em> has a casting time of bonus action.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                    <description>For you, Anticipation has a casting time of bonus action.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_SPELL_ANTICIPATION" known="true" prepared="true" spellcasting="Oracle" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Piercing Sight" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRUTHSEEKER_PIERCING_SIGHT">
                <description>
                    <p>Also at 2nd level, your power to bend destiny to its true course manifests in greater precision than to most oracles. When you roll a Destiny die, you can choose to use the die maximum instead of the roll. You must choose to do so before the roll.</p>
                    <p>You can use this feature twice, and regain all uses after a long rest.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="2/Long Rest">
                    <description>When you roll a Destiny die, you can choose to use the die maximum instead of the roll. You must choose to do so before the roll.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Silent Truth" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRUTHSEEKER_SILENT_TRUTH">
                <description>
                    <p>The truth is often left unsaid, and lies have short legs. Your mystical gift lends itself to your pursuit of truth and finding falsehoods.</p>
                    <p class="indent">At 6th level, you can cast divination spells without needing Verbal or Somatic components. Additionally, you have advantage on Wisdom (Insight) checks to see if someone is lying.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>You can cast divination spells without needing Verbal or Somatic components. Additionally, you have advantage on Wisdom (Insight) checks to see if someone is lying.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Clarity of Sight" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRUTHSEEKER_CLARITY_OF_SIGHT">
                <description>
                    <p>At 10th level, you become more adept at influencing destiny and may add your Wisdom modifier to your Destiny die rolls.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>You add your Wisdom modifier (+{{wisdom:modifier}}) to your Destiny die rolls.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Dispel Falsehood" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRUTHSEEKER_DISPEL_FALSEHOOD">
                <description>
                    <p>At 15th level, your pursuit of truth has granted you greater nsight about the world around you. You may cast the <em>Divine Word</em> or <em>Find the Path</em> spell without using a spell slot. With this casting of <em>Divine Word</em>, you may also attempt to dispel a single illusion spell within the spell’s range as if you’d cast <em>Dispel Magic</em> at 7th level.</p>
                    <p>After you’ve cast either spell in this way, you can’t use this feature again until you finish a long rest.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                    <description>You may cast the Divine Word or Find the Path spell without using a spell slot. With this casting of Divine Word, you may also attempt to dispel a single illusion spell within the spell’s range as if you’d cast Dispel Magic at 7th level.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DIVINE_WORD" spellcasting="Oracle" known="false" prepared="false" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIND_THE_PATH" spellcasting="Oracle" known="false" prepared="false" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Truth Hurts" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRUTHSEEKER_TRUTH_HURTS">
                <description>
                    <p>A 18th level, you are able to twist the fates in a way that the fabric of reality bends around your targets. Many creatures are not able to withstand the probabilities of fate, and are held in an uncomprehending daze.</p>
                    <p class="indent">When your Prophetic Sight changes an outcome, you may force the target creature to make a Wisdom saving throw against your spell save DC. You may subtract half the destiny die result of the Prophetic Sight from the target’s saving throw. On a failure, the creature is paralyzed. This effect lasts for 1 minute, until the creature takes damage, or until someone else uses an action to shake the creature out of its stupor.</p>
                    <p class="indent">If the target successfully saves against the effect, or if the effect on it ends, the target is immune to your Prophetic Sight for the next 24 hours.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a long rest.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                    <description>When your Prophetic Sight changes an outcome, you may force the target creature to make a Wisdom saving throw against (save DC {{spellcasting:dc}}). You may subtract half the destiny die result of the Prophetic Sight from the target’s saving throw. On a failure, the creature is paralyzed. This effect lasts for 1 minute, until the creature takes damage, or until someone else uses an action to shake the creature out of its stupor. If the target successfully saves against the effect, or if the effect on it ends, the target is immune to your Prophetic Sight for the next 24 hours.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Truthseeker Quirk" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRUTHSEEKER_QUIRK">
                <description>
                    <p>Quirks are personality traits or habits that your oracle might possess, giving them an unique edge. These quirks might be something your character has always had, or are the result or side effect of their oracle powers. While the tables here are arranged by subclasses and some of them are very subclass specific, there is nothing stopping you grabbing a quirk from a table that is not your oracle’s foretold fate if you feel it could fit your character.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <select type="List" name="Truthseeker Quirk">
                        <item id="1">You never lie, for better or worse.</item>
                        <item id="2">You judge others for lying, but have no problem lying yourself.</item>
                        <item id="3">You have strong opinions on many matters that you refuse to change.</item>
                        <item id="4">You hold many secrets close to your heart. Whenever you learn something new, you prefer to keep it to yourself. Knowledge can be dangerous, after all.</item>
                        <item id="5">You believe the best in people, and trust they have honest intentions.</item>
                        <item id="6">You prefer listening over speaking. Easiest way to stick to truth is to speak little.</item>
                    </select>
                </rules>
            </element>

      <!-- Fatebreaker -->
        <element name="Fatebreaker" type="Archetype" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_ORACLE_FATEBREAKER">
            <supports>Foretold Fate</supports>
            <description>
                <p>There are few Oracles who ignore the warnings and try to fight against the tides of fate, twisting it to their will to forge their own destiny. These Fatebreakers are cursed, and mere touch from them can be harmful to others.</p>
                <h5>Fatebreaker Expanded Spell List</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Level</td><td>Spell Names</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>Cantrip</td><td><i>branded grasp<sup>*</sup>, shocking grasp</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>1st</td><td><i>arms of Hadar, inflict wounds</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>2nd</td><td><i>alter self, hold person</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td><i>bestow curse, vampiric touch</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>4th</td><td><i>shadow of Moil<sup>XGtE</sup>, stoneskin</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><i>contagion, enervation<sup>XGtE</sup></i></td></tr>
                </table>
                <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FATEBREAKER_BRAND_OF_THE_BREAKER" />
                <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FATEBREAKER_GUIDE_DESTINY_BROKEN_SIGHT" />
                <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FATEBREAKER_FORGE_YOUR_OWN_PATH" />
                <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FATEBREAKER_PARANOID_PREDICTION" />
                <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FATEBREAKER_CURSE_UNLEASHED" />
                <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FATEBREAKER_STEAL_DESTINY" />
                <h5><i>BREAKING FROM FATE</i></h5>
                <p class="flavor">There are no clear rules and codes of conduct for how oracles should behave and use their power, but these are some examples that DM might consider.</p>
                <p class="flavor indent">One way to approach this subject is to consider where the orace gets their power, and how that might relate to breaking from fate. If oracle gets their power from a deity, going against that deity’s teachings might warrant the wrath of the god. If the oracle’s power comes from otherwordly or infernal spirit possessing their body, exorcising or getting rid of the spirit might make the oracle loose their powers altogether, or perhaps some of the spirit’s power will linger.</p>
                <p class="flavor indent">Other direction that can be taken with this is to look at the oracle’s foretold fate, and decide if that should warrant some special behavior from oracle, or otherwise become fatebreaker. Are stargazers required to spend certain amount of time stargazing, or are truthseekers bound to always tell the truth? Signreaders might have to abandon their subclass if their Tome of Signs gets destroyed without a chance to recover it.</p>
                <p class="flavor indent">Third option is to consider the purpose of the oracle in the world. Is it to help to fulfill the destiny revealed to them, or to stop it? And what happens if they fail?</p>
                <p class="flavor indent">These are only suggestions, of course. DM and the player should discuss whether becoming a fatebreaker is a possibility and how and why it would happen.</p>
                <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FATEBREAKER_BRAND" />
                <div element="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FATEBREAKER_QUIRK" />
            </description>
            <spellcasting name="Oracle" extend="true">
                <extend>ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_SPELL_BRANDED_GRASP</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_SHOCKING_GRASP</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_ARMS_OF_HADAR</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_INFLICT_WOUNDS</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_ALTER_SELF</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_HOLD_PERSON</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_BESTOW_CURSE</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_VAMPIRIC_TOUCH</extend>
                <extend>ID_XGTE_SPELL_SHADOW_OF_MOIL</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_STONESKIN</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_CONTAGION</extend>
                <extend>ID_XGTE_SPELL_ENERVATION</extend>
            </spellcasting>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FATEBREAKER_BRAND_OF_THE_BREAKER" level="1" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FATEBREAKER_GUIDE_DESTINY_BROKEN_SIGHT" level="2" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FATEBREAKER_FORGE_YOUR_OWN_PATH" level="6" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FATEBREAKER_PARANOID_PREDICTION" level="10" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FATEBREAKER_CURSE_UNLEASHED" level="15" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FATEBREAKER_STEAL_DESTINY" level="18" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FATEBREAKER_BRAND" level="1" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FATEBREAKER_QUIRK" level="1" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Brand of the Breaker" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FATEBREAKER_BRAND_OF_THE_BREAKER">
                <description>
                    <p>Fate has cursed you for your actions, marking you forever. At 1st level, you receive a brand anywhere in your body, and it counts as spellcasting focus to you for oracles spells. You gain proficiency with unarmed strikes, and you deal 1d4 necrotic damage with them. You can also use Wisdom instead of Strength for the attacks and damage rolls of your unarmed strikes.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Additionally, your hit point maximum increases by 1 and increases by 1 again whenever you gain a level in this class.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>You use your brand as a spellcasting focus. Your unarmed strike does 1d{{unarmed-strikes:dice}} damage. You can use Strength or Wisdom for these attacks.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="hp" value="level:oracle" />
                    <stat name="unarmed-strikes:dice" value="4" bonus="unarmed-strikes" />
                    <stat name="unarmed-strikes:damage" value="strength:modifier" bonus="unarmed-strikes" />
                    <stat name="unarmed-strikes:damage" value="wisdom:modifier" bonus="unarmed-strikes" />
                    <stat name="unarmed-strikes:attack" value="strength:modifer" bonus="unarmed-strikes" />
                    <stat name="unarmed-strikes:attack" value="wisdom:modifer" bonus="unarmed-strikes" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Guide Destiny: Broken Sight" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FATEBREAKER_GUIDE_DESTINY_BROKEN_SIGHT">
                <description>
                    <p>Also at 2nd level, your field of view with destiny is diminished. Your Prophetic Sight ability is replaced by Broken Sight:</p>
                    <p class="indent">As a bonus action, you grant yourself a glimpse of near future. Until the end of the turn, you have advantage on your next attack roll and you add the half of your Destiny die result, rounded up, to the attack roll.</p>
                    <p class="indent">At 11th level, if the destiny die roll for this feature is 10 or greater, if your attack hits, it deals additional psychic damage equal to your oracle level.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="Guide Destiny">
                    <description>Your Prophetic Sight ability is replaced by Broken Sight: Until the end of the turn, you have advantage on your next attack roll and you add the half of your Destiny die result, rounded up, to the attack roll.</description>
                    <description level="11">Your Prophetic Sight ability is replaced by Broken Sight: Until the end of the turn, you have advantage on your next attack roll and you add the half of your Destiny die result, rounded up, to the attack roll. If the destiny die roll for this feature is 10 or greater, if your attack hits, it deals {{level:oracle}} points additional psychic damage.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Forge Your Own Path" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FATEBREAKER_FORGE_YOUR_OWN_PATH">
                <description>
                    <p>At 6th level, your powers lend themselves to you, stopping others from standing between you and your goals. At the end of each long rest, choose one skill or tool you are proficient with. Until next long rest, your proficiency bonus is doubled for any ability check you make that uses the chosen proficiency.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>At the end of each long rest, choose one skill or tool you are proficient with. Until next long rest, your proficiency bonus is doubled for any ability check you make that uses the chosen proficiency.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Paranoid Prediction" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FATEBREAKER_PARANOID_PREDICTION">
                <description>
                    <p>At 10th level, when you roll initiative, you may as a reaction use Guide Destiny: Prediction ability. You may also concentrate on a spell while concentrating on Prediction, but both effects end if you lose your concentration.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet action="Reaction">
                    <description>When you roll initiative, you may as a reaction use Guide Destiny: Prediction ability. You may also concentrate on a spell while concentrating on Prediction, but both effects end if you lose your concentration.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Curse Unleashed" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FATEBREAKER_CURSE_UNLEASHED">
                <description>
                    <p>At 15th level, you may cast <em>Forcecage</em> or <em>Tenser’s Transformation</em> spell without using a spell slot. With this use of <em>Tenser’s Transformation</em> , you can still cast <em>Branded Grasp</em> or <em>Shocking Grasp</em> cantrips, and whenever the spell’s effect refers to attacks made with weapons, you can add the benefits to these cantrips as well.</p>
                    <p class="indent">After you’ve cast either spell in this way, you can’t use this feature again until you finish a long rest.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                    <description>You may cast Forcecage or Tenser’s Transformation spell without using a spell slot. With this use of Tenser’s Transformation, you can still cast Branded Grasp or Shocking Grasp cantrips, and whenever the spell’s effect refers to attacks made with weapons, you can add the benefits to these cantrips as well.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FORCECAGE" spellcasting="Oracle" known="false" prepared="false" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_TENSERS_TRANSFORMATION" spellcasting="Oracle" known="false" prepared="false" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Steal Destiny" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FATEBREAKER_STEAL_DESTINY">
                <description>
                    <p>At 18th level, your brand’s power grows to a point where it can steal a sliver of someone’s else destiny, empowering itself in the process. As an action, make a melee spell attack against a creature, dealing your unarmed damage die on hit. Additionally, you regain up to four expended uses of Guide Destiny.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Having a piece of your destiny stolen from you is tiring. When you hit a creature with this feature, they must succeed a Constitution saving throw against your spell save DC or suffer one point of exhaustion.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a long rest.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="1/Long Rest" action="Action">
                    <description>Make a melee spell attack against a creature, dealing your unarmed damage die on hit. Additionally, you regain up to four expended uses of Guide Destiny. When you hit a creature with this feature, they must succeed a Constitution saving throw against your spell save DC or suffer one point of exhaustion.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Fatebreaker Brand" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FATEBREAKER_BRAND">
                <description>
                    <p>Unlike the fate-touched mark, the brand of fatebreaker is usually very noticeable and distinguishable mark. It can be an alteration of your fate-touched mark, like the change in eye colour from white to black, or mysterious mark turning into a new burn mark of more horrific design. The brand can also be wholly new mark on your body.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <select type="List" name="Fatebreaker Brand">
                        <item id="1"><strong>Head</strong>: A symbol appears on your forehead, as if branded by hot iron.</item>
                        <item id="2"><strong>Eyes</strong>: Your eyes turn black, and black tears keep slowly falling from your eyes.</item>
                        <item id="3"><strong>Hands</strong>: Your hands become cracked or charred.</item>
                        <item id="4"><strong>Feet</strong>: Your feet look decayed, and wherever you step, grass and other small plant life quickly withers, leaving your foot prints behind.</item>
                        <item id="5"><strong>Body</strong>: Your veins turn black, and become easily noticeable.</item>
                        <item id="6"><strong>Mouth</strong>: Your lips turn to unnatural color and your voice turns noticeably different from the rest of your kind.</item>
                    </select>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Fatebreaker Quirk" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FATEBREAKER_QUIRK">
                <description>
                    <p>Quirks are personality traits or habits that your oracle might possess, giving them an unique edge. These quirks might be something your character has always had, or are the result or side effect of their oracle powers. While the tables here are arranged by subclasses and some of them are very subclass specific, there is nothing stopping you grabbing a quirk from a table that is not your oracle’s foretold fate if you feel it could fit your character.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <select type="List" name="Fatebreaker Quirk">
                        <item id="1">You have a short temper.</item>
                        <item id="2">You flaunt your Brand for all the world to see. The opinions of others on the matter have little meaning to you.</item>
                        <item id="3">You have a feeling that someone or something is out to get you for your transgression.</item>
                        <item id="4">Your devotion belongs to people close to you, not some ambiguous force or distant deity.</item>
                        <item id="5">You take every opportunity to advance your own situation.</item>
                        <item id="6">You try your best to hide your Brand from the rest of the world.</item>
                    </select>
                </rules>
            </element>

  <!-- Oracle Spell List -->
    <!-- Cantrips -->
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_CONTROL_FLAMES">
            <supports>Oracle</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FRIENDS">
            <supports>Oracle</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GUIDANCE">
            <supports>Oracle</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GUST">
            <supports>Oracle</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_INFESTATION">
            <supports>Oracle</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MOLD_EARTH">
            <supports>Oracle</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RESISTANCE">
            <supports>Oracle</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SACRED_FLAME">
            <supports>Oracle</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHAPE_WATER">
            <supports>Oracle</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_THAUMATURGY">
            <supports>Oracle</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TRUE_STRIKE">
            <supports>Oracle</supports>
        </append>
    <!-- 1st Level Spells -->
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ALARM">
            <supports>Oracle</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMPREHEND_LANGUAGES">
            <supports>Oracle</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_EVIL_AND_GOOD">
            <supports>Oracle</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_MAGIC">
            <supports>Oracle</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_POISON_AND_DISEASE">
            <supports>Oracle</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_IDENTIFY">
            <supports>Oracle</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_ANIMALS">
            <supports>Oracle</supports>
        </append>
    <!-- 2nd Level Spells -->
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AUGURY">
            <supports>Oracle</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_THOUGHTS">
            <supports>Oracle</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIND_TRAPS">
            <supports>Oracle</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LOCATE_ANIMALS_OR_PLANTS">
            <supports>Oracle</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LOCATE_OBJECTS">
            <supports>Oracle</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_MIND_SPIKE">
            <supports>Oracle</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SEE_INVISIBILITY">
            <supports>Oracle</supports>
        </append>
    <!-- 3rd Level Spells -->
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CLAIRVOYANCE">
            <supports>Oracle</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SENDING">
            <supports>Oracle</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TONGUES">
            <supports>Oracle</supports>
        </append>
    <!-- 4th Level Spells -->
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ARCANE_EYE">
            <supports>Oracle</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DIVINATION">
            <supports>Oracle</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LOCATE_CREATURE">
            <supports>Oracle</supports>
        </append>
    <!-- 5th Level Spells -->
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMMUNE">
            <supports>Oracle</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LEGEND_LORE">
            <supports>Oracle</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RARYS_TELEPATHIC_BOND">
            <supports>Oracle</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SCRYING">
            <supports>Oracle</supports>
        </append>

  <!-- Oracle Spells -->
    <element name="Anticipation" type="Spell" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_SPELL_ANTICIPATION">
        <supports>Oracle</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You key your senses to the present moment. Until the start of your next turn, you have a +1 bonus to AC and may take one additional reaction. This reaction may only be used to activate abilities that require a destiny die.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">0</set>
            <set name="school">Divination</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Bell of Lies" type="Spell" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_SPELL_BELL_OF_LIES">
        <supports>Oracle</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You touch a small bell and imbue it with your prophetic energies. When a creature speaks an intentional falsehood within 60ft of the bell, the bell will ring within your mind. The spell ends if the bell is more than 10 feet from you.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">4</set>
            <set name="school">Divination</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 hour</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a small silver bell without a clapper worth 25 gp</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Branded Grasp" type="Spell" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_SPELL_BRANDED_GRASP">
        <supports>Oracle</supports>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">(a modified Primal Savagery)</p>
            <p>You channel the negative energy pouring from your brand to harm a creature you touch. Make a melee spell attack against the target. On a hit, the target takes 1d10 necrotic damage.</p>
            <p class="indent">The spell’s damage increases by 1d10 when you reach 5th level (2d10), 11th level (3d10), and 17th level (4d10).</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">0</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Clarity of the Inner Eye" type="Spell" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_SPELL_CLARITY_OF_THE_INNER_EYE">
        <supports>Oracle</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You may cast this spell on one creature within range that is not hostile to you. When you do so, the creature must make a Wisdom saving throw. You know whether a creature succeeds or fails on its saving throw, and a creature can choose to fail the save. On a failure, you immediately know whether the creature is currently charmed, possessed, enthralled, or under a similar mental effect. If it is, it may immediately make an additional saving throw against the effect, even if the spell or effect would not normally permit one.</p>
            <p class="indent"><em><strong>At Higher Levels.</strong></em> When you cast this spell using a 2nd level spell slot or higher, you can target one additional creature for each slot level above lst.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Diviniation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">mud made with your spit</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Darkest Dream" type="Spell" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_SPELL_DARKEST_DREAM">
        <supports>Oracle</supports>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">a modified Vicious Mockery</p>
            <p>You give a creature you can see within range a stare laced with subtle enchantment, invoking glimpses of nightmares to them. If the target can see you, it must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or take 1d4 psychic damage and have disadvantage on the next attack roll it makes before the end of its next turn.</p>
            <p class="indent">This spell’s damage increases by 1d4 when you reach 5th level (2d4), 11th level (3d4) and 17th level (4d4).</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">0</set>
            <set name="school">Divination</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="range">120 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Empowered Bones" type="Spell" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_SPELL_EMPOWERED_BONES">
        <supports>Oracle</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You cast your bones and speak the words of power. While you are reading the divination of the bones, roll a d6. The predictions of the bones provides your group with a boon to prepare for what lies ahead. Consult the table below for the reading of the bones. All effects last 1 hour.</p>
            <h5>Empowered Bones</h5>
            <table>
                <thead><tr><td>d6</td><td>Bone Reading</td></tr></thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>The reading portends of danger and hardship ahead. Your party has advantage on initiative rolls and cannot be surprised.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>The bones tell of a need for fortitude. Your party gains 1d4+4 temporary hit points.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>You foresee entrapment and snares. Your party has advantage on ability checks to discover traps and other environmental dangers.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>The reading speaks of a need for urgency in your future. Your party adds 10 Feet to their base walking speed.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>You read of the weaknesses of your enemies. Your party’s weapon attacks deal an extra 1d4 damage on a hit.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>Roll twice on this table, ignoring 6s and doubles.</td></tr>
            </table>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Divination</set>
            <set name="time">1 minute</set>
            <set name="duration">1 hour</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">six small animal bones</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Empowered Pendulum" type="Spell" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_SPELL_EMPOWERED_PENDULUM">
        <supports>Oracle</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You enchant a makeshift pendulum to lead back to the place where you stand. While in the place you wish to mark, you mutter mystic enchantments over your pendulum. Thereafter your pendulum will always swing in the direction of the location where you cast this spell.</p>
            <p class="indent">This effect ends when this spell is repeated on the same pendulum for a different location, or if dispel magic or a similar effect is successfully applied to the pendulum.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Divination</set>
            <set name="time">1 minute</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a silver coin on a string</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Empowered Detection" type="Spell" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_SPELL_EMPOWERED_DETECTION">
        <supports>Oracle</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You imbue your divining rod with the ability to find what you seek. When you cast this spell, you must describe or name an object. If such an item exists within 1 mile, the rod points in the direction of the nearest object that meets your intentions.</p>
            <p class="indent">The spell can locate a specific object known to you, as long as you have seen it up close—within 30 feet—at least once. Alternatively, the spell can locate the nearest object of a particular kind, such as a certain kind of food, safe water, or a weapon.</p>
            <p class="indent">If no items exist within the given distance but you later move to a location that is within range, the rod will attempt to leap to your hand to guide you. The rod will always point in the most direct route — which does not guarantee safety nor ease of travel.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">4</set>
            <set name="school">Divination</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">1 hour</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a forked branch</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Eyes of Mephwé" type="Spell" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_SPELL_EYES_OF_MEPHWE">
        <supports>Oracle</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Your eyes cloud over with a ivory-white color. For the duration, you are considered blind, and gain blindsight out to a range of 100 feet, and have advantage on Wisdom saving throws and Wisdom ability checks.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">5</set>
            <set name="school">Divination</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 10 minutes</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Foreseen Provisions" type="Spell" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_SPELL_FORESEEN_PROVISIONS">
        <supports>Oracle</supports>
        <description>
            <p>This spell lets you prepare for any situation, even those that are uncertain. When you touch a satchel or other non-magical container and speak the phrase "Always be prepared" it will be able to provide you with one mundane item or weapon worth no more than 2 gold.</p>
            <p class="indent">To retrieve this object, you can use an action to reach into the container and speak the phrase "I never leave home without" and then name the object you desire and the item magically appears on top. The item will exist and function as normal until the end of the spell duration.</p>
            <p class="indent">The spell cannot determine specificity, so requests for a specific item (a key to a specific door, a specific person’s lock of hair) will instead produce a generic version of the item. Other items can be stored in the container without interfering with this spell.</p>
            <p class="indent">The container will create one permanent unit of rations for each item not retrieved when the full duration expires if it has not provided the alloted item(s) by that time. The spell will end early if you cast it again on another container before the full duration expires.</p>
            <p class="indent"><em><strong>At Higher Levels.</strong></em> When you cast this spell using a 2nd level spell slot or higher the container will provide an additional item for each slot level above 1st.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Divination</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">8 hours</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a needle and thread</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Foretell Ruin" type="Spell" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_SPELL_FORTELL_RUIN">
        <supports>Oracle</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You focus your mystical insight toward one target and are able to issue a prophecy about its downfall.</p>
            <p class="indent">Choose one creature you can see within range, and choose one damage type. The target must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or be affected by the spell for its duration. While you concentrate on this spell, any time that creature takes damage from a spell or an attack of the chosen type, it takes an additional 3d8 damage of that type. The target also loses any resistance to that damage type until the spell ends.</p>
            <p class="indent">Moreover, if the creature has 80 hit points or fewer remaining, it becomes vulnerable to that damage type until the spell ends.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">5</set>
            <set name="school">Divination</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 10 minutes</set>
            <set name="range">90 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a smudge of dirt from holy ground</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Hindsight" type="Spell" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_SPELL_HINDSIGHT">
        <supports>Oracle</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You eyes cloud black as your vision is subsumed into the past. You are able to guide the currents of time to show you one event that occurred in the space where you are standing.</p>
            <p>You may choose one past event from the following list:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>birth, summoning, or creation of a creature or legendary item</li>
                <li>death, banishment, or destruction of a creature or legendary item</li>
                <li>an emotionally charged event relevant to you or a companion who is with you</li>
            </ul>
            <p>If you can name or describe a specific event, it will be shown to you if it came to pass within 60 feet of where you stand. If no specific event is named, you will see the most recent event of the type you select that occurred in the space.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Divination</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a pinch of dirt, dust, or ash from the area</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Last Moments" type="Spell" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_SPELL_LAST_MOMENTS">
        <supports>Oracle</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You touch and look into the eyes or sockets of a once-living creature’s corpse and see the last 10 minutes of its life as if through that creature’s eyes.</p>
            <p>While you are experiencing these moments, you are blinded and deafened to your physical surroundings. If you lose concentration, it ends early and any scenes you did not see are lost to you. You can end this ability early with a bonus action.</p>
            <p>This ability does not affect dead creatures currently animated by magic, creatures that did not have eyes in life, creatures that were never alive, nor creatures that have been dead for more than 1 month.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Divination</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 10 minutes</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a glass lens</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Psychometry" type="Spell" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_SPELL_PSYCHOMETRY">
        <supports>Oracle</supports>
        <description>
            <p>This spell allows you to view the recent history of an item. You touch one object and are able to view the last time the item was used during a significant event, up to the duration of the spell. If the thing you touch wasn’t involved in any events of importance, you gain no information. Significant events typically involve powerful emotions, such as assassinations, passionate affairs, and royal decrees.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Divination</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="The Walls Can Talk" type="Spell" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_SPELL_THE_WALLS_CAN_TALK">
        <supports>Oracle</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You place your hand upon a natural or created wall as you cast this spell. For as long as you concentrate, you are able to ask the wall up to five questions regarding things that it has heard. For each question, the wall is able to telepathically answer and repeat conversations or phrases up to twenty-five words or less. Walls have long memories, but can only repeat things that have been said aloud within 25 feet of its surface. It will repeat what it heard in the original language it was spoken.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Divination</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 10 minutes</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Through the Looking Glass" type="Spell" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_SPELL_THROUGH_THE_LOOKING_GLASS">
        <supports>Oracle</supports>
        <description>
            <p>When this spell is cast on a solid, reflective surface no larger than 1 square foot, such as a mirror or reflective glass, you mystically link it to your oracle gazing tool - an augury bowl, crystal ball, or similar. While linked, you can use your action to gaze through your tool to to see out of the other surface. The surface you cast the spell upon may be affixed or portable.</p>
            <p>You can see up to 30 feet away from the surface . A creature that can see invisible objects is able to see your face in the surface while you are gazing through it.</p>
            <p>If this spell is active on multiple surfaces, you may select one when you start gazing, and may use a bonus action to switch to gaze through another surface.</p>
            <p>If you cast this spell on the same surface every day for 30 days, the effect lasts until it is dispelled.</p>
            <p><em><strong>At Higher Levels.</strong></em> When you cast this spell using a 5th level spell slot or higher, you can affect a surface of up to 5 square feet.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">4</set>
            <set name="school">Divination</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">24 hours</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">spring water with a pinch of silver dust</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Twist of Fate" type="Spell" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_SPELL_TWIST_OF_FATE">
        <supports>Oracle</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You focus your mystic abilities on a single creature, causing the tides of destiny to turn against them. Choose one creature you can see within range, and it must succeed on a Charisma saving throw or be affected by the spell for its duration. On a failure, the target has disadvantage on attack rolls and ability checks until the spell ends.</p>
            <p>Bringing so much fate-bending power to bear takes additional effort from you. While concentrating on this spell, you may not take any reactions.</p>
            <p><em><strong>At Higher Levels.</strong></em> When you cast this spell using a 4th level spell slot or higher, you can choose an additional target for each slot level above 3rd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Divination</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="range">90 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Wail of Woe" type="Spell" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_SPELL_WAIL_OF_WOE">
        <supports>Oracle</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Your words resonate with an echo of other voices as you begin to speak in tongues. Any creatures of your choice within 30 feet of you that can hear you must make a Wisdom saving throw. Creatures that fail the save hear your words as a prophecy of a painful future event or a divination of some secret shame from their past, and take 2d10 psychic damage initially and an additional 2d10 psychic damage each turn they move closer to you for the duration of the spell. On a successful save, creatures take no damage initially, and 1d10 psychic each turn they move closer to you.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">4</set>
            <set name="school">Divination</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

  <!-- Oracle Items -->
    <element name="Augury Bowl" type="Item" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ITEM_AUGURY_BOWL">
        <description>
            <p>The most common tool for Gazing is an Augury Bowl. Water, sprinkled with the correct material components, provides the necessary reflective surface for the Oracle. Sturdier than other more expensive options (such as crystal balls or magic mirrors), a bowl of wood or metal can be carried more easily during travels without worry of loss, damage, or theft. The surface of the bowl is typically covered with natural salves to preserve it during arduous travel.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Spellcasting Focus</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="container">Oracle Focus</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Oracle Bones" type="Item" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ITEM_ORACLE_BONES">
        <description>
            <p>Reading bones is a practice that dates back to the earliest diviners. Different cultures have adopted assorted practices with the bones of animals or even people. Some throw smaller bones and read how they lay, others expose larger bits to flame and read how the bone cracks to determine the fates. Oracles of sufficient ability are able to fuse the cracks to reuse the bones repeatedly, and often prefer larger bones from mystical creatures which better respond to their magics.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Spellcasting Focus</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="container">Oracle Focus</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Witching Rods" type="Item" source="GM Binder" id="ID_ZEKARATH_GM_BINDER_ITEM_WITCHING_RODS">
        <description>
            <p>Divining, dowsing, or witching rods are used in a third type of divination: Detecting and Finding. The Oracle will use these tools, often a forked branch or rod, to follow the subtle pull of energy until they reach the desired destination. These tools can also be used to indicate the direction (and in some cases, distance) of an individual item or creature. Due to the divine energies that often flow through these items, they are quite sturdy and often survive difficult strain.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Spellcasting Focus</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="container">Oracle Focus</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
</elements>