<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Planeshifter</name>
        <author url="http://guidetohomebrew.blogspot.com/p/classes.html">u/Jonoman3000</author>
        <update version="0.0.5">
            <file name="class-planeshifter.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/classes/class-planeshifter.xml" />
        </update>
        <!-- https://drive.google.com/open?id=0B-g9vLTX0eHKZ0RTU0toUFcteG8 -->
    </info>
    
    <element name="Planeshifter" type="Class" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_CLASS_PLANESHIFTER">
        <description>
            <p>Clad in dark brown robes, a human unsheathes her sword and draws her hand back, whispering a quiet chant as undead creatures surround her. With a flick of her wrist, a bead of fire leaves her fingertips and streaks forward, erupting into a ball of fire once it reaches their ranks. As the flames disperse, she rushes into the fray with her blade, knocking aside the undead with deft strikes and precise blasts of water.</p>
            <p class="indent">Her long hair whipped by conjured wind, a gnome leaps into the air. Momentarily floating above the battlefield, she soon crashes down into a mass of kobolds. As she lands, her skin becomes stonelike and an earthen shield surrounds her.</p>
            <p class="indent">Crouching on a high tree branch, a high elf draws back his bow. Focusing his gaze on the sleeping hill giant below, he releases an arrow. The fiery streak whistles as it flies towards its target, finding its mark in the back of the giant’s head.</p>
            <p class="indent">Planeshifters are masters of both arcane magic and the sword. Whatever their background, they are united by their study and mastery of the planes of existence. Drawing on the weaves of magic that permeate these planes, planeshifters cast spells of blazing fire, rushing wind, and even more powerful effects. Their traditions also stress the importance of physical strength and dexterity, as these traits are invaluable when traversing the highly varied and dangerous planar locations. Against some otherworldly creatures, an over-reliance on magic can spell a planeshifter’s destruction.</p>
            <h4>STUDENT OF THE PLANES</h4>
            <p>Alien and enigmatic, the otherworldly planes of existence draw the attention of many scholars and adventurers that seek to gain knowledge of their mysteries. The planes of existence teach of many things—while planes such as Elysium and Arcadia focus on magic, planes like Ysgard and Acheron seek out only mighty warriors. The halls teach that a planeshifter must learn from and study all the various planes, even if they specialize in only a few of them. Most planeshifters initially study and attune themselves to the elemental planes—the planes of fire, water, earth, and air, which allow them to learn elemental spells—but later they attune themselves to some of the many outer planes.</p>
            <p class="indent">In order to harness planar magic, planeshifters must study the creatures of the planes they wish to attune to, and they also seek out and examine ancient relics and manuscripts that write of the planes of existence.</p>
            <p class="indent">As the creatures of the multiverse are often dangerous, becoming a powerful planeshifter can be a deadly task. In their pursuit of knowledge, planeshifters often come across powerful elementals, genies, and an assortment of other extra-dimensional beings.</p>
            <h4>DUAL HALLS OF LEARNING</h4>
            <p>A few ancient halls dot the landscapes of the worlds, acting as great schools of learning for prospective students. Much like the schools of wizardry, the halls of the planeshifters act like universities, teaching students of the powers of the multiverse and allowing them to research, and sometimes travel to the different planes of existence. These halls are usually quite large, though very few of their students are ever able to gain even apprentice level mastery of the planes.</p>
            <p class="indent">Planeshifter halls, like the planes themselves, have a dualistic nature. Any one hall often teaches only two of the major traditions, and they emphasize the importance of balance in all things—a planeshifter must learn of both the positive and negative planes, and they must balance their learning of both the martial and the arcane. A planeshifter that over-specializes is sure to find themselves unequipped to deal with the varied conditions of the planes.</p>
            <p class="indent">Planeshifters spend a lot of their time outside of the hall, however. The lure of knowledge or the rumors of an extraplanar object might call even prudent planeshifters to a life of adventure. If rumors of a particularly powerful or rare relic emerge, many planeshifters leave their halls on great adventures in their attempts to find it before others do.</p>
            <h4>CREATING A PLANESHIFTER</h4>
            <p>When you create a planeshifter, think about the history you have with your hall. Were you born there to parents that also learned or taught there? Did you enter the hall in order live a more secluded life, where you wouldn’t be judged for your past deeds? Or perhaps you just chose this life on a whim?</p>
            <p class="indent">You must also consider why you left the hall to adventure. Did you hear a particularly exciting rumor? Were you placed on a mission to recover a lost artifact or to seek out a an extraplanar being? Did you want to leave, or did you feel like you were pressured or even forced to go? Is there a secondary, personal quest that you wish to accomplish? Do you want to make this adventure quick so you can return to your studies, or do you want to go out and see the world?</p>
            <h5>QUICK BUILD</h5>
            <p>You can make a planeshifter quickly by following these suggestions. First, make Strength or Dexterity your highest ability score, depending on what weapons you want to use. Your next highest ability score should be Intelligence, your spellcasting ability. Second, choose the sage background.</p>
            <h5>MULTICLASSING</h5>
            <p>The prerequisites for multiclassing into a planeshifter are: Dexterity 13 and Intelligence 13. When you multiclass into Planeshifter, you gain proficiency in light armor, simple weapons, and martial weapons. When determining your total spell slots, you add half of your planeshifter levels (rounded down) to the total.</p>
            <h2>CLASS FEATURES</h2>
            <p>As a planeshifter, you gain the following class features.</p>
            <h5>HIT POINTS</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Hit Dice:</strong> 1d10 per class level</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at 1st Level:</strong> 10 + your Constitution modifier</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at Higher Levels:</strong> 1d10 (or 6) + your Constitution modifier per class level after 1st</li>
            </ul>
            <h5>PROFICIENCIES</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Armor:</strong> Light armor, medium armor, shields</li>
                <li><strong>Weapons:</strong> Simple weapons, martial weapons</li>
                <li><strong>Tools:</strong> None</li>
            </ul>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Saving Throws:</strong> Dexterity, Intelligence</li>
                <li><strong>Skills:</strong> Choose two from Acrobatics, Arcana, Athletics, History, Perception, and Religion.</li>
            </ul>
            <h5>EQUIPMENT</h5>
            <p>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>(a) scale mail or (b) leather armor</li>
                <li>(a) a longbow or (b) two simple weapons</li>
                <li>(a) an explorer’s pack or (b) a scholar’s pack</li>
                <li>A longsword and two daggers</li>
            </ul>
			<h5 class="caption">THE PLANESHIFTER</h5>
            <table class="class-features">
                <thead>
                    <tr><th class="col-5">Level</th><th>Proficiency Bonus</th><th class="left">Features</th><th>Attunements Known</th><th class="col-5">1st</th><th class="col-5">2nd</th><th class="col-5">3rd</th><th class="col-5">4th</th><th class="col-5">5th</th></tr>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                    <tr><td>1st</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Extraplanar Sensitivity, Planar Traditions</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>2nd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Fighting Style, Spellcasting, Ethereal Shift (1/rest)</td><td>—</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Planar Attunements, Planar Tradition features</td><td>1</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>4th</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>1</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Extra Attack, Brand</td><td>1</td><td>4</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>6th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Planar Tradition features</td><td>1</td><td>4</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>7th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Ethereal Sight</td><td>2</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>8th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>2</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">—</td><td>2</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>10th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Planar Tradition features</td><td>2</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>11th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Brand Improvement</td><td>3</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>12th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>3</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>13th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">—</td><td>3</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>1</td><td>—</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>14th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Planar Tradition features</td><td>3</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>1</td><td>—</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>15th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Ethereal Shift (2/rest)</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>16th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>17th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">—</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>1</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>18th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Planar Tradition features</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>1</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>19th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>20th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Ethereal Shift (unlimited)</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td></tr>
                </tbody>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_EXTRAPLANAR_SENSITIVITY" />
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_PLANAR_TRADITION" />
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_FIGHTING_STYLE" />
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_SPELLCASTING" />
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_ETHEREAL_SHIFT" />
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_PLANAR_ATTUNEMENTS" />
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_ABILITY_SCORE_INCREASE" />
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_EXTRA_ATTACK" />
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_BRAND" />
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_ETHEREAL_SIGHT" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <setters>
            <set name="short">A master of magic and sword that draws powers from the planes of existence.</set>
            <set name="hd">d10</set>
        </setters>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_MEDIUM_ARMOR" requirements="!ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_MULTICLASS_PLANESHIFTER" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_SHIELDS" requirements="!ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_MULTICLASS_PLANESHIFTER" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_MARTIAL_WEAPONS" />

            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_DEXTERITY" requirements="!ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_MULTICLASS_PLANESHIFTER" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_INTELLIGENCE" requirements="!ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_MULTICLASS_PLANESHIFTER" />
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency (Planeshifter)" number="2" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ACROBATICS|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ARCANA|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ATHLETICS|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_HISTORY|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_RELIGION" requirements="!ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_MULTICLASS_PLANESHIFTER" />

            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_EXTRAPLANAR_SENSITIVITY" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_PLANAR_TRADITION" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_FIGHTING_STYLE" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_SPELLCASTING" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_ETHEREAL_SHIFT" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_PLANAR_ATTUNEMENTS" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_ABILITY_SCORE_INCREASE" level="4" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_EXTRA_ATTACK" level="5" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_BRAND" level="5" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_PLANAR_TRADITION_FEATURE_6" level="6" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_ETHEREAL_SIGHT" level="7" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_PLANAR_TRADITION_FEATURE_18" level="18" />
        </rules>
        <multiclass id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_MULTICLASS_PLANESHIFTER">
            <prerequisite>Dexterity 13, Intelligence 13</prerequisite>
            <requirements>[dex:13],[int:13]</requirements>
            <setters>
                <set name="multiclass proficiencies">Light armor, simple weapons, martial weapons</set>
            </setters>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS" />
            </rules>
        </multiclass>
    </element>
    <element name="Extraplanar Sensitivity" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_EXTRAPLANAR_SENSITIVITY">
        <description>
            <p>Your attunement to the outer planes allows you to notice extraplanar beings when others would not. As an action, you can tune your senses to detect such beings. Until the end of your next turn, you know the location of any creature within 60 feet of you that is native to a plane other than the material plane. You know the native plane of any being whose presence you sense, but not its identity or type. You also know the distance and direction to any planar portals within 1000 feet of you.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can use this feature a number of times equal to 1 + your Intelligence modifier. When you finish a long rest, you regain all expended uses.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="{{extraplanar-sensitivity:uses}}/Long Rest" action="Action">
            <description>You can tune your senses to detect extraplanar beings. Until the end of your next turn, you know the location of any creature within 60 feet of you that is native to a plane other than the material plane. You know the native plane of any being whose presence you sense, but not its identity or type. You also know the distance and direction to any planar portals within 1000 feet of you.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="extraplanar-sensitivity:uses" value="1" />
            <stat name="extraplanar-sensitivity:uses" value="intelligence:modifier" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Planar Tradition" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_PLANAR_TRADITION">
        <description>
            <p>Choose two different planar traditions related to the planes that you study, as detailed at the end of the class description. Each choice grants you features at 1st level, planar spells starting at 2nd level, and additional features at 3rd, 6th, 14th, and 18th levels. You can “shift” between these two planes, as detailed in the Planar Shift section below.</p>
            <h5>PLANAR SPELLS</h5>
            <p>Each tradition has a list of spells that you gain at the planeshifter levels noted in the tradition description. While you are shifted to a plane, you have access to the spells associated with that plane.</p>
            <h5>PLANAR SHIFT</h5>
            <p>As a planeshifter, you are attuned to two planes of existence as determined by your planar tradition. As an action, you may “shift” between these two planes, granting you different features and abilities dependent on the plane you are currently shifted to.</p>
            <p class="indent">Each plane has its own features and spells, and you may only access and use these features when you are shifted to that plane. When you are shifted to a plane, you do not gain any of the features of your other plane, and you may not cast or concentrate on the spells associated with the other plane, unless you have learned them through another means outside of the planeshifter class.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Action">
            <description>You may “shift” between your two planes selected for your planar traditions, granting you different features and abilities dependent on the plane you are currently shifted to.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Archetype" name="Planar Tradition" number="2" supports="Planar Tradition" />
         </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Fighting Style" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_FIGHTING_STYLE">
        <description>
            <p>At 2nd level, you have adopted a style of fighting as your specialty. Choose one of the following options. You can’t take a fighting style more than once, even if you later get to choose again.</p>
            <h5>ARCHERY</h5>
            <p>You gain a +2 bonus to attack rolls you make with ranged weapons.</p>
            <h5>DEFENSE</h5>
            <p>While you are wearing armor, you gain a +1 bonus to AC.</p>
            <h5>DUELING</h5>
            <p>When you are wielding a melee weapon in one hand and no other weapons, you gain a +2 bonus to damage rolls with that weapon.</p>
            <h5>GREAT WEAPON FIGHTING</h5>
            <p>When you roll a 1 or 2 on a damage die for an attack you make with a melee weapon that you are wielding with two hands, you can reroll the die and must use the new roll, even if the new roll is a 1 or a 2. The weapon must have the two-handed or versatile property for you to gain this benefit.</p>
            <h5>TWO-WEAPON FIGHTING</h5>
            <p>When you engage in two-weapon fighting, you can add your ability modifier to the damage of the second attack.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Fighting Style" supports="Fighting Style, Planeshifter" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Spellcasting" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_SPELLCASTING">
        <description>
            <p>By the time you reach 2nd level, you have learned to use your attunement to the planes to cast spells. See chapter 10 of the Player’s Handbook for the general rules of spellcasting.</p>
            <h5>SPELL SLOTS</h5>
            <p>The Planeshifter table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your spells of 1st level and higher. To cast one of these spells, you must expend a slot of the spell’s level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.</p>
            <h5>SPELLS KNOWN OF 1ST LEVEL AND HIGHER</h5>
            <p>You know the spells listed in the planar spell list of the plane you’re shifted to. Each of these spell lists give you spells at 2nd, 5th, 9th, 13th, and 17th levels.</p>
            <h5>SPELLCASTING ABILITY</h5>
            <p>Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for your planeshifter spells, since your magic draws on your studies into the different planes of existence. You use your Intelligence whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Intelligence modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a planeshifter spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b>Spell save DC</b> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier</p>
            <p class="indent"><b>Spell attack modifier</b> = your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier</p>
            <h5>SPELLCASTING FOCUS</h5>
            <p>You can use an arcane focus as a spellcasting focus for your planeshifter spells.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <spellcasting name="Planeshifter" ability="Wisdom" prepare="false">
            <list>Planeshifter</list>
        </spellcasting>
        <setters>
            <set name="spellcaster">true</set>
            <set name="spellcastingAbility">Intelligence</set>
        </setters>
        <rules>
            <stat name="planeshifter:spellcasting:slots:1" value="2" level="2" />
            <stat name="planeshifter:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="3" />
            <stat name="planeshifter:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="5" />
            <stat name="planeshifter:spellcasting:slots:2" value="2" level="5" />
            <stat name="planeshifter:spellcasting:slots:2" value="1" level="7" />
            <stat name="planeshifter:spellcasting:slots:3" value="2" level="9" />
            <stat name="planeshifter:spellcasting:slots:3" value="1" level="11" />
            <stat name="planeshifter:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="13" />
            <stat name="planeshifter:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="15" />
            <stat name="planeshifter:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="17" />
            <stat name="planeshifter:spellcasting:slots:5" value="1" level="17" />
            <stat name="planeshifter:spellcasting:slots:5" value="1" level="19" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Ethereal Shift" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_ETHEREAL_SHIFT">
        <description>
            <p>Beginning at 2nd level, you gain the ability to momentarily shunt yourself to the ethereal plane and use your proximity to the inner planes to more easily shift between them. As a bonus action on your turn, you can transport yourself to the ethereal plane and then immediately reappear at a location within 10 feet of where you left. When you do so, you can choose to shift to your other plane as you reappear.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you use your Ethereal Shift, you must finish a short or long rest before you can use it again.</p>
            <p class="indent">Beginning at 15th level, you can use your Ethereal Shift twice between rests, regaining all expended uses when you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            <p class="indent">At 20th level, you can use your Ethereal Shift an unlimited number of times.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="{{ethereal-shift:uses}}">
            <description>You can transport yourself to the ethereal plane and then immediately reappear at a location within 10 feet of where you left. When you do so, you can choose to shift to your other plane as you reappear.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="ethereal-shift:uses" value="1/Short Rest" inline="true" level="2" />
            <stat name="ethereal-shift:uses" value="2/Short Rest" inline="true" level="15" />
            <stat name="ethereal-shift:uses" value="Unlimited" inline="true" level="20" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Planar Attunements" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_PLANAR_ATTUNEMENTS">
        <description>
            <p>In your studies of the planes of existence, you have learned how to attune to some of the outer planes of existence.</p>
            <p class="indent">At 3rd level, you gain access to an extraplanar attunement of your choice. You can choose any one of the sixteen outer planes of existence, which each give unique features outlined at the end of the class description. When you gain certain planeshifter levels, you gain the ability to attune to more planes of your choice, as shown in the Attunements Known column of the Planeshifter table.</p>
            <h5>ATTUNEMENT SPELLS</h5>
            <p>Each attunement has a list of spells that you gain at the planeshifter levels noted in the attunement description. Once you reach the required level, you can cast these spells using your spell slots.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Planar Attunement" supports="Planar Attunement" level="3" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Planar Attunement" supports="Planar Attunement" level="7" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Planar Attunement" supports="Planar Attunement" level="11" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Planar Attunement" supports="Planar Attunement" level="15" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Ability Score Increase" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_ABILITY_SCORE_INCREASE">
        <description>
            <p>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Planeshifter 4)" supports="Improvement Option,Planeshifter,4" level="4" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Planeshifter 8)" supports="Improvement Option,Planeshifter,8" level="8" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Planeshifter 12)" supports="Improvement Option,Planeshifter,12" level="12" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Planeshifter 16)" supports="Improvement Option,Planeshifter,16" level="16" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Planeshifter 19)" supports="Improvement Option,Planeshifter,19" level="19" />     
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Extra Attack" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_EXTRA_ATTACK">
        <description>
            <p>Beginning at 5th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="extra attack:count" value="2" level="5" bonus="extra attack" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Brand" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_BRAND">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 5th level, you can use a bonus action on your turn to brand a creature that you can see within 60 feet of you. The brand appears as the symbol of one of the planes that you have chosen with your Planar Tradition or Planar Attunement features, and it lasts for 1 minute. For the duration, your weapon attacks against that creature are treated as magical for the purpose of overcoming resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage.</p>
            <p class="indent">Additionally, if the creature is native to the plane whose symbol you branded it with, that creature takes an additional 1d4 force damage from your weapon attacks.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you reach 11th level, your attacks against branded creatures deal an additional 2d4 force damage. If the creature is native to the plane whose symbol you branded it with, the damage adds together for a total of 3d4.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Bonus Action">
            <description>You can brand a creature that you can see within 60 feet of you. The brand appears as the symbol of one of the planes that you have chosen with your Planar Tradition or Planar Attunement features, and it lasts for 1 minute. For the duration, your weapon attacks against that creature are treated as magical for the purpose of overcoming resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage. dditionally, if the creature is native to the plane whose symbol you branded it with, that creature takes an additional 1d4 force damage from your weapon attacks.</description>
            <description level="11">You can brand a creature that you can see within 60 feet of you. The brand appears as the symbol of one of the planes that you have chosen with your Planar Tradition or Planar Attunement features, and it lasts for 1 minute. For the duration, your weapon attacks against that creature do an additional 2d4 force damage and are treated as magical for the purpose of overcoming resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage. dditionally, if the creature is native to the plane whose symbol you branded it with, that creature takes an additional 3d4 force damage from your weapon attacks.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Planar Tradition Feature (6th)" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_PLANAR_TRADITION_FEATURE_6">
        <description>
            <p>Your planar traditions grant you a feature that you can use once per short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Ethereal Sight" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_ETHEREAL_SIGHT">
        <description>
            <p>At 7th level, you can see into the Ethereal plane within 30 feet of you.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can see into the Ethereal plane within 30 feet of you.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Planar Tradition Feature (18th)" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_PLANAR_TRADITION_FEATURE_18">
        <description>
            <p>Your planar traditions grant you a feature that you can use once per short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

  <!-- Planar Traditions -->
    <element name="Hall of the Maelstrom" type="Archetype" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_PLANESHIFTER_HALL_OF_THE_MAELSTROM">
        <supports>Planar Tradition</supports>
        <description>
            <p>As a member of the Hall of the Maelstrom, you specialize in elemental magics that produce torrents of water and great floods. While attuned to the plane of water, you gain access to abilities that help you control the battlefield.</p>
            <p class="indent">Affiliates of this hall might find themselves as tacticians and low ranking military commanders, using their abilities to assist their allies and force their enemies into an inferior position.</p>
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_MAELSTROM_PLANAR_SPELLS" />
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_MAELSTROM_ONE_WITH_THE_MAELSTROM" />
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_MAELSTROM_ICY_REBUKE" />
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_MAELSTROM_TIDAL_CHAMPION" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_MAELSTROM_PLANAR_SPELLS" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_MAELSTROM_ONE_WITH_THE_MAELSTROM" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_MAELSTROM_ICY_REBUKE" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_MAELSTROM_TIDAL_CHAMPION" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Water Planar Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_MAELSTROM_PLANAR_SPELLS">
            <description>
                <p>You gain the planar spells in the table below at the planeshifter levels listed.</p>
                <h5>WATER SPELLS</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Planeshifter Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>2nd</td><td><i>fog cloud, create water</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><i>grasping pool, water whips</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><i>wall of water, water breathing</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>13th</td><td><i>control water, watery sphere</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>17th</td><td><i>maelstrom, geyser</i></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FOG_CLOUD" level="2" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CREATE_WATER" level="2" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_SPELL_PLANESHIFTER_GRASPING_POOL" level="5" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_SPELL_PLANESHIFTER_WATER_WHIPS" level="5" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_WALL_OF_WATER" level="9" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WATER_BREATHING" level="9" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONTROL_WATER" level="13" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_WATERY_SPHERE" level="13" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_MAELSTROM" level="17" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_SPELL_PLANESHIFTER_GEYSER" level="17" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="One with the Maelstrom" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_MAELSTROM_ONE_WITH_THE_MAELSTROM">
            <description>
                <p>When you choose this tradition at 1st level, you gain the ability to shift to the elemental plane of water to augment your attacks with watery blasts. Once per turn when you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can choose to push the target up to 5 feet away from you.</p>
                <p class="indent">At 3rd level, you can push the target up to 10 feet away from you. At 10th level, this increases to 15 feet, and at 14th level this increases to 20 feet.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Once per turn when you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can choose to push the target up to {{maelstrom:distance}} feet away from you.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="maelstrom:distance" value="5" level="1" />
                <stat name="maelstrom:distance" value="5" level="3" />
                <stat name="maelstrom:distance" value="5" level="10" />
                <stat name="maelstrom:distance" value="5" level="14" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Planar Tradition Feature (6th): Icy Rebuke" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_MAELSTROM_ICY_REBUKE">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 6th level, you can rebuke your attackers with a blast of ice and frigid air. When you take damage, you can use your reaction to freeze your opponent. The creature that attacked you must make a Dexterity saving throw against your spell save DC. On a failed save, they are restrained until the end of their next turn and knocked prone. On a successful save, they are only knocked prone.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use either of your 6th level planar tradition features, you can’t use either feature again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Planar Tradition Feature (6th)" alt="Icy Rebuke" action="Reaction">
                <description>When you take damage, you can freeze your opponent. The creature that attacked you must make a Dexterity saving throw (save DC {{spellcasting:dc}}). On a failed save, they are restrained until the end of their next turn and knocked prone. On a successful save, they are only knocked prone.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Planar Tradition Feature (18th): Tidal Champion" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_MAELSTROM_TIDAL_CHAMPION">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 18th level, you can assume the form of a mighty ocean spirit. Using your action, you undergo a transformation. For 1 minute, you gain the following benefits:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>You have resistance to cold damage.</li>
                    <li>The ground in a 15-foot radius centered on you is difficult terrain for enemies.</li>
                    <li>Whenever you hit an enemy with a weapon attack, they must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw against your Planeshifter spell save DC or be knocked prone.</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">Once you use either of your 18th level planar tradition features, you can’t use either feature again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Planar Tradition Feature (18th)" alt="Tidal Champion" action="Action">
                <description>You can assume the form of a mighty ocean spirit. For 1 minute, you gain the following benefits: you have resistance to cold damage; the ground in a 15-foot radius centered on you is difficult terrain for enemies; whenever you hit an enemy with a weapon attack, they must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw (save DC {{spellcasting:dc}}) or be knocked prone.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    <element name="Hall of the Inferno" type="Archetype" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_PLANESHIFTER_HALL_OF_THE_INFERNO">
        <supports>Planar Tradition</supports>
        <description>
            <p>As a member of the Hall of the Inferno, you specialize in elemental magics that produce blasts of fire and scorching heat. While attuned to the plane of fire, you gain abilities that help you destroy your opposition.</p>
            <p class="indent">Followers of this tradition often find themselves in military positions, acting as powerful mid-ranged blasters and front-line fighters. Others might make their due as simple adventurers, detering monsters with great infernos and destructive blasts.</p>
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_INFERNO_PLANAR_SPELLS" />
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_INFERNO_ONE_WITH_THE_INFERNO" />
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_INFERNO_FIERY_BLAST" />
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_INFERNO_LORD_OF_EMBERS" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_INFERNO_PLANAR_SPELLS" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_INFERNO_ONE_WITH_THE_INFERNO" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_INFERNO_FIERY_BLAST" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_INFERNO_LORD_OF_EMBERS" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Flame Planar Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_INFERNO_PLANAR_SPELLS">
            <description>
                <p>You gain the planar spells in the table below at the planeshifter levels listed.</p>
                <h5>FLAME SPELLS</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Planeshifter Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>2nd</td><td><i>burning hands, hellish rebuke</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><i>flaming sphere, scorching ray</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><i>fireball, Melf’s minute meteors</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>13th</td><td><i>fire shield, wall of fire</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>17th</td><td><i>flame strike, immolation</i></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BURNING_HANDS" level="2" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HELLISH_REBUKE" level="2" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FLAMING_SPHERE" level="5" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SCORCHING_RAY" level="5" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIREBALL" level="9" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_MELFS_MINUTE_METEORS" level="9" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIRE_SHIELD" level="13" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WALL_OF_FIRE" level="13" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FLAME_STRIKE" level="17" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_IMMOLATION" level="17" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="One with the Inferno" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_INFERNO_ONE_WITH_THE_INFERNO">
            <description>
                <p>When you choose this tradition at 1st level, you gain the ability to shift to the elemental plane of fire to wreath your weapons in flame. Once per turn when you hit a creature with a weapon attack, the creature takes an extra 1d4 fire damage.</p>
                <p class="indent">At 3rd level, the extra fire damage is increased to 1d6. At 10th level, this increases to 1d8, and at 14th level this increases to 1d10.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Once per turn when you hit a creature with a weapon attack, the creature takes an extra 1d{{inferno:die-type}} fire damage.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="inferno:die-type" value="4" bonus="base" level="1" />
                <stat name="inferno:die-type" value="6" bonus="base" level="3" />
                <stat name="inferno:die-type" value="8" bonus="base" level="10" />
                <stat name="inferno:die-type" value="10" bonus="base" level="14" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Planar Tradition Feature (6th): Fiery Blast" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_INFERNO_FIERY_BLAST">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 6th level, you can unleash devastating infernos. When you roll fire damage, you can use this feature to deal maximum damage, instead of rolling.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use either of your 6th level planar tradition features, you can’t use either feature again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Planar Tradition Feature (6th)" alt="Fiery Blast">
                <description>When you roll fire damage, you can use this feature to deal maximum damage, instead of rolling.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Planar Tradition Feature (18th): Lord of Embers" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_INFERNO_LORD_OF_EMBERS">
            <description>
                <p>At 18th level, as an action, you can wreath your entire body in flame. For 1 minute, you have resistance to fire damage and at the end of each of your turns each enemy within 10 feet of you takes 2d10 fire damage. When you take damage, you can use your reaction to activate this effect again.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use either of your 18th level planar tradition features, you can’t use either feature again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Planar Tradition Feature (18th)" alt="Lord of Embers" action="Action">
                <description>For 1 minute, you have resistance to fire damage and at the end of each of your turns each enemy within 10 feet of you takes 2d10 fire damage. When you take damage, you can use your reaction to activate this effect again.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    <element name="Hall of the Earth" type="Archetype" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_PLANESHIFTER_HALL_OF_THE_EARTH">
        <supports>Planar Tradition</supports>
        <description>
            <p>As a member of the Hall of the Earth, you have learned to transmute the earth to your will and shape it to your command. While attuned to the plane of earth, you have access to powerful defensive capabilities.</p>
            <p class="indent">Those that practice this tradition often act as guardians and bodyguards, utilizing their increased physical durability to stay standing when others would fall.</p>
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_EARTH_PLANAR_SPELLS" />
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_EARTH_ONE_WITH_THE_EARTH" />
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_EARTH_EARTHEN_SKIN" />
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_EARTH_UNYIELDING_MOUNTAIN" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_EARTH_PLANAR_SPELLS" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_EARTH_ONE_WITH_THE_EARTH" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_EARTH_EARTHEN_SKIN" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_EARTH_UNYIELDING_MOUNTAIN" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Earth Planar Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_EARTH_PLANAR_SPELLS">
            <description>
                <p>You gain the planar spells in the table below at the planeshifter levels listed.</p>
                <h5>EARTH SPELLS</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Planeshifter Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>2nd</td><td><i>absorb elements, earth tremor</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><i>Maximilian’s earthen grasp, earth dome</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><i>erupting earth, meld into stone</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>13th</td><td><i>stone shape, stoneskin</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>17th</td><td><i>transmute rock, wall of stone</i></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ABSORB_ELEMENTS" level="2" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_EARTH_TREMOR" level="2" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_MAXIMILIANS_EARTHEN_GRASP" level="5" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_SPELL_PLANESHIFTER_EARTH_DOME" level="5" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ERUPTING_EARTH" level="9" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MELD_INTO_STONE" level="9" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_STONE_SHAPE" level="13" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_STONESKIN" level="13" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_TRANSMUTE_ROCK" level="17" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WALL_OF_STONE" level="17" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="One with the Earth" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_EARTH_ONE_WITH_THE_EARTH">
            <description>
                <p>When you choose this tradition at 1st level, you gain the ability to shift to the elemental plane of earth to gain a coating of rocky armor. Bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage you would take is reduced by 2.</p>
                <p class="indent">At 3rd level, the damage you would take is instead reduced by 3. At 10th level, the damage is reduced by 4, and at 14th level it is reduced by 5.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage you would take is reduced by {{earthen:damage-reduction}}.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="earthen:damage-reduction" value="2" level="1" />
                <stat name="earthen:damage-reduction" value="1" level="3" />
                <stat name="earthen:damage-reduction" value="1" level="10" />
                <stat name="earthen:damage-reduction" value="1" level="14" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Planar Tradition Feature (6th): Earthen Skin" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_EARTH_EARTHEN_SKIN">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 6th level, you can cover your skin with a stony covering in response to attack. When you’re hit by an attack but before you’re dealt damage, you can use your reaction to gain a number of temporary hit points equal to 1d8 + your Planeshifter level. These temporary hit points last until the end of your next turn.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use either of your 6th level planar tradition features, you can’t use either feature again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Planar Tradition Feature (6th)" alt="Earthen Skin" action="Reaction">
                <description>When you’re hit by an attack but before you’re dealt damage, you can gain a number of temporary hit points equal to 1d8 + {{level:planeshifter}}. These temporary hit points last until the end of your next turn.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Planar Tradition Feature (18th): Unyielding Mountain" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_EARTH_UNYIELDING_MOUNTAIN">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 18th level, as an action, you can transform yourself into a stone guardian. For 1 minute, you have resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage. For the duration, you and allies within 5 feet of you gain a +1 bonus to their AC and cannot be moved unwillingly.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use either of your 18th level planar tradition features, you can’t use either feature again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Planar Tradition Feature (18th)" alt="Unyielding Mountain" action="Action">
                <description>You can transform yourself into a stone guardian. For 1 minute, you have resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage. For the duration, you and allies within 5 feet of you gain a +1 bonus to their AC and cannot be moved unwillingly.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    <element name="Hall of the Sky" type="Archetype" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_PLANESHIFTER_HALL_OF_THE_SKY">
        <supports>Planar Tradition</supports>
        <description>
            <p>As a member of the Hall of the Sky, you have learned to shape the wind at your command and harness it to grant you bursts of speed and flight. While attuned to the plane of air, you are granted greatly increased mobility and flight.</p>
            <p class="indent">Practitioners of this hall are often travelers and adventurers, using their unique powers to swiftly navigate the worlds. Still others might use their abilities to work as thieves or assassins, using powers of flight and swiftness to make their entrances and getaways.</p>
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_SKY_PLANAR_SPELLS" />
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_SKY_ONE_WITH_THE_SKY" />
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_SKY_BURST_OF_FLIGHT" />
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_SKY_WINDBORN_VINDICATOR" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_SKY_PLANAR_SPELLS" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_SKY_ONE_WITH_THE_SKY" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_SKY_BURST_OF_FLIGHT" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_SKY_WINDBORN_VINDICATOR" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Air Planar Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_SKY_PLANAR_SPELLS">
            <description>
                <p>You gain the planar spells in the table below at the planeshifter levels listed.</p>
                <h5>AIR SPELLS</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Planeshifter Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>2nd</td><td><i>featherfall, longstrider</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><i>gust of wind, levitate</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><i>fly, wind wall</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>13th</td><td><i>freedom of movement, cloud form</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>17th</td><td><i>control winds, rushing wind</i></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FEATHERFALL" level="2" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LONGSTRIDER" level="2" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GUST_OF_WIND" level="5" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LEVITATE" level="5" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FLY" level="9" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WIND_WALL" level="9" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FREEDOM_OF_MOVEMENT" level="13" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_SPELL_PLANESHIFTER_CLOUD_FORM" level="13" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_CONTROL_WINDS" level="17" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_SPELL_PLANSHIFTER_RUSHING_WIND" level="17" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="One with the Sky" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_SKY_ONE_WITH_THE_SKY">
            <description>
                <p>When you choose this tradition at 1st level, you gain the ability to shift to the elemental plane of air to enhance your speed. Your walking speed increases by 5 feet, and your jump distance is doubled.</p>
                <p class="indent">At 3rd level, the speed bonus increases to 10 feet. At 10th level, this increases to 15 feet, and at 14th level it increases to 20 feet.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Your walking speed increases by {{sky:speed-bonus}} feet, and your jump distance is doubled.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="sky:speed-bonus" value="5" level="1" />
                <stat name="sky:speed-bonus" value="5" level="3" />
                <stat name="sky:speed-bonus" value="5" level="10" />
                <stat name="sky:speed-bonus" value="5" level="14" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Planar Tradition Feature (6th): Burst of Flight" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_SKY_BURST_OF_FLIGHT">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 6th level, you can quickly take to the skies. As a bonus action, you can fly a distance up to your walking speed without provoking opportunity attacks.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use either of your 6th level planar tradition features, you can’t use either feature again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Planar Tradition Feature (6th)" alt="Burst of Flight" action="Bonus Action">
                <description>You can fly a distance up to your walking speed without provoking opportunity attacks.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Planar Tradition Feature (18th): Windborn Vindicator" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_SKY_WINDBORN_VINDICATOR">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 18th level, you can grant yourself the powers of a sovereign wind spirit. Using your action, you undergo a transformation. For 1 minute, you gain the following benefits:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>You have a flying speed of 60 feet.</li>
                    <li>You can take the dash action as a bonus action on your turn.</li>
                    <li>Ranged weapon attacks have disadvantage against you.</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">Once you use either of your 18th level planar tradition features, you can’t use either feature again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Planar Tradition Feature (18th)" alt="Windborn Vindicator" action="Action">
                <description>You transform into a wind spirit. For 1 minute, you gain the following benefits: you have a flying speed of 60 feet; you can take the dash action as a bonus action on your turn; ranged weapon attacks have disadvantage against you.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    <element name="Hall of the Shadowfell" type="Archetype" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_PLANESHIFTER_HALL_OF_THE_SHADOWFELL">
        <supports>Planar Tradition</supports>
        <description>
            <p>As a member of the Hall of the Shadowfell, you study the malevolent and dark energies that persist throughout the Shadowfell, learning to manipulate those forces to your will. While attuned to the shadowfell, you gain powers that allow you to disable your foes, leaving them confused, frightened, and unnerved.</p>
            <p class="indent">Most that follow this tradition are seen as threatening, or sometimes even evil.While many of them do fall into this stereotype, some use the foul abilities of the Shadowfell for good and to neutralize evil.</p>
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_SHADOWFELL_PLANAR_SPELLS" />
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_SHADOWFELL_ONE_WITH_THE_SHADOWFELL" />
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_SHADOWFELL_INDUCE_FEAR" />
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_SHADOWFELL_LORD_OF_THE_SHADOWS" />
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_SHADOWFELL_PLANAR_SPELLS" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_SHADOWFELL_ONE_WITH_THE_SHADOWFELL" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_SHADOWFELL_INDUCE_FEAR" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_SHADOWFELL_LORD_OF_THE_SHADOWS" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Shadowfell Planar Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_SHADOWFELL_PLANAR_SPELLS">
            <description>
                <p>You gain the planar spells in the table below at the planeshifter levels listed.</p>
                <h5>SHADOWFELL SPELLS</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Planeshifter Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>2nd</td><td><i>bane, ray of sickness</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><i>blindness/deafness, ray of enfeeblement</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><i>enemies abound, fear</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>13th</td><td><i>phantasmal killer, sickening radiance</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>17th</td><td><i>contagion, insect plague</i></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BANE" level="2" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RAY_OF_SICKNESS" level="2" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLINDNESS_DEAFNESS" level="5" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RAY_OF_ENFEEBLEMENT" level="5" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ENEMIES_ABOUND" level="9" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FEAR" level="9" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PHANTASMAL_KILLER" level="13" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_SICKENING_RADIANCE" level="13" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONTAGION" level="17" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INSECT_PLAGUE" level="17" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="One with the Shadowfell" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_SHADOWFELL_ONE_WITH_THE_SHADOWFELL">
            <description>
                <p>When you choose this tradition at 1st level, a well aimed attack can pierce into your enemy’s mind, disorienting them. When you score a critical hit on a creature, that creature has disadvantage on attacks until the end of its next turn, and has its speed reduced by half for the same duration.</p>
                <p class="indent">At 3rd level, your weapon attacks score a critical hit on a roll of 19 or 20. At 10th level, your critical hits restrain their target until the end of their next turn, and at 14th level your weapon attacks score a critical hit on a roll of 18-20.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you score a critical hit on a creature, that creature has disadvantage on attacks until the end of its next turn, and has its speed reduced by half for the same duration.</description>
                <description level="3">Your weapon attacks score a critical hit on a roll of 19 or 20. When you score a critical hit on a creature, that creature has disadvantage on attacks until the end of its next turn, and has its speed reduced by half for the same duration.</description>
                <description level="10">Your weapon attacks score a critical hit on a roll of 19 or 20. When you score a critical hit on a creature, that creature has disadvantage on attacks until the end of its next turn, and it is restrained for the same duration.</description>
                <description level="14">Your weapon attacks score a critical hit on a roll of 18-20. When you score a critical hit on a creature, that creature has disadvantage on attacks until the end of its next turn, and it is restrained for the same duration.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Planar Tradition Feature (6th): Induce Fear" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_SHADOWFELL_INDUCE_FEAR">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 6th level, you use your action to attempt to frighten a creature within 60 feet of you. That creature must make a Wisdom saving throw against your spell save DC. On a failed save, they take 2d6 psychic damage, and become frightened of you until the end of their next turn. On that turn, they must take the Dash action and move away from you by the safest available route. On a successful save, they take half as much damage and suffer no secondary effect.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use either of your 6th level planar tradition features, you can’t use either feature again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Planar Tradition Feature (6th)" alt="Induce Fear" action="Action">
                <description>You can attempt to frighten a creature within 60 feet of you. That creature must make a Wisdom saving throw (save DC {{spellcasting:dc}}). On a failed save, they take 2d6 psychic damage, and become frightened of you until the end of their next turn. On that turn, they must take the Dash action and move away from you by the safest available route. On a successful save, they take half as much damage and suffer no secondary effect.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Planar Tradition Feature (18th): Lord of the Shadows" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_SHADOWFELL_LORD_OF_THE_SHADOWS">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 18th level, as an action, you can surround yourself with an aura of swirling shadows. For 1 minute, the area within 10 feet of you is considered difficult terrain for enemies, and at the end of each of your turns each creature of your choice within 10 feet of you becomes poisoned until the start of your next turn.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use either of your 18th level planar tradition features, you can’t use either feature again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Planar Tradition Feature (18th)" alt="Lord of the Shadows" action="Action">
                <description>You can surround yourself with an aura of swirling shadows. For 1 minute, the area within 10 feet of you is considered difficult terrain for enemies, and at the end of each of your turns each creature of your choice within 10 feet of you becomes poisoned until the start of your next turn.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    <element name="Hall of the Feywild" type="Archetype" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_PLANESHIFTER_HALL_OF_THE_FEYWILD">
        <supports>Planar Tradition</supports>
        <description>
            <p>As a member of the Hall of the Feywild, you specialize in the deceptive malice that characterizes fey magic. While attuned to this plane, you can misdirect and deceive your foes with fae charms, invisibility, and illusions.</p>
            <p class="indent">Some practitioners of this hall act as benevolent tricksters, not unlike the fey creatures they emulate. Others might use their abilities for evil purposes, tricking those they come across and acting as thieves or robbers.</p>
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_FEYWILD_PLANAR_SPELLS" />
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_FEYWILD_ONE_WITH_THE_FEYWILD" />
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_FEYWILD_MISDIRECTION" />
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_FEYWILD_ELUSIVE_TRICKSTER" />
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_FEYWILD_PLANAR_SPELLS" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_FEYWILD_ONE_WITH_THE_FEYWILD" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_FEYWILD_MISDIRECTION" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_FEYWILD_ELUSIVE_TRICKSTER" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Feywild Planar Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_FEYWILD_PLANAR_SPELLS">
            <description>
                <p>You gain the planar spells in the table below at the planeshifter levels listed.</p>
                <h5>FEYWILD SPELLS</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Planeshifter Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>2nd</td><td><i>charm person, faerie fire</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><i>invisibility, misty step</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><i>counterspell, major image</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>13th</td><td><i>hallucinatory terrain, greater invisibility</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>17th</td><td><i>dominate person, dream</i></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CHARM_PERSON" level="2" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FAERIE_FIRE" level="2" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INVISIBILITY" level="5" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MISTY_STEP" level="5" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COUNTERSPELL" level="9" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAJOR_IMAGE" level="9" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HALLUCINATORY_TERRAIN" level="13" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GREATER_INVISIBILITY" level="13" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DOMINATE_PERSON" level="17" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DREAM" level="17" known="true" spellcasting="Planeshifter" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="One with the Feywild" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_FEYWILD_ONE_WITH_THE_FEYWILD">
            <description>
                <p>When you choose this tradition at 1st level, you gain the ability to become briefly invisible. Whenever you reduce a creature to 0 hit points on your turn, you become invisible until the end of your turn, or until you attack or cast a spell.</p>
                <p class="indent">At 3rd level, the duration of your invisibility is extended to the start of your next turn. At 10th level, it is extended until the end of your next turn, and at 14th level you can attack or cast a spell without breaking your invisibility.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Whenever you reduce a creature to 0 hit points on your turn, you become invisible until the end of your turn, or until you attack or cast a spell.</description>
                <description level="3">Whenever you reduce a creature to 0 hit points on your turn, you become invisible until the start of your next turn, or until you attack or cast a spell.</description>
                <description level="10">Whenever you reduce a creature to 0 hit points on your turn, you become invisible until the end of your next turn, or until you attack or cast a spell.</description>
                <description level="14">Whenever you reduce a creature to 0 hit points on your turn, you become invisible until the end of your next turn. You can attack or cast a spell without breaking this invisibility.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Planar Tradition Feature (6th): Misdirection" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_FEYWILD_MISDIRECTION">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, you can blink to a new location, leaving behind an illusory double. As an action on your turn, you create an illusory double of yourself where your standing, and then teleport up to 30 feet to an unoccupied location that you can see. The illusory double lasts for up to one minute, and remains perfectly still for the duration. If another creature interacts with the illusion, it immediately disappears in a burst of smoke.</p>
                <p class="indent">As long as the illusory double lasts, you can use your bonus action to teleport back to its location as long as you are within 30 feet of it. Once you do so, the illusion disappears.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use either of your 6th level planar tradition features, you can’t use either feature again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Planar Tradition Feature (6th)" alt="Misdirection" action="Action">
                <description>You create an illusory double of yourself where your standing, and then teleport up to 30 feet to an unoccupied location that you can see. The illusory double lasts for up to one minute, and remains perfectly still for the duration. If another creature interacts with the illusion, it immediately disappears in a burst of smoke. As long as the illusory double lasts, you can use your bonus action to teleport back to its location as long as you are within 30 feet of it. Once you do so, the illusion disappears.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Planar Tradition Feature (18th): Elusive Trickster" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_FEYWILD_ELUSIVE_TRICKSTER">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 18th level, as an action, you can imbue your form with fey magic. For the next minute, you gain a climbing and swimming speed equal to your walking speed, and when you hit a creature with a weapon attack you deal 1d8 bonus psychic damage and become invisible to that creature until the start of your next turn. The bonus damage and invisibility only activates once per turn for the duration.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use either of your 18th level planar tradition features, you can’t use either feature again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Planar Tradition Feature (18th)" alt="Elusive Trickster" action="Action">
                <description>You can imbue your form with fey magic. For the next minute, you gain a climbing and swimming speed equal to {{speed}} feet, and when you hit a creature with a weapon attack you deal 1d8 bonus psychic damage and become invisible to that creature until the start of your next turn. The bonus damage and invisibility only activates once per turn for the duration.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

  <!-- Planar Attunements -->
        <element name="Elysium" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_PLANAR_ATTUNEMENT_ELYSIUM">
            <supports>Planar Attunement</supports>
            <description>
                <p>The Blessed Fields of Elysium embody the concept of pure good, and they are the home of many celestials. When you choose this attunement, you gain the following benefits:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>You can speak, read, and write a language of your choice.</li>
                    <li>When you cast a spell of 1st level or higher and expend a spell slot, you regain a number of hit points equal to your Intelligence modifier + the spell’s level.</li>
                    <li>You gain the following Attunement Spells at the levels listed below:</li>
                </ul>
                <h5>ELYSIUM SPELLS</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Planeshifter Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><i>zone of truth</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><i>daylight</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>13th</td><td><i>death ward</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>17th</td><td><i>commune</i></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you cast a spell of 1st level or higher and expend a spell slot, you regain a number of hit points equal to your Intelligence modifier + the spell’s level.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ZONE_OF_TRUTH" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DAYLIGHT" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DEATH_WARD" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="13" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMMUNE" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="17" />
                <select type="Language" name="Language Proficiency (Planar Attunement)" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="The Beastlands" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_PLANAR_ATTUNEMENT_THE_BEASTLANDS">
            <supports>Planar Attunement</supports>
            <description>
                <p>The Wilderness of the Beastlands is a land of verdant greenery and endless nature, and it is the home of beasts and plants of all kinds. When you choose this attunement, you gain the following benefits:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>You can speak, read, and write Druidic.</li>
                    <li>You can cast <i>beast bond</i> and <i>speak with animals</i> at will, without expending a spell slot or material components.</li>
                    <li>You gain the following Attunement Spells at the levels listed below:</li>
                </ul>
                <h5>BEASTLANDS SPELLS</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Planeshifter Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><i>animal messenger</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><i>conjure animals</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>13th</td><td><i>dominate beast</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>17th</td><td><i>awaken</i></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can cast beast bond and speak with animals at will, without expending a spell slot or material components.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANIMAL_MESSENGER" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONJURE_ANIMALS" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DOMINATE_BEAST" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="13" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AWAKEN" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="17" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BEAST_BOND" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_ANIMALS" />
                <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_DRUIDIC" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Arborea" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_PLANAR_ATTUNEMENT_ARBOREA">
            <supports>Planar Attunement</supports>
            <description>
                <p>The Olympian Glades of Arborea is a peaceful plane dominated by vast tall forests, and both Olympian gods and Elvish gods make their home there. When you choose this attunement, you gain the following benefits:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>You can speak, read, and write Sylvan.</li>
                    <li>As an action, you can use fey magic to charm a creature of your choice. One creature of your choice within 10 feet of you must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw against your Planeshifter spell save DC or be charmed by you until the end of your next turn.<br />You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier (a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</li>
                    <li>You gain the following Attunement Spells at the levels listed below:</li>
                </ul>
                <h5>ARBOREA SPELLS</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Planeshifter Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><i>pass without trace</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><i>speak with plants</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>13th</td><td><i>conjure woodland beings</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>17th</td><td><i>commune with nature</i></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="{{arborea-attunement:uses}}/Long Rest">
                <description>One creature of your choice within 10 feet of you must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw (save DC {{spellcasting:dc}}) or be charmed by you until the end of your next turn.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PASS_WITHOUT_TRACE" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_PLANTS" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONJURE_WOODLAND_BEINGS" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="13" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMMUNE_WITH_NATURE" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="17" />
                <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_SYLVAN" />
                <stat name="arborea-attunement:uses" value="1" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="arborea-attunement:uses" value="intelligence:modifier" bonus="base" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Ysgard" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_PLANAR_ATTUNEMENT_YSGARD">
            <supports>Planar Attunement</supports>
            <description>
                <p>The Heroic Domains of Ysgard embody the idea of a glorious individual struggle, culminating in heroic rewards. When you choose this attunement, you gain the following benefits:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>You can speak, read, and write Giant.</li>
                    <li>When you reduce a creature to 0 hit points with a melee weapon attack, you gain a number of temporary hit points equal to your Intelligence modifier + half your planeshifter level. These temporary hit points last until the start of your next turn.</li>
                    <li>You gain the following Attunement Spells at the levels listed below:</li>
                </ul>
                <h5>YSGARD SPELLS</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Planeshifter Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><i>magic weapon</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><i>spirit guardians</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>13th</td><td><i>guardian of faith</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>17th</td><td><i>raise dead</i></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you reduce a creature to 0 hit points with a melee weapon attack, you gain {{ysgard-attunement:temp-hp}} temporary hit points. These temporary hit points last until the start of your next turn.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGIC_WEAPON" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPIRIT_GUARDIANS" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GUARDIAN_OF_FAITH" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="13" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RAISE_DEAD" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="17" />
                <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_GIANT" />
                <stat name="ysgard-attunement:temp-hp" value="intelligence:modifier" />
                <stat name="ysgard-attunement:temp-hp" value="level:planeshifter:half" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Limbo" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_PLANAR_ATTUNEMENT_LIMBO">
            <supports>Planar Attunement</supports>
            <description>
                <p>The Everchanging Chaos of Limbo is a plane of pure chaos and randomness, where everything is in constant turmoil, and it is the home of the Slaad and the Gith. When you choose this attunement, you gain the following benefits:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>You can speak, read, and write Slaad and Gith.</li>
                    <li>You learn the <i>mage hand</i> cantrip.</li>
                    <li>You can communicate telepathically with creatures within 30 feet of you, using a language that you know.</li>
                    <li>You gain the following Attunement Spells at the levels listed below:</li>
                </ul>
                <h5>LIMBO SPELLS</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Planeshifter Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><i>detect thoughts</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><i>tongues</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>13th</td><td><i>confusion</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>17th</td><td><i>seeming</i></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can communicate telepathically with creatures within 30 feet of you, using a language that you know.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_THOUGHTS" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TONGUES" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONFUSION" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="13" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SEEMING" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="17" />
                <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_GITH" />
                <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_SLAAD" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGE_HAND" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Pandemonium" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_PLANAR_ATTUNEMENT_PANDEMONIUM">
            <supports>Planar Attunement</supports>
            <description>
                <p>The Windswept Depths of Pandemonium is a plane of endless caverns and howling winds that driven its residents mad. When you choose this attunement, you gain the following benefits:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>You can speak, read, and write a language of your choice.</li>
                    <li>You can cast <i>silent image</i> at will, without expending a spell slot or material components.</li>
                    <li>You gain the following Attunement Spells at the levels listed below:</li>
                </ul>
                <h5>PANDEMONIUM SPELLS</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Planeshifter Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><i>crown of madness</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><i>hypnotic pattern</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>13th</td><td><i>Evard’s black tentacles</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>17th</td><td><i>modify memory</i></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can cast silent image at will, without expending a spell slot or material components.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CROWN_OF_MADNESS" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HYPNOTIC_PATTERN" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_EVARDS_BLACK_TENTACLES" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="13" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MODIFY_MEMORY" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="17" />
                <select type="Language" name="Language Proficiency (Planar Attunement)" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SILENT_IMAGE" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="The Abyss" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_PLANAR_ATTUNEMENT_THE_ABYSS">
            <supports>Planar Attunement</supports>
            <description>
                <p>The Infinite Layers of the Abyss is a plane of unending malevolence and violence, and the birthplace of the vile race of demons. When you choose this attunement, you gain the following benefits:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>You can speak, read, and write Abyssal.</li>
                    <li>You can cast <i>detect magic</i> and <i>detect poison and disease</i> at will, without expending a spell slot or material components.</li>
                    <li>You gain the following Attunement Spells at the levels listed below:</li>
                </ul>
                <h5>ABYSS SPELLS</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Planeshifter Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><i>protection from poison</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><i>stinking cloud</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>13th</td><td><i>dimension door</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>17th</td><td><i>cloudkill</i></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>ou can cast detect magic and detect poison and disease at will, without expending a spell slot or material components.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PROTECTION_FROM_POISON" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_STINKING_CLOUD" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DIMENSION_DOOR" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="13" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CLOUDKILL" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="17" />
                <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_ABYSSAL" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_MAGIC" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_POISON_AND_DISEASE" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Carceri" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_PLANAR_ATTUNEMENT_CARCERI">
            <supports>Planar Attunement</supports>
            <description>
                <p>The Tarterian Depths of Carceri is a plane that imprisons the treacherous and hateful souls of malevolent creatures. When you choose this attunement, you gain the following benefits:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>You can speak, read, and write a language of your choice.</li>
                    <li>As an action, you can use fiendish magic to restrain a creature. One creature of your choice within 10 feet of you must succeed on a Strength saving throw against your Planeshifter spell save DC or be restrained until the start of your next turn.<br />You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier (a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</li>
                    <li>You gain the following Attunement Spells at the levels listed below:</li>
                </ul>
                <h5>CARCERI SPELLS</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Planeshifter Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><i>hold person</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><i>magic circle</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>13th</td><td><i>Otiluke’s resilient sphere</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>17th</td><td><i>planar binding</i></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="{{carceri-attunement:uses}}/Long Rest">
                <description>One creature of your choice within 10 feet of you must succeed on a Strength saving throw (save DC {{spellcasting:dc}}) or be restrained until the start of your next turn.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HOLD_PERSON" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGIC_CIRCLE" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_OTILUKES_RESILIENT_SPHERE" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="13" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PLANAR_BINDING" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="17" />
                <select type="Language" name="Language Proficiency (Planar Attunement)" />
                <stat name="carceri-attunement:uses" value="1" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="carceri-attunement:uses" value="intelligence:modifier" bonus="base" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Hades" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_PLANAR_ATTUNEMENT_HADES">
            <supports>Planar Attunement</supports>
            <description>
                <p>The Grey Wastes of Hades embody the concept of pure evil, and it is the home of fiendish and evil creatures. When you choose this attunement, you gain the following benefits:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>You can speak, read, and write a language of your choice.</li>
                    <li>Your spells are infused with necrotic energy. When you cast a spell of 1st level or higher that imposes a saving throw, any creature that fails their save against that spell becomes poisoned until the start of your next turn.</li>
                    <li>You gain the following Attunement Spells at the levels listed below:</li>
                </ul>
                <h5>HADES SPELLS</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Planeshifter Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><i>phantasmal force</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><i>animate dead</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>13th</td><td><i>blight</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>17th</td><td><i>antilife shell</i></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you cast a spell of 1st level or higher that imposes a saving throw, any creature that fails their save against that spell becomes poisoned until the start of your next turn.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PHANTASMAL_FORCE" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANIMATE_DEAD" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLIGHT" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="13" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANTILIFE_SHELL" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="17" />
                <select type="Language" name="Language Proficiency (Planar Attunement)" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Gehenna" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_PLANAR_ATTUNEMENT_GEHENNA">
            <supports>Planar Attunement</supports>
            <description>
                <p>The Bleak Eternity of Gehenna is a plane filled with fire and evil, and it is the home of the yugoloths. When you choose this attunement, you gain the following benefits:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>You can speak, read, and write a language of your choice.</li>
                    <li>You can cast <i>disguise self</i> at will, without expending a spell slot.</li>
                    <li>You gain the following Attunement Spells at the levels listed below:</li>
                </ul>
                <h5>GEHENNA SPELLS</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Planeshifter Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><i>alter self</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><i>dispel magic</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>13th</td><td><i>dimension door</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>17th</td><td><i>dispel evil and good</i></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can cast disguise self at will, without expending a spell slot.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ALTER_SELF" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISPEL_MAGIC" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DIMENSION_DOOR" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="13" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISPEL_EVIL_AND_GOOD" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="17" />
                <select type="Language" name="Language Proficiency (Planar Attunement)" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISGUISE_SELF" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="The Nine Hells" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_PLANAR_ATTUNEMENT_THE_NINE_HELLS">
            <supports>Planar Attunement</supports>
            <description>
                <p>The Nine Hells of Baator is a plane of sinister evil and institutional cruelty, organized into a strict caste system by the Devils. When you choose this attunement, you gain the following benefits:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>You can speak, read, and write Infernal.</li>
                    <li>You can see normally in darkness, both magical and nonmagical, to a distance of 120 feet.</li>
                    <li>You gain the following Attunement Spells at the levels listed below:</li>
                </ul>
                <h5>NINE HELLS SPELLS</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Planeshifter Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><i>darkness</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><i>bestow curse</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>13th</td><td><i>banishment</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>17th</td><td><i>banishing smite</i></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can see normally in darkness, both magical and nonmagical, to a distance of 120 feet.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DARKNESS" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BESTOW_CURSE" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BANISHMENT" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="13" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BANISHING_SMITE" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="17" />
                <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_INFERNAL" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Acheron" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_PLANAR_ATTUNEMENT_ACHERON">
            <supports>Planar Attunement</supports>
            <description>
                <p>The Infernal Battlefield of Acheron is a plane of eternal battle and unending conflict, where huge armies of all numbers of creatures do battle for eternity. When you choose this attunement, you gain the following benefits:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>You can speak, read, and write a language of your choice.</li>
                    <li>As a bonus action, you can command an ally to attack. One friendly creature of your choice within 30 feet of you can use its reaction to make a weapon attack.<br />You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier (a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</li>
                    <li>You gain the following Attunement Spells at the levels listed below:</li>
                </ul>
                <h5>ACHERON SPELLS</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Planeshifter Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><i>enhance ability</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><i>elemental weapon</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>13th</td><td><i>elemental bane</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>17th</td><td><i>geas</i></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="{{acheron-attunement:uses}}/Long Rest">
                <description>One friendly creature of your choice within 30 feet of you can use its reaction to make a weapon attack.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENHANCE_ABILITY" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ELEMENTAL_WEAPON" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ELEMENTAL_BANE" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="13" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GEAS" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="17" />
                <select type="Language" name="Language Proficiency (Planar Attunement)" />
                <stat name="acheron-attunement:uses" value="1" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="acheron-attunement:uses" value="intelligence:modifier" bonus="base" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Mechanus" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_PLANAR_ATTUNEMENT_MECHANUS">
            <supports>Planar Attunement</supports>
            <description>
                <p>The Clockwork Nirvana of Mechanus is a plane of machines inhabited by an array of clockwork beings, including the Modron. When you choose this attunement, you gain the following benefits:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>You can speak, read, and write Modron.</li>
                    <li>You cannot be charmed, and you have advantage on against effects that would frighten you.</li>
                    <li>You gain the following Attunement Spells at the levels listed below:</li>
                </ul>
                <h5>MECHANUS SPELLS</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Planeshifter Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><i>heat metal</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><i>slow</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>13th</td><td><i>compulsion</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>17th</td><td><i>animate objects</i></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You cannot be charmed, and you have advantage on against effects that would frighten you.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HEAT_METAL" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SLOW" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMPULSION" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="13" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANIMATE_OBJECTS" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="17" />
                <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_MODRON" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Arcadia" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_PLANAR_ATTUNEMENT_ARCADIA">
            <supports>Planar Attunement</supports>
            <description>
                <p>The Peaceable Kingdoms of Arcadia embody the concept of the greater good, where man and nature live in perfect harmony. When you choose this attunement, you gain the following benefits:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>You can speak, read, and write two languages of your choice.</li>
                    <li>You learn the <i>friends</i> cantrip</li>
                    <li>You gain proficiency in the Insight and Persuasion skills.</li>
                    <li>You gain the following Attunement Spells at the levels listed below:</li>
                </ul>
                <h5>ARCADIA SPELLS</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Planeshifter Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><i>calm emotions</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><i>sending</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>13th</td><td><i>Mordenkainen’s private sanctum</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>17th</td><td><i>hallow</i></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CALM_EMOTIONS" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SENDING" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MORDENKAINENS_PRIVATE_SANCTUM" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="13" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HALLOW" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="17" />
                <select type="Language" name="Language Proficiency (Planar Attunement)" number="2" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FRIENDS" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERSUASION" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Mount Celestia" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_PLANAR_ATTUNEMENT_MOUNT_CELESTIA">
            <supports>Planar Attunement</supports>
            <description>
                <p>The Seven Mounting Heavens of Celestia embody the ideals of law and goodness. It is the home of many celestials, as well as the souls of lawful good creatures. When you choose this attunement, you gain the following benefits:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>You can speak, read, and write Celestial.</li>
                    <li>When a creature within 5 feet of you makes an attack against an ally that is also within 5 feet of you, you can use your reaction to make a weapon attack against them.<br />You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier (a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</li>
                    <li>You gain the following Attunement Spells at the levels listed below:</li>
                </ul>
                <h5>MOUNT CELESTIA SPELLS</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Planeshifter Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><i>find steed</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><i>crusader’s mantle</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>13th</td><td><i>aura of purity</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>17th</td><td><i>circle of power</i></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Reaction" usage="{{celestia-attunement:uses}}/Long Rest">
                <description>When a creature within 5 feet of you makes an attack against an ally that is also within 5 feet of you, you can use your reaction to make a weapon attack against them.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIND_STEED" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CRUSADERS_MANTLE" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AURA_OF_PURITY" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="13" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CIRCLE_OF_POWER" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="17" />
                <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_CELESTIAL" />
                <stat name="celestia-attunement:uses" value="1" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="celestia-attunement:uses" value="intelligence:modifier" bonus="base" />      
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Bytopia" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_PLANESHIFTER_PLANAR_ATTUNEMENT_BYTOPIA">
            <supports>Planar Attunement</supports>
            <description>
                <p>The Twin Paradises of Bytopia is a plane consisting of dual layers, each facing each other. One of the layers is the home to souls of honest craftsmen and workers, while the opposite houses hidden beasts, monsters, and Gnomish cities. When you choose this attunement, you gain the following benefits:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>You can speak, read, and write a language of your choice.</li>
                    <li>You learn the <i>mending</i> cantrip</li>
                    <li>You can cast <i>unseen servant</i> and <i>Tenser’s floating disk</i> at will, without expending a spell slot.</li>
                    <li>You gain the following Attunement Spells at the levels listed below:</li>
                </ul>
                <h5>BYTOPIA SPELLS</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Planeshifter Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><i>mirror image</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><i>clairvoyance</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>13th</td><td><i>arcane eye </i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>17th</td><td><i>mislead</i></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can cast unseen servant and Tenser’s floating disk at will, without expending a spell slot.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MIRROR_IMAGE" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CLAIRVOYANCE" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ARCANE_EYE" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="13" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MISLEAD" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" level="17" />
                <select type="Language" name="Language Proficiency (Planar Attunement)" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MENDING" spellcasting="Planeshifter" known="true" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_UNSEEN_SERVANT" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TENSERS_FLOATING_DISK" />
            </rules>
        </element>

  <!-- Spells -->
    <element name="Cloud Form" type="Spell" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_SPELL_PLANESHIFTER_CLOUD_FORM">
        <supports>Planeshifter</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You assume a gaseous form for the duration, appearing as a wisp of cloud. While in this cloud form, you have a flying speed of 150 feet and have resistance to damage from nonmagical weapons. The only actions you can take in this form are the Dash action or to revert to your normal form. Reverting takes 1 minute, during which time a creature is incapacitated and can’t move. Until the spell ends, a creature can revert to cloud form, which also requires the 1-minute transformation.</p>
            <p class="indent">If a creature is in cloud form and flying when the effect ends, the creature descends 60 feet per round for 1 minute until it lands, which it does safely. If it can’t land after 1 minute, the creature falls the remaining distance.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">4</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 minute</set>
            <set name="duration">1 hour</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Earth Dome" type="Spell" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_SPELL_PLANESHIFTER_EARTH_DOME">
        <supports>Planeshifter</supports>
        <description>
            <p>A 5-foot radius immobile dome of earth is conjured around and above you and remains stationary for the duration.</p>
            <p class="indent">The dome can only fit you inside it, and any other creatures that would be in the area are pushed out of it as the spell forms. The dome gives you total cover, and spells or magical effects cannot extend through the dome or be cast through it. The dome can be attacked, and it has 10 AC and 20 hit points. The spell ends if the dome is reduced to 0 hit points.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the hit points of the dome are increased by 10 points for each slot level above 2nd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Conjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 hour</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Geyser" type="Spell" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_SPELL_PLANESHIFTER_GEYSER">
        <supports>Planeshifter</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Choose a point you can see on the ground within range. The ground begins to crack and crumble, creating difficult terrain in a 20 foot radius centered on that point. At the start of your next turn, a huge blast of water erupts from the area. Each creature that is within the area of difficult terrain when it erupts must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes 6d6 bludgeoning damage, and is thrown 40 feet straight up. If the creature collides with something before reaching its maximum height, such as a ceiling, it takes an additional 2d6 bludgeoning damage. On a successful save, a creature takes half damage from both instances, and is only thrown 20 feet up.</p>
            <p class="indent">The water then disappears back into the ground, but the area remains difficult terrain until it is cleared away. Each 5-foot square portion of the area requires at least 1 minute to clear by hand.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">5</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Grasping Pool" type="Spell" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_SPELL_PLANESHIFTER_GRASPING_POOL">
        <supports>Planeshifter</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You conjure a thin sheet of animated water over a point of your choice within range. The water covers a 15-foot radius area centered on that point for the duration. The water is difficult terrain.</p>
            <p class="indent">Each creature that ends its turn in the area must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, a creature is restrained until the start of its next turn, and it is pulled up to 10 feet towards the center of the pool.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Conjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 hour</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Rushing Wind" type="Spell" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_SPELL_PLANSHIFTER_RUSHING_WIND">
        <supports>Planeshifter</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Aided by a strong wind, you rush forward, knocking small obstacles aside as you travel. You move a distance equal to triple your speed in a straight line. Each creature that you come within 10 feet of during your movement must make a dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes 4d8 bludgeoning damage, is pushed 20 feet away from you perpendicular to the direction you’re traveling, and is knocked prone. On a successful save, a creature takes half damage, and is only pushed 10 feet and not knocked prone. Small objects are also pushed aside as you travel at the DM’s discretion.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">5</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Water Whips" type="Spell" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_RDDT_UA_SPELL_PLANESHIFTER_WATER_WHIPS">
        <supports>Planeshifter</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You conjure three long whips of water in an unoccupied space of your choice within range. Each whip can be directed to lash out at a different creature within 20 feet of it that you can see. Each creature must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or be pulled 15 feet directly toward the whips.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, you conjure one more whip for each slot level above 2nd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Conjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="range">20 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Slaad" type="Language" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_LANGUAGE_SLAAD">
        <supports>ID_INTERNAL_SUPPORT_LANGUAGE_EXOTIC, Exotic</supports>
        <requirements />
        <description>
            <p>Typically spoken by slaad.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="Speakers">Slaad</set>
            <set name="Script"></set>
            <set name="Exotic">true</set>
        </setters>
        <rules />
    </element>
    <element name="Modron" type="Language" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_LANGUAGE_MODRON">
        <supports>ID_INTERNAL_SUPPORT_LANGUAGE_EXOTIC, Exotic</supports>
        <requirements />
        <description>
            <p>Typically spoken by modrons.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="Speakers">Modron</set>
            <set name="Script"></set>
            <set name="Exotic">true</set>
        </setters>
        <rules />
    </element>

    <!-- Planeshifter Fighting Styles -->
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_ARCHERY">
        <supports>Planeshifter</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_DEFENSE">
        <supports>Planeshifter</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_DUELING">
        <supports>Planeshifter</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_GREAT_WEAPON_FIGHTING">
        <supports>Planeshifter</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_TWOWEAPON_FIGHTING">
        <supports>Planeshifter</supports>
    </append>

</elements>