<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>The Shaman Class</name>
        <update version="0.0.5">
            <file name="class-shaman.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/classes/class-shaman.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="The Shaman Class" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_GMBINDER_SOURCE_SHAMAN">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p>Channel the Raw Power of Nature with this new Class for the World’s Greatest Roleplaying Game!</p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation"></set>
            <set name="url">https://www.gmbinder.com/share/-M-6Rt87VW4p1cfPpPWO</set>
            <set name="image">https://i.pinimg.com/originals/32/b2/0c/32b20cb90d6c176c94767d8c8174632e.png</set>
            <set name="author" abbreviation="LL" url="https://www.gmbinder.com/profile/laserllama">laserllama</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20200415</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Shaman" type="Class" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_SHAMAN">
        <description>
            <p>A wild looking half-orc lumbers through the forest, his arcane tattoos glistening in the light that penetrates the forest canopy. A child from his tribe had reportedly seen a group of goblins cutting down ceremonial trees in their sacred grove. Slicing his hand the half-orc smeared his blood on a the hilt of his heartwood maul. His weapon now pulsed with a deep green energy as he ventured forth to deal with the fools that would dare profane their grove. They would pay for desecrating the resting place of his ancestors.</p>
            <p class="indent">A hunched over, elderly halfling grips his necklace as he faces down the leader of the hobgoblin war-band. The necklace, made from the finger bones of the previous shamans of his tribe, allows their spirits to take charge of his body. With their aid his life force is enhanced by theirs and he moves with the vigor of youth. Quick as lightning, he strikes at the hobgoblin’s head with his ancient club. As his foe slumps to the ground, he reflects on his time defending his people as their champion. Soon his time would end, and his body would die, but his spirit would join the previous shamans, aiding the next champion of their tribe.</p>
            <p class="indent">A hunched over elvish woman uses her primal connection to life-magic to conduct an ancient ritual on a stolen lock of hair. Far across town, the village fool comes down with a mysterious illness, and within hours he succumbs to the strange pox. The townsfolk suspect dark magic was at play, but after a few days they bury the fool and move on. The man who had dared to insult the old elf had paid for the transgression with his life.</p>
            <h4>CONDUITS OF NATURAL ENERGY</h4>
            <p>Shamans are the rare few that learn to open themselves to the natural energy that exists in all living things. Using their connection to this power, they are able to use primal energy to enhance their bodies, place curses on foes, or heal the sick. Shamanistic magic is ancient in its origins, and the teachings of shamans that are passed from one generation to the next trace their beginnings to the dawn of the world. Most Shamans embrace the old ways. They find civilized society uncomfortable, instead preferring to spend time in the wild.</p>
            <h4>OVERWHELMING POWER</h4>
            <p>Shamans don’t come to learn their magic by study, but through meditation and introspection they learn to channel the raw power innate in all living things. Their connection to the natural world is intense, and they have little control over the flow of energy once they open themselves up to the primal powers of creation. Many who seek become shamans are overwhelmed and consumed by the life-energies around them, turning into large trees or stone statues vaguely reminiscent of humanoids. But, for the few that survive the initiation rituals, they become conduits able to channel the primal energy of creation to perform powerful and overwhelming feats of magic.</p>
            <h4>CREATING A SHAMAN</h4>
            <p>When creating your Shaman consider how you came to be a conduit for the power of nature. Were you chosen from birth to be the champion of your tribe, destined to bear the power that comes with the spiritual support of your ancestors? Did a terrible hag steal you away and raise you in her ways, teaching you the secrets of curses and hex magic? Or did you study under an ancient hermit, learning to manipulate the primal forces present in all things to heal the broken?</p>
            <p class="indent">Whatever your origin, consider how your relationship to the natural world effects your character. Do you gently beseech the power of nature? Or do you violently wrest control of the primeval creative energies around you?</p>
            <h5 class="caption">QUICK BUILD</h5>
            <p>You can make a Shaman quickly by following these suggestions. First, make Wisdom your highest ability score followed by Constitution. Second choose the hermit background. Third select the shillelagh and vicious mockery cantrips along with the 1st-level spells entangle and heroism.</p>
            <h5>OPTIONAL RULE: MULTICLASSING</h5>
            <p>If your group uses the optional rule on multiclassing in the Player’s Handbook, here’s what you need to know if you choose the savant as one of your classes.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Minimum.</em></strong> As a multiclass character, you must have at least a 13 in both Constitution and Wisdom to take a level in this class, or to take a level in another class if you are already a shaman.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Proficiencies Gained.</em></strong> If shaman isn’t your initial class, you gain proficiency in light armor, simple weapons, and one skill from the shaman skill list.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Spellcasting.</em></strong> If you have both the Spellcasting class feature and the Primal Magic class feature from the shaman class, you can use the spell slots you gain from the Primal Magic feature to cast spells you know or have prepared from classes with the Spellcasting class feature, and you can use the spell slots you gain from the Spellcasting class feature to cast shaman spells you know.</p>
            <h2>CLASS FEATURES</h2>
            <p>As an shaman, you gain the following class features.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">HIT POINTS</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Hit Dice:</strong> 1d8 per shaman level</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at 1st Level:</strong> 8 + your Constitution modifier</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at Higher Levels:</strong> 1d8 (or 5) + your Constitution modifier per shaman level after 1st</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">PROFICIENCIES</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled mb">
                <li><strong>Armor:</strong> Light armor, shields</li>
                <li><strong>Weapons:</strong> Simple weapons, blow guns, and nets. </li>
                <li><strong>Tools:</strong> None</li>
            </ul>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Saving Throws:</strong> Wisdom, Charisma</li>
                <li><strong>Skills:</strong> Choose two from Animal Handling, Arcana, Insight, Medicine, Nature, Performance, or Religion</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">EQUIPMENT</h5>
            <p>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>(a) quarterstaff or (b) any simple weapon</li>
                <li>(a) a shortbow and 20 arrows or (b) 5 javelins</li>
                <li>(a) an explorer’s pack or (b) a priest’s pack</li>
                <li>Leather armor and a druidic focus</li>
            </ul>
        <!-- class table here -->
            <h5 class="caption">THE SHAMAN</h5>
            <table class="class-features">
                <thead>
                    <tr><td class="col-5">Level</td><td>Proficiency Bonus</td><td class="left">Features</td><td class="col-10">Cantrips Known</td><td class="col-10">Spells Known</td><td>Spell Slotss</td><td>Slot Level</td><td>Totems</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td> 1st</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Spirituality, Primal Magic</td><td>2</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>1st</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 2nd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Totems</td><td>2</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>1st</td><td>2</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 3rd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Spirituality Feature</td><td>2</td><td>4</td><td>2</td><td>2nd</td><td>2</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 4th</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>3</td><td>5</td><td>2</td><td>2nd</td><td>2</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 5th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">─</td><td>3</td><td>6</td><td>2</td><td>3rd</td><td>3</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 6th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Spirituality Feature</td><td>3</td><td>7</td><td>2</td><td>3rd</td><td>3</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 7th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">─</td><td>3</td><td>8</td><td>2</td><td>4th</td><td>4</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 8th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>3</td><td>9</td><td>2</td><td>4th</td><td>4</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 9th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">─</td><td>3</td><td>10</td><td>2</td><td>5th</td><td>5</td></tr>
                <tr><td>10th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Spirituality Feature</td><td>4</td><td>10</td><td>2</td><td>5th</td><td>5</td></tr>
                <tr><td>11th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Primeval Conduit (6th)</td><td>4</td><td>11</td><td>3</td><td>5th</td><td>5</td></tr>
                <tr><td>12th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>4</td><td>11</td><td>3</td><td>5th</td><td>6</td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Primeval Conduit (7th)</td><td>4</td><td>12</td><td>3</td><td>5th</td><td>6</td></tr>
                <tr><td>14th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Spirituality Feature</td><td>4</td><td>12</td><td>3</td><td>5th</td><td>6</td></tr>
                <tr><td>15th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Primeval Conduit (8th)</td><td>4</td><td>13</td><td>3</td><td>5th</td><td>7</td></tr>
                <tr><td>16th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>4</td><td>13</td><td>3</td><td>5th</td><td>7</td></tr>
                <tr><td>17th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Primeval Conduit (9th)</td><td>4</td><td>14</td><td>4</td><td>5th</td><td>7</td></tr>
                <tr><td>18th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">—</td><td>4</td><td>14</td><td>4</td><td>5th</td><td>8</td></tr>
                <tr><td>19th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>4</td><td>15</td><td>4</td><td>5th</td><td>8</td></tr>
                <tr><td>20th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Totemic Mastery</td><td>4</td><td>15</td><td>4</td><td>5th</td><td>8</td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_SPIRITUALITY" />
            <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_PRIMAL_MAGIC" />
            <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_TOTEMS" />
            <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" />
            <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_PRIMEVAL_CONDUIT" />
            <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_TOTEMIC_MASTERY" />
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="short">A class that channels the raw power of nature.</set>
            <set name="hd">d8</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" requirements="!ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_MULTICLASS_SHAMAN" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_SHIELDS" requirements="!ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_MULTICLASS_SHAMAN" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" requirements="!ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_MULTICLASS_SHAMAN" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_WISDOM" requirements="!ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_MULTICLASS_SHAMAN" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CHARISMA" requirements="!ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_MULTICLASS_SHAMAN" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_BLOWGUN" requirements="!ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_MULTICLASS_SHAMAN" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_NET" requirements="!ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_MULTICLASS_SHAMAN" />
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency, Shaman" supports="LL Shaman" number="2" requirements="!ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_MULTICLASS_SHAMAN" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_SPIRITUALITY" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_PRIMAL_MAGIC" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_TOTEMS" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" level="4" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_PRIMEVAL_CONDUIT" level="11" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_TOTEMIC_MASTERY" level="20" />
        </rules>
        <multiclass id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_MULTICLASS_SHAMAN">
            <prerequisite>Constitution 13, Wisdom 13</prerequisite>
            <requirements>[con:13],[wis:13]</requirements>
            <setters>
                <set name="multiclass proficiencies">If shaman isn’t your initial class, you gain proficiency in light armor, simple weapons, and one skill from the shaman skill list.</set>
            </setters>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" />
                <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency, Shaman" supports="LL Shaman" />
            </rules>
        </multiclass>
    </element>
        <element name="Spirituality" type="Class Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_SPIRITUALITY">
            <description>
                <p>At 1st level, you choose your Spirituality, the way that you interact with the primal forces of nature. Choose between the Curse-Binder, Spirit-Warrior, or Witch-Doctor, each of which is detailed at the end of this class description.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Archetype" name="Shaman Spirituality" supports="Shaman Spirituality" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Primal Magic" type="Class Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_PRIMAL_MAGIC">
            <description>
                <p>The Shaman table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your shaman spells of 1st through 5th level. The table also shows what the level of those slots is; all of your spell slots are the same level. To cast one of your shaman spells of 1st-level or higher, you must expend a spell slot. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a short or long rest.</p>
                <p class="indent">For example, when you are 5th level, you have two 3rd-level spell slots. To cast the 1st-level spell heroism you must spend one of those slots, and you cast it as a 3rd-level spell.</p>
                <h5>CANTRIPS</h5>
                <p>You know two cantrips of your choice from the shaman spell list. You learn additional shaman cantrips of your choice at higher levels, as shown in the Cantrips Known column of the Shaman table.</p>
                <h5>SPELLS KNOWN OF 1ST LEVEL AND HIGHER</h5>
                <p>At 1st level, you know two 1st-level spells of your choice from the shaman spell list, which is detailed below. The Spells Known column of the Shaman table shows when you learn more shaman spells of your choice of 1st level and higher. A spell you choose must be of a level no higher than what’s shown in the table’s Slot Level column for your level. When you reach 6th level, for example, you learn a new shaman spell, which can be 1st, 2nd, or 3rd level.</p>
                <p class="indent">Whenever you finish a long rest, you can replace one spell you learned from this Spellcasting feature with another spell from the shaman spell list. The new spell must be the same level as the spell you replace.</p>
                <h5>SPELLCASTING ABILITY</h5>
                <p>Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for your shaman spells, so you use your Wisdom whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Wisdom modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a shaman spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.</p>
                <center>
                    <p><strong>Spell save DC</strong> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier</p>
                    <p><strong>Spell attack modifier</strong> = your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier</p>
                </center>
                <h5>SPELLCASTING FOCUS</h5>
                <p>You can use a Druidic Focus (see the Adventuring Gear section) as a spellcasting focus for your Shaman spells. A shaman’s spellcasting focus is often an item of great personal or tribal significance, like the bone of an ancestor, the branch from a sacred tree, or a small doll made in the likeness of their spirit animal.</p>
                <h5>RITUAL CASTING</h5>
                <p>You can cast a shaman spell as a ritual if that spell has the ritual tag. The spell does not need to be one of your known shaman spells to be cast as a ritual.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <spellcasting name="Shaman" ability="Wisdom" prepare="false">
                <list>Shaman</list>
            </spellcasting>
            <rules>
    			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS_SPELLCASTING_SLOTS_SOLO" requirements="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS"/>
    			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_RITUAL_CASTING" />
                <stat name="shaman:spellcasting:slots:count" value="1" level="1"/>
                <stat name="shaman:spellcasting:slots:count" value="1" level="2"/>
                <stat name="shaman:spellcasting:slots:count" value="1" level="11"/>
                <stat name="shaman:spellcasting:slots:count" value="1" level="17"/>

                <stat name="shaman:spellcasting:slot" value="1" level="1" />
                <stat name="shaman:spellcasting:slot" value="1" level="3" />
                <stat name="shaman:spellcasting:slot" value="1" level="5" />
                <stat name="shaman:spellcasting:slot" value="1" level="7" />
                <stat name="shaman:spellcasting:slot" value="1" level="9" />

                <!-- negative count to remove slots -->
                <stat name="shaman:spellcasting:slots:1" value="shaman:spellcasting:slots:count" level="1" />
                <stat name="shaman:spellcasting:slots:1" value="-shaman:spellcasting:slots:count" level="3" />
                <stat name="shaman:spellcasting:slots:2" value="shaman:spellcasting:slots:count" level="3" />
                <stat name="shaman:spellcasting:slots:2" value="-shaman:spellcasting:slots:count" level="5" />
                <stat name="shaman:spellcasting:slots:3" value="shaman:spellcasting:slots:count" level="5" />
                <stat name="shaman:spellcasting:slots:3" value="-shaman:spellcasting:slots:count" level="7" />
                <stat name="shaman:spellcasting:slots:4" value="shaman:spellcasting:slots:count" level="7" />
                <stat name="shaman:spellcasting:slots:4" value="-shaman:spellcasting:slots:count" level="9" />
                <stat name="shaman:spellcasting:slots:5" value="shaman:spellcasting:slots:count" level="9" />

                <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Shaman)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),0" level="1" number="2" spellcasting="Shaman" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Shaman)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),0" level="4" spellcasting="Shaman" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Shaman)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),0" level="10" spellcasting="Shaman" />

                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Shaman)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="1" number="2" spellcasting="Shaman" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Shaman)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="2" spellcasting="Shaman" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Shaman)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="3" spellcasting="Shaman" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Shaman)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="4" spellcasting="Shaman" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Shaman)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="5" spellcasting="Shaman" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Shaman)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="6" spellcasting="Shaman" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Shaman)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="7" spellcasting="Shaman" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Shaman)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="8" spellcasting="Shaman" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Shaman)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="9" spellcasting="Shaman" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Shaman)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="11" spellcasting="Shaman" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Shaman)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="13" spellcasting="Shaman" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Shaman)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="15" spellcasting="Shaman" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Shaman)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="17" spellcasting="Shaman" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Shaman)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="19" spellcasting="Shaman" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Totems" type="Class Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_TOTEMS">
            <description>
                <p>You insight into the natural world has given you the ability to enhance your own body with the forces of nature. Special Totems allow you to tap into primeval power without the risk of overwhelming your body and soul. Your Totems could be carved from wood, tattooed onto your body with magical inks, or made from the shrunken heads of your enemies.</p>
                <p class="indent">At 2nd level, you gain two Totems of your choice. When you gain certain shaman levels, you gain additional totems of your choice, as shown in the Totems column of the Shaman table. Additionally, when you complete a long rest, you can swap out one of the Totems you have selected for another.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Totem" supports="LL Shaman Totem" number="2" level="2" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Totem" supports="LL Shaman Totem" level="5" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Totem" supports="LL Shaman Totem" level="7" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Totem" supports="LL Shaman Totem" level="9" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Totem" supports="LL Shaman Totem" level="12" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Totem" supports="LL Shaman Totem" level="15" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Totem" supports="LL Shaman Totem" level="18" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Ability Score Improvement" type="Class Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Shaman 4)" supports="Improvement Option,Shaman,4" level="4" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Shaman 8)" supports="Improvement Option,Shaman,8" level="8" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Shaman 12)" supports="Improvement Option,Shaman,12" level="12" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Shaman 16)" supports="Improvement Option,Shaman,16" level="16" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Shaman 19)" supports="Improvement Option,Shaman,19" level="19" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Primeval Conduit" type="Class Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_PRIMEVAL_CONDUIT">
            <description>
                <p>At 11th level, your spiritual connection with the natural world deepens, and you gain the ability to directly channel the raw power of nature. Choose one 6th-level spell from the Shaman spell list. You can cast your Primeval Conduit spell once without expending a spell slot. You must finish a long rest before you can do so again.</p>
                <p class="indent">At higher levels, you gain more shaman spells of your choice that can be cast in this way: one 7th-level spell at 13th level, one 8th-level spell at 15th level, and one 9th-level spell at 17th level. You regain all uses of your Primeval Conduit spells when you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You can cast your Primeval Conduit spells once per long rest.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Spell" name="Conduit Spell (Primeval Conduit)" supports="Shaman,6" level="11" spellcasting="Shaman" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Conduit Spell (Primeval Conduit)" supports="Shaman,7" level="13" spellcasting="Shaman" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Conduit Spell (Primeval Conduit)" supports="Shaman,8" level="15" spellcasting="Shaman" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Conduit Spell (Primeval Conduit)" supports="Shaman,9" level="17" spellcasting="Shaman" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Totemic Mastery" type="Class Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_TOTEMIC_MASTERY">
            <description>
                <p>At 20th level, you can draw the natural energy of the world around to regain expended spell slots. As an action, you can regain one expended spell slot. You can use this ability a number of times equal to your Constitution modifier. You regain all uses when you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="{{constitution:modifier}}/Long Rest">
                <description>You can regain one expended spell slot.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    <!-- Shaman Spirituality -->
        <element name="Curse-Binder" type="Archetype" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_SHAMAN_CURSE_BINDER">
            <supports>Shaman Spirituality</supports>
            <description>
                <p>You have attuned yourself to the foul side of shamanism. Often learned from hags and other less-then-savory spell casters, the way of the Curse-Binder uses the magic of nature to hinder and hurt their foes. Your familiarity with dark magic also provides you with certain measures of protection against curses and foul magic targeted at yourself.</p>
                <p class="indent">You trap the life-magic of others in cursed objects and twist their own innate life force against them. With careful preparation and planning, you can take down your enemies before they come to face you on the field of battle.</p>
                <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CURSE_BINDER_EXPANDED_SPELL_LIST" />
                <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CURSE_BINDER_MINOR_HEX" />
                <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CURSE_BINDER_SPIRITUAL_ANALYST" />
                <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CURSE_BINDER_PRIMAL_CURSE" />
                <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CURSE_BINDER_INSCRUTABLE_MIND" />
                <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CURSE_BINDER_SHAMANISTIC_WARD" />
                <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CURSE_BINDER_FOUL_SUMMONER" />
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CURSE_BINDER_EXPANDED_SPELL_LIST" level="1" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CURSE_BINDER_MINOR_HEX" level="1" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CURSE_BINDER_SPIRITUAL_ANALYST" level="1" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CURSE_BINDER_PRIMAL_CURSE" level="3" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CURSE_BINDER_INSCRUTABLE_MIND" level="6" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CURSE_BINDER_SHAMANISTIC_WARD" level="10" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CURSE_BINDER_FOUL_SUMMONER" level="14" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Expanded Spell List" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CURSE_BINDER_EXPANDED_SPELL_LIST">
                <description>
                    <p>The Curse-Binder Spirituality grants you additional spells known when you gain certain shaman levels. The following spells are added to your spell list, but don’t count against your number of spells known.</p>
                    <h5 class="caption">CURSE-BINDER SPELLS</h5>
                    <table>
                        <thead>
                            <tr><td>Slot Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                        </thead>
                        <tr><td>1st</td><td><em>bane, hex</em></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>2nd</td><td><em>blindness/deafness, ray of enfeeblement</em></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>bestow curse, vampiric touch</em></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>4th</td><td><em>blight, phantasmal killer</em></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>contagion, enervation</em></td></tr>
                    </table>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BANE" spellcasting="Shaman" known="true" level="1" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HEX" spellcasting="Shaman" known="true" level="1" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLINDNESS_DEAFNESS" spellcasting="Shaman" known="true" level="3" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RAY_OF_ENFEEBLEMENT" spellcasting="Shaman" known="true" level="3" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BESTOW_CURSE" spellcasting="Shaman" known="true" level="5" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_VAMPIRIC_TOUCH" spellcasting="Shaman" known="true" level="5" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLIGHT" spellcasting="Shaman" known="true" level="7" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PHANTASMAL_KILLER" spellcasting="Shaman" known="true" level="7" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONTAGION" spellcasting="Shaman" known="true" level="9" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ENERVATION" spellcasting="Shaman" known="true" level="9" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Minor Hex" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CURSE_BINDER_MINOR_HEX">
                <description>
                    <p>Starting at 1st level you gain the ability to inflict minor hexes upon your enemies. When a creature that you can see within 60 ft. has advantage on an attack roll or saving throw, you can use your reaction to cancel their advantage, and they must make the roll as normal.</p>
                    <p class="indent">You may use this ability a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier. You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet action="Reaction" usage="{{wisdom:modifier}}/Long Rest">
                    <description>When a creature that you can see within 60 ft. has advantage on an attack roll or saving throw, you can cancel their advantage, and they must make the roll as normal.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Spiritual Analyst" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CURSE_BINDER_SPIRITUAL_ANALYST">
                <description>
                    <p>Also at 1st level you gain insight into curses and other effects. If you spend one minute observing a creature, you can determine the source and school of magic of any malady or curse currently afflicting them.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>If you spend one minute observing a creature, you can determine the source and school of magic of any malady or curse currently afflicting them.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Primal Curse" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CURSE_BINDER_PRIMAL_CURSE">
                <description>
                    <p>At 3rd level your ability to place curses on the living grows. If you gain a sample of a creature’s blood, some of their hair, or an item of great importance to them you can create a special cursed totem at the end of a short or long rest.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Once you create this cursed totem, that creature has disadvantage on saving throws against your spells as long as you are in possession of the cursed totem, or until the cursed totem is destroyed. You can only have one of these cursed totems created at a time, once you create another the magic in the first one dissipates.</p>
                    <p class="indent">At 10th level you can have two cursed totems active at once, and at 15th level you can have up to three active.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>If you gain a sample of a creature’s blood, some of their hair, or an item of great importance to them you can create a special cursed totem at the end of a short or long rest. Once you create this cursed totem, that creature has disadvantage on saving throws against your spells as long as you are in possession of the cursed totem, or until the cursed totem is destroyed. You can only have one of these cursed totems created at a time, once you create another the magic in the first one dissipates.</description>
                    <description level="10">If you gain a sample of a creature’s blood, some of their hair, or an item of great importance to them you can create a special cursed totem at the end of a short or long rest. Once you create this cursed totem, that creature has disadvantage on saving throws against your spells as long as you are in possession of the cursed totem, or until the cursed totem is destroyed. You can only have two of these cursed totems created at a time, once you create another the magic in the first one dissipates.</description>
                    <description level="15">If you gain a sample of a creature’s blood, some of their hair, or an item of great importance to them you can create a special cursed totem at the end of a short or long rest. Once you create this cursed totem, that creature has disadvantage on saving throws against your spells as long as you are in possession of the cursed totem, or until the cursed totem is destroyed. You can only have three of these cursed totems created at a time, once you create another the magic in the first one dissipates.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Inscrutable Mind" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CURSE_BINDER_INSCRUTABLE_MIND">
                <description>
                    <p>Starting at 6th level, your work manipulating the natural forces of the world to cause maladies has given you insights into warding your own mind against such misfortunes. You are immune to having your emotions or thoughts read by magic. Creatures that make Wisdom (Insight) checks against you do so with disadvantage.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>You are immune to having your emotions or thoughts read by magic. Creatures that make Insight checks against you do so with disadvantage.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Shamanistic Ward" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CURSE_BINDER_SHAMANISTIC_WARD">
                <description>
                    <p>Starting at 10th level, you can ward your body with magic to resists specific types of attacks. At the end of each short or long rest, you choose one damage type to gain resistance to. Damage with silvered weapons ignores this resistance.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>At the end of each short or long rest, you choose one damage type to gain resistance to. Damage with silvered weapons ignores this resistance.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Foul Summoner" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CURSE_BINDER_FOUL_SUMMONER">
                <description>
                    <p>At 14th level, you can cast the spell <em>create undead</em> at 6th level without providing any of the material components or using a spell slot. Spirits of long dead creatures rise out of the ground in the shape of the undead you summon. They are under your control until the end of your next long rest, or they are destroyed.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Once you use this ability you must complete a long rest before you can use it again.</p>
                    <div class="reference">
                        <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_CREATE_UNDEAD" />
                    </div>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                    <description>You can cast the spell create undead at 6th level without providing any of the material components or using a spell slot. Spirits of long dead creatures rise out of the ground in the shape of the undead you summon. They are under your control until the end of your next long rest, or they are destroyed.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CREATE_UNDEAD" />
                </rules>
            </element>


        <element name="Spirit-Warrior" type="Archetype" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_SHAMAN_SPIRIT_WARRIOR">
            <supports>Shaman Spirituality</supports>
            <description>
                <p>As a Spirit-Warrior, you allow the spirits of the natural world to flow into you and enhance your physical and mental abilities. Once enhanced, these champions act as protectors of ancient temples, sacred groves, and burial grounds.</p>
                <p class="indent">With their impressive martial prowess, Spirit-Warriors make stalwart allies and terrible foes. Woe to those who would rouse these ancient protectors to action.</p>
                <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_WARRIOR_EXPANDED_SPELL_LIST" />
                <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_WARRIOR_WAY_OF_THE_SPIRITS" />
                <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_WARRIOR_GUARDIANS_PROFICIENCIES" />
                <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_WARRIOR_PRIMAL_WEAPON" />
                <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_WARRIOR_EYES_OF_THE_SPIRIT_WORLD" />
                <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_WARRIOR_ONE_FOOT_IN_THE_GRAVE" />
                <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_WARRIOR_POSSESSED_WARRIOR" />
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_WARRIOR_EXPANDED_SPELL_LIST" level="1" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_WARRIOR_WAY_OF_THE_SPIRITS" level="1" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_WARRIOR_GUARDIANS_PROFICIENCIES" level="1" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_WARRIOR_PRIMAL_WEAPON" level="3" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_WARRIOR_EYES_OF_THE_SPIRIT_WORLD" level="6" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_WARRIOR_ONE_FOOT_IN_THE_GRAVE" level="10" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_WARRIOR_POSSESSED_WARRIOR" level="14" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Expanded Spell List" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_WARRIOR_EXPANDED_SPELL_LIST">
                <description>
                    <p>The Spirit-Warrior Spirituality grants you additional spells known when you gain certain shaman levels. The following spells are added to your spell list, but don’t count against your number of spells known.</p>
                    <h5 class="caption">SPIRIT-WARRIOR SPELLS</h5>
                    <table>
                        <thead>
                            <tr><td>Slot Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                        </thead>
                        <tr><td>1st</td><td><em>compelled duel, wrathful smite</em></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>2nd</td><td><em>branding smite, magic weapon</em></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>blinding smite, spirit guardians</em></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>4th</td><td><em>guardian of faith, staggering smite</em></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>banishing smite, steel wind strike</em></td></tr>
                    </table>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMPELLED_DUEL" spellcasting="Shaman" known="true" level="1" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WRATHFUL_SMITE" spellcasting="Shaman" known="true" level="1" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BRANDING_SMITE" spellcasting="Shaman" known="true" level="3" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGIC_WEAPON" spellcasting="Shaman" known="true" level="3" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLINDING_SMITE" spellcasting="Shaman" known="true" level="5" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPIRIT_GUARDIANS" spellcasting="Shaman" known="true" level="5" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GUARDIAN_OF_FAITH" spellcasting="Shaman" known="true" level="7" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_STAGGERING_SMITE" spellcasting="Shaman" known="true" level="7" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BANISHING_SMITE" spellcasting="Shaman" known="true" level="9" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_STEEL_WIND_STRIKE" spellcasting="Shaman" known="true" level="9" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Way of the Spirits" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_WARRIOR_WAY_OF_THE_SPIRITS">
                <description>
                    <p>Starting at 1st level, your connection to the spirits of the world prevent you from becoming lost. Thanks to the aid of local spirits, you have perfect recall of any path that you have traveled and cannot become lost.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>You have perfect recall of any path that you have traveled and cannot become lost, even by magical means.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Guardian’s Proficiencies" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_WARRIOR_GUARDIANS_PROFICIENCIES">
                <description>
                    <p>Additionally, at 1st level when you adopt this spirituality, you gain proficiency with medium armor and martial weapons. Shamans are particular about what weapons and armor they choose to use. Many frown upon the use of things forged by industry, claiming that these unnatural processes hamper their power.</p>
                    <div class="sidebar">
                        <h5 class="caption">Non-Metal Weapons &amp; Armor</h5>
                        <p>Despite their refusal to use weapons and armor forged from metal, Spirit-Warriors find other ways to arm themselves. Some use stone mauls carved with druidic runes, or battleaxes with a blade made of sharpened flint.</p>
                        <p class="indent">Talk to your Dungeon Master about creating weapons from alternate materials, like volcanic glass or the wood of a heartwood tree.</p>
                    </div>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_MEDIUM_ARMOR" />
                    <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_MARTIAL_WEAPONS" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Primal Weapon" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_WARRIOR_PRIMAL_WEAPON">
                <description>
                    <p>At 3rd level, you can construct a Primal Weapon inscribed with special totemic glyphs, granting you special abilities while wielding the weapon. Your Primal Weapon can be any weapon you have proficiency with, as long as it contains no metal. At the end of a long rest, choose one of the following totemic glyphs to inscribe into your primal weapon.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><strong><em>Glyph of Aggression.</em></strong> While wielding this weapon you can use a bonus action on your turn to move up to your movement speed towards an enemy creature that you can see. You must end your turn closer to the enemy creature.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><strong><em>Glyph of Binding.</em></strong> You have advantage on Strength (athletics) checks to grapple creatures, and advantage on attack rolls against creatures currently grappled by you.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><strong><em>Glyph of Draining.</em></strong> When you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack, you gain temporary hit points equal to your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>At the end of a long rest, choose one of the following totemic glyphs to inscribe into your Primal Weapon: Glyph of Aggression, Glyph of Binding, or Glyph of Draining.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Eyes of the Spirit World" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_WARRIOR_EYES_OF_THE_SPIRIT_WORLD">
                <description>
                    <p>Starting at 6th level, your bond with the spiritual world grants you enhanced sight. You have advantage on saving throws and skill checks to see through illusions. This sight also allows you to see 60 ft. into the Ethereal Plane when you are on the Material Plane, and vice versa.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>You have advantage on saving throws and skill checks to see through illusions. This sight also allows you to see 60 ft. into the Ethereal Plane when you are on the Material Plane, and vice versa.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="One Foot in the Grave" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_WARRIOR_ONE_FOOT_IN_THE_GRAVE">
                <description>
                    <p>When you draw close to death your connection to the spirits strengthens as your own life force wanes. At 10th level, when have 10 hit points or fewer (this does not include temporary hit points), you gain resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage from non-magical weapons. You have advantage on melee attack rolls, and your melee weapon attacks deal an extra 2d6 of their damage type on hit.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>At 10th level, when have 10 hit points or fewer (this does not include temporary hit points), you gain resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage from non-magical weapons. You have advantage on melee attack rolls, and your melee weapon attacks deal an extra 2d6 of their damage type on hit.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Possessed Warrior" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_WARRIOR_POSSESSED_WARRIOR">
                <description>
                    <p>At 14th level you can allow the spirits of the natural world to take control of your body. As a bonus action on your turn, you enter a possessed state that lasts for one minute, or until you are reduced to 0 hit points. While in this state your movement speed is doubled, and your melee weapon attacks deal an additional 2d6 necrotic damage on hit.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Additionally, your body becomes semi-corporeal, allowing you to move through other creatures and objects as if they were difficult terrain. If you end your turn inside an object, you are shunted to the nearest open space and take 1d6 force damage for every 5 ft. you are forced to move.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Once you use this ability you must complete a long rest until you can use it again.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
                    <description>You enter a possessed state that lasts for one minute, or until you are reduced to 0 hit points. While in this state your movement speed is doubled, and your melee weapon attacks deal an additional 2d6 necrotic damage on hit. Additionally, your body becomes semi-corporeal, allowing you to move through other creatures and objects as if they were difficult terrain. If you end your turn inside an object, you are shunted to the nearest open space and take 1d6 force damage for every 5 ft. you are forced to move.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>


        <element name="Witch-Doctor" type="Archetype" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_SHAMAN_WITCH_DOCTOR">
            <supports>Shaman Spirituality</supports>
            <description>
                <p>When all other options for help have been exhausted, nobles and peasants alike will turn to the medicine men of old, the Witch-Doctors. They are practitioners of ancient healing ceremonies and traditional herbal remedies.</p>
                <p class="indent">As a Witch-Doctor, your connection to the life-energy that flows through all things allows you to manipulate that energy to mend the spiritual and physical ailments of those around you. You channel the primal magic of creation to enhance your allies, and heal those marred by the foul touch of evil.</p>
                <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WITCH_DOCTOR_EXPANDED_SPELL_LIST" />
                <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WITCH_DOCTOR_ANCIENT_MEDICINE" />
                <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WITCH_DOCTOR_VIBRANT_LIFE_FORCE" />
                <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WITCH_DOCTOR_PRIMAL_BLESSING" />
                <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WITCH_DOCTOR_POTENT_LIFE_FORCE" />
                <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WITCH_DOCTOR_IMPROVED_PRIMAL_BLESSING" />
                <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WITCH_DOCTOR_CONDUIT_OF_CREATION" />
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WITCH_DOCTOR_EXPANDED_SPELL_LIST" level="1" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WITCH_DOCTOR_ANCIENT_MEDICINE" level="1" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WITCH_DOCTOR_VIBRANT_LIFE_FORCE" level="1" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WITCH_DOCTOR_PRIMAL_BLESSING" level="3" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WITCH_DOCTOR_POTENT_LIFE_FORCE" level="6" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WITCH_DOCTOR_IMPROVED_PRIMAL_BLESSING" level="10" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WITCH_DOCTOR_CONDUIT_OF_CREATION" level="14" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Expanded Spell List" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WITCH_DOCTOR_EXPANDED_SPELL_LIST">
                <description>
                    <p>The Witch-Doctor Spirituality grants you additional spells known when you gain certain shaman levels. The following spells are added to your spell list, but don’t count against your number of spells known.</p>
                    <h5 class="caption">WITCH-DOCTOR SPELLS</h5>
                    <table>
                        <thead>
                            <tr><td>Slot Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                        </thead>
                        <tr><td>1st</td><td><em>bless, cure wounds</em></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>2nd</td><td><em>enhance ability, lesser restoration</em></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>beacon of hope, revivify</em></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>4th</td><td><em>aura of life, death ward</em></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>creation, greater restoration</em></td></tr>
                    </table>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLESS" spellcasting="Shaman" known="true" level="1" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CURE_WOUNDS" spellcasting="Shaman" known="true" level="1" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENHANCE_ABILITY" spellcasting="Shaman" known="true" level="3" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LESSER_RESTORATION" spellcasting="Shaman" known="true" level="3" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BEACON_OF_HOPE" spellcasting="Shaman" known="true" level="5" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_REVIVIFY" spellcasting="Shaman" known="true" level="5" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AURA_OF_LIFE" spellcasting="Shaman" known="true" level="7" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DEATH_WARD" spellcasting="Shaman" known="true" level="7" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CREATION" spellcasting="Shaman" known="true" level="9" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GREATER_RESTORATION" spellcasting="Shaman" known="true" level="9" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Ancient Medicine" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WITCH_DOCTOR_ANCIENT_MEDICINE">
                <description>
                    <p>Starting at 1st level, you gain proficiency with the Herbalism Kit if you are not already, and you may add double your proficiency bonus to any ability check you make with it.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Additionally, whenever you use your action to restore hit points or stabilize a friendly creature, you are under the effects of the Dodge action until the start of your next turn.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>You may add double your proficiency bonus to any ability check you make with your Herbalism Kit. Additionally, whenever you use your action to restore hit points or stabilize a friendly creature, you are under the effects of the Dodge action until the start of your next turn.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_HERBALISM_KIT" />
                    <stat name="herbalism kit:proficiency" bonus="double" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Vibrant Life Force" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WITCH_DOCTOR_VIBRANT_LIFE_FORCE">
                <description>
                    <p>At 1st level when you adopt this spirituality, you gain insight in how to manipulate the life energy that flows through all creatures. As an action, you can touch one creature, enhancing their life energy. They have advantage their next ability check or saving throw.</p>
                    <p class="indent">You may use this ability a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier. You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet action="Action" usage="{{wisdom:modifier}}/Long Rest">
                    <description>You can touch one creature. They have advantage their next ability check or saving throw.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Primal Blessing" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WITCH_DOCTOR_PRIMAL_BLESSING">
                <description>
                    <p>At 3rd level, your ability to enhance your allies increases. At the end of a long rest you may bless a friendly creature with the benefits of one of your Totems that you have prepared for the day. Upon blessing a friendly creature with this power, you lose any abilities gained from the Totem.</p>
                    <p class="indent">You may distribute a number of your Totems equal to half of the number you have (rounded up). A friendly creature may only be under the effects of one of your Totems at a time.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>At the end of a long rest you may bless a friendly creature with the benefits of one of your Totems that you have prepared for the day. Upon blessing a friendly creature with this power, you lose any abilities gained from the Totem. You may distribute a number of your Totems equal to half of the number you have (rounded up). A friendly creature may only be under the effects of one of your Totems at a time.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Potent Life Force" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WITCH_DOCTOR_POTENT_LIFE_FORCE">
                <description>
                    <p>Starting at 6th level, your knowledge of your own body and soul grants you abilities beyond that of a normal mortal. Any time you gain hit points you gain additional hit points equal to your Wisdom modifier (this does not include temporary hit points).</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>Any time you gain hit points you gain and additional {{wisdom:modifier}} hit points (this does not include temporary hit points).</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Improved Primal Blessing" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WITCH_DOCTOR_IMPROVED_PRIMAL_BLESSING">
                <description>
                    <p>At 10th level, your spirit is enhanced when you grant blessings to your allies. For each Totem granted to an allied creature through your Primal Blessing feature you gain a +1 bonus to each of your saving throws.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>For each Totem granted to an allied creature through your Primal Blessing feature you gain a +1 bonus to each of your saving throws.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Conduit of Creation" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WITCH_DOCTOR_CONDUIT_OF_CREATION">
                <description>
                    <p>At 14th level, the line between your own life energy and that of the lives around you has blurred. You can choose to fall unconscious and distribute your life force among creatures within 60 ft. As an action, you distribute all of your remaining hit points among allied creatures, and if you have any spell slots remaining, you can use them to restore an allied creature’s spell slot of that level or lower.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Upon using this action you immediately fall unconscious, but stabilized. You do not need to make death saving throws. Once you use this feature, you cannot use it again until you complete a long rest.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
                    <description>You distribute all of your remaining hit points among allied creatures, and if you have any spell slots remaining, you can use them to restore an allied creature’s spell slot of that level or lower. Upon using this action you immediately fall unconscious, but stabilized. You do not need to make death saving throws.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>


    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ANIMALHANDLING">
        <supports>LL Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ARCANA">
        <supports>LL Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT">
        <supports>LL Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_MEDICINE">
        <supports>LL Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_NATURE">
        <supports>LL Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERFORMANCE">
        <supports>LL Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_RELIGION">
        <supports>LL Shaman</supports>
    </append>

    <!-- Shaman Totems -->
    <element name="Totem of the Avalanche" type="Class Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_TOTEM_TOTEM_OF_THE_AVALANCHE">
        <supports>LL Shaman Totem</supports>
        <requirements>[level:shaman:5], ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_SHAMAN_SPIRIT_WARRIOR</requirements>
        <prerequisite>5th level, Spirit-Warrior Spirituality</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 5th level, Spirit-Warrior Spirituality</p>
            <p>You may cast the ’enlarge’ version of the enlarge/reduce spell on yourself, without using a spell slot, a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier. You regain all uses when you finish a long rest.</p>
            <div class="reference">
                <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENLARGE_REDUCE" />
            </div>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="{{wisdom:modifier}}/Long Rest">
            <description>You may cast the ’enlarge’ version of the enlarge/reduce spell on yourself, without using a spell slot.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENLARGE_REDUCE" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Totem of the Beast" type="Class Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_TOTEM_TOTEM_OF_THE_BEAST">
        <supports>LL Shaman Totem</supports>
        <requirements></requirements>
        <prerequisite></prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p>You gain proficiency in the Perception skill if you do not already have it, and you have advantage on perception checks that rely on sight or smell.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You have advantage on perception checks that rely on sight or smell.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Totem of Bloodlust" type="Class Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_TOTEM_TOTEM_OF_BLOODLUST">
        <supports>LL Shaman Totem</supports>
        <requirements>[level:shaman:9], ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_SHAMAN_CURSE_BINDER</requirements>
        <prerequisite>9th level, Curse-Binder Spirituality</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 9th level, Curse-Binder Spirituality</p>
            <p>You have advantage on attack rolls against enemy creatures that are not at their maximum hit points.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You have advantage on attack rolls against enemy creatures that are not at their maximum hit points.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Totem of the Cave" type="Class Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_TOTEM_TOTEM_OF_THE_CAVE">
        <supports>LL Shaman Totem</supports>
        <requirements>[level:shaman:5]</requirements>
        <prerequisite>5th level</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 5th level</p>
            <p>As long as part of your body is touching the ground, you have tremorsense with a radius 30 ft. At 9th level the radius of your tremorsense increases to 60 ft.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>As long as part of your body is touching the ground, you have tremorsense with a radius 30 ft. At 9th level the radius of your tremorsense increases to 60 ft.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Totem of Darkness" type="Class Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_TOTEM_TOTEM_OF_DARKNESS">
        <supports>LL Shaman Totem</supports>
        <requirements>[level:shaman:9]</requirements>
        <prerequisite>9th level</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 9th level</p>
            <p>You gain blindsight with a radius of 30 ft. At 15th level the radius increases to 60 ft.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You have blindsight with a radius of 30 ft.</description>
            <description level="15">You have blindsight with a radius of 60 ft.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Totem of the Dawn" type="Class Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_TOTEM_TOTEM_OF_THE_DAWN">
        <supports>LL Shaman Totem</supports>
        <requirements>[level:shaman:7], ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_SHAMAN_WITCH_DOCTOR</requirements>
        <prerequisite>7th level, Witch-Doctor Spirituality</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 7th level, Witch-Doctor Spirituality</p>
            <p>You have advantage on all Charisma, Intelligence, and Wisdom saving throws against magic.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You have advantage on all Charisma, Intelligence, and Wisdom saving throws against magic.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Totem of the Earthquake" type="Class Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_TOTEM_TOTEM_OF_THE_EARTHQUAKE">
        <supports>LL Shaman Totem</supports>
        <requirements>[level:shaman:6], ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_SHAMAN_SPIRIT_WARRIOR</requirements>
        <prerequisite>6th level, Spirit-Warrior Spirituality</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 6th level, Spirit-Warrior Spirituality</p>
            <p>When you hit an enemy creature with a melee attack you deal an additional 1d4 of the weapons damage type on hit. This additional damage increases to 1d6 at 11th level, and 1d8 at 16th level.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you hit an enemy creature with a melee attack you deal an additional 1d{{totem-of-the-earthquake:damage-die}} of the weapons damage type on hit.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="totem-of-the-earthquake:damage-die" value="4" bonus="base" level="6" />
            <stat name="totem-of-the-earthquake:damage-die" value="6" bonus="base" level="11" />
            <stat name="totem-of-the-earthquake:damage-die" value="8" bonus="base" level="16" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Totem of the Eclipse" type="Class Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_TOTEM_TOTEM_OF_THE_ECLIPSE">
        <supports>LL Shaman Totem</supports>
        <requirements>[level:shaman:9], ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_SHAMAN_CURSE_BINDER</requirements>
        <prerequisite>9th level, Curse-Binder Spirituality</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 9th level, Curse-Binder Spirituality</p>
            <p>You have advantage on saving throws to resist spells and other magical effects. Additionally, at 16th level you gain resistance to damage from spells.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You have advantage on saving throws to resist spells and other magical effects.</description>
            <description level="16">You have advantage on saving throws to resist spells and other magical effects. You have resistance to damage from spells.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Totem of the Forest" type="Class Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_TOTEM_TOTEM_OF_THE_FOREST">
        <supports>LL Shaman Totem</supports>
        <requirements></requirements>
        <prerequisite></prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p>You gain proficiency in the stealth skill if you do not already have it, and you have advantage on stealth checks made to hide in natural environments.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You have advantage on stealth checks made to hide in natural environments.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_STEALTH" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Totem of the Hunt" type="Class Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_TOTEM_TOTEM_OF_THE_HUNT">
        <supports>LL Shaman Totem</supports>
        <requirements>[level:shaman:7]</requirements>
        <prerequisite>7th level</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 7th level</p>
            <p>You have advantage on melee attack rolls against enemy creatures that are within 5 ft. of a friendly creature.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You have advantage on melee attack rolls against enemy creatures that are within 5 ft. of a friendly creature.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Totem of the Hurricane" type="Class Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_TOTEM_TOTEM_OF_THE_HURRICANE">
        <supports>LL Shaman Totem</supports>
        <requirements>[level:shaman:7]</requirements>
        <prerequisite>7th level</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 7th level</p>
            <p>You gain the Long-Limbed trait. When you make a melee attack on your turn, your reach increases by 5 ft.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you make a melee attack on your turn, your reach increases by 5 ft.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Totem of Light" type="Class Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_TOTEM_TOTEM_OF_LIGHT">
        <supports>LL Shaman Totem</supports>
        <requirements>[level:shaman:6], ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_SHAMAN_WITCH_DOCTOR</requirements>
        <prerequisite>6th level, Witch-Doctor Spirituality</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 6th level, Witch-Doctor Spirituality</p>
            <p>When you hit an enemy creature with a melee attack, you deal an additional 1d6 radiant damage. The additional radiant damage increases to 2d6 at 11th level, and 3d6 at 16th level.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you hit an enemy creature with a melee attack, you deal an additional {{totem-of-light:damage-dice}}d6 radiant damage.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="totem-of-light:damage-dice" value="1" level="6" />
            <stat name="totem-of-light:damage-dice" value="1" level="11" />
            <stat name="totem-of-light:damage-dice" value="1" level="16" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Totem of the Moon" type="Class Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_TOTEM_TOTEM_OF_THE_MOON">
        <supports>LL Shaman Totem</supports>
        <requirements>[level:shaman:16], ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_SHAMAN_WITCH_DOCTOR</requirements>
        <prerequisite>16th level, Witch-Doctor Spirituality</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 16th level, Witch-Doctor Spirituality</p>
            <p>You may add your Wisdom modifier to your armor class as long as you are conscious.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You add your Wisdom modifier to your armor class as long as you are conscious.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="ac:misc" value="wisdom:modifier" /> 
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Totem of the Mountain" type="Class Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_TOTEM_TOTEM_OF_THE_MOUNTAIN">
        <supports>LL Shaman Totem</supports>
        <requirements></requirements>
        <prerequisite></prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p>While not wearing armor or using a shield your armor class is equal to 13 + your Constitution modifier.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
			<stat name="ac:totem-of-the-mountain:base" value="13" />
			<stat name="ac:totem-of-the-mountain:constitution" value="constitution:modifier" />
			<stat name="ac:totem-of-the-mountain" value="ac:totem-of-the-mountain:base" />
			<stat name="ac:totem-of-the-mountain" value="ac:totem-of-the-mountain:constitution" />
			<stat name="ac:calculation" value="ac:totem-of-the-mountain" bonus="calculation" equipped="[armor:none],[shield:none]" alt="Totem of the Mountain (Shaman)" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Totem of the North Wind" type="Class Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_TOTEM_TOTEM_OF_THE_NORTH_WIND">
        <supports>LL Shaman Totem</supports>
        <requirements></requirements>
        <prerequisite></prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p>Your base movement speed is increased by 5 ft. This increases to 10 ft. at 5th level, 15 ft. at 11th level, and 20 ft. at 16th level.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="innate speed:misc" value="5" level="1" />
            <stat name="innate speed:misc" value="5" level="5" />
            <stat name="innate speed:misc" value="5" level="11" />
            <stat name="innate speed:misc" value="5" level="15" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Totem of the Oak" type="Class Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_TOTEM_TOTEM_OF_THE_OAK">
        <supports>LL Shaman Totem</supports>
        <requirements>ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_SHAMAN_WITCH_DOCTOR</requirements>
        <prerequisite>Witch-Doctor Spirituality</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Witch-Doctor Spirituality</p>
            <p>You have advantage on saving throws to resist the frightened and charmed conditions.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You have advantage on saving throws to resist the frightened and charmed conditions.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Totem of the Ooze" type="Class Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_TOTEM_TOTEM_OF_THE_OOZE">
        <supports>LL Shaman Totem</supports>
        <requirements>[level:shaman:7], ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_SHAMAN_CURSE_BINDER</requirements>
        <prerequisite>7th level, Curse-Binder Spirituality</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 7th level, Curse-Binder Spirituality</p>
            <p>You can move through a space as narrow as one inch wide without squeezing.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can move through a space as narrow as one inch wide without squeezing.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Totem of the Pond" type="Class Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_TOTEM_TOTEM_OF_THE_POND">
        <supports>LL Shaman Totem</supports>
        <requirements></requirements>
        <prerequisite></prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p>You can hold your breath for up to 1 hour, and you gain a viscous coating on your skin that gives you advantage on skill checks to escape the grappled condition.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can hold your breath for up to 1 hour, and you gain a viscous coating on your skin that gives you advantage on skill checks to escape the grappled condition.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Totem of the Rainstorm" type="Class Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_TOTEM_TOTEM_OF_THE_RAINSTORM">
        <supports>LL Shaman Totem</supports>
        <requirements></requirements>
        <prerequisite></prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p>You gain resistance to acid and poison damage, and have advantage on saving throws to resist being poisoned.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You have advantage on saving throws to resist being poisoned.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_ACID" />
            <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_POISON" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Totem of the River" type="Class Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_TOTEM_TOTEM_OF_THE_RIVER">
        <supports>LL Shaman Totem</supports>
        <requirements>[level:shaman:7]</requirements>
        <prerequisite>7th level</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 7th level</p>
            <p>You gain a swimming speed equal to your movement speed, and you can breathe both air and water.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can breathe both air and water.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="speed:swim" value="speed" bonus="base" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Totem of the Rockslide" type="Class Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_TOTEM_TOTEM_OF_THE_ROCKSLIDE">
        <supports>LL Shaman Totem</supports>
        <requirements></requirements>
        <prerequisite></prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p>Your unarmed attacks deal bludgeoning damage equal to 1d6 + your Strength modifier on hit. If you attack with two free hands, the damage is a d8 instead of a d6. At 6th level, your unarmed attacks count as magical for the sake of overcoming resistances.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Your unarmed attacks deal bludgeoning damage equal to 1d6 + {{strength:modifier}} on hit, or 1d8 + {{strenghth:modifier}} if you use two hands.</description>
            <description level="6">Your unarmed attacks deal bludgeoning damage equal to 1d6 + {{strength:modifier}} on hit, or 1d8 + {{strenghth:modifier}} if you use two hands. Your unarmed attacks count as magical for the sake of overcoming resistances.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Totem of the Sapling" type="Class Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_TOTEM_TOTEM_OF_THE_SAPLING">
        <supports>LL Shaman Totem</supports>
        <requirements>[level:shaman:9], ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_SHAMAN_WITCH_DOCTOR</requirements>
        <prerequisite>9th level, Witch-Doctor Spirituality</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 9th level, Witch-Doctor Spirituality</p>
            <p>As a bonus action on your turn you grant yourself temporary hit points equal to your Wisdom modifier + your proficiency bonus.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Bonus Action">
            <description>You grant yourself {{totem-of-the-sapling:temp-hp}} temporary hit points.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="totem-of-the-sapling:temp-hp" value="wisdom:modifier" />
            <stat name="totem-of-the-sapling:temp-hp" value="proficiency" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Totem of the Skies" type="Class Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_TOTEM_TOTEM_OF_THE_SKIES">
        <supports>LL Shaman Totem</supports>
        <requirements>[level:shaman:16], ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_SHAMAN_SPIRIT_WARRIOR</requirements>
        <prerequisite>16th level, Spirit-Warrior Spirituality</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 16th level, Spirit-Warrior Spirituality</p>
            <p>You gain a flying speed equal to your movement speed, and as a reaction you can reduce any falling damage you take by an amount equal to your shaman level.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Reaction">
            <description>You can reduce any falling damage you take by [level:shaman].</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="speed:fly" value="speed" bonus="base" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Totem of the Stars" type="Class Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_TOTEM_TOTEM_OF_THE_STARS">
        <supports>LL Shaman Totem</supports>
        <requirements>[level:shaman:5]</requirements>
        <prerequisite>5th level</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 5th level</p>
            <p>When you roll a 1 on an ability check, attack roll, or saving throw, you may re-roll the die, but you must use the new roll.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you roll a 1 on an ability check, attack roll, or saving throw, you may re-roll the die, but you must use the new roll.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Totem of the Storm" type="Class Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_TOTEM_TOTEM_OF_THE_STORM">
        <supports>LL Shaman Totem</supports>
        <requirements>[level:shaman:5], ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_SHAMAN_SPIRIT_WARRIOR</requirements>
        <prerequisite>5th level, Spirit-Warrior Spirituality</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 5th level, Spirit-Warrior Spirituality</p>
            <p>You can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the attack action on your turn.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the attack action on your turn.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
			<stat name="extra attack:count" value="2" level="5" bonus="extra attack" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Totem of the Sun" type="Class Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_TOTEM_TOTEM_OF_THE_SUN">
        <supports>LL Shaman Totem</supports>
        <requirements>[level:shaman:9]</requirements>
        <prerequisite>9th level</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 9th level</p>
            <p>When you fail a saving throw, you may choose to succeed instead. Once you use this ability you must complete a long rest before you can use it again. Starting at 16th level, you can use this ability twice per long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="{{totem-of-the-sun:uses}}/Long Rest">
            <description>When you fail a saving throw, you may choose to succeed instead.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="totem-of-the-sun:uses" value="1" level="9" />
            <stat name="totem-of-the-sun:uses" value="1" level="16" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Totem of the Swamp" type="Class Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_TOTEM_TOTEM_OF_THE_SWAMP">
        <supports>LL Shaman Totem</supports>
        <requirements>[level:shaman:5], ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_SHAMAN_CURSE_BINDER</requirements>
        <prerequisite>5th level, Curse-Binder Spirituality</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 5th level, Curse-Binder Spirituality</p>
            <p>As an action, you force every creature within 15 ft. of you to make a Constitution saving throw. On a failure, they are poisoned until the end of your next turn. On a save, the creature is immune to this effect for 24 hours.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Action">
            <description>You force every creature within 15 ft. of you to make a Constitution saving throw. On a failure, they are poisoned until the end of your next turn. On a save, the creature is immune to this effect for 24 hours.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Totem of Twilight" type="Class Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_TOTEM_TOTEM_OF_TWILIGHT">
        <supports>LL Shaman Totem</supports>
        <requirements>ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_SHAMAN_CURSE_BINDER</requirements>
        <prerequisite>Curse-Binder Spirituality</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Curse-Binder Spirituality</p>
            <p>You gain Superior Darkvision. You can see in dim light within 120 ft. as if you were in bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_SUPERIORDARKVISION" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Totem of the Whirlwind" type="Class Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_TOTEM_TOTEM_OF_THE_WHIRLWIND">
        <supports>LL Shaman Totem</supports>
        <requirements></requirements>
        <prerequisite></prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p>When you score a critical hit on a weapon attack you may roll an additional damage die of the weapons damage type.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you score a critical hit on a weapon attack you may roll an additional damage die of the weapons damage type.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Totem of the Waves" type="Class Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_TOTEM_TOTEM_OF_THE_WAVES">
        <supports>LL Shaman Totem</supports>
        <requirements></requirements>
        <prerequisite></prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p>When an enemy creature hits you with a critical hit, you can use your reaction to change it into a regular hit. Once you use this ability, you must finish a short or long rest before you can use it again.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Reaction" usage="1/Short Rest">
            <description>When an enemy creature hits you with a critical hit, you can change it into a regular hit.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Totem of the Autumn Wind" type="Class Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_TOTEM_TOTEM_OF_THE_AUTUMN_WIND">
        <supports>LL Shaman Totem</supports>
        <requirements>ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_SHAMAN_WITCH_DOCTOR</requirements>
        <prerequisite>Witch-Doctor Spirituality </prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Witch-Doctor Spirituality </p>
            <p>When you deal damage to a creature, you can force them to make a Constitution saving throw. On a failure, the creature cannot regain hit points until the beginning of your next turn.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you deal damage to a creature, you can force them to make a Constitution saving throw. On a failure, the creature cannot regain hit points until the beginning of your next turn.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Totem of the Bloom" type="Class Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_TOTEM_TOTEM_OF_THE_BLOOM">
        <supports>LL Shaman Totem</supports>
        <requirements>[level:shaman:5]</requirements>
        <prerequisite>5th level </prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 5th level </p>
            <p>You can cast the <em>plant growth</em> spell once per day, without expending a spell slot. If you do not cast the immediate version of this spell, the 8 hour version of the spell takes effect on the land around you while you long rest.</p>
            <div class="reference">
                <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_PLANT_GROWTH" />
            </div>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can cast the plant growth spell once per day, without expending a spell slot. If you do not cast the immediate version of this spell, the 8 hour version of the spell takes effect on the land around you while you long rest.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PLANT_GROWTH" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Totem of the Grave" type="Class Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_TOTEM_TOTEM_OF_THE_GRAVE">
        <supports>LL Shaman Totem</supports>
        <requirements>[level:shaman:5],ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_SHAMAN_CURSE_BINDER</requirements>
        <prerequisite>5th level, Curse-Binder Spirituality </prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 5th level, Curse-Binder Spirituality </p>
            <p>You can cast <em>animate dead</em> once using a shaman spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            <div class="reference">
                <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANIMATE_DEAD" />
            </div>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>You can cast animate dead once using a shaman spell slot.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANIMATE_DEAD" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Totem of the Harvest" type="Class Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_TOTEM_TOTEM_OF_THE_HARVEST">
        <supports>LL Shaman Totem</supports>
        <requirements></requirements>
        <prerequisite></prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p>You can cast the goodberry spell without expending a spell slot a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier. You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</p>
            <div class="reference">
                <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_GOODBERRY" />
            </div>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="{{wisdom:modifier}}/Long Rest">
            <description>You can cast the goodberry spell without expending a spell slot.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GOODBERRY" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Totem of the Skies" type="Class Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_TOTEM_TOTEM_OF_THE_SKIES">
        <supports>LL Shaman Totem</supports>
        <requirements>[level:shaman:16],ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_ARCHETYPE_SHAMAN_SPIRIT_WARRIOR</requirements>
        <prerequisite>16th level, Spirit-Warrior Spirituality </prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 16th level, Spirit-Warrior Spirituality </p>
            <p>You gain a flying speed equal to your movement speed, and as a reaction you can reduce any falling damage you take by an amount equal to your shaman level.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Reaction">
            <description>You can reduce any falling damage you take by {{level:shaman}}.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="speed:fly" value="speed" bonus="base" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Totem of the Summer Court" type="Class Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_TOTEM_TOTEM_OF_THE_SUMMER_COURT">
        <supports>LL Shaman Totem</supports>
        <requirements>[level:shaman:7]</requirements>
        <prerequisite>7th level</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 7th level </p>
            <p>You can cast <em>conjure woodland beings</em> once using a shaman spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            <div class="reference">
                <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONJURE_WOODLAND_BEINGS" />
            </div>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>You can cast conjure woodland beings once using a shaman spell slot.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONJURE_WOODLAND_BEINGS" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Totem of the Trailblazer" type="Class Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_TOTEM_TOTEM_OF_THE_TRAILBLAZER">
        <supports>LL Shaman Totem</supports>
        <requirements></requirements>
        <prerequisite></prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p>You call out to the spirits of nature to aid you. If there are any tracks on the ground within range, you know where they are, and you make Wisdom (Survival) checks to follow these tracks with advantage for 1 hour.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>If there are any tracks on the ground within range, you know where they are, and you make Survival checks to follow these tracks with advantage for 1 hour.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Totem of the Vine" type="Class Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_TOTEM_TOTEM_OF_THE_VINE">
        <supports>LL Shaman Totem</supports>
        <requirements>[level:shaman:5]</requirements>
        <prerequisite>5th level</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 5th level </p>
            <p>You can cast <em>ensnaring strike</em> at will as a 1st-level spell, without expending a spell slot or material components.</p>
            <div class="reference">
                <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENSNARING_STRIKE" />
            </div>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can cast ensnaring strike at will as a 1st-level spell, without expending a spell slot or material components.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENSNARING_STRIKE" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Totem of the Wilds" type="Class Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_TOTEM_TOTEM_OF_THE_WILDS">
        <supports>LL Shaman Totem</supports>
        <requirements></requirements>
        <prerequisite></prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p>You can cast the <em>speak with animals</em> spell at will. Starting at 5th level, you can cast the <em>speak with plants</em> spell at will.</p>
            <div class="reference">
                <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENSNARING_STRIKE" />
                <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_PLANTS" />
            </div>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can cast the speak with animals spell at will.</description>
            <description level="5">You can cast the speak with animals and speak with plants spells at will.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_ANIMALS" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_PLANTS" level="5" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Totem of the Winter Court" type="Class Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_TOTEM_TOTEM_OF_THE_WINTER_COURT">
        <supports>LL Shaman Totem</supports>
        <requirements>[level:shaman:11]</requirements>
        <prerequisite>11th level </prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 11th level </p>
            <p>You can cast the <em>conjure fey</em> spell at it’s lowest level without expending a spell slot. You must complete a long rest before you can use this ability again.</p>
            <div class="reference">
                <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONJURE_FEY" />
            </div>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>You can cast the conjure fey spell at it’s lowest level without expending a spell slot.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONJURE_FEY" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Totem of the Woodlands" type="Class Feature" source="The Shaman Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_THE_SHAMAN_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAMAN_TOTEM_TOTEM_OF_THE_WOODLANDS">
        <supports>LL Shaman Totem</supports>
        <requirements>[level:shaman:5]</requirements>
        <prerequisite>5th level </prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 5th level </p>
            <p>You can cast <em>conjure animals</em> once using a shaman spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            <div class="reference">
                <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONJURE_ANIMALS" />
            </div>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>You can cast conjure animals once using a shaman spell slot.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONJURE_ANIMALS" />
        </rules>
    </element>

  <!-- Shaman Spell List -->
    <!-- Cantrips (0 Level) -->
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLADE_WARD">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CHILL_TOUCH">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DRUIDCRAFT">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GUIDANCE">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_MAGIC_STONE">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_PRIMAL_SAVAGERY">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RESISTANCE">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHILLELAGH">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPARE_THE_DYING">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_THORN_WHIP">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_TOLL_THE_DEAD">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_VICIOUS_MOCKERY">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>

    <!-- 1st Level -->
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ABSORB_ELEMENTS">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ARMOR_OF_AGATHYS">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_CEREMONY">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMMAND">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_EARTH_TREMOR">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENSNARING_STRIKE">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENTANGLE">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_EXPEDITIOUS_RETREAT">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FALSE_LIFE">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIND_FAMILIAR">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HEROISM">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LONGSTRIDER">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SANCTUARY">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHIELD_OF_FAITH">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>

    <!-- 2nd Level -->
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AID">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ALTER_SELF">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BARKSKIN">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONTINUAL_FLAME">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_DUST_DEVIL">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_EARTHBIND">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENHANCE_ABILITY">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FLAME_BLADE">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GENTLE_REPOSE">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_MAXIMILIANS_EARTHEN_GRASP">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PASS_WITHOUT_TRACE">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PROTECTION_FROM_POISON">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_WARDING_WIND">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>

    <!-- 3rd Level -->
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DAYLIGHT">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISPEL_MAGIC">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ERUPTING_EARTH">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FEIGN_DEATH">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HASTE">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LEOMUNDS_TINY_HUT">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_LIFE_TRANSFERENCE">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PLANT_GROWTH">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PROTECTION_FROM_ENERGY">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_REMOVE_CURSE">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SLEET_STORM">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_THUNDER_STEP">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_TIDAL_WAVE">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>

    <!-- 4th Level -->
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DIVINATION">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ELEMENTAL_BANE">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIRE_SHIELD">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FREEDOM_OF_MOVEMENT">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_GUARDIAN_OF_NATURE">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ICE_STORM">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_STONESKIN">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_STORM_SPHERE">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>

    <!-- 5th Level -->
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AWAKEN">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_COMMUNE_WITH_NATURE">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DREAM">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_MAELSTROM">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_REINCARNATE">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_SKILL_EMPOWERMENT">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_WRATH_OF_NATURE">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>

    <!-- 6th Level -->
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_BONES_OF_THE_EARTH">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CHAIN_LIGHTNING">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_INVESTITURE_OF_FLAME">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_INVESTITURE_OF_ICE">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_INVESTITURE_OF_STONE">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_INVESTITURE_OF_WIND">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_PRIMORDIAL_WARD">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SUNBEAM">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WIND_WALL">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>

    <!-- 7th Level -->
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DIVINE_WORD">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ETHEREALNESS">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIRE_STORM">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_REGENERATE">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RESURRECTION">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_REVERSE_GRAVITY">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SEQUESTER">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_WHIRLWIND">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>

    <!-- 8th Level -->
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ABI-DALZIMS_HORRID_WILTING">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANTIPATHY_SYMPATHY">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONTROL_WEATHER">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_EARTHQUAKE">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INCENDIARY_CLOUD">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SUNBURST">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TSUNAMI">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>

    <!-- 9th Level -->
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ASTRAL_PROJECTION">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FORESIGHT">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_INVULNERABILITY">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_METEOR_SWARM">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_STORM_OF_VENGEANCE">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TRUE_RESURRECTION">
        <supports>Shaman</supports>
    </append>


</elements>