<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Lord (2018)</name>
        <author url="https://www.gmbinder.com/share/-LRwOD9O9Y147D72snxv">GM Binder</author>
        <update version="0.0.45">
            <file name="class-lord.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/classes/class-lord.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Lord" type="Class" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_LORD">
        <description>
            <p>All voices fall silent as the woman approaches the execution grounds. She walks with elegance and a dignity scarcely seen in dark times such as these. Every move she makes, every breath she takes, is calculated. She cannot move too fast, lest one would think she is eager to get it over with. She cannot move too slowly, else her people might think her nervous or weak.</p>
            <p class="indent">As she stands before the bound prisoner, she draws her blade. Its decorated hilt and expertly sharpened blade stand in stark contrast to the men it was made to kill, and even more so to the prisoner now cowering before the chopping block.</p>
            <p class="indent">The lord addresses the man, hears his last words and considers them. The prisoner speaks of desperation and regret, but neither is enough to change his fate. The lord raises her voice. She speaks of her duties and her name, and the judgment she came to carry out today. She swings. A head rolls to the ground. The sword is passed to a guard. No blood shall sully the lord’s scabbard.</p>
            <p class="indent">Amongst heroes and adventurers stands the lord. They serve as a pillar to their people and as an instrument of justice. Whether they have been born into their duties or earned them through dedication and service, the lord is an individual like no other. Few exert as much power by merely being present on the battlefield. Like a flag, the lord inspires their companions to fight to victory or until their bitter end. Unlike a flag however, the lord is armed and a force to be reckoned with.</p>
            <h4>BORN TO LEAD</h4>
            <p>From the moment they can walk, a lord is schooled in history, religion and the arts. Their training in military tactics and combat starts once they can hold up a sword without falling over. And once it begins, it never stops. Many lords consider themselves scholars; some are more akin to politicians, skilled with words and smiles; and others are warriors, born to lead armies, and not to talk pleasantries. No two lords think or act alike.</p>
            <p class="indent">Their talents make themselves known at a young age. They find approaches to things others didn’t, or didn’t want to see. In a social situation, they know exactly which buttons to push to get what they want.</p>
            <p class="indent">In combat the lord is a presence to fear. While there are certainly more powerful fighters on the battlefield, lords are distinguished through the pressure they exert. Nothing is more intimidating than the aura of a true leader. Those that fight alongside a lord make an effort to live up to their expectations, while those that fight against one have to ask themselves what might happen to them should they lose and become subjected to their judgment.</p>
            <h4>CREATING A LORD</h4>
            <p>As you create your lord character, consider where you hail from and why you are adventuring. Are you on a quest to make a name for yourself? Are you out in the wilds to earn titles and land? Have they grown tired of walls and the warmth of home? What was it that led you away from your previous life? Did tragedy strike or might it be a tragedy that can yet be prevented? Do you have to prove yourself worthy? Are you one of many possible heirs to your father or mother?</p>
            <p class="indent">Did you serve in an army? Did you lose someone under your command? Are you a hero or do you serve only yourself? Do you fight for your people or do they fight for you? Maybe your father died and you don’t think you’re yet worthy to succeed him. Or maybe there was a rebellion and your birthright was taken away from you. Maybe the army didn’t see you fit to lead, and you desperately want to prove them wrong. Think about what makes a lord and what qualities your lord represents. </p>
            <h4>FAMILY HEIRLOOM</h4>
            <p>For a lord, equipment is there both to keep them alive, and to serve as an important status symbol. Passed down through generations from one head of the family to the next, the family heirloom reminds the lord of where they hail from and about the responsibilities that weight on their shoulders.</p>
            <p class="indent">These items aren’t crafted to be more effective or sturdier than their lesser versions, but to make the importance of the wearer obvious with but a single look. A pommel crafted out of exotic jewelery or armor, decorated with the ancient runes of a dwarven clan. It is not important what kind of item the heirloom is, but how expensive it was to produce it (especially when compared to those of competing rival families).</p>
            <p class="indent">Consider working with your dungeon master to create one or more heirlooms that your character will carry. These objects should tie you to the family or clan you hail from and be of significant importance to your character. Think about how your character feels about these heirlooms and what they would do if they were to lose them.</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d6</td><td>Heirloom</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>A circlet gifted to your family by an ancient dragon.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>A great cloak fashioned from the hides of even greater beasts.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>A sword forged by the finest dwarven smiths and decorated by the finest elven jeweler.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>An embroided leather pouch, carrying within a token for every ancestor that owned it before you.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>A shield decorated in your house’s colours and inscribed with your family motto.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>A chain whose links are crafted from the melted down heirlooms of families yours has brought to ruin.</td></tr>
            </table>
            <h4>HERALDRY</h4>
            <p>For those moving in the closed off circles of high society nothing is more important than to be known and recognized. The personal heraldry serves this purpose and tends to look mighty fashionable as an added bonus.</p>
            <p class="indent">Some lords prefer to keep but subtle reminders of their heraldry on a gauntlet or the inside of their cloak, while other lords prefer to have it draped over every chair in their estate and hanging from the highest towers in the realm. You might display your symbol on a flag, a banner, on every piece of equipment you have and that of your allies to boot!</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d6</td><td>Heraldry</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>A mighty tower on a green field, representing the watchful guard your family keeps over their lands.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>A flaming sword, reminding everyone of the warring ways of your ancestors.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>A sack of gold in a ring of gold, for those that are wealthy and want everyone to know it.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>A white feather, representing the way of peace and prosperity your family has chosen.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>A white lion on a black field, displaying both your nobility and ferocity.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>A stack of books, representing the wisdom your family seeks.</td></tr>
            </table>
            <h4>AMBITION</h4>
            <p>Few lords have a good reason to go out adventuring. It is a much more dangerous business than learning a mercantile trade. Some lords have lost their earthly possessions and are out to reclaim them, while others might already think of themselves as a mighty lord even though their income is only somewhere slightly above the poverty line. Beyond finding a treasure or two, why is your lord character out in the world slaying monsters? </p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d6</td><td>Ambition</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>Legend says one of your ancestors once slew a mighty dragon. Folks don’t believe it anymore, so you’re out to do it again.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>Your father was a fool and gambled away both your money and your estate. Now you are trying to regain it in the quickest way possible.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>Being rich is nice and all, but why be a noble when you could be a king?</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>You seek true love and to find it you must travel whilst concealing your wealth.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>Your sibling has fallen ill with an illness even the most expensive doctors and clerics cannot cure. You seek a fabled cure-all.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>Your idiot older sibling lost the family heirloom while on an expedition. You will reclaim it at all cost.</td></tr>
            </table>
            <h5>QUICK BUILD</h5>
            <p>You can make a lord character quickly by following these suggestions. First, Charisma and Constitution should be your highest ability scores, followed by Strength. Second, choose the noble background.</p>
            <h2>CLASS FEATURES</h2>
            <p>As a lord, you gain the following class features.</p>
            <h5>HIT POINTS</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Hit Dice:</strong> 1d10 per class level</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at 1st Level:</strong> 10 + your Constitution modifier</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at Higher Levels:</strong> 1d10 (or 6) + your Constitution modifier per class level after 1st</li>
            </ul>
            <h5>PROFICIENCIES</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Armor:</strong> All armor and shields</li>
                <li><strong>Weapons:</strong> All weapons</li>
                <li><strong>Tools:</strong> None</li>
            </ul>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Saving Throws:</strong> Charisma, Constitution</li>
                <li><strong>Skills:</strong> Choose two from Persuasion, Performance, History, Religion, Insight, Intimidation, and Deception</li>
            </ul>
            <h5>EQUIPMENT</h5>
            <p>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>(a) a martial weapon and a shield or (b) two martial weapons</li>
                <li>(a) five javelins or (b) any simple melee weapon</li>
                <li>(a) scale mail or (b) chain mail</li>
                <li>(a) a scholar’s pack or (b) a diplomat’s pack</li>
            </ul>
			<h5 class="caption">THE LORD</h5>
            <table class="class-features">
                <thead>
                    <tr>Level<th></th><th>Proficiency Bonus</th><th class="left">Features</th><th>Might</th></tr>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                    <tr><td>1st</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Expertise, Fighting Style</td><td>-</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>2nd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Aristocracy, Moment’s Rest</td><td>2</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Leadership Style</td><td>3</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>4th</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>4</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Extra Attack</td><td>5</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>6th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Worldly Might</td><td>6</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>7th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Leadership Style feature</td><td>7</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>8th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>8</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Right of Protection</td><td>9</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>10th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Towering Presence</td><td>10</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>11th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Manifest Destiny</td><td>11</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>12th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>12</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>13th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Right of Way</td><td>13</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>14th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Leadership Style feature</td><td>14</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>15th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Freedom of Thought</td><td>15</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>16th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>16</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>17th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Leadership Style feature</td><td>17</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>18th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Right to Life</td><td>18</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>19th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>19</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>20th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Grand Order</td><td>20</td></tr>
                </tbody>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_EXPERTISE" />
            <div element="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_FIGHTING_STYLE" />
            <div element="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_ARISTOCRACY" />
            <div element="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_MOMENTS_REST" />
            <div element="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_LEADERSHIP_STYLE" />
            <div element="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" />
            <div element="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_EXTRA_ATTACK" />
            <div element="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_WORLDLY_MIGHT" />
            <div element="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_RIGHT_OF_PROTECTION" />
            <div element="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_TOWERING_PRESENCE" />
            <div element="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_MANIFEST_DESTINY" />
            <div element="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_RIGHT_OF_WAY" />
            <div element="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_FREEDOM_OF_THOUGHT" />
            <div element="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_RIGHT_TO_LIFE" />
            <div element="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_GRAND_ORDER" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description>A born leader and part of the nobility, skilled in directing others on the field of combat.</description>
        </sheet>
        <setters>
            <set name="short">A born leader and part of the nobility, skilled in directing others on the field of combat.</set>
            <set name="hd">d10</set>
        </setters>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_MEDIUM_ARMOR" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_HEAVY_ARMOR" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_SHIELDS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_MARTIAL_WEAPONS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" />

            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CHARISMA" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CONSTITUTION" />

            <select name="Skills (Lord)" number="2" type="Proficiency" supports="Skill,Lord,!ID_INTERNAL_SUPPORT_EXPERTISE" />

            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_EXPERTISE" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_FIGHTING_STYLE" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_ARISTOCRACY" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_MOMENTS_REST" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_LEADERSHIP_STYLE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" level="4" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_EXTRA_ATTACK" level="5" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_WORLDLY_MIGHT" level="6" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_RIGHT_OF_PROTECTION" level="9" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_TOWERING_PRESENCE" level="10" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_MANIFEST_DESTINY" level="11" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_RIGHT_OF_WAY" level="13" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_FREEDOM_OF_THOUGHT" level="15" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_RIGHT_TO_LIFE" level="18" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_GRAND_ORDER" level="20" />
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Expertise" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_EXPERTISE">
        <description>
            <p>At 6th level, choose one skill from Persuasion, Intimidation, Performance and Deception and one additional skill of your choice. Your proficiency bonus is doubled for any ability check you make that uses either of the chosen proficiencies. If you choose a skill you are not already proficient in, you instead gain proficiency in that skill.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Expertise (Lord)" supports="Skill,Lord" />
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Expertise (Lord)" supports="Skill||Expertise" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <append id="ID_EXPERTISE_SKILL_PERSUASION">
            <supports>Lord</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_EXPERTISE_SKILL_INTIMIDATION">
            <supports>Lord</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_EXPERTISE_SKILL_PERFORMANCE">
            <supports>Lord</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_EXPERTISE_SKILL_DECEPTION">
            <supports>Lord</supports>
        </append>

    <element name="Fighting Style" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_FIGHTING_STYLE">
        <description>
            <p>At 2nd level, you adopt a particular style of fighting as your specialty. Choose one of the following options. You can’t take a Fighting Style option more than once, even if you later get to choose again.</p>
            <h5>DEFENSE</h5>
            <p>While you are wearing armor, you gain a +1 bonus to AC.</p>
            <h5>DUELING</h5>
            <p>When you are wielding a melee weapon in one hand and no other weapons, you gain a +2 bonus to damage rolls with that weapon.</p>
            <h5>PROTECTION</h5>
            <p>When a creature you can see attacks a target other than you that is within 5 feet of you, you can use your reaction to impose disadvantage on the attack roll. You must be wielding a shield.</p>
            <h5>GREAT WEAPON FIGHTING</h5>
            <p>When you roll a 1 or 2 on a damage die for an attack you make with a melee weapon that you are wielding with two hands, you can reroll the die and must use the new roll, even if the new roll is a 1 or a 2. The weapon must have the two-handed or versatile property for you to gain this benefit.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet />
        <rules>
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Fighting Style" supports="Fighting Style,Lord" level="1"/>
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Aristocracy" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_ARISTOCRACY">
        <description>
            <p>Beginning at 2nd level, your presence holds power and those that listen to your words find themselves outmaneuvering their opponents. This power is represented by might points, which allow you to influence the tides of combat.</p>
            <h5>MIGHT POINTS</h5>
            <p>You have 2 might points, and you gain more as you reach higher levels, as shown in the Might column of the Lord table. You can never have more might points than shown on the table for your level. You regain all spent might points when you finish a long rest.</p>
            <h5>ISSUING ORDERS</h5>
            <p>You instruct your companions in a list of orders that are available for you to issue, choosing from the list at the end of the class description. When you do so, choose a number of orders equal to your Charisma modifier + your proficiency bonus. You can issue the selected orders as a bonus action on your turn by spending its stated might point cost. All orders target one creature within 60 feet of you that can hear you.</p>
            <p class="indent">Unless the target creature is hostile, acting on them consumes the targets reaction. You can change your list of practiced orders when you finish a long rest. To do so, you and your allies must hold a strategy meeting that lasts at least 5 minutes.</p>
            <h5>SAVING THROWS</h5>
            <p>Some of your orders require your target to make a saving throw to resist the order’s effects. The saving throw DC is calculated as follows:</p>
            <p class="indent"><b>Order save DC = </b>8 + your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You have {{might-points}} Might Points. You regain all expended night points on a long rest. Your Order save DC is {{order save:dc}}. You can prepare {{orders:count}} orders.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="might-points" value="level:lord" />
            <stat name="order save:dc" value="8" />
            <stat name="order save:dc" value="charisma:modifier" />
            <stat name="order save:dc" value="proficiency" />
            <stat name="orders:count" value="charisma:modifier" />
            <stat name="orders:count" value="proficiency" />

            <select type="Class Feature" name="Orders" number="2" supports="Lord Order" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Orders" number="1" supports="Lord Order" requirements="[proficiency:3]" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Orders" number="1" supports="Lord Order" requirements="[proficiency:4]" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Orders" number="1" supports="Lord Order" requirements="[proficiency:5]" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Orders" number="1" supports="Lord Order" requirements="[proficiency:6]" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Orders" number="1" supports="Lord Order" requirements="[charisma:modifier:1]" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Orders" number="1" supports="Lord Order" requirements="[charisma:modifier:2]" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Orders" number="1" supports="Lord Order" requirements="[charisma:modifier:3]" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Orders" number="1" supports="Lord Order" requirements="[charisma:modifier:4]" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Orders" number="1" supports="Lord Order" requirements="[charisma:modifier:5]" />
            
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Moment’s Rest" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_MOMENTS_REST">
        <description>
            <p>Also at 2nd level, you know how to quickly recover your spirit, when given the chance. Once per day, when you finish a short rest, you can choose to regain a number of might points equal to half your lord level rounded up.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Day" action="End of a short rest">
            <description>You can regain {{level:lord:half:up}} might points.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="Leadership Style" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_LEADERSHIP_STYLE">
        <description>
            <p>Define what sort of presence you have on the battlefield and how it affects others. Think about the way you lead your friends and soldiers into battle. Choose from either Warlord or Tactician. The style you pick grants you features at 3rd level and again at 7th, 11th and 17th level.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select name="Leadership Style" type="Archetype" supports="Leadership Style" />
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Ability Score Improvement" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT">
        <description>
            <p>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Lord 4)" supports="Improvement Option,Lord,4" level="4" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Lord 8)" supports="Improvement Option,Lord,8" level="8" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Lord 12)" supports="Improvement Option,Lord,12" level="12" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Lord 16)" supports="Improvement Option,Lord,16" level="16" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Lord 19)" supports="Improvement Option,Lord,19" level="19" />     
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Extra Attack" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_EXTRA_ATTACK">
        <description>
            <p>Beginning at 5th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="extra attack:count" value="2" level="5" bonus="extra attack" />
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Worldly Might" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_WORLDLY_MIGHT">
        <description>
            <p>At 6th level, the way you carry yourself distinguishes you from the common rabble. Whenever you use a class feature that requires you to spend might points, you gain temporary hit points equal to your Charisma modifier per might point spent.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Whenever you use a class feature that requires you to spend might points, you gain {{charisma:modifier}} temporary hit points per might point spent.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="Right of Protection" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_RIGHT_OF_PROTECTION">
        <description>
            <p>At 9th level, you are the shield that prevents your companions from succumbing to the enemy. If an allied creature within your movement speed range is hit by an attack or spell that would otherwise leave it unconscious, you can spend your reaction to immediately move to within 5ft of the creature and take the damage instead. This damage to you can’t be reduced or prevented in any way.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you must finish a short or long rest before you can use it again.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Reaction" usage="1/Short Rest">
            <description>If an allied creature within your movement range is hit by an attack or spell that would otherwise leave it unconscious, you can immidiately move to within 5ft of said creature and take the damage instead. This damage to you can’t be reduced or prevented in any way.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="Towering Presence" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_TOWERING_PRESENCE">
        <description>
            <p>At 10th level, it is difficult to ignore your presence on the battlefield. Men and beast alike find themselves drawn to you and find it hard to fall back once they have engaged you in battle. Any hostile creature that starts its turn within 5ft of you has its movement speed halved until the end of its turn.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Any hostile creature that starts its turn within 5ft of you has its movement speed halved until the end of its turn.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="Manifest Destiny" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_MANIFEST_DESTINY">
        <description>
            <p>Beginning at 11th level, destiny dictates your path and no rules shall stop you. By expending your reaction and 1 might point outside of your turn, you can immediately issue one order of your choice or make a single weapon attack against a target within your reach. You must pay the cost of any order you issue as your normally would on your turn.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Reaction">
            <description>By expending 1 might point outside of your turn, you can immediately issue one order of your choice or make a single weapon attack against a target within your reach. You must pay the cost of any order you issue as your normally would on your turn.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="Right of Way" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_RIGHT_OF_WAY">
        <description>
            <p>By 13th level, your aura makes it difficult for opponents and terrain to stop you from going where you desire to go. You ignore difficult terrain.</p>
            <p class="indent">In addition, when you provoke a creature’s opportunity attack, you can spend 1 might point to gain a bonus to your AC equal to your Charisma modifier until the end of the turn.</p>
         </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you provoke a creature’s opportunity attack, you can spend 1 might point to gain a +{{charisma:modifier}} bonus to your AC until the end of the turn. You ignore difficult terrain.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="Freedom of Thought" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_FREEDOM_OF_THOUGHT">
        <description>
            <p>Beginning at 15th level, the might of your voice can help others fend off mind altering effects. You can use your reaction to give an allied creature within 15ft of you that can hear you advantage on a Wisdom saving throw.</p>
            <p class="indent">In addition, your lifelong training prevents your own mind from being swayed or otherwise affected. You gain proficiency in Wisdom Saving throws and your mental capacities no longer diminish with age.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Reaction">
            <description>You give an allied creature within 15ft of you that can hear you advantage on a Wisdom saving throw.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_WISDOM" />
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Right to Life" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_RIGHT_TO_LIFE">
        <description>
            <p>From 18th level onwards, you refuse to go down without a fight. While below a quarter of your maximum hit points rounded down, you can choose to gain resistance to all damage types until you are healed above the stated threshold.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>While below a quarter of your maximum hit points rounded down, you can choose to gain resistance to all damage types until you are healed above the stated threshold.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Grand Order" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_GRAND_ORDER">
        <description>
            <p>At 20th level, the power of your words defies nature. If you give the order, those that fight alongside you can surpass their limits. On your turn as a bonus action, you can choose a creature within 60 feet of you that is allied with you. That creature may pick any feature that would otherwise recharge on a short rest and of which they have depleted all of their uses. They regain one use of said feature.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you must finish a long rest before you can use it again.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest" action="Bonus Action">
            <description>You can choose a creature within 60 feet of you that is allied with you. That creature may pick any feature that would otherwise recharge on a short rest and of which they have depleted all of their uses. They regain one use of said feature.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="Warlord" type="Archetype" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_LORD_WARLORD">
        <supports>Leadership Style</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Some people fight because they must - A warlord fights because he really likes to do it. Warlords are the first to draw blood in battles and the last ones to remain standing. It is their fighting prowess that inspires their troops - someone who leads by example.</p>
            <p class="indent">And their example usually turns out to be quite the bloody ordeal.</p>
            <div element="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARLORD_ART_OF_WAR" />
            <div element="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARLORD_DREADFUL_CHARGE" />
            <div element="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARLORD_CULL_COWARDS" />
            <div element="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARLORD_WAR_CRY" />
            <div element="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARLORD_ONSLAUGHT" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARLORD_ART_OF_WAR" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARLORD_DREADFUL_CHARGE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARLORD_CULL_COWARDS" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARLORD_WAR_CRY" level="14" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARLORD_ONSLAUGHT" level="17" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Art of War" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARLORD_ART_OF_WAR">
            <description>
                <p>At 3rd level, you gain proficiency with one type of instrument or tool of your choice.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Proficiency" name="Art of War (Lord)" supports="Tool||Musical Instrument" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Dreadful Charge" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARLORD_DREADFUL_CHARGE">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 3rd level, you master the art of getting into the thick of things. At the start of your first turn of each combat, your movement speed is doubled and you do not provoke attacks of opportunity.</p>
                <p class="indent">At the start of your first turn, you can choose to duplicate this effect to a number of allied creatures of your choice within range of your aristocracy feature, expending 1 might point for each chosen creature.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>At the start of your first turn of each combat, your movement speed is doubled and you do not provoke attacks of opportunity. You can choose to duplicate this effect to a number of allied creatures of your choice within range of your aristocracy feature, expending 1 might point for each chosen creature.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Cull Cowards" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARLORD_CULL_COWARDS">
            <description>
                <p>At 7th level, whenever you make an attack of opportunity against a target, you can spend 1 might to make one additional weapon attack against the same target.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Opportunity Attack">
                <description>Whenever you make an attack of opportunity against a target, you can spend 1 might to make one additional weapon attack against the same target.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="War Cry" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARLORD_WAR_CRY">
            <description>
                <p>At 14th level, your voice is the fire that sets the battlefield ablaze again, and again.</p>
                <p class="indent">As a bonus action, you instruct your allies to fight as if they were standing in front of the gate of hell itself. Until the beginning of your next turn, all allied creatures within 30ft of you add your charisma modifier as bonus damage of the same type to their weapon attacks and they regain hit points equal to your lord level.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you must finish a long rest before you can use it again.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>Until the beginning of your next turn, all allied creatures within 30ft of you add {{charisma:modifier}} bonus damage of the same type to their weapon attacks and they regain {{level:lord}} hit points.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Onslaught" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARLORD_ONSLAUGHT">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 17th level, your attacks swing wide and hit hard. If you miss with an attack roll on your turn, you can reroll it against a different creature within your weapon’s reach.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can use this feature only once on each of your turns.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Turn">
                <description>If you miss with an attack roll on your turn, you can reroll it against a different creature within your weapon’s reach.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
    

    <element name="Tactician" type="Archetype" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_LORD_TACTICIAN">
        <supports>Leadership Style</supports>
        <description>
            <p>A tactician is the sort to consider every step he takes. They serve as a calm source of inspiration to their allies and as a presence to fear to their enemies. Every hit calculated, every distance measures, a true tactician leaves nothing to chance. They make sure their troupes make it through the battle and are ready for all future fights to come.</p>
            <div element="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_WARRIOR_POET" />
            <div element="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_RALLYING_POINT" />
            <div element="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_REASSURING_PRESENCE" />
            <div element="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_FORTRESS_DEFENSE" />
            <div element="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_COMMANDERS_VIEW" />
       </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_WARRIOR_POET" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_RALLYING_POINT" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_REASSURING_PRESENCE" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_FORTRESS_DEFENSE" level="14" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_FORTRESS_DEFENSE" level="17" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Warrior Poet" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_WARRIOR_POET">
            <description>
                <p>At 3rd level, you learn two languages of your choice.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Language" name="Language (Warrior Poet)" number="2" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Rallying Point" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_RALLYING_POINT">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 3rd level, it is your grand plan the combat should revolve around. The first 10 feet an allied creature moves towards you on its turn do not consume part of its movement.</p>
                <p class="indent">As a reaction, you can expend 1 might point to triple this amount until the end of the current turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Reaction">
                <description>The first 10 feet an allied creature moves towards you on its turn do not consume part of its movement. As a reaction, you can expend 1 might point to triple this amount until the end of the current turn.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Reassuring Presence" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_REASSURING_PRESENCE">
            <description>
                <p>At 7th level, whenever you issue an order to an allied creature, you can expend one additional might point to grant that creature temporary hit points equal to 1d6 + your Charisma modifier.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Whenever you issue an order to an allied creature, you can expend one additional might point to grant that creature 1d6 + {{charisma:modifier}} temporary hit points.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Fortress Defense" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_FORTRESS_DEFENSE">
            <description>
                <p>At 14th level, you do not require a castle or barricades to repel enemies. You are the fortress, and your allies are protected by the mighty walls formed by your presence.</p>
                <p class="indent">As a bonus action, you instruct your allies to form a protective perimeter and to switch to a more defensive fighting style. All allied creatures within 30ft of you add your charisma modifier to their armor class until the beginning of your next turn and they regain hit points equal your lord level.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you must finish a long rest before you can use it again.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>All allied creatures within 30ft of you add {{charisma:modifier}} to their armor class until the beginning of your next turn and they regain {{level:lord}} hit points.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Commander’s View" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_COMMANDERS_VIEW">
            <description>
                <p>At 17th level, nothing on the battlefield escapes your watchful eye. You gain truesight out to a range of 120 feet.</p>
                <p class="indent">In addition, you and any of your companions within 30 ft of you can’t be surprised, except when incapacitated by something other than nonmagical sleep.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You have truesight out to a range of 120 feet. You and any of your companions within 30 ft of you can’t be surprised, except when incapacitated by something other than nonmagical sleep.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_TRUESIGHT" />
            </rules>
        </element>


    <!-- Lord Orders -->
    <element name="Barrage!" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_ORDER_BARRAGE">
        <supports>Lord Order</supports>
        <requirements>[level:9]</requirements>
        <prerequisite>9th level</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 9th level</p>
            <p>The creature adds your Charisma modifier to its spell save DC until the end of your next turn.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="3 might points">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Silence!" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_ORDER_SILENCE">
        <supports>Lord Order</supports>
        <requirements></requirements>
        <prerequisite></prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p>The creature must make a Wisdom Saving throw. On a failed save, the creature cannot open its mouth until the end of your next turn.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1 might point">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Brace Yourself!" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_ORDER_BRACE_YOURSELF">
        <supports>Lord Order</supports>
        <requirements></requirements>
        <prerequisite></prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p>Attack rolls against the creature are made with disadvantage until the end of your next turn.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1 might point">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Charge!" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_ORDER_CHARGE">
        <supports>Lord Order</supports>
        <requirements></requirements>
        <prerequisite></prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p>The creature can immediately move up to half its speed and attempt to shove a creature within reach.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1 might point">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Face Me!" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_ORDER_FACE_ME">
        <supports>Lord Order</supports>
        <requirements></requirements>
        <prerequisite></prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p>The creature must make a Wisdom Saving throw. On a failed save, the target has disadvantage on all attack rolls against targets other than you until the end of your next turn.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1 might point">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Fear Me!" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_ORDER_FEAR_ME">
        <supports>Lord Order</supports>
        <requirements></requirements>
        <prerequisite></prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p>The creature must make a Wisdom Saving throw. On a failed save, the creature is frightened of you until the end of your next turn.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1 might point">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Focus!" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_ORDER_FOCUS">
        <supports>Lord Order</supports>
        <requirements></requirements>
        <prerequisite></prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p>The creature adds your Charisma modifier to its ability checks until the end of your next turn.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1 might point">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Get Up!" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_ORDER_GET_UP">
        <supports>Lord Order</supports>
        <requirements></requirements>
        <prerequisite></prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p>The creature regains hit points equal to your Charisma modifier. This effect does not require the creature’s reaction.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1 might point">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Kneel!" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_ORDER_KNEEL">
        <supports>Lord Order</supports>
        <requirements></requirements>
        <prerequisite></prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p>The creature must make a Wisdom Saving throw. On a failed save, the creature falls prone.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1 might point">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Move It!" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_ORDER_MOVE_IT">
        <supports>Lord Order</supports>
        <requirements></requirements>
        <prerequisite></prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p>The creature can immediately move up to half its speed without provoking opportunity attacks.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1 might point">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Reveal Yourself!" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_ORDER_REVEAL_YOURSELF">
        <supports>Lord Order</supports>
        <requirements>[level:9]</requirements>
        <prerequisite>9th level</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 9th level</p>
            <p>The creature must make a Wisdom Saving throw. On a failed save, the creature becomes visible until the end of your next turn.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="3 might points">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Snap Out of It!" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_ORDER_SNAP_OUT_OF_IT">
        <supports>Lord Order</supports>
        <requirements>[level:5]</requirements>
        <prerequisite>5th level</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 5th level</p>
            <p>The creature is immune to being frightened or charmed until the end of your next turn.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="2 might points">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Stick Together!" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_ORDER_STICK_TOGETHER">
        <supports>Lord Order</supports>
        <requirements>[level:9]</requirements>
        <prerequisite>9th level</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 9th level</p>
            <p>Until the end of your next turn, the creature has advantage on attack rolls against a creature if at least one of the creature’s allies is within 5 feet of the creature and the ally isn’t incapacitated.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="3 might points">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Strike Now!" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_ORDER_STRIKE_NOW">
        <supports>Lord Order</supports>
        <requirements>[level:5]</requirements>
        <prerequisite>5th level</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 5th level</p>
            <p>The creature can immediately make one weapon attack against a target of its choice within reach.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="2 might points">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Strike True!" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_LORD_ORDER_STRIKE_TRUE">
        <supports>Lord Order</supports>
        <requirements>[level:5]</requirements>
        <prerequisite>5th level</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 5th level</p>
            <p>The creature adds your Charisma modifier to its attack rolls until the end of your next turn.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="2 might points">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
    </element>


    <!-- Make fighting styles available for Lord class -->
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_DUELING">
        <supports>Lord</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_GREAT_WEAPON_FIGHTING">
        <supports>Lord</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_PROTECTION">
        <supports>Lord</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_DEFENSE">
        <supports>Lord</supports>
    </append>
    <!-- make skills available to Lord class -->
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERSUASION">
        <supports>Lord</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERFORMANCE">
        <supports>Lord</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_HISTORY">
        <supports>Lord</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_RELIGION">
        <supports>Lord</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT">
        <supports>Lord</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INTIMIDATION">
        <supports>Lord</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_DECEPTION">
        <supports>Lord</supports>
    </append>

    <element name="PLACEHOLDER" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="id">
        <description>
            <p>EMPTY CLASS FEATURE FOR TESTING</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Empty class feature</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
</elements>