<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Bastion Class</name>
        <update version="0.0.2">
            <file name="class-bastion.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/classes/class-bastion.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="The Bastion" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_HOLYFANG_HOMEBREWERY_SOURCE_The Bastion">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation"></set>
            <set name="url">https://homebrewery.naturalcrit.com/share/KXuV-TafZ</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" abbreviation="HF" url="https://www.reddit.com/user/HolyFang_/">u/HolyFang_</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20200529</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Bastion" type="Class" source="The Bastion" id="ID_HF_BASTION_CLASS_BASTION">
        <description>
			<p>Heavily armoured on top of a pile of a thousand goblins stands an old human, his silver hair covered in the blood of his foes but he smiles knowing that the people are safe, knowing that he kept his promise.</p>
            <p class="indent">A young half-orc rests on the blood stained dirt next to a tree, tired from the battle, her armour’s damaged, her blade now dull but her spirit unwavering and ready to fight again.</p>
            <p class="indent">These are Bastions the first and last line of defense for villages and towns alike, mighty warriors trained to fend off the evils that would otherwisa attack villages, town cities and merchants. Most often they are wanderers and don’t stay in a place for too long as there may be other people in need of help.</p>
			<h4>THE STRENGTH OF TITANS</h4>
			<p>Bastions are trained to fight without the use of magic, so much so that overtime almost every order has closed its gate to everyone who could use it and hadn’t forsaken it. For a bastion what really matters is resiliance and strength seeing as a lot of the times those are the deciding factors in battle.</p>
            <p class="indent">These warriors are extremely proud of their physical prowess, since the training they go through to become fully fledged bastions is excruciatingly tough and leaves a good third of the people who join with broken bones and spirits. Very few amongst those who try to become bastions actually succed. Some quit, some get injured and some even die.</p>
			<h4>CREATING A BASTION</h4>
			<p>When creating a bastion there are few things that are as important as choosing the reason why your character joined an order in the first place. Was it determination? Maybe admiration? Or were you left with no choice? You may also wanna consider why your character doesn’t use magic (if you chose to go down that path) did they try and fail? or do they have a personal grudge against it?</p>
            <p class="indent"> It’s also important to consider what your character is fighting for: is it peace? or do they just wish to protect people? Or maybe they get a kick out of slaying mosnters and thought this was the best way to do so.</p>
			<h5>QUICK BUILD</h5>
			<p>You can make a bastion quickly by following these suggestions. First constitution should be your highest ability score, followed by strength. Second choose the soldier background.</p>
            <h2>CLASS FEATURES</h2>
            <p>As a bastion, you gain the following class features.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">HIT POINTS</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Hit Dice:</strong> 1d12 per bastion level</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at 1st Level:</strong> 12 + your Constitution modifier</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at Higher Levels:</strong> 1d12 (or 7) + your Constitution modifier per bastion level after 1st</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">PROFICIENCIES</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled mb">
                <li><strong>Armor:</strong> Medium armour, heavy armour, shields</li>
                <li><strong>Weapons:</strong> Simple weapons, martial weapons</li>
                <li><strong>Tools:</strong> None</li>
            </ul>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Saving Throws:</strong> Strength, Constitution</li>
                <li><strong>Skills:</strong> Choose two from Arcana, Athletics, History, Insight, Intimidation, Perception, Persuasion, Survival.</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">EQUIPMENT</h5>
            <p>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>(a) a martial weapon and 5 javelins or (b) two martial weapons</li>
                <li>(a) a chain mail (b) a scale mail</li>
                <li>(a) an explorer’s pack (b) a dungeoneer’s pack</li>
                <li>a shield </li>
            </ul>
        <!-- class table here -->
			<h5 class="caption">THE BASTION</h5>
            <table class="class-features">
                <thead>
                    <tr><td class="col-5">Level</td><td>Proficiency Bonus</td><td class="left">Features</td><td>Charged Dice</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                    <tr><td>1st</td><td>+2</td><td class="left"></td><td>1d6</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>2nd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left"></td><td>1d6</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left"></td><td>1d6</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>4th</td><td>+2</td><td class="left"></td><td>1d6</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left"></td><td>2d6</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>6th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left"></td><td>2d6</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>7th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left"></td><td>2d6</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>8th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left"></td><td>2d6</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left"></td><td>3d6</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>10th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left"></td><td>3d6</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>11th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left"></td><td>3d6</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>12th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left"></td><td>3d6</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>13th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left"></td><td>4d6</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>14th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left"></td><td>4d6</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>15th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left"></td><td>4d6</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>16th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left"></td><td>4d6</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>17th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left"></td><td>5d6</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>18th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left"></td><td>5d6</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>19th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left"></td><td>5d6</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>20th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left"></td><td>5d6</td></tr>
                </tbody>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_HF_BASTION_CLASS_FEATURE_CHARGED_ATTACK" />
            <div element="ID_HF_BASTION_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTING_STYLE" />
            <div element="ID_HF_BASTION_CLASS_FEATURE_IMMOVABLE_RAMPART" />
            <div element="ID_HF_BASTION_CLASS_FEATURE_IMPETUOUS_REBUKE" />
            <div element="ID_HF_BASTION_CLASS_FEATURE_BASTION_ORDER" />
            <div element="ID_HF_BASTION_CLASS_FEATURE_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" />
            <div element="ID_HF_BASTION_CLASS_FEATURE_EXTRA_ATTACK" />
            <div element="ID_HF_BASTION_CLASS_FEATURE_MIGHTY_CONSTITUTION" />
            <div element="ID_HF_BASTION_CLASS_FEATURE_IMPOSING_CHARGE" />
            <div element="ID_HF_BASTION_CLASS_FEATURE_BULWARK_OF_HOPE" />
            <div element="ID_HF_BASTION_CLASS_FEATURE_SUPERIOR_IMMOVABLE_RAMPART" />
            <div element="ID_HF_BASTION_CLASS_FEATURE_RESILIANT_CONSTITUTION" />
            <div element="ID_HF_BASTION_CLASS_FEATURE_IMPENETRABLE_FORTRESS" />
            <h4>MULTICLASSING</h4>
            <h5 class="caption">MULTICLASSING PREREQUISITES</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Class</td><td>Ability Score Minimum</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>Bastion</td><td>Strength 13 and Constitution 13</td></tr>
            </table>
            <h5 class="caption">MULTICLASSING PROFICIENCIES</h5>
            <p>When multiclassing into this class you gain the following proficencies:</p>
            <p class="indent">Medium armor, heavy armor, shields and martial weapons.</p>
            <p class="indent">You cannot multiclass into this class if you are a Bard, Cleric, Druid, Sorcer, Warlock or Wizard.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="hd">d12</set>
            <set name="short">A mighty warrior that is the first line of defense for towns and villages.</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_MEDIUM_ARMOR" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_HEAVY_ARMOR" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_SHIELDS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" requirements="!ID_HF_BASTION_MULTICLASS_Bastion" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_MARTIAL_WEAPONS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_STRENGTH" requirements="!ID_HF_BASTION_MULTICLASS_Bastion" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CONSTITUTION" requirements="!ID_HF_BASTION_MULTICLASS_Bastion" />
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency, Bastion" supports="Skill,Bastion" number="2" requirements="!ID_HF_BASTION_MULTICLASS_Bastion" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_HF_BASTION_CLASS_FEATURE_CHARGED_ATTACK" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_HF_BASTION_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTING_STYLE" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_HF_BASTION_CLASS_FEATURE_IMMOVABLE_RAMPART" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_HF_BASTION_CLASS_FEATURE_IMPETUOUS_REBUKE" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_HF_BASTION_CLASS_FEATURE_BASTION_ORDER" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_HF_BASTION_CLASS_FEATURE_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" level="4" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_HF_BASTION_CLASS_FEATURE_EXTRA_ATTACK" level="5" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_HF_BASTION_CLASS_FEATURE_MIGHTY_CONSTITUTION" level="7" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_HF_BASTION_CLASS_FEATURE_IMPOSING_CHARGE" level="9" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_HF_BASTION_CLASS_FEATURE_BULWARK_OF_HOPE" level="13" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_HF_BASTION_CLASS_FEATURE_SUPERIOR_IMMOVABLE_RAMPART" level="15" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_HF_BASTION_CLASS_FEATURE_RESILIANT_CONSTITUTION" level="18" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_HF_BASTION_CLASS_FEATURE_IMPENETRABLE_FORTRESS" level="20" />
        </rules>
        <multiclass id="ID_HF_BASTION_MULTICLASS_Bastion">
            <prerequisite>Strength 13, Constitution 13. You cannot multiclass into this class if you are a Bard, Cleric, Druid, Sorcer, Warlock or Wizard.</prerequisite>
            <requirements>[str:13],[con:13],!ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_SPELLCASTING_BASE</requirements>
            <setters>
                <set name="multiclass proficiencies">Medium armour, heavy armour, shields, and martial weapons.</set>
            </setters>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS" />
            </rules>
        </multiclass>
    </element>
        <element name="Charged Attack" type="Class Feature" source="The Bastion" id="ID_HF_BASTION_CLASS_FEATURE_CHARGED_ATTACK">
            <description>
                <p>Because of your hard work and training you are now able to put more force into your attacks. Starting at 1st level you can use your bonus action to charge the first hit of your attack action to do more damage.</p>
                <p class="indent">Using this ability applies the <em>Guardbroken</em> effect on your target until the beginning of its next turn or until the creature is hit, furthermore whenever you use this ability your target has to make a Strength saving throw with a DC equal to 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Strength modifier, on a failed save your target takes extra force damage equal to your charge dice. On a successful save the creature takes half as much damage.</p>
                <div class="sidebar">
                    <h5 class="caption">GUARDBROKEN</h5>
                    <p>When a creature is under the effect of the Guardbroken status all attacks against that creature have advantage, that creature also has disadvantage on Strength saving throws.</p>
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>You can charge the first hit of your attack action. Target must make a Strength saving throw (save DC {{charged-attack:save-dc}}) or take an additional {{charge-dice:count}}d6 {{charged-attack:damage-type}} damage (half if successful). On a fail, the target is under the Guardbroken effect until the start of its next turn or until it is hit. All attacks against it have advantage, and creature has disadvantage on Strength saving throws.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="charged-attack:save-dc" value="8" />
                <stat name="charged-attack:save-dc" value="proficiency" />
                <stat name="charged-attack:save-dc" value="strength:modifier" />
                <stat name="charge-dice:count" value="1" level="1" />
                <stat name="charge-dice:count" value="1" level="5" />
                <stat name="charge-dice:count" value="1" level="9" />
                <stat name="charge-dice:count" value="1" level="13" />
                <stat name="charge-dice:count" value="1" level="17" />
                <stat name="charged-attack:damage-type" inline="true" value="force" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Fighting Style" type="Class Feature" source="The Bastion" id="ID_HF_BASTION_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTING_STYLE">
            <description>
                <p>At 1st level, you adopt a style of fighting as your specialty. Choose one of the following. You can’t take a fighting style option more than once, even if you later get to choose again.</p>
                <h5>ARCHERY</h5>
                <p>You gain a +2 bonus to attack rolls you make with ranged weapons.</p>
                <h5>DEFENSE</h5>
                <p>While you are wearing armour, you gain a +1 bonus to AC.</p>
                <h5>DUELING</h5>
                <p>When you are wielding a melee weapon in one hand and no other weapons, you gain a +2 bonus to damage rolls with that weapon.</p>
                <h5>GREAT WEAPON FIGHTING</h5>
                <p>When you roll a 1 or 2 on a damage die for an attack you make with a melee weapon that you are wielding with two hands, you can reroll the die and must use the new roll, even if the new roll is a 1 or a 2. The weapon must have the two-handed or versatile property for you to gain this benefit.</p>
                <h5>UNARMED FIGHTER</h5>
                <p>Your unarmed strikes can deal bludgeoning damage equal to 1d6 + your Strength modifier. If you strike with two free hands, the d6 becomes a d8.</p>
                <p class="indent">When you successfully start a grapple, you can deal 1d4 bludgeoning damage to the grappled creature. Until the grapple ends, you can also deal this damage to the creature whenever you hit it with a melee attack.</p>
                <h5>WARDEN</h5>
                <p>When you are holding a shield and a creature within 5ft of you is attacked you can use your reaction to add the bonus AC granted to you by your shield to that creature’s AC.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you do this you cannot benefit from your shield until the start of your next turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Fighting Style" supports="Fighting Style,Bastion" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Immovable Rampart" type="Class Feature" source="The Bastion" id="ID_HF_BASTION_CLASS_FEATURE_IMMOVABLE_RAMPART">
            <description>
                <p>Your inhuman diligence has lead to your body being resilient like none other. Starting at 2nd level you can use both your action and your bonus action to enter a state of complete focus, while in this state your movement speed is reduced to 0 and you can’t benefit from any movement speed bonus, you can’t take reaction, cannot be moved or put prone, you also recive a +2 to your AC, also while in this state you can’t focus on any spell, if you were already focusing on a spell your concentration is broken.</p>
                <p class="indent">This state lasts until the start of your next turn.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can’t enter or remain in this state if you have less than half of your maximum hit points.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can use both your action and your bonus action to reduce your movement speed to 0 and also recive a +2 to your AC. You can’t benefit from any movement speed bonus, you can’t take reaction, cannot be moved or put prone. You also you can’t focus on any spell, if you were already focusing on a spell your concentration is broken. This state lasts until the start of your next turn. You can’t enter or remain in this state if you have less than half of your maximum hit points.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Impetuous Rebuke" type="Class Feature" source="The Bastion" id="ID_HF_BASTION_CLASS_FEATURE_IMPETUOUS_REBUKE">
            <description>
                <p>Your strength and determination are your best weapons and your opponents know that. Starting at 2nd level you can, only on the turn after the activation of Immovable Rampart, use an action to force every creature within 5ft of you to make a Dexterity saving throw with a DC equal to 8+ your proficiency bonus + your Strength modifier. On a failed save all the creatures take 2d4 damage of the same type as your weapon’s, half as much on a successful save.</p>
                <p class="indent">The damage dealt by this ability scales with your level, starting from 6th level you deal 2d6, at 9th 2d8, 13th 2d10 and at 17th 2d12.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>You can, only on the turn after the activation of Immovable Rampart, use an action to force every creature within 5 feet of you to make a Dexterity saving throw (save DC {{charged-attack:save-dc}}) or take 2d{{impetuous-rebuke:dice-type}} damage of the same type as your weapon (half on a successful save).</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="impetuous-rebuke:dice-type" value="4" level="2" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="impetuous-rebuke:dice-type" value="6" level="6" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="impetuous-rebuke:dice-type" value="8" level="9" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="impetuous-rebuke:dice-type" value="10" level="13" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="impetuous-rebuke:dice-type" value="12" level="17" bonus="base" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Bastion Order" type="Class Feature" source="The Bastion" id="ID_HF_BASTION_CLASS_FEATURE_BASTION_ORDER">
            <description>
                <p>At 3rd level you choose the bastion order that you have been training under: Order of the Primordial, Order of the Spire and Order of the Argonaut are all detailed at the end of the class description.</p>
                <p class="indent">Each order is unique in the way its disciples handle things and in the role they have. Will you join the dragon-slaying forces of the primordials or are you more cut out for fightining in the frontlines with the Spires?</p>
                <p class="indent">Your choice grants you features at 3rd level and ahain at 6th,11th and 14th.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Archetype" name="Bastion Order" supports="Bastion Order" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Ability Score Improvement" type="Class Feature" source="The Bastion" id="ID_HF_BASTION_CLASS_FEATURE_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 10th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
                <p class="indent">Using the optional feats rule, you can forgo taking this feature to take a feat of your choice instead.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Bastion 4)" supports="Improvement Option,Bastion,4" level="4" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Bastion 8)" supports="Improvement Option,Bastion,8" level="8" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Bastion 10)" supports="Improvement Option,Bastion,10" level="10" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Bastion 12)" supports="Improvement Option,Bastion,12" level="12" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Bastion 14)" supports="Improvement Option,Bastion,14" level="14" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Bastion 16)" supports="Improvement Option,Bastion,16" level="16" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Bastion 19)" supports="Improvement Option,Bastion,19" level="19" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Extra Attack" type="Class Feature" source="The Bastion" id="ID_HF_BASTION_CLASS_FEATURE_EXTRA_ATTACK">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 5th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
			<description level="5">You can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="extra attack:count" value="2" level="5" bonus="extra attack" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Mighty Constitution" type="Class Feature" source="The Bastion" id="ID_HF_BASTION_CLASS_FEATURE_MIGHTY_CONSTITUTION">
            <description>
                <p>Your body has been tempered through constant training to the point that you can resist even the most powerful of strikes. Starting from 7th level you cannot be stunned or incapacitated while using Immovable Rampart. While not using Immovable Rampart you have advantage on saving throws against being stunned or incapacitated.</p>
                <p class="indent">Starting from 17th level you gain immunities to all of these conditions.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You cannot be stunned or incapacitated while using Immovable Rampart. While not using Immovable Rampart you have advantage on saving throws against being stunned or incapacitated.</description>
                <description level="17">You are immune to the stunned and incapacitated conditions.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Imposing Charge" type="Class Feature" source="The Bastion" id="ID_HF_BASTION_CLASS_FEATURE_IMPOSING_CHARGE">
            <description>
                <p>You’ve trained yourself to be able to move through the battlefield with ease. Starting at 9th level, you can use your action to turn all of your movement into an Imposing Charge. While charging you can only move in a straight line and all opportunity attacks against you have disadvantage. Also if you go through a space that already has a creature in it that creature has to make a Dexterity saving throw equal to 8 + your proficincy bonus + your Strength modifier. On a fail each creature takes 2d8 force damage and half as much on a successful save.</p>
                <p class="indent">If while charging you reach 0 hit points you continue with the charge until you are out of movement speed. When charging with 0 hit points, you don’t take any extra damage.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can use this ability a number of times equal to your Constitution modifier per long rest. Because of how tiring it is to use this ability if you use it 3 times in a row you gain 1 level of exhaustion and 1 more for each additional use after that.</p>
                <p class="indent">The damage dealt by this ability scales with your level, 2d10 at 13th level and 2d12 at 17th level.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="{{constitution:modifier}}/Long Rest">
                <description>You can turn all movement into an Imposing Charge. While charging you can only move in a straight line and all opportunity attacks against you have disadvantage. Also if you go through a space that already has a creature in it that creature has to make a Dexterity saving throw (save DC {{charged-attack:save-dc}}). On a fail, target takes 2d{{imposing-charge:dice-type}}, half on a success.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="imposing-charge:dice-type" value="8" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="imposing-charge:dice-type" value="10" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="imposing-charge:dice-type" value="12" bonus="base" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Bulwark of Hope" type="Class Feature" source="The Bastion" id="ID_HF_BASTION_CLASS_FEATURE_BULWARK_OF_HOPE">
            <description>
                <p>With time you have learned how to use your physical prowess to protect others. Starting at 13th level, whenever a creature that is within 10 feet of you is being attacked by another creature with a melee weapon attack you can use your reaction to move towards that creature and make a Strength (Athletics) check with a DC equal to the attackers’ attack roll.</p>
                <p class="indent">You take half of the damage and if you pass the skill check the attack’s target takes no damage while if you fail the skill check the attack’s target takes half of the damage.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Whenever a creature that is within 10 feet of you is being attacked by another creature with a melee weapon attack you can use your reaction to move towards that creature and make an Athletics check with a DC equal to the attacker’s attack roll. You take half of the damage and if you pass the skill check the attack’s target takes no damage while if you fail the skill check the attack’s target takes half of the damage.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Superior Immovable Rampart" type="Class Feature" source="The Bastion" id="ID_HF_BASTION_CLASS_FEATURE_SUPERIOR_IMMOVABLE_RAMPART">
            <description>
                <p>Your presence looms inexorable on your enemies. Starting at 15th level whenever you use Immovable Rampart all opponents within 20ft of you have to make a Wisdom saving throw with a DC equal to 8 + your proficiency modifier + your Constitution modifier. On a failed save the creature switches from its previous target to you. Furthermore all hostile creatures within 20ft of you have disadvantage on all attack rolls that aren’t against you for as long as you keep using Immovable Rampart.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Whenever you use Immovable Rampart all opponents within 20 feet of you have to make a Wisdom saving throw (save DC {{superior-rampart:save-dc}}). On a failed save the creature switches from its previous target to you. Furthermore all hostile creatures within 20ft of you have disadvantage on all attack rolls that aren’t against you for as long as you keep using Immovable Rampart.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="superior-rampart:save-dc" value="8" />
                <stat name="superior-rampart:save-dc" value="proficiency" />
                <stat name="superior-rampart:save-dc" value="constitution:modifier" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Resiliant Constitution" type="Class Feature" source="The Bastion" id="ID_HF_BASTION_CLASS_FEATURE_RESILIANT_CONSTITUTION">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 18th level your body has gotten so used to pain and fatigue that you’ve almost become numb to it. You gain advantage on all Constitution saving throws. Furthermore in order to die you need to fail 4 death saving throws instead of 3.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You gain advantage on all Constitution saving throws. Furthermore in order to die you need to fail 4 death saving throws instead of 3.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Impenetrable Fortress" type="Class Feature" source="The Bastion" id="ID_HF_BASTION_CLASS_FEATURE_IMPENETRABLE_FORTRESS">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 20th level you have trained your body to the point that there is no other creature as resilient as you. Your Constitution score is increased by 4, your new limit for this ability score is 24.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="constitution" value="4" />
                <stat name="constitution:max" value="4" />
            </rules>
        </element>

  <!-- Bastion Orders -->
	<element name="Order of Primordials" type="Archetype" source="The Bastion" id="ID_HF_BASTION_ARCHETYPE_BASTION_ORDER_OF_PRIMORDIALS">
		<supports>Bastion Order</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Primordials are one of the very few orders who allow the teaching of magic, the reason they do that though is because of how overwhelming beasts like Dragons can be without it.</p>
            <p class="indent">Primordials specialize in dealing with monsters that use elemental magic such as dragons or behirs, they usually work in groups as working with other less prepared people might turn out to be fatal for everyone involved. They put a lot of trust in teamwork as it is what keeps them alive most of the times .</p>
			<div element="ID_HF_BASTION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_PRIMORDIALS_ELEMENTAL_MANIPULATION" />
			<div element="ID_HF_BASTION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_PRIMORDIALS_ELEMENTAL_ADEPT" />
			<div element="ID_HF_BASTION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_PRIMORDIALS_ELEMENTAL_MASTER" />
			<div element="ID_HF_BASTION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_PRIMORDIALS_ELEMENTAL_SHIELD" />
			<div element="ID_HF_BASTION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_PRIMORDIALS_ELEMENTAL_WRATH" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_HF_BASTION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_PRIMORDIALS_ELEMENTAL_MANIPULATION" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_HF_BASTION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_PRIMORDIALS_ELEMENTAL_ADEPT" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_HF_BASTION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_PRIMORDIALS_ELEMENTAL_MASTER" level="6" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_HF_BASTION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_PRIMORDIALS_ELEMENTAL_SHIELD" level="11" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_HF_BASTION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_PRIMORDIALS_ELEMENTAL_WRATH" level="14" />
		</rules>
	</element>
		<element name="Elemental Manipulation" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Bastion" id="ID_HF_BASTION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_PRIMORDIALS_ELEMENTAL_MANIPULATION">
			<description>
				<p>Thanks to your training, you have learned to bend an element to your will. At 3rd level you choose one of the following elemental damage types: Fire, Thunder, Acid, Cold, or Lightning. The extra damage dealt by your charged attacks is now of the damage type you selected and is considered magic for the purpose of overcoming resistances.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description>Your charged attack is considered magic for the purpose of overcoming resistances.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Elemental Manipulation" supports="Elemental Manipulation Damage" />
			</rules>
		</element>
            <element name="Fire" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Bastion" id="ID_HF_BASTION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_PRIMORDIALS_ELEMENTAL_MANIPULATION_FIRE">
                <supports>Elemental Manipulation Damage</supports>
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description />
                <sheet display="false" />
                <rules>
                    <stat name="charged-attack:damage-type" value="fire" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Thunder" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Bastion" id="ID_HF_BASTION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_PRIMORDIALS_ELEMENTAL_MANIPULATION_THUNDER">
                <supports>Elemental Manipulation Damage</supports>
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description />
                <sheet display="false" />
                <rules>
                    <stat name="charged-attack:damage-type" value="thunder" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Acid" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Bastion" id="ID_HF_BASTION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_PRIMORDIALS_ELEMENTAL_MANIPULATION_ACID">
                <supports>Elemental Manipulation Damage</supports>
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description />
                <sheet display="false" />
                <rules>
                    <stat name="charged-attack:damage-type" value="acid" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Cold" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Bastion" id="ID_HF_BASTION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_PRIMORDIALS_ELEMENTAL_MANIPULATION_COLD">
                <supports>Elemental Manipulation Damage</supports>
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description />
                <sheet display="false" />
                <rules>
                    <stat name="charged-attack:damage-type" value="cold" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Lightning" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Bastion" id="ID_HF_BASTION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_PRIMORDIALS_ELEMENTAL_MANIPULATION_LIGHTNING">
                <supports>Elemental Manipulation Damage</supports>
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description />
                <sheet display="false" />
                <rules>
                    <stat name="charged-attack:damage-type" value="lightning" />
                </rules>
            </element>
		<element name="Elemental Adept" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Bastion" id="ID_HF_BASTION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_PRIMORDIALS_ELEMENTAL_ADEPT">
			<description>
				<p>You’ve also learned to bend the elements that your foes are using to get an edge in battle. Starting at 3rd level you can cast <em>absorb elements</em> at 2nd level once per long or short rest.</p>
                <p class="indent">The number of times you can use this ability scales at 9th level to two times and at 17th level you can use it 3 times</p>
			</description>
			<sheet usage="{{elemental-adept:uses}}/Short Rest">
				<description>You can cast absorb elements at second level.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <stat name="elemental-adept:uses" value="1" level="3" />
                <stat name="elemental-adept:uses" value="1" level="9" />
                <stat name="elemental-adept:uses" value="1" level="17" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Elemental Master" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Bastion" id="ID_HF_BASTION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_PRIMORDIALS_ELEMENTAL_MASTER">
			<description>
				<p>You’ve practiced manipulating your element of choice to the point that now you are able to resist its effects. Starting at 6th level you gain resistance to the element you have chosen, also now all damage that you do with that element ignores resistances.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description>All {{charged-attack:damage-type}} damage you do ignores resistances.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_FIRE" requirements="ID_HF_BASTION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_PRIMORDIALS_ELEMENTAL_MANIPULATION_FIRE" />
                <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_THUNDER" requirements="ID_HF_BASTION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_PRIMORDIALS_ELEMENTAL_MANIPULATION_THUNDER" />
                <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_ACID" requirements="ID_HF_BASTION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_PRIMORDIALS_ELEMENTAL_MANIPULATION_ACID" />
                <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_COLD" requirements="ID_HF_BASTION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_PRIMORDIALS_ELEMENTAL_MANIPULATION_COLD" />
                <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_LIGHTNING" requirements="ID_HF_BASTION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_PRIMORDIALS_ELEMENTAL_MANIPULATION_LIGHTNING" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Elemental Shield" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Bastion" id="ID_HF_BASTION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_PRIMORDIALS_ELEMENTAL_SHIELD">
			<description>
				<p>The control that you have over elements has increased to the point that now even your allies can benefit from it.</p>
                <p class="indent">Starting at 11th level, you can use your action to extend your damage resistances to a friendly creature within 20 feet. The effect of this ability lasts for 1 minute, you can only extend your resistances to only one creature at the time.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can use this ability 2 times per long rest until you reach 17th level, from then on you can use it 3 times.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet action="Action" usage="{{elemental-shield:uses}}/Long Rest">
				<description>You can extend your damage resistances to a friendly creature within 20 feet for 1 minute.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <stat name="elemental-shield:uses" value="2" level="11" />
                <stat name="elemental-shield:uses" value="1" level="17" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Elemental Wrath" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Bastion" id="ID_HF_BASTION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_PRIMORDIALS_ELEMENTAL_WRATH">
			<description>
				<p>Your control of elemental magic has grown to the point that you can start to use it offensively. Starting at 14th level, as an action, you can target a creature within 20 feet of you, that creature must make a Dexterity saving throw with a DC equal to 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Constitution modifier on a failed save the creature takes damage of your chosen elemental typing equal to 2d6 + your charged dice. Magic is very tiring for your body so you can only use this ability a number of times equal to your Constitution modifier per long rest.</p>
				<div>
					<h5 class="caption">MAGIC AND THE PRIMORDIALS</h5>
					<p>Please note that for most bastions casting spells is close to impossible. Although some, like the Primordials, are somewhat able to use magic and bend it at their will, it does not come without a cost. In fact, almost every Primordial has some kind of scar left by the intense training to be able to use the very little magic that they use. For example, those who chose the element of fire or acid might have burns all over their hands and arms. Those who chose cold or necrotic might have lost the sense of touch on their hands. Maybe those who chose thunder might have lightning shaped scars all over their body.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Also remember that although Primordials do learn how to use magic they still don’t allow normal magic users to join the order. In very few cases a bastion might never be able to learn to use magic, in that case they might choose to use a magic item of sorts to channel magic and be able to control it properly. In case you wanted to go down this path please talk it over with your DM and decide on what that magic item should be.</p>
				</div>
			</description>
			<sheet action="Action" usage="{{constitution:modifier}}/Long Rest">
				<description>You can target a creature within 20 feet of you, that creature must make a Dexterity saving throw (save DC {{elemental-wrath:save-dc}}). On a failed save the creature takes damage of your chosen elemental typing equal to 2d6 + your charged dice.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <stat name="elemental-wrath:save-dc" value="8" />
                <stat name="elemental-wrath:save-dc" value="proficiency" />
                <stat name="elemental-wrath:save-dc" value="constitution:modifier" />
			</rules>
		</element>

	<element name="Order of Spires" type="Archetype" source="The Bastion" id="ID_HF_BASTION_ARCHETYPE_BASTION_ORDER_OF_SPIRES">
		<supports>Bastion Order</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Spires are bastions that train themselves to be as tough as they can. They make up both the first and the last line of defnse of towns cities often times as leaders of either armies or small defensive units. Spires are often reguarded as the original bastions as the Order of Spires was the first to be created and the one from which all others stemmed from, as such they are also those who are most common and most widespread.</p>
			<div element="ID_HF_BASTION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_SPIRES_NATURAL_BORN_LEADER" />
			<div element="ID_HF_BASTION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_SPIRES_SENTRY" />
			<div element="ID_HF_BASTION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_SPIRES_IMPOSING_SPIRE" />
			<div element="ID_HF_BASTION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_SPIRES_MASTER_OF_SKIRMISHES" />
			<div element="ID_HF_BASTION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_SPIRES_RESILIENCE_OF_A_TITAN" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_HF_BASTION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_SPIRES_NATURAL_BORN_LEADER" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_HF_BASTION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_SPIRES_SENTRY" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_HF_BASTION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_SPIRES_IMPOSING_SPIRE" level="6" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_HF_BASTION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_SPIRES_MASTER_OF_SKIRMISHES" level="11" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_HF_BASTION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_SPIRES_RESILIENCE_OF_A_TITAN" level="14" />
		</rules>
	</element>
		<element name="Natural Born Leader" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Bastion" id="ID_HF_BASTION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_SPIRES_NATURAL_BORN_LEADER">
			<description>
				<p>Your ability to lead and your confidence inspires others, at 3rd level you gain proficiency in the Persuasion skill, if you already are proficient in it then your proficiency bonus is doubled. Furthermore you can now use your Help action as a bonus action and from up to 30 feet away from the action’s target.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet action="Bonus Action">
				<description>You can use your Help action from up to 30 feet away from the action’s target.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_OR_DOUBLE_PERSUASION" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Sentry" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Bastion" id="ID_HF_BASTION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_SPIRES_SENTRY">
			<description>
				<p>You’ve trained yourself to keep watch during the night and now you don’t need as much rest as others may. Starting at 3rd level you only need 6 hours to complete a long rest and can do up to 3 hours of light activity.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description>You only need 6 hours to complete a long rest and can do up to 3 hours of light activity.</description>
			</sheet>
		</element>
		<element name="Imposing Spire" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Bastion" id="ID_HF_BASTION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_SPIRES_IMPOSING_SPIRE">
			<description>
				<p>Starting at 6th level you can resist even the toughest of hits. You can use this ability to reduce the damage you would take by 1d10. The amount of damage reduced by Imposing Spire scales as you level up, at 11th level it becomes 2d10 and at 17th level it becomes 3d10. You can use this ability a number of times equal to your Constitution modifier per long rest.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet usage="{{constitution:modifier}}/Long Rest">
				<description>You can reduce the damage you would take by {{imposing-spire:die-type}}d10.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <stat name="imposing-spire:die-type" value="1" level="6" />
                <stat name="imposing-spire:die-type" value="1" level="11" />
                <stat name="imposing-spire:die-type" value="1" level="17" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Master of Skirmishes" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Bastion" id="ID_HF_BASTION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_SPIRES_MASTER_OF_SKIRMISHES">
			<description>
				<p>You’ve learned how to position yourself perfectly in the battlefield. Starting at 11th when you are surrounded and a creature is about to attack you, you can use your reaction to impose disadvantage on the next atack of all creatures that you can see and are within 5 feet of you.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description>When you are surrounded and a creature is about to attack you, you can use your reaction to impose disadvantage on the next atack of all creatures that you can see and are within 5 feet of you.</description>
			</sheet>
		</element>
		<element name="Resilience of a Titan" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Bastion" id="ID_HF_BASTION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_SPIRES_RESILIENCE_OF_A_TITAN">
			<description>
				<p>You’ve strengthened your body, turning it into an impenetrable fortress and now you can withstand attacks that would be deadly for most creatures. Starting at 14th level, you are resistant to nonmagical piercing, slashing and bludgeoning damage and can negate crtitical hits.</p>
				<div>
					<h5 class="caption">THE SPIRES AND THE PINNACLES</h5>
					<p>Bastions were created with the intent to protect cities, towns and villages from hordes of monsters as such over time most of the orders have become specialized in a particular style of combat in order to take down a specific type of monster in the most efficient way possible. On the other hand the Order of Spires has become more and more specialized in fending off invaders from other towns and cities. This because of the fact that they mostly worked as city or town guards and had to deal with humanoids almost all the times. This transformation has brought to the formation of a smaller more specialized group of bastions amongst the Spires, these are called Pinnacles. Pinnacles specialize in hunting humanoid monsters. If you wanted to play a Pinnacle instead of a Spire then swap out the feature <em>Natural Born Leader</em> for the following.</p>
					<p class="indent"><em>Humanoid Slayer:</em> You’ve spent time studying your foes and now you know how they act. Starting at 3rd level you gain proficiency in the survival skill, if you already are proficient in it then your proficiency bonus is doubled. Furthermore while in combat with a humanoid creature you may use a bonus action roll an Insight check with a DC that is to be decided by your DM to gain advantage on your next hit against that creature.</p>
				</div>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description>You can negate critical hits.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_BLUDGEONING" />
                <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_PIERCING" />
                <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_SLASHING" />
			</rules>
		</element>

	<element name="Order of the Argonauts" type="Archetype" source="The Bastion" id="ID_HF_BASTION_ARCHETYPE_BASTION_ORDER_OF_THE_ARGONAUTS">
		<supports>Bastion Order</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Argonauts are the most well known amongst the Bastions especially between villagers and town’s folk. Unlike the members of other orders Argonauts aren’t based in a particular town or city, Argonauts are wandering warriors who roam from town to town and from village to village. The reason behind this behaviour is that since small towns and villages don’t really have guards of their own they try and fill in instead. It’s not uncommon for villages to have stories about how a mesterious hero came to save the settlement from an horde of goblin or of undead. Loved amongst the folk Argonauts are easily recognizable because their symbol: a golden dragon, which is often depicten on their cape or on their armour. Some argonauts though prefer to work in the shadows withot ever being seen as they feel that that is the very best thing an hero could do, Argonauts that act this way are usually called Umbrals.</p>
			<div element="ID_HF_BASTION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_ARGONAUTS_THE_LIFE_OF_A_WANDERER" />
			<div element="ID_HF_BASTION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_ARGONAUTS_A_HEROS_SOUL" />
			<div element="ID_HF_BASTION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_ARGONAUTS_HORDE_SLAYER" />
			<div element="ID_HF_BASTION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_ARGONAUTS_MASTER_TACTITIAN" />
			<div element="ID_HF_BASTION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_ARGONAUTS_THE_POWER_OF_LEGENDS" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_HF_BASTION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_ARGONAUTS_THE_LIFE_OF_A_WANDERER" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_HF_BASTION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_ARGONAUTS_A_HEROS_SOUL" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_HF_BASTION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_ARGONAUTS_HORDE_SLAYER" level="6" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_HF_BASTION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_ARGONAUTS_MASTER_TACTITIAN" level="11" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_HF_BASTION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_ARGONAUTS_THE_POWER_OF_LEGENDS" level="14" />
		</rules>
	</element>
		<element name="The Life of a Wanderer" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Bastion" id="ID_HF_BASTION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_ARGONAUTS_THE_LIFE_OF_A_WANDERER">
			<description>
				<p>Your time travelling has blessed you with knowledge. Starting at 3rd level you become capable to pilot boats and caravans. Furthermore, you have advantage on all Wisdom (Animal Handling) skill checks to mount and control any kind of mount.</p>
				<div>
					<h5 class="caption">WILDERNESS SETTINGS</h5>
					<p>In case you were to run a wilderness campaign or wanted your Argonaut to have a bit of a different feel to it you can choose to replace the feature Folk Hero with the following feature: Master Tracker Your ability to track your foes is unmatched, at 3rd level you gain proficiency in the survival skill, if you already are proficient in it then your proficiency bonus is doubled. Furthermore your armour doesn’t impose disadvantage on your stealth skillchecks.</p>
				</div>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description>You have advantage on all Animal Handling checks to mount and control any kind of mount.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_VEHICLES_LAND" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_VEHICLES_WATER" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="A Hero’s Soul" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Bastion" id="ID_HF_BASTION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_ARGONAUTS_A_HEROS_SOUL">
			<description>
				<p>Your devotion to your cause has allowed you the ability to heal others. Starting at 3rd level you have a pool of healing power that replenishes when you take a long rest. With that pool, you can restore a total number of hit points equal to your bastion level × 3. As an action, you can touch a creature and draw power from the pool to restore a number of hit points to that creature, up to the maximum amount remaining in your pool.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet usage="{{heros-soul:pool}} Points/Long Rest" action="Action">
				<description>You can touch a creature and draw power from the pool to restore a number of hit points to that creature, up to the maximum amount remaining in your pool.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <stat name="heros-soul:pool" value="level:bastion" />
                <stat name="heros-soul:pool" value="level:bastion" />
                <stat name="heros-soul:pool" value="level:bastion" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Horde Slayer" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Bastion" id="ID_HF_BASTION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_ARGONAUTS_HORDE_SLAYER">
			<description>
				<p>Your expirience in battle now allows you to strike swiftly and with more precision. Starting at 6th level, every time you are fighting a horde, you gain advantage on your attack rolls and a +1 to damage against those enemies.</p>
                <div class="sidebar">
                    <h5 class="caption">HORDES</h5>
                    <p>A group of enemies can be considered a Horde whenever there are at least 2 more enemies than there are friendly combatants.</p>
                </div>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description>Every time you are fighting a three or more enemies, you gain advantage on your attack rolls and a +1 to damage against those enemies.</description>
			</sheet>
		</element>
		<element name="Master Tactitian" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Bastion" id="ID_HF_BASTION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_ARGONAUTS_MASTER_TACTITIAN">
			<description>
				<p>Starting at 11th level, the knowledge of your opponents is not only useful to yourself but also to your allies. Whenever an ally is outnumbered and is about to attack, if they are wihin 30 feet, you can use your reaction to give your ally advantage on that one attack roll.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet action="Reaction">
				<description>Whenever an ally with 30 feet of you is outnumbered and is about to attack, you can use your reaction to give your ally advantage on that one attack roll.</description>
			</sheet>
		</element>
		<element name="The Power of Legends" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Bastion" id="ID_HF_BASTION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_ARGONAUTS_THE_POWER_OF_LEGENDS">
			<description>
				<p>The enemies that you have defeated now give you strength. Starting at 14th level, whenever you are using weapons that have been crafted with monster parts from the creatures that you have slain or any magic weapon of rarities rare and above you gain the following benefits: Your weapon deals +3 damage of the same type as the weapon’s damage. Furthermore when you are wielding that weapon if you used the Charged attack feature your second attack deal 1d6 extra force damage.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description>Whenever you are using weapons that have been crafted with monster parts from the creatures that you have slain or any magic weapon of rarities rare and above you gain the following benefits: Your weapon deals +3 damage of the same type as the weapon’s damage. Furthermore when you are wielding that weapon if you used the Charged attack feature your second attack deal 1d6 extra force damage.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
			</rules>
		</element>

  <!-- Bastion Skills -->
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ARCANA">
        <supports>Bastion</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ATHLETICS">
        <supports>Bastion</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_HISTORY">
        <supports>Bastion</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT">
        <supports>Bastion</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INTIMIDATION">
        <supports>Bastion</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION">
        <supports>Bastion</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERSUASION">
        <supports>Bastion</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SURVIVAL">
        <supports>Bastion</supports>
    </append>

  <!-- Bastion Fighting Styles -->
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_ARCHERY">
        <supports>Bastion</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_DEFENSE">
        <supports>Bastion</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_DUELING">
        <supports>Bastion</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_GREAT_WEAPON_FIGHTING">
        <supports>Bastion</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTING_STYLE_BLIND_FIGHTING">
        <supports>Bastion</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTING_STYLE_INTERCEPTION">
        <supports>Bastion</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTING_STYLE_UNARMED_FIGHTING">
        <supports>Bastion</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTING_STYLE_SUPERIOR_TECHNIQUE">
        <supports>Bastion</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_DEVIKYN_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTING_STYLE_PUGILISM">
        <supports>Bastion</supports>
    </append>

    <element name="Warden" type="Class Feature" source="The Bastion" id="ID_HF_BASTION_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTING_STYLE_WARDEN">
        <supports>Fighting Style, Fighter, Paladin, Viking, Warden, Bastion</supports>
        <description>
            <p>When you are holding a shield and a creature within 5ft of you is attacked you can use your reaction to add the bonus AC granted to you by your shield to that creature’s AC. Once you do this you cannot benefit from your shield until the start of your next turn.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Reaction">
            <description>When you are holding a shield and a creature within 5ft of you is attacked you can use your reaction to add the bonus AC granted to you by your shield to that creature’s AC. Once you do this you cannot benefit from your shield until the start of your next turn.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

</elements>