<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Commander Class</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="class-commander.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/classes/class-commander.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="The Commander" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_AEYANA_GMBINDER_SOURCE_The Commander">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation"></set>
            <set name="url">https://www.gmbinder.com/share/-LthH-sNFxIuClVT52hC</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" url="https://www.gmbinder.com/profile/witchfire">Aeyana</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20200118</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Commander" type="Class" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_COMMANDER">
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">The most important words a man can say are, “I will do better.” These are not the most important words any man can say. I am a man, and they are what I needed to say.</p>
            <p class="indent flavor">The ancient code of the Knights Radiant says "journey before destination." Some may call it a simple platitude, but it is far more. A journey will have pain and failure. It is not only the steps forward that we must accept. It is the stumbles. The trials. The knowledge that we will fail. That we will hurt those around us.</p>
            <p class="indent flavor">But if we stop, if we accept the person we are when we fall, the journey ends. That failure becomes our destination.</p>
            <p class="indent flavor">To love the journey is to accept no such end. I have found, through painful experience, that the most important step a person can take is always the next one.</p>
            <p class="flavor" style="text-align: right;">— Brandon Sanderson, Oathbringer</p>
            <p>A beloved human in a feather hat blows into a golden minotaur horn, the deep sound resonating for miles around. The mighty trumpet awakens his crew with a sense of heroic resolve, signaling the path onwards. His promise for gold pushes them through damp sands, past shambling skeletons, and into a pitch black cavern.</p>
            <p class="indent">Seven devils rise from the depths of hell, walking through an infernal gate to the mortal plane. At their front marches an armored tiefling. The embers of hatred and vengeance glow in her eyes, plainly visible through her black visor. She wields a greatsword of iron, red hot from the lava it was forged in, and upon her head a crown of black flames as the group marches away from Avernus.</p>
            <p class="indent">The sound of cloven hooves rampages down a hallway, a warning for the gang of entrenched smugglers. An armor clad dwarf trails behind his sneering warthog, metal chain in one hand, and shield in the other. The insignia of the king's army reflects off his brightly polished metal. As he lets out a war cry in his king's name, the warthog joins in on the call.</p>
            <p class="indent">These are all powerful leaders with the voice to command. Whether they coordinate with their companions to overcome armies, bring terror with a cursed name, or lead with an animal companion at their side, commanders lead the way to victory.</p>
            <h4>STRENGTH IN NUMBERS</h4>
            <p>On the battlefield, commanders merge martial training with an overbearing cpresence. They rarely ever fight alone, instead preferring to fight alongside their most trusted companions. When they are not engaged in combat, a commander still uses their reputation and charisma to influence others, branding them with a reputation as powerful leaders, dreadful tyrants, or trustworthy allies.</p>
            <p class="indent">A commander leads at the front of a group, using its voice to mold the flow of combat. Despite being fully capable swordsmen, commanders shift some focus away from their own fight to aid others. Commanders rally their companions under a common cause, and their might both inspires allies and demoralizes enemies. If all else fails, a commander can rely on their strong armor and stronger heart to defend themselves from harm.</p>
            <h4>RISE TO THE OCCASION</h4>
            <p>Commanders come from nearly every walk of life, ranging from the local guide to the distinguished diplomat and even to crime lords. At the highest levels of society, a great number of kings and queens are commanders due to their influential nature. The details of each commander's brand of leadership vary between one another. Some lead through diplomacy and camaraderie while others exert terror. A few will find their knack for leadership to come naturally, and perfect it through years of experience. Others require years of formal training at an institution using long established techniques.</p>
            <p class="indent">There are a wide variety of factors that may drive a commander to a life of adventure. For some it is simply the desire to meet new people or explore far lands. Others set out with a more specific goal in mind, one that requires the aid of other adventurers. Sometimes, a commander will be pushed to adventure as their offical duty, usually an order from a formal or divine power. Despite an individual's reason for adventuring, all commanders find comfort alongside groups of adventurers.</p>
            <h4>CREATING YOUR COMMANDER</h4>
            <p>When creating a commander, consider what about you conjures a powerful influence. What causes others to instinctively pay attention to you? Perhaps you have a powerful voice that demands attention? Or do you draw people using your charming personality? Or maybe you're full of old stories you can share with everyone, from the humble peasant to the privileged king. Does your name strike fear and terror in the hearts of mortals? Or is it one associated with heroism and courage? What defining event brought about your current reputation?</p>
            <p class="indent">Consider the events that forced you into a life of adventure. Were you coaxed into a journey by someone else? Or were you forced from your home, causing you to find companionship among adventurers? Perhaps you felt it was a duty for safety and honor? Or do you have a calling so strong you're willing to trample anyone that stands in your way?</p>
            <h5>QUICK BUILD</h5>
            <p>You can make a commander quickly by following these suggestions. First, make Strength or Dexterity your highest ability score, depending on whether you want to focus on melee weapons or on archery (or finesse weapons). Your next-highest score should be Charisma. Second, choose the noble background.</p>
            <h2>CLASS FEATURES</h2>
            <p>As an commander, you gain the following class features.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">HIT POINTS</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Hit Dice:</strong> 1d10 per commander level</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at 1st Level:</strong> 10 + your Constitution modifier</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at Higher Levels:</strong> 1d10 (or 6) + your Constitution modifier per commander level after 1st</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">PROFICIENCIES</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled mb">
                <li><strong>Armor:</strong> All armor, shields</li>
                <li><strong>Weapons:</strong> Simple weapons, martial weapons</li>
                <li><strong>Tools:</strong> Land vehicles</li>
            </ul>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Saving Throws:</strong> Wisdom, Charisma</li>
                <li><strong>Skills:</strong> Choose two from Animal Handling, History, Insight, Medicine, Nature, Intimidation, Perception, and Persuasion.</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">EQUIPMENT</h5>
            <p>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>(a) a martial melee weapon and a shield or (b) any two melee weapons</li>
                <li>(a) a heavy crossbow and 20 bolts or (b) two handaxes</li>
                <li>(a) a chain shirt or (b) chain mail</li>
                <li>(a) a diplomat's pack or (b) an explorer's pack</li>
            </ul>
            <p>Alternatively, you can ignore the equipment from your class and background, and start with 5d4 x 10 gp.</p>
        <!-- class table here -->
            <h5 class="caption">THE COMMANDER</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td class="col-5">Level</td><td class="col-5">Proficiency Bonus</td><td	class="left">Features</td><td class="col-5">Rally Bonus</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1st</td><td>+2</td><td>Rally the Forces, Somatic Communication</td><td>+2</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2nd</td><td>+2</td><td>War Leadership, Dauntless Action</td><td>+2</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3rd</td><td>+2</td><td>Commander's Discipline</td><td>+2</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4th</td><td>+2</td><td>Ability Score Improvement</td><td>+2</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5th</td><td>+3</td><td>Extra Attack, Call to Arms</td><td>+2</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6th</td><td>+3</td><td>Commander's Discipline Feature</td><td>+2</td></tr>
                <tr><td>7th</td><td>+3</td><td>Lead by Example, Rally (2 uses)</td><td>+3</td></tr>
                <tr><td>8th</td><td>+3</td><td>Ability Score Improvement</td><td>+3</td></tr>
                <tr><td>9th</td><td>+4</td><td>Sovereign Influence</td><td>+3</td></tr>
                <tr><td>10th</td><td>+4</td><td>Unwavering Conviction</td><td>+3</td></tr>
                <tr><td>11th</td><td>+4</td><td>War Leadership (2 targets)</td><td>+3</td></tr>
                <tr><td>12th</td><td>+4</td><td>Ability Score Improvement</td><td>+3</td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td>+5</td><td>Commander's Discipline Feature</td><td>+3</td></tr>
                <tr><td>14th</td><td>+5</td><td>Rally (3 uses)</td><td>+4</td></tr>
                <tr><td>15th</td><td>+5</td><td>Unwavering Conviction</td><td>+4</td></tr>
                <tr><td>16th</td><td>+5</td><td>Ability Score Improvement</td><td>+4</td></tr>
                <tr><td>17th</td><td>+6</td><td>War Leadership (3 targets)</td><td>+4</td></tr>
                <tr><td>18th</td><td>+6</td><td>Commander's Discipline Feature</td><td>+4</td></tr>
                <tr><td>19th</td><td>+6</td><td>Ability Score Improvement</td><td>+4</td></tr>
                <tr><td>20th</td><td>+6</td><td>Commander Luminary</td><td>+4</td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_RALLY_THE_FORCES" />
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_SOMATIC_COMMUNICATION" />
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_WAR_LEADERSHIP" />
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_DAUNTLESS_ACTION" />
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_COMMANDERS_DISCIPLINE" />
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" />
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_EXTRA_ATTACK" />
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_CALL_TO_ARMS" />
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_LEAD_BY_EXAMPLE" />
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_SOVEREIGN_INFLUENCE" />
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_UNWAVERING_CONVICTION" />
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_COMMANDER_LUMINARY" />
            <h3>MULTICLASSING</h3>
            <p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Strength 13 and Charisma 13</p>
            <p><strong>Proficiencies Gained:</strong> Light armor, medium armor, shields, simple weapons, and martial weapons.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="hd">d10</set>
            <set name="short">A balanced class for legendary heroes, honored diplomats, and nefarious warlords.</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_MEDIUM_ARMOR" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_HEAVY_ARMOR" requirements="!ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_MULTICLASS_COMMANDER" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_SHIELDS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_MARTIAL_WEAPONS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_VEHICLES_LAND" requirements="!ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_MULTICLASS_COMMANDER" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_WISDOM" requirements="!ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_MULTICLASS_COMMANDER" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CHARISMA" requirements="!ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_MULTICLASS_COMMANDER" />
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency, Commander" supports="Skill, Commander" number="2" requirements="!ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_MULTICLASS_COMMANDER" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_RALLY_THE_FORCES" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_SOMATIC_COMMUNICATION" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_WAR_LEADERSHIP" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_DAUNTLESS_ACTION" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_COMMANDERS_DISCIPLINE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" level="4" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_EXTRA_ATTACK" level="5" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_CALL_TO_ARMS" level="5" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_LEAD_BY_EXAMPLE" level="7" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_SOVEREIGN_INFLUENCE" level="9" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_UNWAVERING_CONVICTION" level="10" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_COMMANDER_LUMINARY" level="20" />
        </rules>
        <multiclass id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_MULTICLASS_COMMANDER">
            <prerequisite>Strength 13 and Charisma 13</prerequisite>
            <requirements>[str:13],[cha:13]</requirements>
            <setters>
                <set name="multiclass proficiencies">Light armor, medium armor, shields, simple weapons, and martial weapons.</set>
            </setters>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS" />
            </rules>
        </multiclass>
    </element>

        <element name="Rally the Forces" type="Class Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_RALLY_THE_FORCES">
            <description>
                <p>Through chanting war cries, reciting inspirational literature, offering reassurance, or similar means you rally your companions, using your bonus action to do so.</p>
                <p class="indent">Select a number of willing creatures up to your Charisma modifier (minimum of 1 other creature). Each creature must be no more than 30 feet from you and able to hear you. You and the chosen creatures become rallied for up to one minute, which ends early on a creature if it falls unconscious or drops to 0 hit points. You must finish a short or long rest before you can use your rally again.</p>
                <p class="indent">Until a creature stops being rallied, it gains a bonus to ability checks and saving throws equal to your rally bonus and has advantage against being frightened. Your rally bonus is shown for your commander level in the Commander table.</p>
                <p class="indent">Beginning at 7th level, you can use your rally twice between rests, and beginning at 14th level, you can use it three times between rests. When you finish a short or long rest, you regain all expended uses.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="{{rally-the-forces:uses}}/Short Rest">
                <description>Select up to {{rally-the-forces:targets}} willing creatures within 30 feet of you that can hear you. You can the chosen creatures get a +{{rally-the-forces:bonus}} bonus to ability checks and saving throws and have advantage against being frightened for up to 1 minute.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="rally-the-forces:uses" value="1" level="1" />
                <stat name="rally-the-forces:uses" value="1" level="7" />
                <stat name="rally-the-forces:uses" value="1" level="14" />
                <stat name="rally-the-forces:bonus" value="2" level="1" />
                <stat name="rally-the-forces:bonus" value="1" level="7" />
                <stat name="rally-the-forces:bonus" value="1" level="14" />
                <stat name="rally-the-forces:targets" value="1" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="rally-the-forces:targets" value="charisma:modifier" bonus="base" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Somatic Communication" type="Class Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_SOMATIC_COMMUNICATION">
            <description>
                <p>You've learned or created a set of somatic gestures that can be used for basic communication. Using a free hand, you can communicate simple messages to nearby creatures. Any creature that knows your set of gestures and can see you understands your messages as if you were speaking. Generally, members belonging to the same organization (such as an adventuring guild, crime syndicate, military faction, or noble house) know the same set of gestures.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can teach your set of gestures to a number of creatures equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum of 1) over the span of one hour, provided you share a language. After 7 days of adventuring with you, a friendly creature that knows your gestures becomes proficient with them and is able to communicate back the same way.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Using a free hand, you can communicate simple messages to nearby creatures. Any creature that knows your set of gestures and can see you understands your messages as if you were speaking. You can teach your set of gestures to {{rally-the-forces:targets}} creatures over an hour, provided you share a language.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="War Leadership" type="Class Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_WAR_LEADERSHIP">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 2nd level, you can issue powerful decrees that propel and direct your allies in combat. You know two different decrees: Press the Assault and On Your Guard, and select which to issue each time.</p>
                <p class="indent">When you take the Attack action, you can forgo your attack to instead issue a decree to a creature you can see within 60 feet. If the target is willing and able to understand you (either verbally or via somatic gestures), it gains the decree's effects. The target can't benefit from another decree until the first one's effects have ended.</p>
                <p class="indent">If you're able to make multiple attacks with your Attack action, issuing a decree replaces one of them.</p>
                <p class="indent">Beginning at 11th level, and again at 17th level, you can target one additional creature when you use your decrees. You don't need to forgo another attack for it, and can select the same or a different decree for each.</p>
                <h5 class="caption">DECREE: PRESS THE ASSAULT</h5>
                <p>You gain a powerful sense of might that gives you an edge in the heat of battle. You grant yourself one of the following effects. If you use neither effect before the end of your next turn, the effects are lost.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Additional Attack.</em></strong> The target gains one attack on its next turn— either as an additional attack if it takes the Attack action, or using its bonus action to attack once.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Focused Fury.</em></strong> When the target makes an attack or casts a spell that targets one creature, it can roll a d4 and either add it to its attack roll or subtract it from one saving throw against the effect. You may only apply this modifier once before the effect ends.</p>
                <h5 class="caption">DECREE: ON YOUR GUARD</h5>
                <p>The target takes heed and brace yourself against incoming damage, granting the benefits of the dodge action until the end of the commander's next turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can forgo one of your attacks to issue a Decree to a creature you can see within 60 feet.</description>
                <description level="11">You can forgo one of your attacks to issue a Decree to up to {{war-leadership:targets}} creatures you can see within 60 feet. You don't need to forgo another attack for it, and can select the same or a different decree for each.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="war-leadership:targets" value="1" level="2" />
                <stat name="war-leadership:targets" value="1" level="11" />
                <stat name="war-leadership:targets" value="1" level="17" />
                <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_DECREE_PRESS_THE_ASSAULT" level="2" />
                <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_DECREE_ON_YOUR_GUARD" level="2" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Decree: Press the Assault" type="Class Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_DECREE_PRESS_THE_ASSAULT">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>You gain a powerful sense of might that gives you an edge in the heat of battle. You grant one of the following effects. If you use neither effect before the end of your next turn, the effects are lost.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><strong><em>Additional Attack.</em></strong> The target gains one attack on its next turn— either as an additional attack if it takes the Attack action, or using its bonus action to attack once.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><strong><em>Focused Fury.</em></strong> When the target makes an attack or casts a spell that targets one creature, it can roll a d4 and either add it to its attack roll or subtract it from one saving throw against the effect. You may only apply this modifier once before the effect ends.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Decree" alt="Press the Assault">
                    <description>You grant one of the following effects: Additional Attack:The target gains one attack on its next turn— either as an additional attack if it takes the Attack action, or using its bonus action to attack once. Focused Fury: When the target makes an attack or casts a spell that targets one creature, it can roll a d4 and either add it to its attack roll or subtract it from one saving throw against the effect. You may only apply this modifier once before the effect ends.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Decree: On Your Guard" type="Class Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_DECREE_ON_YOUR_GUARD">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>The target takes heed and brace yourself against incoming damage, granting the benefits of the dodge action until the end of the commander's next turn.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Decree" alt="On Your Guard">
                    <description>The target takes heed and brace yourself against incoming damage, granting the benefits of the dodge action until the end of the commander's next turn.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
        <element name="Dauntless Action" type="Class Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_DAUNTLESS_ACTION">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 2nd level, if you make no more than one attack on your turn, you can use your bonus action to take the Dash, Disengage, or Help action.</p>
                <p class="indent">If you use the Guard optional rule (found on the next page), you can choose to take the Guard action instead.</p>
                <div class="sidebar">
                    <h5 class="caption">OPTIONAL RULE: GUARD</h5>
                    <p>As an optional rule, any creature can take the Guard action on its turn. This action is also added to the list of actions a commander can take using its Dauntless Action.</p>
                    <h5 class="caption">GUARD</h5>
                    <p>When you take the Guard action, you forgo your own safety to focus on protecting another creature, provided the target is no more than one size larger than you.</p>
                    <p class="indent">The target has advantage on Dexterity saving throws and attacks against it have disadvantage if you can see the attacker, but all attacks against you have advantage. This effect ends if the target moves more than 5 feet from you or at the start of your next turn.</p>
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>If you make no more than one attack on your turn, you can use your bonus action to take the Dash, Disengage, or Help (or Guard, if used) action.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Commander's Discipline" type="Class Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_COMMANDERS_DISCIPLINE">
            <description>
                <p>At 3rd level, you choose an archetype that you strive to emulate in your particular style of leadership, such as the Captain. The archetype you choose grants you features at 3rd level and again at 6th, 13th, and 18th levels in this class.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Archetype" name="Commander's Discipline" supports="Commander Discipline" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Ability Score Improvement" type="Class Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
                <p class="indent">Using the optional feats rule, you can forgo taking this feature to take a feat of your choice instead.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Commander 4)" supports="Improvement Option,Commander,4" level="4" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Commander 8)" supports="Improvement Option,Commander,8" level="8" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Commander 12)" supports="Improvement Option,Commander,12" level="12" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Commander 16)" supports="Improvement Option,Commander,16" level="16" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Commander 19)" supports="Improvement Option,Commander,19" level="19" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Extra Attack" type="Class Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_EXTRA_ATTACK">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 5th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="extra attack:count" value="2" level="5" bonus="extra attack" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Call to Arms" type="Class Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_CALL_TO_ARMS">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 5th level, you shout for nearby allies to join when you charge into battle, moving them to action.</p>
                <p class="indent">When you roll initiative, choose any number of friendly creatures within 60 feet of you that can hear you. You and the chosen creatures each gain an additional 10 feet of movement speed during the first round of combat.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you roll initiative, choose any number of friendly creatures within 60 feet of you that can hear you. You and the chosen creatures each gain an additional 10 feet of movement speed during the first round of combat.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Lead By Example" type="Class Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_LEAD_BY_EXAMPLE">
            <description>
                <p>At 7th level, your leadership moves you to respond quickly to threats. You can give yourself a bonus to your initiative rolls equal to your Charisma modifier. If your initiative roll equals another creature's, you decide if you take your turns before or after that creature.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can give yourself a +{{charisma:modifier}} bonus to your initiative rolls. If your initiative roll equals another creature's, you decide if you take your turns before or after that creature.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Sovereign Influence" type="Class Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_SOVEREIGN_INFLUENCE">
            <description>
                <p>At 9th level, your fame (or infamy) gives you an edge when addressing others. You gain proficiency in the Intimidation and Persuasion skills. If you are already proficient in either skill when you gain this feature, you instead add double your proficiency bonus to any check you make with that skill.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_OR_DOUBLE_INTIMIDATION" />
                <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_OR_DOUBLE_PERSUASION" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Unwavering Conviction" type="Class Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_UNWAVERING_CONVICTION">
            <description>
                <p>At 10th level, your steadfast mind can't be infiltrated by effects that would change it. While you are conscious, you can't be charmed or frightened and have advantage on saving throws against enchantment magic.</p>
                <p class="indent">When you reach 15th level, rallying your allies calls forth the same sense of determination. While a creature is rallied by you, it can't be charmed or frightened and has advantage on saving throws against enchantment magic. If a creature is already under such an effect when you rally it, it has advantage on any new rolls made to end the effect for the duration.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>While you are conscious, you can't be charmed or frightened and have advantage on saving throws against enchantment magic.</description>
                <description level="15">While you are conscious, you can't be charmed or frightened and have advantage on saving throws against enchantment magic. While a creature is rallied by you, it can't be charmed or frightened and has advantage on saving throws against enchantment magic. If a creature is already under such an effect when you rally it, it has advantage on any new rolls made to end the effect for the duration</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Commander Luminary" type="Class Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_COMMANDER_LUMINARY">
            <description>
                <p>At 20th level, you are an exemplary master of valor and leadership. Your rally's effects last for 1 hour (instead of 1 minute) and if you have no uses of your rally left when you roll initiative, you gain one use of it.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Your rally's effects last for 1 hour (instead of 1 minute) and if you have no uses of your rally left when you roll initiative, you gain one use of it.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

  <!-- Commander Disciplines -->        
    <element name="Captain" type="Archetype" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_COMMANDER_CAPTAIN">
        <supports>Commander Discipline</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Captains are masterful leaders that maintain a powerful bond with those they lead. They do not necessarily find success in an individual's actions, but rather in a shared victory among allies. A captain's powerful voice and exquisite tact allows them to mold the flow of combat at their direction.</p>
            <p class="indent">A small party of combatants led by an experienced captain operates like a well oiled machine, able to challenge even the most impossible of odds.</p>
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CAPTAIN_ARTFUL_SPEAKER" />
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CAPTAIN_COMPELLING_MANEUVER" />
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CAPTAIN_PARAMOUNT_LEADER" />
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CAPTAIN_CAPTAINS_RIGHT_HAND" />
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CAPTAIN_LEAD_THE_CHARGE" />
         </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CAPTAIN_ARTFUL_SPEAKER" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CAPTAIN_COMPELLING_MANEUVER" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CAPTAIN_PARAMOUNT_LEADER" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CAPTAIN_CAPTAINS_RIGHT_HAND" level="13" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CAPTAIN_LEAD_THE_CHARGE" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Artful Speaker" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CAPTAIN_ARTFUL_SPEAKER">
            <description>
                <p>At 3rd level, you are proficient in the Persuasion skill. If you are already proficient with it, you instead gain proficiency in one other skill from the class's skill list.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency, Artful Speaker" supports="Skill, Commander" default="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERSUASION" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Compelling Maneuver" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CAPTAIN_COMPELLING_MANEUVER">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 3rd level, your decrees create openings in the flow of battle, which your allies can exploit to better position themselves. When a creature gains the effects of your decree, it can use its reaction to move up to half its speed without triggering opportunity attacks.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When a creature gains the effects of your decree, it can use its reaction to move up to half its speed without triggering opportunity attacks.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Paramount Leader" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CAPTAIN_PARAMOUNT_LEADER">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level your powerful enthusiasm makes you a more capable leader. When you issue Press the Assault or On Your Guard to a creature, it gains an additional effect depending on the decree issued.</p>
                <h5 class="caption">PRESS THE ASSAULT</h5>
                <p>If you issue Press the Assault, the target can forgo the decree's normal effects to use the following instead.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Overwhelming Force:</em></strong> If the target makes an attack or cast a spell that targets one creature, you can add an additional 2d8 damage to one of its damage rolls. You may only apply this bonus damage once before the decree ends.</p>
                <h5 class="caption">ON YOUR GUARD</h5>
                <p>If you issue On Your Guard, as part of its effects the target's movement doesn't provoke opportunity attacks from creatures it can see.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you issue Press the Assault or On Your Guard to a creature, it gains an additional effect depending on the decree issued. The target can forgo the normal effects of Press the Assault, and instead add 2d8 damage to one of its damage rolls for an attack or spell that targets one creature. The target of On Your Guard can move without provoking opportunity attacks from creatures it can see.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Captain's Right Hand" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CAPTAIN_CAPTAINS_RIGHT_HAND">
            <description>
                <p>At 13th level, your ability to aid others is unprecedented. When you take the Help action, you gain the following benefits.</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>If you aid an ally in performing a task and it makes its roll with advantage, it can re-roll one of the dice and take either result.</li>
                    <li>If you aid an ally in attacking a creature you can see, the target of that attack can be within 30 feet of you, rather than 5 feet of you.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you take the Help action, you gain the following benefits. If you aid an ally in performing a task and it makes its roll with advantage, it can re-roll one of the dice and take either result. If you aid an ally in attacking a creature you can see, the target of that attack can be within 30 feet of you, rather than 5 feet of you.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Lead the Charge" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CAPTAIN_LEAD_THE_CHARGE">
            <description>
                <p>At 18th level your command over the battlefield provokes your allies to push their abilities to their limits. As a bonus action, you can expend one use of your rally to guide your allies in a combined effort, rather than the normal effects.</p>
                <p class="indent">You target another willing creature within 60 feet of you who can understand you. The target gains 2d10 temporary hit points and can take one additional action during its next turn, on top of its regular action and a possible bonus action.</p>
                <p class="indent">When you use this feature, you can expend additional uses of your rally to target one additional creature per use after the first. The creatures must be within 30 feet of each other when you target them.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="Rally">
                <description>You target another willing creature within 60 feet of you who can understand you. The target gains 2d10 temporary hit points and can take one additional action during its next turn, on top of its regular action and a possible bonus action. You can expend additional uses of your rally to target one additional creature per use after the first. The creatures must be within 30 feet of each other when you target them.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    <element name="Huntmaster" type="Archetype" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_COMMANDER_HUNTMASTER">
        <supports>Commander Discipline</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Huntmasters have gained the service of a spirit companion, an otherworldly ally that takes the appearance of a natural creature. While a spirit companion is independent from its master, it always fights besides them, acting as an extension of their leadership. The commander unites its band as one by fostering a powerful sense of kinship.</p>
            <p class="indent">A huntmaster never fights alone— constantly surrounded by spiritual and natural allies alike.</p>
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTMASTER_KINDRED_COMPANION" />
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTMASTER_DIRE_TACTICS" />
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTMASTER_AVATAR_OF_HOPE" />
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTMASTER_UNITY_OF_THE_PACK" />
         </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTMASTER_KINDRED_COMPANION" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTMASTER_DIRE_TACTICS" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTMASTER_AVATAR_OF_HOPE" level="13" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTMASTER_UNITY_OF_THE_PACK" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Kindred Companion" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTMASTER_KINDRED_COMPANION">
            <description>
                <p>At 3rd level, you gain the service of a spirit from another plane — the spirit companion. The spirit companion has its own personality and is friendly to you and your allies.</p>
                <p>When you gain the spirit companion you determine its form including its size (Small or Medium), its type (a celestial, a fey, or a fiend), and whether it has a climb speed or a swim speed. It can be bipedal or quadrupedal, but its statistics do not change, using the statistics on the next page.</p>
                <p class="indent">The spirit companion has a number of hit dice (which are d8s) equal to your level in this class. If it dies, the bond you share with it can bring it back to life. You can spend 50 gp and eight hours in solidarity to revive the spirit companion, even if you don't possess its body. This cost represents the time and labor needed to guide its soul back to the living. On occasion, a spirit companion will return to life with a different form than it originally had.</p>
                <h5 class="caption">FIGHTING ALONGSIDE YOUR COMPANION</h5>
                <p>During combat, the spirit companion shares your initiative count but takes its turn immediately after yours.</p>
                <p class="indent">The spirit companion can move and use its reaction on its own, but otherwise requires your command, using your bonus action. If you make no more than one attack on your turn, you can command it to take an action from its stat block or the Dash, Disengage, Help, Hide or Search action. Otherwise, it takes the Dodge action on its own. While it is away from you, the spirit companion takes actions without your command.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can target the spirit companion with a decree as you would any other creature. It understands your verbal commands and your somatic gestures.</p>
                <h5 class="caption">RALLYING HOWL</h5>
                <p>Your spirit companion is an extension of your command. When you use your rally, you can rally the spirit companion as an additional creature without counting towards the total number of rallied creatures.</p>
                <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_COMPANION_SPIRIT_COMPANION" />
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>During combat, the spirit companion shares your initiative count but takes its turn immediately after yours. The spirit companion can move and use its reaction on its own, but otherwise requires your command, using your bonus action. When you use your rally, you can rally the spirit companion as an additional creature without counting towards the total number of rallied creatures.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Companion" name="Huntmaster Spirit Companion" supports="Huntmaster Commander" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Dire Tactics" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTMASTER_DIRE_TACTICS">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, you are at your most capable when you fight alongside the spirit companion. While it's close, you coordinate attacks with it to distract your foes.</p>
                <p class="indent">While the spirit companion is within 30 feet of you and you're able to see it, its movement doesn't provoke opportunity attacks from creatures you can see. If it hits a creature with a melee attack while in range it marks the target until the end of your next turn, granting you advantage on your next attack against the marked target.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>While the spirit companion is within 30 feet of you and you're able to see it, its movement doesn't provoke opportunity attacks from creatures you can see. If it hits a creature with a melee attack while in range it marks the target until the end of your next turn, granting you advantage on your next attack against the marked target.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Avatar of Hope" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTMASTER_AVATAR_OF_HOPE">
            <description>
                <p>At 13th level, the spirit companion is bringer of hope, uniting you and your allies under one cause. While the spirit companion is rallied, it creates an aura of courage in a 30 foot radius around it. Creatures of your choice have advantage on Wisdom saving throws and gain the maximum number of temporary hit points from any sources while in range.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>While the spirit companion is rallied, it creates an aura of courage in a 30 foot radius around it. Creatures of your choice have advantage on Wisdom saving throws and gain the maximum number of temporary hit points from any sources while in range.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Unity of the Pack" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTMASTER_UNITY_OF_THE_PACK">
            <description>
                <p>At 18th level, rallying your allies creates a strong kinship among one another. When a member of the pack goes down, the presence of nearby allies inspires it to power through even severe injuries.</p>
                <p class="indent">If damage would reduce you or a creature rallied by you to zero hit points, that creature can make a Wisdom saving throw if it's within 30 feet of a different creature rallied by you. If it succeeds the creature drops to 1 hit point instead, otherwise it is immediately stabilized. The save DC for this effect equals 10 or half the damage taken, whichever is greater.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>If damage would reduce you or a creature rallied by you to zero hit points, that creature can make a Wisdom saving throw (save DC 10 or half the damage taken, whichever is greater) if it's within 30 feet of a different creature rallied by you. If it succeeds the creature drops to 1 hit point instead, otherwise it is immediately stabilized.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    <element name="Dread Lord" type="Archetype" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_COMMANDER_DREAD_LORD">
        <supports>Commander Discipline</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Bards sing legends of the infamous chieftains who lead campaigns of terror, conquerors whose name alone is enough to cause fear. Wherever they go, armies of blood thirsty followers trail behind them, leaving death and destruction in their wake. These commanders are ruthless warlords who trample anyone that stands in their path. The only people who survive an encounter with an infamous dread lord are those purposefully left to tell the tale.</p>
            <p class="indent">The stench of death is ever present around a dread lord's company. The terror brought on by a dread lord is as powerful as the sharpness of its blades.</p>
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAD_LORD_MENACING" />
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAD_LORD_INCITE_VIOLENCE" />
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAD_LORD_CAMPAIGN_OF_TERROR" />
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAD_LORD_SMITE_THE_WEAK" />
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAD_LORD_DREAD_LORDS_REVENGE" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAD_LORD_MENACING" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAD_LORD_INCITE_VIOLENCE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAD_LORD_CAMPAIGN_OF_TERROR" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAD_LORD_SMITE_THE_WEAK" level="13" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAD_LORD_DREAD_LORDS_REVENGE" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Menacing" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAD_LORD_MENACING">
            <description>
                <p>At 3rd level, you are proficient in the Intimidation skill. If you are already proficient with it, you instead gain proficiency in one other skill from the class's skill list.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency, Menacing" supports="Skill, Commander" default="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INTIMIDATION" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Incite Violence" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAD_LORD_INCITE_VIOLENCE">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 3rd level, if you make no more than one attack when you take the Attack action, you can use your bonus action to provoke an ally towards attacking a certain creature.</p>
                <p class="indent">You select a creature within 30 feet, and if your ally can understand you, it gains advantage on its next attack against that creature before the end of its next turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>You select a creature within 30 feet, and if your ally can understand you, it gains advantage on its next attack against that creature before the end of its next turn.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Campaign of Terror" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAD_LORD_CAMPAIGN_OF_TERROR">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, your name carries with it a mortal terror. As a bonus action, you can expend one use of your rally to instill dread into nearby creatures, rather than the normal effects.</p>
                <p class="indent">You force a number of creatures within 60 feet up to your Charisma modifier (minimum of 1 creature) to make Wisdom saving throws. On a failed save, a target becomes unnerved by you for up to 1 minute, granting you advantage on attacks and Intimidation checks made against it for the duration. The target can repeat the saving throw at the end of its turns if it's unable to see you, ending the effect on itself on success.</p>
                <p class="indent">The save DC for the initial and subsequent saving throws equals 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier. A target that can't be frightened is unaffected by it.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can use this feature once without expending a use of your rally, but must finish a long rest before you can do so again.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="Rally">
                <description>You force up to {{campaign-of-terror:targets}} creatures within 60 feet to make a Wisdom saving throw (save DC {{campaign-of-terror:save-dc}}) or become unnerved by you for up to 1 minute, granting you advantage on attacks and Intimidation checks made against it for the duration. You can use this feature once without expending a use of your rally, but must finish a long rest before you can do so again.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="campaign-of-terror:targets" value="1" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="campaign-of-terror:targets" value="charisma:modifier" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="campaign-of-terror:save-dc" value="8" />
                <stat name="campaign-of-terror:save-dc" value="proficiency" />
                <stat name="campaign-of-terror:save-dc" value="charisma:modifier" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Smite the Weak" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAD_LORD_SMITE_THE_WEAK">
            <description>
                <p>At 13th level, you have advantage on melee attacks against a creature if its hit points are equal to or less than your level in this class + your Charisma score, and if you hit it with an attack, it is a critical hit.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You have advantage on melee attacks against a creature if its hit points are equal to or less than {{smite-the-weak:hp}}, and if you hit it with an attack, it is a critical hit.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="smite-the-weak:hp" value="level:commander" />
                <stat name="smite-the-weak:hp" value="charisma:modifier" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Dread Lord's Revenge" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAD_LORD_DREAD_LORDS_REVENGE">
            <description>
                <p>At 18th level, your dreaded reputation permeates even the most hardened minds. Other creatures can't gain advantage on saving throws made to resist being frightened by you. If a creature's Intelligence score is 4 or higher, you also ignore any immunity to the Frightened condition it may have.</p>
                <p class="indent">Furthermore, your melee attacks deal an additional 2d6 psychic damage to frightened creatures and those under the effects of your Campaign of Terror.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Other creatures can't gain advantage on saving throws made to resist being frightened by you. If a creature's Intelligence score is 4 or higher, you also ignore any immunity to the Frightened condition it may have. Your melee attacks deal an additional 2d6 psychic damage to frightened creatures and those under the effects of your Campaign of Terror.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

  <!-- Commander Skills -->
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ANIMALHANDLING">
        <supports>Commander</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_HISTORY">
        <supports>Commander</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT">
        <supports>Commander</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_MEDICINE">
        <supports>Commander</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_NATURE">
        <supports>Commander</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INTIMIDATION">
        <supports>Commander</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION">
        <supports>Commander</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERSUASION">
        <supports>Commander</supports>
    </append>

  <!-- Huntmaster Companion -->
    <element name="Spirit Companion" type="Companion" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_COMPANION_SPIRIT_COMPANION">
        <supports>Huntmaster Commander</supports>
		<description>
            <p class="flavor">Small or Medium celestial, fey, or fiend, lawful neutral</p>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Armor Class</strong> 12 + your Charisma modifier</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points</strong> equals five times your commander level</li>
                <li><strong>Speed</strong> 30 ft., climb or swim 30 ft. (your choice)</li>
            </ul>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>STR</td><td>DEX</td><td>CON</td><td>INT</td><td>WIS</td><td>CHA</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>14 (+2)</td><td>14 (+2</td><td>13 (+1)</td><td>4 (-2)</td><td>12 (+1)</td><td>10 (0)</td></tr>
            </table>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Saving Throws</strong> Dex +4, Wis +3</li>
                <li><strong>Skills</strong> Perception +3, Stealth +4</li>
                <li><strong>Senses</strong> darkvision 60ft., passive Perception 13</li>
                <li><strong>Languages</strong> Understands your somatic gestures and the languages you speak, and can convey simple ideas using its body language.</li>
            </ul>
            <p><strong><em>Born of Unity.</em></strong> If the spirit companion has died within the last hour, you can use your bonus action to touch it and expend a use of your rally. The spirit companion returns to life after 1 minute with all of its hit points restored.</p>
            <p><strong><em>Might of the Master.</em></strong> The following numbers increase by 1 when your proficiency bonus increases by 1: the spirit companion’s skill and saving throw bonuses (above) and the bonuses to hit and damage of its thrash attack.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">Actions (Requires your Command)</h5>
            <p><strong><em>Thrash.</em></strong> <em>Melee Weapon Attack:</em> +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. <em>Hit:</em> 1d6 + 2 bludgeoning, piercing, or slashing damage, which ignores resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage.</p>
            <p><strong><em>Gain Resolve (3/day).</em></strong> The spirit companion gains temporary hit points equal to your 1d8 + half your level in this class.</p>
            <div class="sidebar">
                <h5 class="caption">ABOUT SPIRIT COMPANIONS</h5>
                <p>The appearance of a spirit companion is most often animal-like in form. For instance, a spirit companion may appear to be a bear, a lion, a wolf, or even a dragon. Its largest size may range anywhere from 3 feet at the shortest to 8 feet at the tallest. Because to their otherworldly nature, some spirit companions have features that give them a unique appearance. For instance, a celestial may have a shimmering aura around it, a fey may have bright patterns in its fur, and a fiend may have a demonic appearance.</p>
                <p class="indent">A spirit companion has its own personality unique from its commander's. Its bond is always the commander it travels with. You can select a trait for the spirit companion from the following table.</p>
                <h5 class="caption">SPIRIT COMPANION TRAITS</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>d6</td><td>Personality Trait</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1</td><td>I am always hungry. I can sense food a mile away, it's there waiting for me.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>2</td><td>Despite my braveness in battle, I whimper and whine when my best friend isn't around.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3</td><td>My curiosity often gets the better of me. I always stick my nose where it doesn't belong.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>4</td><td>I have a sworn duty to protect my friends. If anyone approaches them, I get defensive.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5</td><td>I am incredibly stubborn. When I'm tired I sit down and refuse to move.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>6</td><td>I expect a treat any time I do something good!</td></tr>
                </table>
            </div>
        </description>
		<setters>
			<set name="strength">14</set>
			<set name="dexterity">14</set>
			<set name="constitution">13</set>
			<set name="intelligence">4</set>
			<set name="wisdom">12</set>
			<set name="charisma">10</set>
			<set name="ac">12 + your Charisma modifier</set>
			<set name="hp">equals five times your commander level</set>
			<set name="speed">30 ft., climb or swim 30 ft.</set>
            <set name="senses">Darkvision 60ft., passive Perception 13</set>
			<set name="languages">Understands your somatic gestures and the languages you speak, and can convey simple ideas using its body language.</set>
			<set name="skills">Perception +3, Stealth +4</set>
            <set name="saves">Dex +4, Wis +3</set>
			<set name="type">Celestial, fey, or fiend</set>
			<set name="size">Small or Medium</set>
			<set name="alignment">lawful neutral</set>
			<set name="challenge">1</set>
            <set name="traits">ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_COMPANION_TRAIT_SPIRIT_COMPANION_BORN_OF_UNITY,ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_COMPANION_TRAIT_SPIRIT_COMPANION_MIGHT_OF_THE_MASTER</set>
			<set name="actions">ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_COMPANION_ACTION_SPIRIT_COMPANION_THRASH,ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_COMPANION_ACTION_SPIRIT_COMPANION_GAIN_RESOLVE</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="companion:ac" value="12" />
            <stat name="companion:ac" value="charisma:modifier" />
			<stat name="companion:hp:max" value="level:commander" />
			<stat name="companion:hp:max" value="level:commander" />
			<stat name="companion:hp:max" value="level:commander" />
			<stat name="companion:hp:max" value="level:commander" />
			<stat name="companion:hp:max" value="level:commander" />
			<stat name="companion:speed" value="30" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="companion:proficiency" value="proficiency" />
			<stat name="companion:stealth:proficiency" value="companion:proficiency" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="companion:perception:proficiency" value="companion:proficiency" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="companion:dexterity:save:proficiency" value="companion:proficiency" bonus="proficiency" />
			<stat name="companion:wisdom:save:proficiency" value="companion:proficiency" bonus="proficiency" />
		</rules>
	</element>
        <element name="Born of Unity" type="Companion Trait" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_COMPANION_TRAIT_SPIRIT_COMPANION_BORN_OF_UNITY">
            <description>
                <p>If the spirit companion has died within the last hour, you can use your bonus action to touch it and expend a use of your rally. The spirit companion returns to life after 1 minute with all of its hit points restored.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>If the spirit companion has died within the last hour, you can use your bonus action to touch it and expend a use of your rally. The spirit companion returns to life after 1 minute with all of its hit points restored.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Might of the Master" type="Companion Trait" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_COMPANION_TRAIT_SPIRIT_COMPANION_MIGHT_OF_THE_MASTER">
            <description>
                <p>The following numbers increase by 1 when your proficiency bonus increases by 1: the spirit companion’s skill and saving throw bonuses (above) and the bonuses to hit and damage of its thrash attack.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Total melee attack bonus is 2 + your proficiency.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Thrash" type="Companion Action" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_COMPANION_ACTION_SPIRIT_COMPANION_THRASH">
            <description>
                <p>Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 1d6 + 2 bludgeoning, piercing, or slashing damage, which ignores resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 1d6 + 2 bludgeoning, piercing, or slashing damage, which ignores resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Gain Resolve (3/day)" type="Companion Action" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_COMPANION_ACTION_SPIRIT_COMPANION_GAIN_RESOLVE">
            <description>
                <p>The spirit companion gains temporary hit points equal to your 1d8 + half your level in this class.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>The spirit companion gains temporary hit points equal to your 1d8 + half your level in this class.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

</elements>