<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>The Tamer Class v1.1</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="class-tamer.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/classes/class-tamer.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="The Tamer Class" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_VERELTH_GMBINDER_SOURCE_THE_TAMER_CLASS">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation">TAMER</set>
            <set name="url">https://www.gmbinder.com/share/-MIuAfv3JrhsSUWSqFbh</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" abbreviation="VERELTH" url="https://www.gmbinder.com/profile/verelth">Verelth</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20210114</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Tamer" type="Class" source="source" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_TAMER">
        <description>
            <p>A young human shepherd brandishes his crook as wolves approach from all sides. In a flash of light a bear appears by his side, and they face the foes as one.</p>
            <p class="indent">A goliath treads lighly upon the snow as ahead of him a winter wolf eyes his approach. He offers a flank of elk, speaking a few words in giant and showing a pale mark above his heart in the shape of a fang. The wolf accepts the offering, and it fades away as a white mark appears next to his heart.</p>
            <p class="indent">With a fierce roar, a chimera shouts a challenge to an approaching horde of goblins, and the elf upon it’s back nocks an arrow to her bow. She grins, as from behind the goblins, an owlbear devours their chieftan, and they scatter in fear.</p>
            <p class="indent">Tamers seek to use the power of the wilds as their own. They see the creatures that inhabit the world as untapped potential, and will stop at nothing to tame a beast that has caught their eye.</p>
            <h4>VARIED APPROACH</h4>
            <p>Each tamer takes a different approach to taming and fighting with their creatures. Some tamers see their summons as valued allies, and see taming as a way to make new friends and travel the world with them. Other tamers see the creatures around them as an untapped source of power, and desire to tame only the strongest creatures.</p>
            <p class="indent">No matter their approach, most tamers traverse the wilds in order to expand their team. Each new habitat or terrain brings with it wonderous new creatures to discover, and possibly some new allies. Some strong tamers even make their way into the lairs of formidable monstrosities in order to coerce them into aiding them, or, failing that, forcing them into their mark.</p>
            <h4>THE MARK OF THE WILDS</h4>
            <p>One thing that all tamers have in common, regardless of their background or approach to taming, is their mark. Each tamer has a mark somewhere on their body, which gives them their magic ability and allows them to tame and summon monsters.</p>
            <p class="indent">There are many different ways in which a tamer obtains a mark. Some have one from birth, their mark inherited from a family member, sometimes even inheriting their first beast from a mother or father. Others recieve one from a fey creature, who chooses them to be a warden of the wilds. Some tamers naturally develop a mark, as a result of a deep connection to a creature close to them and a desire for a stronger bond.</p>
            <p class="indent">Marks can take on a variety of forms, appearing in different colors, shapes, and positions. The mark may appear anywhere on the body, and can range in size from coin-sized to the size of a dinner plate. Sometimes the mark takes on the appearance of a body part of the Tamers first tamed creature, such as a fang or paw. Often the mark glows when the tamer summons a creature or casts a spell.</p>
            <div class="caption">
                <h5 class="caption">Dragonmarks</h5>
                <p>You may have noticed the the Tamer Mark feature of this class bears a striking resemblance to the Dragonmark feature from the Eberron setting. This class was heavily inspired by the mark of Handling, and fulfills a desire to flesh it out and fill the niche of a beast taming focused class. Feel free to flavor this classes abilities as coming entirely from a Dragonmark your character possesses.</p>
            </div>
            <h2>CLASS FEATURES</h2>
            <p>As an tamer, you gain the following class features.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">HIT POINTS</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Hit Dice:</strong> 1d8 per tamer level</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at 1st Level:</strong> 8 + your Constitution modifier</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at Higher Levels:</strong> 1d8 (or 5) + your Constitution modifier per tamer level after 1st</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">PROFICIENCIES</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled mb">
                <li><strong>Armor:</strong> Light armor, medium armor, shields</li>
                <li><strong>Weapons:</strong> Simple weapons,</li>
                <li><strong>Tools:</strong> None</li>
            </ul>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Saving Throws:</strong> Intelligence, Wisdom</li>
                <li><strong>Skills:</strong> Choose three from Animal Handling, Athletics, Insight, Nature, Perception, Persuasion, Stealth, and Survival.</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">EQUIPMENT</h5>
            <p>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>(a) a light crossbow and quiver of 20 bolts or (b) any simple weapon and a shield.</li>
                <li>(a) scale mail or (b) leather armor.</li>
                <li>An explorer’s pack.</li>
                <li></li>
            </ul>
        <!-- class table here -->
            <h5 class="caption">THE TAMER</h5>
            <table class="class-features">
                <thead>
                    <tr><td class="col-5">Level</td><td class="col-10">Proficiency Level</td><td class="left">Features</td><td class="col-10">Cantrips Known</td><td class="col-10">Spells Known</td><td>1st</td><td>2nd</td><td>3rd</td><td>4th</td><td>5th</td><td>Summon CR</td><td>Tamed Creatures</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td> 1st</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Spellcasting, Mark of the Tamer</td><td>2</td><td>2</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>1/4</td><td>1</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 2nd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Incremental Growth, Expanded Mark</td><td>2</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>1/2</td><td>2</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 3rd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Taming Approach, Expanded Mark</td><td>2</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>1</td><td>3</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 4th</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>2</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>1</td><td>3</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 5th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Expanded Mark, Bigger Friends, Perfect Coordination</td><td>2</td><td>5</td><td>4</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>1</td><td>4</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 6th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Combined Might</td><td>2</td><td>5</td><td>4</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>2</td><td>4</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 7th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Approach Feature</td><td>2</td><td>6</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>2</td><td>4</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 8th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>2</td><td>6</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>2</td><td>4</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 9th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">─</td><td>2</td><td>7</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>3</td><td>4</td></tr>
                <tr><td>10th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Expanded Mark</td><td>3</td><td>7</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>3</td><td>5</td></tr>
                <tr><td>11th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Approach Feature</td><td>3</td><td>8</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>3</td><td>5</td></tr>
                <tr><td>12th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>3</td><td>8</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>4</td><td>5</td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">─</td><td>3</td><td>9</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>1</td><td>—</td><td>4</td><td>5</td></tr>
                <tr><td>14th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Long Distance Summons</td><td>4</td><td>9</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>1</td><td>—</td><td>4</td><td>5</td></tr>
                <tr><td>15th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Approach Feature</td><td>4</td><td>10</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>5</td><td>5</td></tr>
                <tr><td>16th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>4</td><td>10</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>5</td><td>5</td></tr>
                <tr><td>17th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">─</td><td>4</td><td>11</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>1</td><td>5</td><td>5</td></tr>
                <tr><td>18th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Expanded Mark</td><td>4</td><td>11</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>1</td><td>6</td><td>6</td></tr>
                <tr><td>19th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>4</td><td>12</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>6</td><td>6</td></tr>
                <tr><td>20th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Perfect Harmony</td><td>4</td><td>12</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>6</td><td>6</td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_TAMER_SPELLCASTING" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_TAMER_MARK_OF_THE_TAMER" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_TAMER_INCREMENTAL_GROWTH" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_TAMER_EXPANDED_MARK" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_TAMER_TAMING_APPROACH" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_TAMER_TAMING_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_TAMER_BIGGER_FRIENDS" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_TAMER_PERFECT_COORDINATION" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_TAMER_COMBINED_MIGHT" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_TAMER_LONG_DISTANCE_SUMMONS" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_TAMER_PERFECT_HARMONY" />
            <h5>MULTICLASSING</h5>
            <p>To multiclass into tamer, you must meet the following prerequisites. If you multiclass into tamer, you also gain the following proficiencies.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b>Prerequisite:</b> 13 Wisdom</p>
            <p class="indent"><b>Proficiencies gained:</b> Animal Handling skill, light armor.</p>
            <p class="indent">When gaining spell slots, treat this class like a Paladin or Ranger. (Add half of your tamer level rounded down to the multiclassing spell slots table.)</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="hd">d8</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_TAMER_SPELLCASTING" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_TAMER_MARK_OF_THE_TAMER" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_TAMER_INCREMENTAL_GROWTH" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_TAMER_EXPANDED_MARK" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_TAMER_TAMING_APPROACH" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_TAMER_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" level="4" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_TAMER_BIGGER_FRIENDS" level="5" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_TAMER_PERFECT_COORDINATION" level="5" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_TAMER_COMBINED_MIGHT" level="6" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_TAMER_LONG_DISTANCE_SUMMONS" level="14" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_TAMER_PERFECT_HARMONY" level="20" />
        </rules>
        <multiclass id="ID_author_source_MULTICLASS_TAMER">
            <prerequisite>Wisdom 13</prerequisite>
            <requirements>[wis:13]</requirements>
            <setters>
                <set name="multiclass proficiencies"></set>
            </setters>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS" />
            </rules>
        </multiclass>
    </element>
        <element name="Spellcasting" type="Class Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_TAMER_SPELLCASTING">
            <description>
                <p>Using your own magical power in addition to the power of your summons, you may cast spells to communicate with beasts and strengthen your companions.</p>
                <h5>CANTRIPS</h5>
                <p>At 1st level, you know two cantrips of your choice from the tamer spell list. You learn additional tamer cantrips of your choice at higher levels, as shown in the Cantrips Known column of the Tamer table.</p>
                <h5>SPELL SLOTS</h5>
                <p>The tamer table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your tamer spells of 1st level and higher. To cast one of your tamer spells, you must expend a slot of the spell’s level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.</p>
                <h5>SPELLS KNOWN OF 1ST LEVEL AND HIGHER</h5>
                <p>You know two 1st-level spells of your choice from the tamer spell list. The Spells Known column of the tamer table shows when you learn more tamer spells of your choice.</p>
                <p class="indent">Each of these spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots. For instance, when you reach 5th level in this class, you can learn one new spell of 1st or 2nd level.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, when you gain a level in this class, you can choose one of the tamer spells you know and replace it with another spell from the tamer spell list, which also must be of a level for which you have spell slots.</p>
                <p class="indent">Spell save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier.</p>
                <p class="indent">Spell attack modifier = your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier.</p>
                <h5>SPELLCASTING FOCUS</h5>
                <p>Your tamer mark acts as a spellcasting focus for your tamer spells.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Mark of the Tamer" type="Class Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_TAMER_MARK_OF_THE_TAMER">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 1st level, you absorb beasts into a mark on your body. It can be anywhere on your body and look like any symbol, but regardless of form, it acts as a spellcasting focus and glows slightly when you cast a spell or summon a creature.</p>
                <h5>SUMMONING CREATURES</h5>
                <p>As an action, you may summon a creature you have tamed from your mark. It appears within five feet of you, or in the closest space it can fit in if the spaces around you are occupied. If there is no space for your creature to appear within 15 feet, this ability fails. Your summons are dismissed immediately if they reach 0 hit points and are knocked unconscious, or you may dismiss a summon early as a bonus action. You may not use this ability to summon a creature that has been knocked unconscious.</p>
                <p class="indent">Your summons recover completely upon a long rest, but regain no hit points on a short rest. A creature’s hit points remain the same if it is dismissed and resummoned. You control your summons in combat, and you and your summons act on your initiative count, and act one after the other, in any order. Your summon doesn’t act unless you command it to. On your turn, you can verbally command your summon to move (no action required by you.). You can use your action to verbally command your summon to take the Attack, Dash, Disengage, Dodge, or Help action. If the creature has any legendary or Lair Actions, you can’t use them. You may only have one creature summoned at a time.</p>
                <h5>TAMING CREATURES</h5>
                <p>You may tame additional creatures to add to your mark. You may only tame creatures whose CR is equal to or less than your summon CR, as shown in the Tamer table. At 1st level, you begin with a medium or smaller Beast of your choice. At first level, you may only tame Beasts, but beginning at 5th level you may also tame Monstrosities.</p>
                <p class="indent">You may tame a beast by besting it in combat. As a bonus action, you may target a creature within sight, if it dies within one minute, you may add it to your mark if it is tamable. The creature must be killed by you or your allies, if it dies to another enemy, old age, or another effect outside your control, it is not tamed.</p>
                <p class="indent">You may also convince creatures to join you willingly. As an action, you may make an Animal Handling check to tame a creature that is friendly to you and within 10 feet, and make that check at advantage if the creature is charmed. The Animal Handling check has a DC equal to 10 plus twice the creature’s CR. If you fail this check, the creature may become hostile to you, and you may not attempt this on that creature again until you complete a long rest.</p>
                <p class="indent">You may only have a number of tamed creatures equal to your Tamed Creatures limit, as shown in the Tamer table. If you would tame a creature while you have the maximum number of tamed creatures, you may release one of your other summons, it is transfered to a smaller mark next to your Tamer mark. You may only have a number of creatures stored in this way equal to your wisdom modifier, if you have no more room, you must set creatures free. You may swap which creatures are in your Tamer Mark and which ones are stored as part of a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Incremental Growth" type="Class Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_TAMER_INCREMENTAL_GROWTH">
            <description>
                <p>Your creatures grow alongside you. When you reach 2nd level, and upon each level up onwards, the creatures you currently have tamed gain a hit die and increase their hit points accordingly. Whenever you gain the Ability Score Improvement class feature, your creatures’ abilities also improve. Your creatures each can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or they can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, your summons can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature unless their descriptions say otherwise. Additionally, at levels 6, 12, and 18, you may have each of your summons increase the damage die of one of their attacks by one.</p>
                <p class="indent">When you tame a new summon, you treat it as if it was captured at the earliest level you could have tamed it at, and it gains all of the improvements from that level up to your current level.</p>
                <div class="sidebar">
                    <h5 class="caption">Evolving Beasts</h5>
                    <p>Having your beasts gain Health and damage die are not the only ways of having your beasts grow stronger. With your DM’s permission, you may have your creatures evolve into larger or more powerful versions of their base form. For example, you may have a wolf turn into a dire wolf when you reach level three, and have it become a winter wolf when you reach level nine. These evolutions replace the ordinary health and damage increases they would recieve from this ability.</p>
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Expanded Mark" type="Class Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_TAMER_EXPANDED_MARK">
            <description>
                <p>At 2nd level, and again at levels 3, 5, 10, and 18, you increase the maximum number of creatures you may store in your mark by one.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Taming Approach" type="Class Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_TAMER_TAMING_APPROACH">
            <description>
                <p>At 3rd level, you have begun to perfect your approach to taming, either: Canine, Ursine, Feline, or Shepherd, all of which are detailed at the end of the class description. Your choice grants you features at 3rd level and again at 7th, 11th, and 15th level.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Ability Score Improvement" type="Class Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_TAMER_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
				<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Tamer 4)" supports="Improvement Option,Tamer,4" level="4" />
				<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Tamer 8)" supports="Improvement Option,Tamer,8" level="8" />
				<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Tamer 12)" supports="Improvement Option,Tamer,12" level="12" />
				<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Tamer 16)" supports="Improvement Option,Tamer,16" level="16" />
				<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Tamer 19)" supports="Improvement Option,Tamer,19" level="19" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Bigger Friends" type="Class Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_TAMER_BIGGER_FRIENDS">
            <description>
                <p>At 5th level, your knowledge of the creatures around you has increased considerably. You may now tame Monstrosities in addition to beasts, and spells you cast that target Beasts may now also target Monstrosities. You may not tame Monstrosities with humanoid features and intelligence. (Ex. You may tame a Manticore, but not a Lamia)</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Perfect Coordination" type="Class Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_TAMER_PERFECT_COORDINATION">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 5th level, you and your summons have mastered the ability to act synchronously, your summons now act one their own, without any command or action required from you.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Combined Might" type="Class Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_TAMER_COMBINED_MIGHT">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 6th level, the magic you use to cast your spells has seeped into your tamed creatures. Your summons attacks are now considered magical for the purpose of overcoming resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Long Distance Summons" type="Class Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_TAMER_LONG_DISTANCE_SUMMONS">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 14th level, the magic that brings forth your summons from your mark strengthens. You may summon your creatures up to 100 feet away from you. In addition, you may use a bonus action to swap places with a summoned creature. You can use this ability a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier (Minimum of once) and regain all uses on a short or long rest. This ability fails if you and that creature are not on the same plane of existence.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Perfect Harmony" type="Class Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_TAMER_PERFECT_HARMONY">
            <description>
                <p>At 20th level, you exist in perfect harmony with all creatures. You may now tame any kind of creature, except humanoids or creatures with humanoid levels of intelligence. (This is up to your DM to decide.) You may also tame creatures of CR 7 or 8. You may only have one creature of CR 7 or 8 in your mark at a time.</p>
                <p class="indent">Creatures now recognize you as a master tamer. All Beasts are friendly to you, and you have advantage on all Animal Handling checks.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>

    <!-- Tamer Approaches -->
    <element name="The Canine Approach" type="Archetype" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_TAMER_THE_CANINE_APPROACH">
        <supports>Tamer Approach</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Some tamers see themselves as part of the pack. To them, they are just another animal, and are not above wading into the fray alongside their allies.</p>
            <p class="indent">Canine tamers train with weapons and armor to make up for their thin skin and lack of fangs, and make formidible enemies. Strong, dignified, and resolute, Canine tamers fight as a wolf does, with guile and vigor.</p>
            <div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CANINE_CANINE_MAGIC" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CANINE_LUPINE_WARRIOR" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CANINE_TANDEM_STRIKES" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CANINE_SWIFT_ATTACK" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CANINE_SHARED_MIGHT" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CANINE_TWIN_SUMMONS" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CANINE_CANINE_MAGIC" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CANINE_LUPINE_WARRIOR" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CANINE_TANDEM_STRIKES" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CANINE_SWIFT_ATTACK" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CANINE_SHARED_MIGHT" level="11" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CANINE_TWIN_SUMMONS" level="15" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Canine Magic" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CANINE_CANINE_MAGIC">
            <description>
                <p>You learn an additional spell when you reach certain levels in this class, as shown in the Canine Spells table. The spell counts as a tamer spell for you, but it doesn’t count against the number of tamer spells you know.</p>
                <h5 class="caption">Canine Spells</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Tamer Level</td><td>Spell</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>ensnaring strike</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>barkskin</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><em>haste</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>13th</td><td><em>Mordenkainen’s faithful hound</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>17th</td><td><em>steel wind strike</em></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENSNARING_STRIKE" spellcasting="Tamer" known="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BARKSKIN" spellcasting="Tamer" known="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HASTE" spellcasting="Tamer" known="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MORDENKAINENS_FAITHFUL_HOUND" spellcasting="Tamer" known="true" level="13" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_STEEL_WIND_STRIKE" spellcasting="Tamer" known="true" level="17" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Lupine Warrior" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CANINE_LUPINE_WARRIOR">
            <description>
                <p>At 3rd level, after observing the fighting tactics of the creatures around you, you have learned how to fight with sword and dagger as they do with tooth and claw. You gain proficiency with heavy armor and martial weapons.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Tandem Strikes" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CANINE_TANDEM_STRIKES">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 3rd level, you and your summons are more effective when attacking together. When you hit an enemy with a weapon attack, you mark it. The next time one of your summons hits that enemy with an attack, it deals an extra 1D6 damage of that attack’s damage type and consumes the mark. This damage increases to 2D6 at 7th level, 3D6 at 11th level, and 4D6 at 15th level. This mark fades away at the end of your next turn if not already consumed.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Swift Attack" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CANINE_SWIFT_ATTACK">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 7th level, when you use your action to cast a Tamer spell, you may make one weapon attack as a bonus action that turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Shared Might" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CANINE_SHARED_MIGHT">
            <description>
                <p>At 11th level, the magic that flows through your veins now courses through your summons. When you cast a spell that targets only yourself, you may have it also target all of your active summons. If you lose concentration on the spell, it ends for all targets.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Twin Summons" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CANINE_TWIN_SUMMONS">
            <description>
                <p>At 15th level, you may now call on the full might of the pack. As a bonus action, you may summon an additional creature, and for the next minute, you may have two summons out at the same time. You may use this ability only once, and regain the ability to do so upon a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>

    <element name="The Ursine Approach" type="Archetype" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_TAMER_THE_URSINE_APPROACH">
        <supports>Tamer Approach</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Some tamers value strength above all else. These tamers take the Ursine Approach to taming, choosing to tame juggernauts, capable of breaking through enemy lines and laying waste to their foes.</p>
            <p class="indent">Some tamers of this school choose to let their summons take care of the close range fighting, preferring to support from a safe distance. Others choose to use their summons as mounts, riding into battle from a safe vantage point and picking off enemies.</p>
            <div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_URSINE_URSINE_MAGIC" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_URSINE_ABUNDANT_VITALITY" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_URSINE_DOMINATING_PRESENCE" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_URSINE_THICK_SKIN" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_URSINE_SAVAGE_FEROCITY" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_URSINE_TITANIC_GROWTH" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_URSINE_URSINE_MAGIC" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_URSINE_ABUNDANT_VITALITY" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_URSINE_DOMINATING_PRESENCE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_URSINE_THICK_SKIN" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_URSINE_SAVAGE_FEROCITY" level="11" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_URSINE_TITANIC_GROWTH" level="15" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Ursine Magic" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_URSINE_URSINE_MAGIC">
            <description>
                <p>You learn an additional spell when you reach certain levels in this class, as shown in the Canine Spells table. The spell counts as a tamer spell for you, but it doesn’t count against the number of tamer spells you know.</p>
                <h5 class="caption">Ursine Spells</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Tamer Level</td><td>Spell</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>shield of faith</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>enlarge/reduce</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><em>aura of vitality</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>13th</td><td><em>stoneskin</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>17th</td><td><em>destructive wave</em></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHIELD_OF_FAITH" spellcasting="Tamer" known="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENLARGE_REDUCE" spellcasting="Tamer" known="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AURA_OF_VITALITY" spellcasting="Tamer" known="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_STONESKIN" spellcasting="Tamer" known="true" level="13" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DESTRUCTIVE_WAVE" spellcasting="Tamer" known="true" level="17" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Abundant Vitality" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_URSINE_ABUNDANT_VITALITY">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 3rd level, you and the creatures you summon are strengthened by the vigorous energy of your magic. Your hit point maximum increases by an amount equal to your level. Each of your summons hit point maximums increase by an amount equal to your level plus their constitution modifier.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Dominating Presence" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_URSINE_DOMINATING_PRESENCE">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 3rd level, when one of your summons hits an enemy with an attack, that enemy is marked. While that enemy is within 5 feet of your summon, it has disadvantage on any attack roll that doesn’t target your summon. This mark fades at the start of your summon’s next turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Thick Skin" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_URSINE_THICK_SKIN">
            <description>
                <p>At 7th level, your summons have toughened up considerably, your summon’s AC becomes their normal AC or 12 plus their constitution modifier, whichever is higher.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Savage Ferocity" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_URSINE_SAVAGE_FEROCITY">
            <description>
                <p>At 11th level, your summons have learned how to brute force their way past almost any obstacle. Each of your summons adds two extra damage dice to one of their attacks. If they have multiattack, they instead add one damage die to each of their attacks. When one of your summons is hit by an attack, they may make one attack as a reaction if they are within range.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Titanic Growth" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_URSINE_TITANIC_GROWTH">
            <description>
                <p>At 15th level, you may use your action to cause your summon to grow explosively in a short period of time. It’s size becomes huge, and it gains temporary hit points equal to half of it’s max hit points, and it’s Strength and Constitution scores become 24. It doubles the number of damage die for each of it’s attacks. Any creature that is in your summon’s space after this transformation is pushed directly away until it is next to your summon. If your creature does not have enough space to transform, it remains at it’s current size, it’s Strength and Constitution scores become 20, and it adds two damage dice to each of it’s attacks. This transformation lasts for one minute. You may only use this ability once, and regain the ability to do so upon a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>

    <element name="The Feline Approach" type="Archetype" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_TAMER_THE_FELINE_APPROACH">
        <supports>Tamer Approach</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Some tamers value the ability to slay enemies before they have a chance to fight back. These tamers take the Feline approach to taming, choosing only the most cunning and vicious of creatures.</p>
            <p class="indent">A Feline tamer prefers stealth and information gathering to raw strength, often sending in small, inconspicuous creatures to scout ahead. They stalk their prey, and only move in when the moment is just right.</p>
            <div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FELINE_FELINE_MAGIC" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FELINE_FELINE_AGILITY" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FELINE_AMBUSH_PREDATOR" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FELINE_KEEN_AWARENESS" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FELINE_GO_FOR_THE_THROAT" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FELINE_PERFECT_STEALTH" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FELINE_FELINE_MAGIC" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FELINE_FELINE_AGILITY" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FELINE_AMBUSH_PREDATOR" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FELINE_KEEN_AWARENESS" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FELINE_GO_FOR_THE_THROAT" level="11" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FELINE_PERFECT_STEALTH" level="15" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Feline Magic" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FELINE_FELINE_MAGIC">
            <description>
                <p>You learn an additional spell when you reach certain levels in this class, as shown in the Canine Spells table. The spell counts as a tamer spell for you, but it doesn’t count against the number of tamer spells you know.</p>
                <h5 class="caption">Feline Spells</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Tamer Level</td><td>Spell</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>hunter’s mark</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>pass without trace</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><em>nondetection</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>13th</td><td><em>freedom of movement</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>17th</td><td><em>far step</em></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HUNTERS_MARK" spellcasting="Tamer" known="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PASS_WITHOUT_TRACE" spellcasting="Tamer" known="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_NONDETECTION" spellcasting="Tamer" known="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FREEDOM_OF_MOVEMENT" spellcasting="Tamer" known="true" level="13" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_FAR_STEP" spellcasting="Tamer" known="true" level="17" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Feline Agility" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FELINE_FELINE_AGILITY">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 3rd level, you and your summons gain the effortless grace and acuity of a cat. You and your summons have proficiency in stealth, and your summons use your proficiency bonus on stealth checks, rather than their own. Additionally, you can communicate with your summons telepathically so long as you are both on the same plane of existence.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Ambush Predator" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FELINE_AMBUSH_PREDATOR">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 3rd level, you and your summons have mastered the art of the ambush. You and your summons have advantage on attack rolls against creatures that have not yet taken a turn in combat. In addition, any hit you or your summons score against a creature that is surprised is a critical hit.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Keen Awareness" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FELINE_KEEN_AWARENESS">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 7th level, you and your summons have the finely tuned senses of a cat. You and your summons gain darkvision out to a range of 60 feet, if you or any of your summons already have darkvision, it instead increases by 30 feet. You and your summons gain a +5 bonus to your passive perception scores, and you gain a bonus to initiative rolls equal to your Wisdom modifier.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Go For The Throat" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FELINE_GO_FOR_THE_THROAT">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 11th level, you and your summons know the weak spots of your enemies. Once per turn, when you or your summon deals damage to an enemy, that attack deals an extra 3D6 if you or your summon had advantage on the attack roll. If you made the attack, it must use a finesse or ranged weapon to gain the extra damage. You or your summon don’t need advantage on the attack roll if another enemy of the target is within 5 feet of it, that enemy isn’t incapacitated, and you or your summon do not have disadvantage on the attack roll.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Perfect Stealth" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FELINE_PERFECT_STEALTH">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 15th level, you and your summons know how to perfectly blend into your environments. As an action, both you and your summon may become invisible for a minute. This invisibility is not broken by taking damage or making attacks. You may use this ability only once, and regain the ability to do so upon a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>

    <element name="The Shepherd Approach" type="Archetype" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_TAMER_THE_SHEPHERD_APPROACH">
        <supports>Tamer Approach</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Some Tamers wish only to guide and protect their flock, seeing the value of companions as guides and treasured friends. A shepherd sees the world as a dangerous place, and uses their power to protect the weak and the innocent.</p>
            <p class="indent">A shepherd supports their allies, calling on their woodland friends for help and quietly ensuring everyone reaches their destination unharmed.</p>
            <div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHEPHERD_SHEPHERD_MAGIC" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHEPHERD_SHEPHERDS_CROOK" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHEPHERD_DEEP_CONNECTION" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHEPHERD_SKILLED_CASTER" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHEPHERD_SUMMON_THE_FLOCK" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHEPHERD_SELFLESS_SACRIFICE" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHEPHERD_SHEPHERD_MAGIC" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHEPHERD_SHEPHERDS_CROOK" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHEPHERD_DEEP_CONNECTION" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHEPHERD_SKILLED_CASTER" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHEPHERD_SUMMON_THE_FLOCK" level="11" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHEPHERD_SELFLESS_SACRIFICE" level="15" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Shepherd Magic" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHEPHERD_SHEPHERD_MAGIC">
            <description>
                <p>You learn an additional spell when you reach certain levels in this class, as shown in the Canine Spells table. The spell counts as a tamer spell for you, but it doesn’t count against the number of tamer spells you know.</p>
                <h5 class="caption">Shepherd Spells</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Tamer Level</td><td>Spell</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>sanctuary</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>calm emotions</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><em>conjure animals</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>13th</td><td><em>conjure woodland beings</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>17th</td><td><em>wrath of nature</em></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SANCTUARY" spellcasting="Tamer" known="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CALM_EMOTIONS" spellcasting="Tamer" known="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONJURE_ANIMALS" spellcasting="Tamer" known="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONJURE_WOODLAND_BEINGS" spellcasting="Tamer" known="true" level="13" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_WRATH_OF_NATURE" spellcasting="Tamer" known="true" level="17" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Shepherds Crook" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHEPHERD_SHEPHERDS_CROOK">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 3rd level, you know how to guide your allies back onto the right path. You learn the Guidance cantrip, and treat any quarterstaff or club you wield as if it was under the effect of the Shillelagh spell. You gain proficiency in the Animal Handling skill if you do not already have it, and your proficiency bonus is doubled for any ability check you make that uses that proficiency. If you were already proficient in Animal Handling, you instead gain proficency in a skill of your choice.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Deep Connection" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHEPHERD_DEEP_CONNECTION">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 3rd level, having traveled the world for years, you develop a strong bond to the earth itself. You may ritual cast any spell on the Tamer spell list with the ritual tag, regardless of whether you know it or not. You must be of a level at which you would normally be able to cast the spell. You may do this a number of times equal your Wisdom modifier (Minimum of once) and regain the ability to do so upon a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Skilled Caster" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHEPHERD_SKILLED_CASTER">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 7th level, you have mastered the ability to cast spells through your Tamer Mark. You may add your wisdom modifier to the damage you deal with any tamer cantrip. In addition, you no longer have a limit on the number of times you may use your Deep Connection skill.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Summon the Flock" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHEPHERD_SUMMON_THE_FLOCK">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 11th level, you may have any number of creatures summoned, so long as their combined CR does not exceed your max summon CR. You may also summon multiple creatures from your mark at the same time. You gain three tamed creatures, which must be of CR 1/2 or less, and do not count against your maximum number of tamed creatures.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Selfless Sacrifice" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHEPHERD_SELFLESS_SACRIFICE">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 15th level, you may sacrifice your own life force in order to save your friends. When one of your summons is knocked unconscious, you may use your reaction to cause it to regain all of it’s hit points and stand up. Doing so takes a heavy toll, and you take necrotic damage equal to 2D8 per CR of the creature. You may only use this ability once, and regain the ability to do so upon a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>

    <!-- Tamer Skills -->
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ANIMALHANDLING">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ATHLETICS">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_NATURE">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERSUASION">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_STEALTH">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SURVIVAL">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>

    <!-- Tamer Spells -->
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DANCING_LIGHTS">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FRIENDS">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_FROSTBITE">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_INFESTATION">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LIGHT">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_MAGIC_STONE">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MENDING">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MESSAGE">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_PRIMAL_SAVAGERY">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PRODUCE_FLAME">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPARE_THE_DYING">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_THORN_WHIP">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_THUNDERCLAP">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ABSORB_ELEMENTS">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANIMAL_FRIENDSHIP">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_BEAST_BOND">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CURE_WOUNDS">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_MAGIC">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FAERIE_FIRE">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FEATHER_FALL">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIND_FAMILIAR">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FOG_CLOUD">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HEALING_WORD">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_JUMP">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LONGSTRIDER">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PURIFY_FOOD_AND_DRINK">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SLEEP">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_SNARE">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_ANIMALS">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_WOTC_UA20170403_SPELL_WILD_CUNNING">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ALTER_SELF">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANIMAL_MESSENGER">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BEAST_SENSE">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DARKVISION">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_EARTHBIND">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LESSER_RESTORATION">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LOCATE_ANIMALS_OR_PLANTS">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PROTECTION_FROM_POISON">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPIDER_CLIMB">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SUGGESTION">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_WOTC_UA20200326_SPELL_SUMMON_BESTIAL_SPIRIT">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WEB">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_CATNAP">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISPEL_MAGIC">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FEIGN_DEATH">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PLANT_GROWTH">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PROTECTION_FROM_ENERGY">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_REMOVE_CURSE">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_PLANTS">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TONGUES">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WATER_BREATHING">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_CHARM_MONSTER">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DOMINATE_BEAST">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GIANT_INSECT">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GRASPING_VINE">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_GUARDIAN_OF_NATURE">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LOCATE_CREATURE">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_POLYMORPH">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AWAKEN">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMMUNE_WITH_NATURE">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GREATER_RESTORATION">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HOLD_MONSTER">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INSECT_PLAGUE">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_WRATH_OF_NATURE">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
        </append>

    <!-- New Spells -->
        <element name="Ferocious Strike" type="Spell" source="source" id="ID_author_source_SPELL_FEROCIOUS_STRIKE">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
            <description>
                <p>As part of the action used to cast this spell, you must make a melee attack with a weapon against one creature within the spell’s range, otherwise the spell fails. On a hit, the target suffers the attack’s normal effects, and the targets weak points are exposed until the start of your next turn. If the target is hit before then by a creature with a type that is not Humanoid, it takes an additional 1D6 of that attack’s damage type, and the spell ends.</p>
                <p class="indent">This spell’s damage increases when you reach higher levels. At 5th level, the melee attack deals an extra 1D6 damage of the attack’s damage type to the target, and the damage the target takes from a non-Humanoids attack increases to 2D6. Both damage rolls increase by 1D6 at 11th level and 17th level.</p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="keywords"></set>
                <set name="level">0</set>
                <set name="school">Divination</set>
                <set name="isRitual">false</set>
                <set name="time">1 action</set>
                <set name="range">5 feet</set>
                <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
                <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
                <set name="materialComponent">a weapon</set>
                <set name="duration">1 round</set>
                <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
        <element name="Revive Beast" type="Spell" source="source" id="ID_author_source_SPELL_REVIVE_BEAST">
            <supports>Tamer</supports>
            <description>
                <p>You select a tamed creature in your Tamer Mark that is currently unconscious. That creature regains 20 hit points and may now be summoned again.</p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="keywords"></set>
                <set name="level">3</set>
                <set name="school">Necromancy</set>
                <set name="isRitual">false</set>
                <set name="time">1 action</set>
                <set name="range">Special</set>
                <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
                <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
                <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
                <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
</elements>