<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Cardmaster Class</name>
        <update version="0.0.2">
            <file name="class-cardmaster.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/classes/class-cardmaster.xml" />
        </update>
        <!-- https://drive.google.com/file/d/1uSidsAyupkfLssvpj4MCX0ftUsFjvNd9/view -->
    </info>
    
    <element name="THE Cardmaster" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_SOURCE_CARDMASTER">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p>A spellcaster that relies on chance to power spells.</p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation"></set>
            <set name="url">https://drive.google.com/file/d/1uSidsAyupkfLssvpj4MCX0ftUsFjvNd9/view</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" url="http://guidetohomebrew.blogspot.com">Jonoman3000</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20200118</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Cardmaster" type="Class" source="The Cardmaster" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_CLASS_CARDMASTER">
        <description>
            <p>His eyes fleeting across the surrounding forest, a short, dark-clothed human reaches towards the inner pocket of his jacket and pulls out an intricately detailed card. With a flick of his wrist, the card burns away and a barely visible blanket of magical energy manifests around his body. Taking the initiative against his would be ambushers, he takes another card from his pocket and speaks a short incantation. As his incantation completes, the card burns away and a bolt of lightning streaks into the forest.</p>
            <p class="indent">Holding a blade of hellfire in one hand and an assortment of cards in the other, a nimble tiefling rushes into the fray. Her blade flashes each time it strikes, felling a wretched goblin with every blow. With every strike made against her, a bolt of flame streaks towards her attacker.</p>
            <p class="indent">Her long, silvery hair billowing behind her, an elf darts behind a stone pillar. Hastily looking through her hand of cards, she selects a white card decorated with blue floral designs. She speaks a word and the card dissipates, as she teleports to the balcony above. Now in a better position, she conjures two cards, both neatly tucked between her fingers. She throws them in the same motion, causing them to fly towards her opponents below.</p>
            <p class="indent">Cardmasters are powerful magic-users, defined by their unique method of spellcasting. Utilizing the magic stored within a repository of magical power, called a card case, cardmasters create magical items that resemble playing cards. These creations are called spell cards, and they hold spells that only those that have taken the time to study this ancient art can cast.</p>
            <h4>UNEARTHED MAGIC</h4>
            <p>The magic of a cardmaster is neither innate, like a sorcerer, nor the pure product of years of learning, like a wizard. A cardmaster begins their delve into the arcane arts through their acquisition of a card case, which might be given to them by a master or simply found as treasure. The card case holds all of a cardmaster’s power—it is from this item that they gain all of their magical prowess, and they are nothing without it.</p>
            <p class="indent">Learning how to utilize the magic held within a card case is not a simple matter for most. A cardmaster often requires years of study before they reach the point where they are able to cast even the simplest spells from their card case. Once a cardmaster reaches this point, however, their being has become permanently bonded with their card case. Even if the case is lost or destroyed, they are able to summon it back to themselves, with all of their collected cards intact.</p>
            <h4>CREATING A CARDMASTER</h4>
            <p>When creating a cardmaster, the most important question you must consider is that of how you acquired your card case. Perhaps you were tutored by another cardmaster that was skilled enough to create a card case for his or her apprentice. Or perhaps you simply found a card case that had been long abandoned by its previous user. Or maybe you managed to take the card case from another cardmaster after their death.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you decide how you came across your card case, you need to determine how your training went. Did card magic come naturally to you, or did it takes years of concentrated study? Did you have the help of a teacher, or were you self-taught? If you had a teacher, do you still learn under them, or have you parted ways?</p>
            <p class="indent">Also consider the playstyle that you will choose at 2nd level. While this choice isn’t set in stone, many cardmasters know what playstyle they intend to master before they even learn the basics of this magical art.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">QUICK BUILD</h5>
            <p>You can make a cardmaster quickly by following these suggestions. First, Intelligence should be your highest ability score, followed by Constitution or Dexterity. If you plan to use the Demon’s Inferno playstyle, make Dexterity or Strength your next-best score. Second, choose the sage background. Third, choose the mage hand and light cantrips, along with the following 1st-level spells for your card case: absorb elements, burning hands, chromatic orb, <em>expeditious retreat</em>, <em>mage armor</em>, <em>magic missile</em>, <em>shield</em>, and <em>sleep</em>.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">MULTICLASSING</h5>
            <p>The prerequisite for multiclassing into a cardmaster is an Intelligence of 13 or higher. When multiclassing into cardmaster, you gain proficiency in light armor and simple weapons. If you have both Card Magic and another form of spellcasting, you keep the forms of spellcasting entirely separate. You cannot use your spell cards and wildcards to cast spells not gained from the cardmaster class, and you cannot use spell slots to cast spell cards.</p>
            <h2>CLASS FEATURES</h2>
            <p>As a cardmaster, you gain the following class features.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">HIT POINTS</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Hit Dice:</strong> 1d8 per CARDMASTER level</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at 1st Level:</strong> 8 + your Constitution modifier</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at Higher Levels:</strong> 1d8 (or 5) + your Constitution modifier per CARDMASTER level after 1st</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">PROFICIENCIES</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled mb">
                <li><strong>Armor:</strong> Light armor</li>
                <li><strong>Weapons:</strong> Simple weapons</li>
                <li><strong>Tools:</strong> Playing cards</li>
            </ul>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Saving Throws:</strong> Dexterity, Intelligence</li>
                <li><strong>Skills:</strong> Choose two skills from Arcana, Deception, History Insight, Investigation, Performance, Persuasion, Stealth, and Sleight of Hand.</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">EQUIPMENT</h5>
            <p>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>(a) a quarterstaff or (b) a dagger</li>
                <li>(a) a scholar’s pack or (b) an explorer’s pack</li>
                <li>A card case and a deck of playing cards</li>
            </ul>
			<h5 class="caption">THE CARDMASTER</h5>
            <table class="class-features">
                <thead>
                    <tr>Level<th></th><th>Proficiency Bonus</th><th class="left">Features</th><th>Cantrips</th><th>Hand Size</th><th>Wild Cards</th><th>Maximum Spell Level</th></tr>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                    <tr><td>1st</td><td>+2</td>Card Magic, Deadly Dealer<td class="left"></td><td>2</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>1st</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>2nd</td><td>+2</td>Playstyle<td class="left"></td><td>2</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>1st</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td>+2</td>Card Tricks<td class="left"></td><td>2</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2nd</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>4th</td><td>+2</td>Ability Score Improvement<td class="left"></td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>4</td><td>2nd</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td>+3</td>—<td class="left"></td><td>3</td><td>4</td><td>6</td><td>3rd</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>6th</td><td>+3</td>Playstyle feature<td class="left"></td><td>3</td><td>4</td><td>7</td><td>3rd</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>7th</td><td>+3</td>Card Tricks<td class="left"></td><td>3</td><td>4</td><td>8</td><td>4th</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>8th</td><td>+3</td>Ability Score Improvement<td class="left"></td><td>3</td><td>5</td><td>9</td><td>4th</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td>+4</td>Scry<td class="left"></td><td>3</td><td>5</td><td>10</td><td>5th</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>10th</td><td>+4</td>Playstyle feature<td class="left"></td><td>4</td><td>5</td><td>11</td><td>5th</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>11th</td><td>+4</td>Card Magic Improvement (Recreate table during a short rest)<td class="left"></td><td>4</td><td>6</td><td>13</td><td>6th</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>12th</td><td>+4</td>Ability Score Improvement<td class="left"></td><td>4</td><td>6</td><td>14</td><td>6th</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>13th</td><td>+5</td>Card Tricks<td class="left"></td><td>4</td><td>6</td><td>15</td><td>7th</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>14th</td><td>+5</td>Playstyle feature<td class="left"></td><td>4</td><td>7</td><td>16</td><td>7th</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>15th</td><td>+5</td>Scry Improvement<td class="left"></td><td>4</td><td>7</td><td>17</td><td>8th</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>16th</td><td>+5</td>Ability Score Improvement<td class="left"></td><td>4</td><td>7</td><td>18</td><td>8th</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>17th</td><td>+6</td>—<td class="left"></td><td>4</td><td>8</td><td>20</td><td>9th</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>18th</td><td>+6</td>Fluent Casting<td class="left"></td><td>4</td><td>8</td><td>21</td><td>9th</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>19th</td><td>+6</td>Ability Score Improvement<td class="left"></td><td>4</td><td>8</td><td>22</td><td>9th</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>20th</td><td>+6</td>At the Ready<td class="left"></td><td>4</td><td>9</td><td>23</td><td>9th</td></tr>
                </tbody>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_CLASS_FEATURE_CARDMASTER_CARD_MAGIC" />
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_CLASS_FEATURE_CARDMASTER_DEADLY_DEALER" />
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_CLASS_FEATURE_CARDMASTER_PLAYSTYLE" />
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_CLASS_FEATURE_CARDMASTER_CARD_TRICKS" />
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_CLASS_FEATURE_CARDMASTER_ABILITY_SCORE_INCREASE" />
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_CLASS_FEATURE_CARDMASTER_SCRY" />
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_CLASS_FEATURE_CARDMASTER_FLUENT_CASTING" />
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_CLASS_FEATURE_CARDMASTER_AT_THE_READY" />
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="hd">d8</set>
            <set name="short">A spellcaster that relies on chance to power spells.</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" requirements="!ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_MULTICLASS_CARDMASTER" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" requirements="!ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_MULTICLASS_CARDMASTER" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_GAMING_SET_PROFICIENCY_PLAYING_CARD_SET" requirements="!ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_MULTICLASS_CARDMASTER" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_DEXTERITY" requirements="!ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_MULTICLASS_CARDMASTER" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_INTELLIGENCE" requirements="!ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_MULTICLASS_CARDMASTER" />
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency, Cardmaster" number="2" supports="Cardmaster" requirements="!ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_MULTICLASS_CARDMASTER" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_CLASS_FEATURE_CARDMASTER_CARD_MAGIC" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_CLASS_FEATURE_CARDMASTER_DEADLY_DEALER" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_CLASS_FEATURE_CARDMASTER_PLAYSTYLE" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_CLASS_FEATURE_CARDMASTER_CARD_TRICKS" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_CLASS_FEATURE_CARDMASTER_ABILITY_SCORE_INCREASE" level="4" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_CLASS_FEATURE_CARDMASTER_SCRY" level="9" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_CLASS_FEATURE_CARDMASTER_FLUENT_CASTING" level="18" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_CLASS_FEATURE_CARDMASTER_AT_THE_READY" level="20" />
        </rules>
        <multiclass id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_MULTICLASS_CARDMASTER">
            <prerequisite>Intelligence 13</prerequisite>
            <requirements>[int:13]</requirements>
            <setters>
                <set name="multiclass proficiencies">Light armor and simple weapons</set>
            </setters>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" />
            </rules>
        </multiclass>
    </element>
        <element name="Card Magic" type="Class Feature" source="The Cardmaster" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_CLASS_FEATURE_CARDMASTER_CARD_MAGIC">
            <description>
                <p>As a card master, you have acquired a magical card case that contains the beginnings of your meager collection of spell cards. See chapter 10 of the <em>Player’s Handbook</em> for the general rules of spellcasting, and the end of this document for the cardmaster spell list.</p>
                <h5>CANTRIPS</h5>
                <p>At 1st level, you know two cantrips of your choice from the cardmaster spell list. You learn additional cardmaster cantrips of your choice at higher levels, as shown in the Cantrips Known column of the Cardmaster table.</p>
                <h5>CARD CASE</h5>
                <p>At 1st level, you have a card case containing eight 1st-level cardmaster spells of your choice.</p>
                <h5>WILD CARDS</h5>
                <p>You have a number of wild cards, as shown in the Wild Cards column of the Cardmaster table. Wild cards have two uses: casting spells and drawing additional spell cards. Spell cards are described in detail in the next section.</p>
                <p class="indent">Unlike regular spellcasters, you do not have spell slots. Instead, you cast spells using wild cards in combination with spell cards. To cast one of your spell cards, you must expend a number of wild cards equal to the level of the spell.</p>
                <p class="indent">The maximum level spells you can cast are 1st level spells. This increases as you level, as shown in the Maximum Spell Level column in the Cardmaster table.</p>
                <p class="indent">When you cast a 6th, 7th, 8th, or 9th level spell with this feature, you can’t cast another spell of that particular level again until you complete a long rest.</p>
                <p class="indent">As long as your hand isn’t full, you can use your bonus action and expend a wild card to draw a new spell card. The process for drawing a spell card is described below.</p>
                <p class="indent">You regain all expended wild cards upon completing a short or long rest.</p>
                <h5>USING AND DRAWING SPELL CARDS</h5>
                <p>When you want to cast a spell, you do so using spell cards and wild cards. Spell cards represent the spells you can cast, while wild cards are used in place of spell slots. Your hand consists of the spell cards that you’ve drawn but not used.</p>
                <p class="indent">The spells you can cast at any given time are determined by the spell cards in your hand. Whenever you complete a short or long rest, you draw spell cards until you have a number of cards in your hand equal to your hand size, shown in the Hand Size column of the Cardmaster table.</p>
                <p class="indent">In order to draw a spell card, you first construct a table of spell cards that you will draw from. The table should contain 10 rows and 2 columns, with the first column being numbers from 1 to 10, and the second column being unique spell cards that you have in your card case. Two of the spell cards you choose can appear in up to two rows of the table, while the other spell cards can only appear in one row each.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once the table is set up, you draw a card by rolling a d10. You then add to your hand whatever spell card corresponds to the number you rolled.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you construct a table, you can’t reconstruct the table until you finish a long rest. Once you reach 11th level, you can reconstruct the table upon finishing a short rest.</p>
                <p class="indent">For example, if you’re a 2nd-level cardmaster that has absorb elements, burning hands, charm person, chromatic orb, color spray, false life, fog cloud, magic missile, shield, and sleep in their card case, you might construct the following table:</p>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>d10</td><td>Spell Card</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1</td><td><i>burning hands</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>2</td><td><i>burning hands</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3</td><td><i>charm person</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>4</td><td><i>chromatic orb</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5</td><td><i>color spray</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>6</td><td><i>false life</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>7</td><td><i>magic missile</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>8</td><td><i>shield</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9</td><td><i>shield</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>10</td><td><i>sleep</i></td></tr>
                </table>
                <p class="indent">If you’re refilling your hand after a short or long rest, you roll 3 times on the table, as your hand size is 3. If you roll, for example, 2-4-4, then your hand consists of burning hands, and two castings of chromatic orb.</p>
                <h5>DISCARDING A SPELL CARD</h5>
                <p>You discard a spell card after casting it, or when a feature tells you to discard a spell card. If a feature tells you to discard a spell card, you choose any one of the cards in your hand. A discarded card is no longer in your hand.</p>
                <h5>SPELLCASTING FOCUS</h5>
                <p>Your spell cards act as spellcasting foci for the cardmaster spells you cast.</p>
                <h5>SPELLCASTING ABILITY</h5>
                <p>Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for your cardmaster spells, since you endlessly study and experiment with your cards. You use your Intelligence whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. You use your Intelligence modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a cardmaster spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.</p>
                <center>
                    <p><strong>Spell save DC</strong> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier</p>
                    <p><strong>Spell attack modifier</strong> = your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier</p>
                </center>
                <h5>GAINING SPELLS OF 1ST LEVEL AND HIGHER</h5>
                <p>Each time you gain a cardmaster level, you can add two cardmaster spell cards of your choice to your card case. Each of these must be of a level that you can cast, as shown in the Maximum Spell Level column in the Cardmaster table. On your adventures, you might find other spell cards that you can add to your card case.</p>
                <div class="reference">
                    <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_CLASS_FEATURE_CARDMASTER_YOUR_CARD_CASE" />
                </div>
            </description>
            <spellcasting name="Cardmaster" ability="Intelligence" prepare="false">
                <list>Cardmaster</list>
            </spellcasting>
            <sheet>
                <description>You have {{wild-card:count}} wild cards. When you cast a spell, you must expend a number of wild cards equal to the level of the spell. You can reconstruct your spell table after a long rest. You can fill your hand with {{hand-size:count}} cards from your spell table at the end of a short or long rest.</description>
                <description level="11">You have {{wild-card:count}} wild cards. When you cast a spell, you must expend a number of wild cards equal to the level of the spell. You can reconstruct your spell table after a short or long rest. You can fill your hand with {{hand-size:count}} cards from your spell table at the end of a short or long rest. You can cast a spell of 6th level once per long rest.</description>
                <description level="13">You have {{wild-card:count}} wild cards. When you cast a spell, you must expend a number of wild cards equal to the level of the spell. You can reconstruct your spell table after a short or long rest. You can fill your hand with {{hand-size:count}} cards from your spell table at the end of a short or long rest. You can cast spells of 6th or 7th level once per long rest.</description>
                <description level="15">You have {{wild-card:count}} wild cards. When you cast a spell, you must expend a number of wild cards equal to the level of the spell. You can reconstruct your spell table after a short or long rest. You can fill your hand with {{hand-size:count}} cards from your spell table at the end of a short or long rest. You can cast spells of 6th, 7th or 8th level once per long rest.</description>
                <description level="17">You have {{wild-card:count}} wild cards. When you cast a spell, you must expend a number of wild cards equal to the level of the spell. You can reconstruct your spell table after a short or long rest. You can fill your hand with {{hand-size:count}} cards from your spell table at the end of a short or long rest. You can cast spells of 6th, 7th, 8th or 9th level once per long rest.</description>
                <description level="17">You have {{wild-card:count}} wild cards. When you cast a spell, you must expend a number of wild cards equal to the level of the spell. You can reconstruct your spell table after a short or long rest. You can fill your hand with {{hand-size:count}} cards from your spell table at the end of a short or long rest. You can cast a spell of 6th level twice and spells of 7th, 8th or 9th level once per long rest.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Cardmaster)" supports="Cardmaster,0" number="2" spellcasting="Cardmaster" level="1" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Cardmaster)" supports="Cardmaster,0" number="1" spellcasting="Cardmaster" level="4" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Cardmaster)" supports="Cardmaster,0" number="1" spellcasting="Cardmaster" level="10" />
                <stat name="wild-card:count" value="1" level="1" />
                <stat name="wild-card:count" value="1" level="2" />
                <stat name="wild-card:count" value="1" level="3" />
                <stat name="wild-card:count" value="1" level="4" />
                <stat name="wild-card:count" value="2" level="5" />
                <stat name="wild-card:count" value="1" level="6" />
                <stat name="wild-card:count" value="1" level="7" />
                <stat name="wild-card:count" value="1" level="8" />
                <stat name="wild-card:count" value="1" level="9" />
                <stat name="wild-card:count" value="1" level="10" />
                <stat name="wild-card:count" value="2" level="11" />
                <stat name="wild-card:count" value="1" level="12" />
                <stat name="wild-card:count" value="1" level="13" />
                <stat name="wild-card:count" value="1" level="14" />
                <stat name="wild-card:count" value="1" level="15" />
                <stat name="wild-card:count" value="1" level="16" />
                <stat name="wild-card:count" value="2" level="17" />
                <stat name="wild-card:count" value="1" level="18" />
                <stat name="wild-card:count" value="1" level="19" />
                <stat name="wild-card:count" value="1" level="20" />

                <stat name="hand-size:count" value="2" level="1" />
                <stat name="hand-size:count" value="1" level="2" />
                <stat name="hand-size:count" value="1" level="5" />
                <stat name="hand-size:count" value="1" level="8" />
                <stat name="hand-size:count" value="1" level="11" />
                <stat name="hand-size:count" value="1" level="14" />
                <stat name="hand-size:count" value="1" level="17" />
                <stat name="hand-size:count" value="1" level="20" />

                <stat name="cardmaster:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="1" />
                <stat name="cardmaster:spellcasting:slots:1" value="-1" level="3" />
                <stat name="cardmaster:spellcasting:slots:2" value="1" level="3" />
                <stat name="cardmaster:spellcasting:slots:2" value="-1" level="5" />
                <stat name="cardmaster:spellcasting:slots:3" value="1" level="5" />
                <stat name="cardmaster:spellcasting:slots:3" value="-1" level="7" />
                <stat name="cardmaster:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="7" />
                <stat name="cardmaster:spellcasting:slots:4" value="-1" level="9" />
                <stat name="cardmaster:spellcasting:slots:5" value="1" level="9" />
                <stat name="cardmaster:spellcasting:slots:5" value="-1" level="11" />
                <stat name="cardmaster:spellcasting:slots:6" value="1" level="11" />
                <stat name="cardmaster:spellcasting:slots:7" value="1" level="13" />
                <stat name="cardmaster:spellcasting:slots:8" value="1" level="15" />
                <stat name="cardmaster:spellcasting:slots:9" value="1" level="17" />
                <stat name="cardmaster:spellcasting:slots:6" value="1" level="18" />

                <select type="Spell" name="Card Case (Cardmaster)" number="8" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" spellcasting="Cardmaster" level="1" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Card Case (Cardmaster)" number="2" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" spellcasting="Cardmaster" level="2" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Card Case (Cardmaster)" number="2" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" spellcasting="Cardmaster" level="3" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Card Case (Cardmaster)" number="2" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" spellcasting="Cardmaster" level="4" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Card Case (Cardmaster)" number="2" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" spellcasting="Cardmaster" level="5" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Card Case (Cardmaster)" number="2" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" spellcasting="Cardmaster" level="6" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Card Case (Cardmaster)" number="2" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" spellcasting="Cardmaster" level="7" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Card Case (Cardmaster)" number="2" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" spellcasting="Cardmaster" level="8" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Card Case (Cardmaster)" number="2" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" spellcasting="Cardmaster" level="9" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Card Case (Cardmaster)" number="2" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" spellcasting="Cardmaster" level="10" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Card Case (Cardmaster)" number="2" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" spellcasting="Cardmaster" level="11" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Card Case (Cardmaster)" number="2" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" spellcasting="Cardmaster" level="12" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Card Case (Cardmaster)" number="2" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" spellcasting="Cardmaster" level="13" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Card Case (Cardmaster)" number="2" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" spellcasting="Cardmaster" level="14" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Card Case (Cardmaster)" number="2" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" spellcasting="Cardmaster" level="15" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Card Case (Cardmaster)" number="2" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" spellcasting="Cardmaster" level="16" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Card Case (Cardmaster)" number="2" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" spellcasting="Cardmaster" level="17" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Card Case (Cardmaster)" number="2" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" spellcasting="Cardmaster" level="18" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Card Case (Cardmaster)" number="2" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" spellcasting="Cardmaster" level="19" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Card Case (Cardmaster)" number="2" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" spellcasting="Cardmaster" level="20" />
                <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_CLASS_FEATURE_CARDMASTER_YOUR_CARD_CASE" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Your Card Case" type="Class Feature" source="The Cardmaster" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_CLASS_FEATURE_CARDMASTER_YOUR_CARD_CASE">
                <description>
                    <p>The card case that you acquired when you chose this class is an extension of yourself, and the source of your spellcasting abilities. When you add a spell to your card case, you do so by inscribing the spell upon a card, utilizing special inks and your own unique designs in the process. Once you finish this step, you place the card in your card case, and it becomes available to be drawn. When you draw a spell card, you aren’t drawing the original card that you inscribed—you’re drawing a copy of that card, created by the card case with arcane magic.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><strong><em>Copying Spell Cards.</em></strong> When you find a cardmaster spell of 1st level or higher, you can add it to your card case if it is of a level for which you have spell slots and if you can spare the time and materials needed to inscribe it.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Inscribing a spell card that you find involves reproducing the magical designs and words that hold the spells magic, and rewriting them to work with your card case. All card cases are slightly different, so a card from another card case won’t work without modification.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Adding a spell card you find requires 2 hours of work and 50 gold pieces of material for every level of the spell. Once you finish this process, the spell is ready to be drawn.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><strong><em>Losing your Card Case.</em></strong> Due to your magical bond with your card case, you can resummon it after it is lost or destroyed by concentrating and meditating during a long rest. Your spell cards are not preserved, however, and you need to copy them again. Recopying a spell only requires 1 hour of work and 25 gp of material per level of the spell.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><strong><em>Your Card Case’s Appearance.</em></strong> All card cases are unique, though they all generally have the form of a small box. As your card case isn’t something you craft yourself, you aren’t the one that chooses how it looks. You should consider its appearance based on how and from whom you acquired it.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>You can add cardmaster spells you find to your card case if it is a level you can cast.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
        <element name="Deadly Dealer" type="Class Feature" source="The Cardmaster" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_CLASS_FEATURE_CARDMASTER_DEADLY_DEALER">
            <description>
                <p>You learn the <em>card throw</em> cantrip, described at the end of this document. If you already know it, you gain another cardmaster cantrip of your choice.</p>
                <p class="indent">When you hit a creature with one of the cards created with card throw, you can choose to discard one of your spell cards. If you do so, the thrown card gains an additional effect based on the discarded card’s school of magic. The different effects are described below:</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong>Abjuration.</strong> You gain temporary hit points equal to the damage dealt by the card. These temporary hit points last for up to 1 minute.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong>Conjuration.</strong> The target must succeed on a Strength saving throw against your spell save DC or be knocked prone as a wire of force attempts to trip it.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong>Divination.</strong> Your next attack against the target before the end of your next turn is made at advantage, and scores a critical hit on a roll of 19-20.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong>Enchantment.</strong> The target must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw against your spell save DC or be charmed by you until the end of your next turn.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong>Evocation.</strong> Each creature within 5 feet of the target, not including the target, must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw against your spell save DC or take damage equal to the damage dealt by the initial attack.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong>Illusion.</strong> The target must make a Wisdom saving throw against your spell save DC. On a failed save, you are invisible to that creature until the start of your next turn.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong>Necromancy.</strong> The target takes 1d8 necrotic damage, and can’t regain hit points until the end of your next turn.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong>Transmutation.</strong> A square area centered beneath the target that extends 5 feet beyond their space becomes difficult terrain for creatures other than you until cleared. A creature can use their action to clear a 5-foot square of the terrain.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you hit a creature with one of the cards created with card throw, you can choose to discard one of your spell cards. If you do so, the thrown card gains an additional effect based on the discarded card’s school of magic.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_SPELL_CARD_THROW" known="true" spellcasting="Cardmaster" level="1" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Playstyle" type="Class Feature" source="The Cardmaster" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_CLASS_FEATURE_CARDMASTER_PLAYSTYLE">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 2nd level, you choose a playstyle that you begin to emulate. Each playstyle is a long-standing tradition that has been passed down from various creatures: common playstyles include Beholder’s Paranoia, Devil’s Gambit, Demon’s Inferno, and Lich’s Tomb. Each of these playstyles grant you features at 2nd level, and again at 6th, 10th, and 14th levels.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Archetype" name="Cardmaster Playstyle" supports="Cardmaster Playstyle" level="2" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Card Tricks" type="Class Feature" source="The Cardmaster" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_CLASS_FEATURE_CARDMASTER_CARD_TRICKS">
            <description>
                <p>At 3rd level, you learn how to better manipulate your card magic. You gain two of the following Card Trick options of your choice. You gain another one at 7th and 13th level.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use a Card Trick, you can’t use any of the Card Tricks you have learned until you complete a short or long rest, score a critical hit against a hostile creature with a spell attack, or have a hostile creature roll a 1 on a saving throw against one of your spells.</p>
                <h5>COPYCAT</h5>
                <p>As a bonus action, you discard a spell card, and then replace it with a copy of another card in your hand.</p>
                <h5>DEFENDER</h5>
                <p>Using your action, you conjure a card that circles around you, attempting to intercept attacks. The first time an attack is made against you while the card lasts, the card imposes disadvantage on the attack roll. The card disappears once it imposes disadvantage, after 1 hour, or once you use Card Trick again.</p>
                <h5>LINKED CARDS</h5>
                <p>Using your action, you conjure two cards. As long as the cards are within a mile of each other, you can look through the face of one card to see as if you were looking through the face of the opposing card. To creatures other than you, the cards appear blank. The cards disappear after 1 hour, or once you use Card Trick again.</p>
                <h5>MISDIRECT</h5>
                <p>Using your action, you conjure a card and throw it at a point you can see within 60 feet of you. Once the card lands on the ground, it creates a perfect visual illusion of you that stands at that point for as long as the card remains. Interaction with the illusion reveals it to be an illusion, as objects pass through it. The card disappears once the illusion is revealed, after 1 hour, or once you use Card Trick again.</p>
                <h5>RECALL</h5>
                <p>As a bonus action, you conjure a card and lay it at your feet. At the end of your turn, you teleport back to the card’s location, and the card disappears.</p>
                <h5>RE-DRAW</h5>
                <p>As a bonus action, you draw a card, then discard any card in your hand.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Once you use a Card Trick, you can’t use any of the Card Tricks you have learned until you complete a short or long rest, score a critical hit against a hostile creature with a spell attack, or have a hostile creature roll a 1 on a saving throw against one of your spells.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Cardmaster Card Trick" number="2" supports="Cardmaster Card Trick" level="3" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Cardmaster Card Trick" number="1" supports="Cardmaster Card Trick" level="7" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Cardmaster Card Trick" number="1" supports="Cardmaster Card Trick" level="13" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Copycat" type="Class Feature" source="The Cardmaster" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_CLASS_FEATURE_CARDMASTER_CARD_TRICK_COPYCAT">
                <supports>Cardmaster Card Trick</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>As a bonus action, you discard a spell card, and then replace it with a copy of another card in your hand.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Card Trick" action="Bonus Action">
                    <description>You discard a spell card, and then replace it with a copy of another card in your hand.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Defender" type="Class Feature" source="The Cardmaster" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_CLASS_FEATURE_CARDMASTER_CARD_TRICK_DEFENDER">
                <supports>Cardmaster Card Trick</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>Using your action, you conjure a card that circles around you, attempting to intercept attacks. The first time an attack is made against you while the card lasts, the card imposes disadvantage on the attack roll. The card disappears once it imposes disadvantage, after 1 hour, or once you use Card Trick again.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Card Trick" action="Action">
                    <description>You conjure a card that circles around you, attempting to intercept attacks. The first time an attack is made against you while the card lasts, the card imposes disadvantage on the attack roll. The card disappears once it imposes disadvantage, after 1 hour, or once you use Card Trick again.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Linked Cards" type="Class Feature" source="The Cardmaster" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_CLASS_FEATURE_CARDMASTER_CARD_TRICK_LINKED CARDS">
                <supports>Cardmaster Card Trick</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>Using your action, you conjure two cards. As long as the cards are within a mile of each other, you can look through the face of one card to see as if you were looking through the face of the opposing card. To creatures other than you, the cards appear blank. The cards disappear after 1 hour, or once you use Card Trick again.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Card Trick" action="Action">
                    <description>You conjure two cards. As long as the cards are within a mile of each other, you can look through the face of one card to see as if you were looking through the face of the opposing card. To creatures other than you, the cards appear blank. The cards disappear after 1 hour, or once you use Card Trick again.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Misdirect" type="Class Feature" source="The Cardmaster" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_CLASS_FEATURE_CARDMASTER_CARD_TRICK_MISDIRECT">
                <supports>Cardmaster Card Trick</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>Using your action, you conjure a card and throw it at a point you can see within 60 feet of you. Once the card lands on the ground, it creates a perfect visual illusion of you that stands at that point for as long as the card remains. Interaction with the illusion reveals it to be an illusion, as objects pass through it. The card disappears once the illusion is revealed, after 1 hour, or once you use Card Trick again.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Card Trick" action="Action">
                    <description>You conjure a card and throw it at a point you can see within 60 feet of you. Once the card lands on the ground, it creates a perfect visual illusion of you that stands at that point for as long as the card remains. Interaction with the illusion reveals it to be an illusion, as objects pass through it. The card disappears once the illusion is revealed, after 1 hour, or once you use Card Trick again.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Recall" type="Class Feature" source="The Cardmaster" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_CLASS_FEATURE_CARDMASTER_CARD_TRICK_RECALL">
                <supports>Cardmaster Card Trick</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>As a bonus action, you conjure a card and lay it at your feet. At the end of your turn, you teleport back to the card’s location, and the card disappears.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Card Trick" action="Bonus Action">
                    <description>You conjure a card and lay it at your feet. At the end of your turn, you teleport back to the card’s location, and the card disappears.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Re-Draw" type="Class Feature" source="The Cardmaster" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_CLASS_FEATURE_CARDMASTER_CARD_TRICK_RE-DRAW">
                <supports>Cardmaster Card Trick</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>As a bonus action, you draw a card, then discard any card in your hand.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Card Trick" action="Bonus Action">
                    <description>You draw a card, then discard any card in your hand.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
        <element name="Ability Score Increase" type="Class Feature" source="The Cardmaster" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_CLASS_FEATURE_CARDMASTER_ABILITY_SCORE_INCREASE">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Cardmaster 4)" supports="Improvement Option,Cardmaster,4" level="4" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Cardmaster 8)" supports="Improvement Option,Cardmaster,8" level="8" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Cardmaster 12)" supports="Improvement Option,Cardmaster,12" level="12" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Cardmaster 16)" supports="Improvement Option,Cardmaster,16" level="16" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Cardmaster 19)" supports="Improvement Option,Cardmaster,19" level="19" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Scry" type="Class Feature" source="The Cardmaster" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_CLASS_FEATURE_CARDMASTER_SCRY">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 9th level, you gain more control over the cards you can place in your hand. When you would draw a card, you can choose to instead to add to your hand any card from your card case, even if it isn’t part of your drawing table.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you do so, you must finish a long rest before you can use this feature again.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you reach 15th level, you regain the use of this feature when completing a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>When you would draw a card, you can choose to instead to add to your hand any card from your card case, even if it isn’t part of your drawing table.</description>
                <description level="15" usage="1/Short Rest">When you would draw a card, you can choose to instead to add to your hand any card from your card case, even if it isn’t part of your drawing table.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Fluent Casting" type="Class Feature" source="The Cardmaster" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_CLASS_FEATURE_CARDMASTER_FLUENT_CASTING">
            <description>
                <p>By 18th level, you have mastered the casting of low-level spell cards. When you cast a spell card at 1st level or 2nd level, you don’t need to expend any wild cards in the casting. You still discard the spell card afterwards, however.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, you may cast 6th level spell cards twice per long rest, rather than only once.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you cast a spell card at 1st level or 2nd level, you don’t need to expend any wild cards in the casting. You still discard the spell card afterwards, however.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="At the Ready" type="Class Feature" source="The Cardmaster" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_CLASS_FEATURE_CARDMASTER_AT_THE_READY">
            <description>
                <p>At 20th level, you are always ready when you encounter any threat. Whenever you roll initiative and your hand isn’t full, you draw spell cards until your hand is full.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Whenever you roll initiative and your hand isn’t full, you draw spell cards until your hand is full.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>


  <!-- Cardmaster Playstyles -->
    <element name="Beholder’s Paranoia" type="Archetype" source="The Cardmaster" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_ARCHETYPE_CARDMASTER_BEHOLDERS_PARANOIA">
        <supports>Cardmaster Playstyle</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Beholder’s Paranoia is a playstyle based upon being constantly vigilant, always on the lookout for danger. Like their namesake, those that follow this playstyle often believe that they are in constant danger, and suspect that others are plotting against them. It is believed that this playstyle was originally developed by an ancient, powerful beholder from a bygone age, who used its expertise in card magic to protect itself from many an experienced adventurer.</p>
            <p class="indent">This style is one of the rarer playstyles, as those paranoid enough to practice it would often be reluctant to take on an apprentice. Therefore, most that learn it do so through books and self-study, though even basic manuscripts on the subject are hard to come by.</p>
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BEHOLDERS_PARANOIA_QUICK_WITTED" />
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BEHOLDERS_PARANOIA_SPELLBREAKER" />
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BEHOLDERS_PARANOIA_PRESERVATION" />
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BEHOLDERS_PARANOIA_ARCANE_VIGILANCE" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BEHOLDERS_PARANOIA_QUICK_WITTED" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BEHOLDERS_PARANOIA_SPELLBREAKER" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BEHOLDERS_PARANOIA_PRESERVATION" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BEHOLDERS_PARANOIA_ARCANE_VIGILANCE" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Quick-witted" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Cardmaster" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BEHOLDERS_PARANOIA_QUICK_WITTED">
            <description>
                <p>Starting when you choose this playstyle at 2nd level, you become more alert to danger and quicker to respond to it. You add your Intelligence modifier to your initiative rolls.</p>
                <p class="indent">When you roll initiative, you can use your reaction to cast a spell card in your hand with a casting time of 1 action or 1 bonus action that only targets and effects you. Once you do so, you can’t do so again until you complete a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Reaction" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>When you roll initiative, you can cast a spell card in your hand with a casting time of 1 action or 1 bonus action that only targets and effects you.</description>
                <description level="14" action="Reaction">When you roll initiative, you can cast a spell card in your hand with a casting time of 1 action or 1 bonus action that only targets and effects you.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="initiative" value="intelligence:modifier" level="2" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Spellbreaker" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Cardmaster" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BEHOLDERS_PARANOIA_SPELLBREAKER">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, you have learned the anti-magic techniques of a beholder. Whenever a creature within 60 feet of you that you can see casts a spell, you automatically know what spell is being cast.</p>
                <p class="indent">Whenever you identify a spell in this way, you can use your reaction to discard a spell card in your hand that is of the same school of magic as the triggering spell. Make an Intelligence check with a DC equal to 12 + the spell’s level. On a successful check, the spell fails and has no effect.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Whenever a creature within 60 feet of you that you can see casts a spell, you automatically know what spell is being cast. Whenever you identify a spell in this way, you can use your reaction to discard a spell card in your hand that is of the same school of magic as the triggering spell. Make an Intelligence check with a DC equal to 12 + the spell’s level. On a successful check, the spell fails and has no effect.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Preservation" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Cardmaster" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BEHOLDERS_PARANOIA_PRESERVATION">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 10th level, you can use your spell cards to heal your wounds. As a bonus action on your turn, you can discard a number of spell cards from your hand, up to your Intelligence modifier (minimum 1) at maximum. You regain 1d8 hit points, plus 1d8 hit points for every card discarded.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you complete a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You can discard up to {{preservation:card-limit}} spell cards from your hand. You regain 1d8 hit points, plus 1d8 hit points for every card discarded.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="preservation:card-limit" value="1" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="preservation:card-limit" value="intelligence:modifier" bonus="base" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Arcane Vigilance" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Cardmaster" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BEHOLDERS_PARANOIA_ARCANE_VIGILANCE">
            <description>
                <p>At 14th level, you and creatures of your choice within 60 feet of you cannot be surprised while you are conscious.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, you can use your quick-witted feature every time you roll initiative, without needing to complete a long rest to use it again.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You and creatures of your choice within 60 feet of you cannot be surprised while you are conscious.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    <element name="Demon’s Inferno" type="Archetype" source="The Cardmaster" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_ARCHETYPE_CARDMASTER_DEMONS_INFERNO">
        <supports>Cardmaster Playstyle</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Demon’s Inferno is one of the more widely used playstyles, especially among tieflings and those that deal with the inhabitants of the abyss. Specializing in melee combat, practitioners of this playstyle have unparalleled offensive capabilities, but sacrifice the safety of other playstyles. This playstyle is occasionally still practiced by demons, though only the more intelligent among their race.</p>
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEMONS_INFERNO_DEMONIC_CHAMPION" />
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEMONS_INFERNO_GIFT_OF_THE_ABYSS" />
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEMONS_INFERNO_EXTRA_ATTACK" />
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEMONS_INFERNO_DEMONIC_ASPECT" />
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEMONS_INFERNO_ABYSSAL_FORM" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEMONS_INFERNO_DEMONIC_CHAMPION" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEMONS_INFERNO_GIFT_OF_THE_ABYSS" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEMONS_INFERNO_EXTRA_ATTACK" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEMONS_INFERNO_DEMONIC_ASPECT" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEMONS_INFERNO_ABYSSAL_FORM" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Demonic Champion" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Cardmaster" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEMONS_INFERNO_DEMONIC_CHAMPION">
            <description>
                <p>When you choose this playstyle at 2nd level, you gain proficiency with medium armor and shields.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, you can use your action to conjure a weapon made from hellfire. You are proficient with this weapon, and it has the properties of any simple or martial melee weapon, except it deals fire damage on a hit rather than bludgeoning, piercing, or slashing damage. The weapon remains until you stop holding it, conjure a different weapon, or die.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>You can conjure a weapon made from hellfire. You are proficient with this weapon, and it has the properties of any simple or martial melee weapon, except it deals fire damage on a hit rather than bludgeoning, piercing, or slashing damage. The weapon remains until you stop holding it, conjure a different weapon, or die.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_MEDIUM_ARMOR" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_SHIELDS" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Gift of the Abyss" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Cardmaster" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEMONS_INFERNO_GIFT_OF_THE_ABYSS">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 2nd level, your spell cards do not disappear when cast, but instead burn into magical flames that move to your will. Whenever you cast a spell card, a number of wisps of flame equal to 1 + half the spell’s level begin to circle around you. These wisps last for up to 1 minute, and you can have a number of them conjured at once equal to your Intelligence modifier + half your Cardmaster level (minimum 2).</p>
                <p class="indent">Whenever a creature within 5 feet of you makes an attack against you, one of these wisps launches at them after the attack is made, hit or miss. The attacker takes 1d4 fire damage, and the wisp disappears.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Your spell cards do not disappear when cast, but instead burn into magical flames that move to your will. Whenever you cast a spell card, a number of wisps of flame equal to 1 + half the spell’s level begin to circle around you. These wisps last for up to 1 minute, and you can have {{gift-of-the-abyss:wisp-count}} of them conjured at once. Whenever a creature within 5 feet of you makes an attack against you, one of these wisps launches at them after the attack is made, hit or miss. The attacker takes 1d4 fire damage, and the wisp disappears.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="gift-of-the-abyss:wisp-count" value="2" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="gift-of-the-abyss:wisp-count:calc-value" value="intelligence:modifier" />
                <stat name="gift-of-the-abyss:wisp-count:calc-value" value="level:cardmaster:half" />
                <stat name="gift-of-the-abyss:wisp-count" value="gift-of-the-abyss:wisp-count:calc-value" bonus="base" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Extra Attack" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Cardmaster" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEMONS_INFERNO_EXTRA_ATTACK">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 6th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
    			<stat name="extra attack:count" value="2" level="6" bonus="extra attack" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Demonic Aspect" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Cardmaster" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEMONS_INFERNO_DEMONIC_ASPECT">
            <description>
                <p>At 10th level, you gain resistance to fire damage, and once per turn when you deal fire damage, you can add your Intelligence modifier to the damage roll.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Once per turn when you deal fire damage, you can add {{intelligence:modifier}} to the damage roll.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_FIRE" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Abyssal Form" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Cardmaster" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEMONS_INFERNO_ABYSSAL_FORM">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 14th level, you can take on a demonic form that wreaths you in flame and grants you fiery wings. As an action, you enter this form. For 1 minute, you gain the following benefits:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>You gain a flying speed equal to your walking speed</li>
                    <li>Whenever you discard a card for any reason, each creature within 5 feet of you must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw against your spell save DC or take 2d6 fire damage.</li>
                    <li>When you reduce a creature to 0 hit points, you regain hit points equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum 1), or double that if the damage dealt was fire damage.</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You can take on a demonic form, that lasts for 1 minute. You gain a flying speed of {{speed}} feet. Whenever you discard a card for any reason, each creature within 5 feet of you must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw against your spell save DC or take 2d6 fire damage. When you reduce a creature to 0 hit points, you regain {{abyssal-form:hp-regain}} hit points, or double that if the damage dealt was fire damage.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="abyssal-form:hp-regain" value="1" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="abyssal-form:hp-regain" value="intelligence:modifier" bonus="base" />
            </rules>
        </element>

    <element name="Devil’s Gambit" type="Archetype" source="The Cardmaster" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_ARCHETYPE_CARDMASTER_DEVILS_GAMBIT">
        <supports>Cardmaster Playstyle</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Devil’s Gambit is a playstle that, as its name implies, exemplifies the idea of risk and reward. Still widely used among some groups of devils, this playstyle is quite widespread, despite the danger involved in using it. Among humanoid cardmasters, this playstyle can lead to the doom of an unwise or unlucky practitioner, as they don’t have pseudo-immortality of a devil that can simply reform itself in the nine hells upon being defeated. Many apprentice cardmasters of this playstyle meet their demise in the early stages of their learning, but those that practice and master its techniques can prove themselves powerful casters.</p>
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEVILS_GAMBIT_GIFT_OF_THE_NINE_HELLS" />
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEVILS_GAMBIT_DEVIL’S_LUCK" />
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEVILS_GAMBIT_UNSTABLE_MAGIC" />
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEVILS_GAMBIT_DEAL_WITH_THE_DEVIL" />
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEVILS_GAMBIT_EXPLOITER_OF_FATE" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEVILS_GAMBIT_GIFT_OF_THE_NINE_HELLS" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEVILS_GAMBIT_DEVIL’S_LUCK" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEVILS_GAMBIT_UNSTABLE_MAGIC" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEVILS_GAMBIT_DEAL_WITH_THE_DEVIL" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEVILS_GAMBIT_EXPLOITER_OF_FATE" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Gift of the Nine Hells" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Cardmaster" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEVILS_GAMBIT_GIFT_OF_THE_NINE_HELLS">
            <description>
                <p>When you choose this playstyle at 2nd level, you learn how to use a volatile energy harnessed from the nine hells. As a bonus action on your turn, you fill yourself with this energy. Your next spell attack before the end of your turn is made at advantage. If you miss this attack, its energy backfires onto you. Make the spell attack again, exactly as before, except this time targeting yourself. If the attack hits you and deals damage, its damage cannot be reduced in any way.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>You fill yourself with this energy from the nine hells. Your next spell attack before the end of your turn is made at advantage. If you miss this attack, its energy backfires onto you. Make the spell attack again, exactly as before, except this time targeting yourself. If the attack hits you and deals damage, its damage cannot be reduced in any way.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Devil’s Luck" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Cardmaster" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEVILS_GAMBIT_DEVIL’S_LUCK">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 2nd level, you can call upon the devil’s luck to aid you. When you miss an attack or are hit by an attack, you can use this feature to reroll that attack and take the new roll. Once you use this feature, your future luck becomes tainted. You derive no damage bonus from your next critical hit against a hostile creature, and you can’t use this feature again until after you would have scored one.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you miss an attack or are hit by an attack, you can use this feature to reroll that attack and take the new roll. Once you use this feature, your future luck becomes tainted. You derive no damage bonus from your next critical hit against a hostile creature, and you can’t use this feature again until after you would have scored one.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Unstable Magic" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Cardmaster" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEVILS_GAMBIT_UNSTABLE_MAGIC">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 6th level, whenever you make a spell attack with advantage, you can choose to make the attack with disadvantage instead. If the attack hits, it is a critical hit.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Whenever you make a spell attack with advantage, you can choose to make the attack with disadvantage instead. If the attack hits, it is a critical hit.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Deal with the Devil" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Cardmaster" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEVILS_GAMBIT_DEAL_WITH_THE_DEVIL">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 10th level, you can beseech upon the power of the nine hells whenever you are reduced to 0 hit points but not killed outright.</p>
                <p class="indent">When you do so, roll a d20, adding no modifiers to the roll. On a roll of 10 or above, you drop to 1 hit point instead. On a roll of 9 or below, you are reduced to 0 hit points as normal, and you suffer a death saving throw failure for each time that you’ve used this feature since your last long rest, not including the current usage.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you are reduced to 0 hit points but not killed outright, roll a d20, adding no modifiers to the roll. On a roll of 10 or above, you drop to 1 hit point instead. On a roll of 9 or below, you are reduced to 0 hit points as normal, and you suffer a death saving throw failure for each time that you’ve used this feature since your last long rest, not including the current usage.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Exploiter of Fate" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Cardmaster" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEVILS_GAMBIT_EXPLOITER_OF_FATE">
            <description>
                <p>At 14th level, you gain advantage on death saving throws and the d20 rolls used in your <em>Deal with the Devil</em> feature.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, when you make an attack roll, you can use this feature to add a d4 to your roll. You make this choice after you see the roll, but before the DM says whether the attack hits or misses. If the attack misses, you can’t use this feature again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You gain advantage on death saving throws and the d20 rolls used in your Deal with the Devil feature. Additionally, when you make an attack roll, you can use this feature to add a d4 to your roll. You make this choice after you see the roll, but before the DM says whether the attack hits or misses. If the attack misses, you can’t use this feature again until you finish a short or long rest.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    <element name="Lich’s Tomb" type="Archetype" source="The Cardmaster" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_ARCHETYPE_CARDMASTER_LICHS_TOMB">
        <supports>Cardmaster Playstyle</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Lich’s Tomb is a playstyle based on utilizing necromantic magic and overwhelming your opponent with arcane power. Those that follow this playstyle often do so in seek of power, and are typically not of the most cordial of acquaintances. Most cardmasters see this playstyle as villainous an menacing, though not all of its practitioners are evil.</p>
            <p class="indent">Its originators are just as evil as the stereotypes lead people to believe, however. Created many hundreds of years ago by an ancient lich, this playstyle was passed on to humanoids through chance alone, as the notes and cards of the lich were unearthed centuries after its demise.</p>
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LICHS_TOMB_POWER_FROM_THE_GRAVE" />
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LICHS_TOMB_NECROMANCER_ADEPT" />
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LICHS_TOMB_AURA_OF_UNDEATH" />
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LICHS_TOMB_NECROMANCER_OVERLORD" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LICHS_TOMB_POWER_FROM_THE_GRAVE" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LICHS_TOMB_NECROMANCER_ADEPT" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LICHS_TOMB_AURA_OF_UNDEATH" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LICHS_TOMB_NECROMANCER_OVERLORD" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Power from the Grave" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Cardmaster" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LICHS_TOMB_POWER_FROM_THE_GRAVE">
            <description>
                <p>When you choose this playstyle at 2nd level, your card magic is imbued with necrotic energy. Whenever you cast a spell card, rather than discarding it, it is considered to be in your “tomb,” and it remains there for up to 1 minute. While a spell card is in your tomb, you can still use it to cast spells as if it were in your hand, but you cannot use it for other features that call for discarding a spell card. When you cast a card from within your tomb, it is discarded, and therefore no longer in your tomb.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, at the start of each of your turns you gain temporary hit points equal to half the combined spell level of all the spell cards within your tomb. If you cast a spell card at a higher level, it is considered to be of the spell level that you cast it.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Additionally, when you make an attack roll, you can use this feature to add a d4 to your roll. You make this choice after you see the roll, but before the DM says whether the attack hits or misses. If the attack misses, you can’t use this feature again until you finish a short or long rest. Additionally, at the start of each of your turns you gain temporary hit points equal to half the combined spell level of all the spell cards within your tomb. If you cast a spell card at a higher level, it is considered to be of the spell level that you cast it.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Necromancer Adept" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Cardmaster" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LICHS_TOMB_NECROMANCER_ADEPT">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, you can discard a spell card in your hand or tomb and expend three wild cards to cast <em>animate dead</em> as a third level spell. You can use this feature twice, and regain expended uses when you finish a long rest.</p>
                <p class="indent">In addition, whenever an undead created with this feature dies, you can use your reaction and discard a spell card from your tomb to revive it, returning it to a state of undeath with 1d6 hit points.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="2/Long Rest">
                <description>You can discard a spell card in your hand or tomb and expend three wild cards to cast animate dead as a third level spell. In addition, whenever an undead created with this feature dies, you can use your reaction and discard a spell card from your tomb to revive it, returning it to a state of undeath with 1d6 hit points.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANIMATE_DEAD" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Aura of Undeath" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Cardmaster" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LICHS_TOMB_AURA_OF_UNDEATH">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 10th level, you gain resistance to necrotic damage, and whenever you gain temporary hit points from your <em>Power from the Grave</em> feature, you can have another creature of your choice within 10 feet of you gain the same number of temporary hit points. These temporary hit points last until the start of your next turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Whenever you gain temporary hit points from your Power from the Grave feature, you can have another creature of your choice within 10 feet of you gain the same number of temporary hit points. These temporary hit points last until the start of your next turn.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_NECROTIC" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Necromancer Overlord" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Cardmaster" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LICHS_TOMB_NECROMANCER_OVERLORD">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 14th level, you can discard a spell card in your hand or tomb and expend six wild cards to cast create undead as a sixth level spell. Once you do so, you can’t do so again until you complete a long rest. Undead created with this feature can be revived with your <em>Necromancer Adept</em> feature. That feature is also improved, and restores 3d6 hit points, rather than 1d6, when it revives an undead creature.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You can discard a spell card in your hand or tomb and expend six wild cards to cast create undead as a sixth level spell. Undead created with this feature can be revived with your Necromancer Adept feature. That feature is also improved, and restores 3d6 hit points, rather than 1d6, when it revives an undead creature.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CREATE_UNDEAD" />
            </rules>
        </element>


  <!-- Cardmaster Skills -->
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ARCANA">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_DECEPTION">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_HISTORY">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INVESTIGATION">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERFORMANCE">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERSUASION">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_STEALTH">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SLEIGHTOFHAND">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>

  <!-- Cardmaster Spell list -->
  <!-- Cantrips -->
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ACID_SPLASH">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLADE_WARD">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CHILL_TOUCH">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CREATE_BONFIRE">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DANCING_LIGHTS">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FROSTBITE">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LIGHT">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGE_HAND">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MENDING">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MESSAGE">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MINOR_ILLUSION">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_POISON_SPRAY">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PRESTIDIGITATION">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SWORD_BURST">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TOLL_THE_DEAD">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TRUE_STRIKE">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
  <!-- 1st level -->
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ABSORB_ELEMENTS">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BURNING_HANDS">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_SPELL_SPELL_CARD_OF_MADNESS">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CATAPULT">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CAUSE_FEAR">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CHARM_PERSON">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CHROMATIC_ORB">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COLOR_SPRAY">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_MAGIC">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISGUISE_SELF">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_EARTH_TREMOR">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_EXPEDITIOUS_RETREAT">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FALSE_LIFE">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FEATHER_FALL">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FOG_CLOUD">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ICE_KNIFE">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INFLICT_WOUNDS">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_JUMP">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LONGSTRIDER">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGE_ARMOR">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGIC_MISSILE">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PROTECTION_FROM_EVIL/GOOD">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RAY_OF_SICKNESS">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHIELD">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SILENT_IMAGE">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SLEEP">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_THUNDERWAVE">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WITCH_BOLT">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
  <!-- 2nd level -->
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ALTER_SELF">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ARCANE_LOCK">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLINDNESS/DEAFNESS">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLUR">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CLOUD_OF_DAGGERS">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CROWN_OF_MADNESS">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DARKNESS">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DARKVISION">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_THOUGHTS">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DRAGONS_BREATH">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DUST_DEVIL">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_EARTHBIND">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENLARGE/REDUCE">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FLAMING_SPHERE">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GUST_OF_WIND">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HOLD_PERSON">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INVISIBILITY">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_KNOCK">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LEVITATE">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LOCATE_OBJECT">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGIC_WEAPON">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAXIMILIANS_EARTHEN_GRASP">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MELFS_ACID_ARROW">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MIND_SPIKE">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MIRROR_IMAGE">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MISTY_STEP">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PHANTASMAL_FORCE">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PYROTECHNICS">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RAY_OF_ENFEEBLEMENT">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SCORCHING_RAY">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SEE_INVISIBILITY">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHADOW_BLADE">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHATTER">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SNILLOCS_SNOWBALL_SWARM">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPIDER_CLIMB">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SUGGESTION">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WEB">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
  <!-- 3rd level -->
    <append id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_SPELL_SPELL_ARCANE_FLUX">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLINK">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CLAIRVOYANCE">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COUNTERSPELL">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DAYLIGHT">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISPEL_MAGIC">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENEMIES_ABOUND">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ERUPTING_EARTH">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FEAR">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIREBALL">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FLY">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GASEOUS_FORM">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HASTE">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HYPNOTIC_PATTERN">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LIGHTNING_BOLT">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGIC_CIRCLE">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAJOR_IMAGE">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MELFS_MINUTE_METEORS">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PROTECTION_FROM_ENERGY">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SLEET_STORM">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SLOW">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_STINKING_CLOUD">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_THUNDER_STEP">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TONGUES">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_VAMPIRIC_TOUCH">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WALL_OF_SAND">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WALL_OF_WATER">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
  <!-- 4th level -->
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ARCANE_EYE">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BANISHMENT">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLIGHT">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CHARM_MONSTER">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONFUSION">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONTROL_WATER">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DIMENSION_DOOR">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ELEMENTAL_BANE">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIRE_SHIELD">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GREATER_INVISIBILITY">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ICE_STORM">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_SPELL_SPELL_MAGIC_RUNE">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PHANTASMAL_KILLER">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_POLYMORPH">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SICKENING_RADIANCE">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_STONESKIN">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_STORM_SPHERE">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_VITRIOLIC_SPHERE">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WALL_OF_FIRE">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
  <!-- 5th level -->
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BIGBYS_HAND">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_SPELL_SPELL_BOLTS_OF_BULWARK">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CLOUDKILL">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONE_OF_COLD">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONTACT_OTHER_PLANE">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONTAGION">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONTROL_WINDS">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CREATION">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DANSE_MACABRE">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DOMINATE_PERSON">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DREAM">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENERVATION">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FAR_STEP">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HOLD_MONSTER">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_IMMOLATION">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LEGEND_LORE">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MISLEAD">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MODIFY_MEMORY">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_NEGATIVE_ENERGY_FLOOD">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SCRYING">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SEEMING">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SYNAPTIC_STATIC">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TELEKINESIS">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WALL_OF_STONE">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WALL_OF_LIGHT">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
  <!-- 6th level -->
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ARCANE_GATE">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CHAIN_LIGHTNING">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CIRCLE_OF_DEATH">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONTINGENCY">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISINTEGRATE">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_EYEBITE">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FLESH_TO_STONE">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GLOBE_OF_INVULNERABILITY">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INVESTITURE_OF_FLAME">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INVESTITURE_OF_ICE">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INVESTITURE_OF_STONE">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INVESTITURE_OF_WIND">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MASS_SUGGESTION">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MENTAL_PRISON">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_OTILUKES_FREEZING_SPHERE">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PROGRAMMED_ILLUSION">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SCATTER">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TENSERS_TRANSFORMATION">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TRUE_SEEING">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WALL_OF_ICE">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
  <!-- 7th level -->
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CROWN_OF_STARS">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DELAYED_BLAST_FIREBALL">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ETHEREALNESS">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FINGER_OF_DEATH">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FORCECAGE">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MORDENKAINENS_MAGNIFICENT">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MANSION">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MORDENKAINENS_SWORD">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PLANE_SHIFT">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_POWER_WORD_PAIN">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PRISMATIC_SPRAY">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_REVERSE_GRAVITY">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TELEPORT">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
  <!-- 8th level -->
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ABI-DALZIMS_HORRID_WILTING">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANTIMAGIC_FIELD">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DEMIPLANE">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DOMINATE_MONSTER">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FEEBLEMIND">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ILLUSORY_DRAGON">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INCENDIARY_CLOUD">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MADDENING_DARKNESS">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MIND_BLANK">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_POWER_WORD_STUN">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SUNBURST">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
  <!-- 9th level -->
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ASTRAL_PROJECTION">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FORESIGHT">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GATE">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_IMPRISONMENT">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INVULNERABILITY">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MASS_POLYMORPH">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_METEOR_SWARM">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_POWER_WORD_KILL">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PSYCHIC_SCREAM">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TIME_STOP">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TRUE_POLYMORPH">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
    </append>

  <!-- Cardmaster-specific spells -->
    <element name="Arcane Flux" type="Spell" source="The Cardmaster" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_SPELL_ARCANE_FLUX">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You conjure a card of fluctuating arcane energy that circles around you for the duration or until you throw it. As you cast this spell, roll a d4. The card’s color depends on the number you roll: green for 1, red for 2, blue for 3, and yellow for 4. At the start of each of your turns, you roll the die again, and the card’s color changes to whatever you roll.</p>
            <p class="indent">As an action on your turn, you throw the conjured card. Make a spell attack against a target within 60 feet of you. On a hit, the card has an effect based on its color:</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Green.</strong> The target takes 6d6 poison damage, and its vision becomes momentarily blurred, unless it is immune to poison damage. Until the end of your next turn, the target can’t see beyond a 10-foot radius extending from it.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Red.</strong> The target takes 4d6 fire damage, and the card explodes in a fiery burst. Each creature within 10 feet of the target, including the target, must make a Dexterity saving throw. A creature takes 4d6 fire damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Blue.</strong> The target takes 5d6 cold damage, and is restrained until the end of your next turn.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Yellow.</strong> The target takes 3d6 lightning damage, and is stunned until the end of your next turn. Once you throw the card, the spell ends.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">conjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">1 minute</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Bolts of Bulwark" type="Spell" source="The Cardmaster" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_SPELL_BOLTS_OF_BULWARK">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Five silvery bolts lash out towards targets within range. You can send these rays at one target or several.</p>
            <p class="indent">Make a ranged spell attack for each bolt. On a hit, a target takes 1d6 force damage.</p>
            <p class="indent">At the start of your next turn, remnants of the spell’s magic return to protect you. For each bolt that hit a target, you gain 2d6 temporary hit points that last for the duration.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 6th level or higher, you create one additional ray for each spell slot above 5th.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">5</set>
            <set name="school">abjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">120 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">1 hour</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Card of Madness" type="Spell" source="The Cardmaster" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_SPELL_CARD_OF_MADNESS">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The face of a card appears imprinted on your body or on the body of a willing creature within range, filling that creature with arcane might, but also eating at its mind. The creature deals 1d6 additional damage on all of its attacks, and whenever it rolls a 5 or 6 on that damage die, the creature takes 1d6 psychic damage. This damage cannot be reduced in any way, but also doesn’t require you to make a Constitution saving throw to retain your concentration.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">conjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
            <set name="range">30 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 10 minutes</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Card Throw" type="Spell" source="The Cardmaster" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_SPELL_CARD_THROW">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You conjure a card of a random color and throw it at a creature or object within range. Make a ranged spell attack against the target. On a hit, the target takes damage equal to 1d6 + your spellcasting ability modifier. The damage type depends on the number you roll on the d6: 1 deals poison, 2 deals fire, 3 deals cold, 4 deals lightning, 5 deals acid, and 6 deals psychic. If you roll multiple d6 for the damage roll, such as after scoring a critical hit, you choose the damage type among the numbers rolled.</p>
            <p class="indent">This spell allows you to conjure and throw more than one card when you reach higher levels: two cards at 5th level, three cards at 11th level, and four cards at 17th level. You can direct the cards towards the same target or to different ones. Make a separate attack roll for each card.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">0</set>
            <set name="school">Conjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">90 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Magic Rune" type="Spell" source="The Cardmaster" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_CARDMASTER_SPELL_MAGIC_RUNE">
        <supports>Cardmaster</supports>
        <description>
            <p>A bolt of arcane energy streaks towards a creature within range. Make a ranged spell attack against that creature. On a hit, the target takes 4d8 force damage, and a magical rune is inscribed upon on that creature. On a miss, the target is dealt no damage, and the rune instead appears on the ground directly beneath the targeted creature. Either way, the rune lasts for 1 minute, or until it is detonated.</p>
            <p class="indent">If the rune is on a creature, damaging that creature causes the rune to detonate. If the rune is on the ground, it detonates when it is targeted by a damaging attack, or when it is within the area of a damaging ability, such as the fireball spell.</p>
            <p class="indent">When the rune detonates, each creature within 10 feet of it must make a Dexterity saving throw. If the rune is inscribed on a creature, that creature makes the save at disadvantage. A creature takes 4d8 force damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, the damage of the detonation increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 4th.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">4</set>
            <set name="school">evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">120 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
</elements>