<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Warden Class</name>
        <author url="https://www.reddit.com/user/layhnet">Layhnet</author>
        <update version="0.0.7">
            <file name="class-warden.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/classes/class-warden.xml" />
        </update>
        <!-- version 2.1: https://drive.google.com/open?id=1XKnQu_8_HEav2RK55e0awi_xAZGkH_lA -->
    </info>
    
    <element name="Warden" type="Class" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_WARDEN">
        <description>
            <p>As his footfalls touch down upon the snow, it melts around their cloven shape. He’s lived among the frozen embrace of the north for so long, sustained by the fire burning inside of him. His spear drags along the snow beside him as his pace picks up. His dark eyes suddenly glowing with a fierce amber light as he enters a full running stride. His prey lay still, staining the snow in his wake. Unwanted guests will not encroach upon his territory so long as he draws breath.</p>
            <p class="indent">Thunder booms in the distance. The dark halls of this ruined castle alight with each crack of lightning. The diminutive goblin crouches in the corner, seeming to cower from each bolt. The heavily armored adventurer steps through the hallway, each step like an echo to the storm outside. As he rounds the next corner, the small goblin pounces onto his back, unleashing an electrified energy from his finger tips that courses throughout the adventurer’s armor and brings him to his knees. The goblin cocks his fist and plunges it into a kink in the armor and knocks the adventurer out cold.</p>
            <p class="indent">Perched atop a rocky outcropping a travel worn elf gestures with her hands and summons a cloud of fog and sends it into the mountain pass with a gust of wind. The trolls who have taken up residence at the narrowest part of the pass, claiming tolls on unsuspecting travelers, are completely enveloped by the thick miasma and bewildered as to its source. The rest of the adventuring party descend on the trolls and carve them in twain, opening the passage for their contract holder.</p>
            <p class="indent">No matter their duties, no matter their creed, a warden will have honed his skill in battle alongside his attunement to the elemental power of the material plane into a force of nature. Each warden has a different take on what the natural order of things is but the one thing they have in common is a natural born ability to command the elements and an aptitude for combat.</p>
            <h4>FORCES OF NATURE</h4>
            <p>Wardens all share an innate ability to command the elements to some degree. They are durable and have a survivalist instinct as well which leads most wardens to specialize in formal combat as well, often supplementing a powerful weapon strike with an elemental edge. Beyond those basic similarities, each warden will specialize in a specific area of the battlefield. Either as a stalwart defender in the vanguard, following up the rear using ranged weaponry and spells, or skirmishing around the battlefield and using the terrain to their advantage. This combination of innate magical power and martial prowess gives the warden an edge in combat and a unique place amongst an adventuring party.</p>
            <h4>DISTANT COUSINS</h4>
            <p>Unlike a druid, a warden does not serve nature; but rather commands nature to serve them. Their power is raw and innate and does not come from a lifetime of patience and practice. They are more at home in the confine of cities than other naturalists too and often find a position of duty within the civilized world.</p>
            <p class="indent">The work of a warden is never quite done, however. They often find themselves on the move from task to task, only very rarely spending their entire life dedicated to a single cause and working to achieve its resolution.</p>
            <h5>ELEMENTAL AWAKENING</h5>
            <p>Wardens are a product of their elemental awakening. Regardless of their prime elemental affinity, their being is intrinsic with their inner connection to the elements. Consider the circumstance of your awakening when creating a warden. Think about how that might connect you to the world and its denizens.</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d6</td><td>Elemental Awakening</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>When I was young, I found a cave outside of town. I made this my secret hideout and spent all my free time here. Little did I know it was a portal to one of the Elemental Planes.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>I was immaculately conceived. When I was born, my body was covered in aspects of the elements (ash, water, vines, etc.)</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>My hometown exists where a mage war once occured, and the elemental residue has tainted the land.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>Deep into my lineage, my ancestors immigrated from an elemental plane.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>One day, when I awoke, my eyes suddenly changed colour. At random times, they change between red, blue, green, white, and grey.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>On each of my birthdays each year, a local natural disaster occurs.</td></tr>
            </table>
            <h5>PLACE IN THE WORLD</h5>
            <p>While a helpful warden is well received in any community, how they feel about being part of civilization differs between each warden. Consider how you regard society and how you respond to living in or visiting bustling city centers.</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d6</td><td>Place in the World</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>You feel as though your powers ostracize you from society, and you go to great lengths to keep them a secret.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>Wherever you travel to new places, you wish to use your powers to help the disenfranchised.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>A long time ago, you were cornered for showing your powers and had to use them to escape grave injury. You have a general anxiety that this will occur again some day.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>You yearn to visit the City of Brass and feel that other cities pale in comparison.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>You feel much more comfortable in druid groves or camping in the wild, as being surrounded in worked stone makes you unsettled.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>You relish the opportunity to be part of society, as you were sheltered from it in the past.</td></tr>
            </table>
            <h4>CREATING A WARDEN</h4>
            <p>The most important aspect of a warden is their affinity to the natural world and how they marry it to their combat techniques. While the specific discipline of a warden’s martial prowess is chosen at 1st level, their prime element doesn’t mature until 3rd. This prime element affects the playstyle of your warden, so plan by reading the features. Do you thrum with a fiery core? Are your movements as still as the snow atop a mountain? Or does the tenacity of a storm rage within you?</p>
            <p class="indent">Do you see yourself taking up arms to defend your fellow adventurers? Or stalwartly defending your home town? Or do you set yourself out as a contract for hire – combatting the enemies of your employer to aid in your pursuits to cleanse nature.</p>
            <p class="indent">Your duties can often conflict with the laws of civilization and thus wardens typically lean to the chaotic or neutral good alignments. However, some are known to take their duties more seriously will walk the fine line between good and evil.</p>
            <h5>QUICK BUILD</h5>
            <p>You can make a warden quickly by following these suggestions. First, Strength or Dexterity should be your highest score to improve your martial presence. Then make Wisdom or Constitution your next highest score depending on your place on the battlefield. Second, choose the outlander background</p>
            <h2>CLASS FEATURES</h2>
            <p>As a warden, you gain the following class features.</p>
            <h5>HIT POINTS</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Hit Dice:</strong> 1d10 per class level</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at 1st Level:</strong> 10 + your Constitution modifier</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at Higher Levels:</strong> 1d10 (or 6) + your Constitution modifier per class level after 1st</li>
            </ul>
            <h5>PROFICIENCIES</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Armor:</strong> Light armor, medium armor, shields</li>
                <li><strong>Weapons:</strong> Simple weapons</li>
                <li><strong>Tools:</strong> None</li>
            </ul>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Saving Throws:</strong> Wisdom, Strength</li>
                <li><strong>Skills:</strong> Choose two skills from Animal Handling, Athletics, Arcana, Intimidation, Investigation, Nature and Survival</li>
            </ul>
            <h5>EQUIPMENT</h5>
            <p>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>(a) any two simple weapons or (b) any martial weapon (if proficient)</li>
                <li>(a) leather armor or (b) scale mail armor</li>
                <li>(a) a shortbow and 20 arrows or (b) a shield</li>
                <li>An explorer’s pack, and a component pouch</li>
            </ul>
            <p>Alternatively, you can ignore the equipment here and in your background, and buy 5d4 × 10gp worth of equipment from chapter 5 in the Player’s Handbook.</p>
			<h5 class="caption">THE WARDEN</h5>
            <table class="class-features">
                <thead>
                    <tr>Level<th></th><th>Proficiency Bonus</th><th class="left">Features</th><th>Power Die</th><th>Spells Known</th><th>Spell Slots</th><th>Slot Level</th></tr>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                    <tr><td>1st</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Combat Discipline, Natural Awareness, Natural Power</td><td>4 (d4)</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>2nd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Glamour, Source Magic</td><td>4 (d4)</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>1st</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Prime Element</td><td>4 (d4)</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>1st</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>4th</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>4 (d4)</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>1st</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Extra Attack</td><td>5 (d6)</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>2nd</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>6th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Combat Discipline Feature</td><td>5 (d6)</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>2nd</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>7th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Prime Elemental Shield</td><td>5 (d6)</td><td>4</td><td>2</td><td>2nd</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>8th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>5 (d6)</td><td>4</td><td>2</td><td>2nd</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">—</td><td>6 (d6)</td><td>5</td><td>2</td><td>3rd</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>10th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Combat Discipline Feature, Nature Sense</td><td>6 (d6)</td><td>5</td><td>2</td><td>3rd</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>11th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Primeval Magic</td><td>6 (d8)</td><td>6</td><td>2</td><td>3rd</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>12th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>6 (d8)</td><td>6</td><td>2</td><td>3rd</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>13th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">—</td><td>7 (d8)</td><td>7</td><td>3</td><td>4th</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>14th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Combat Discipline Feature</td><td>7 (d8)</td><td>7</td><td>3</td><td>4th</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>15th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Channel Power</td><td>7 (d8)</td><td>8</td><td>3</td><td>4th</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>16th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>7 (d8)</td><td>8</td><td>3</td><td>4th</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>17th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">—</td><td>8 (d10)</td><td>9</td><td>3</td><td>5th</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>18th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Improved Natural Awareness</td><td>8 (d10)</td><td>9</td><td>3</td><td>5th</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>19th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>8 (d10)</td><td>10</td><td>3</td><td>5th</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>20th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Master of Elements</td><td>8 (d10)</td><td>10</td><td>3</td><td>5th</td></tr>
                </tbody>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_COMBAT_DISCIPLINE" />
            <div element="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_NATURAL_AWARENESS" />
            <div element="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_NATURAL_POWER" />
            <div element="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_GLAMOUR" />
            <div element="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_SOURCE_MAGIC" />
            <div element="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_PRIME_ELEMENT" />
            <div element="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_ABILITY_SCORE_INCREASE" />
            <div element="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_EXTRA_ATTACK" />
            <div element="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_PRIME_ELEMENTAL_SHIELD" />
            <div element="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_NATURE_SENSE" />
            <div element="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_PRIMEVAL_MAGIC" />
            <div element="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_CHANNEL_POWER" />
            <div element="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_MASTER_OF_ELEMENTS" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <setters>
            <set name="short">A warrior-caster that commands the forces of nature.</set>
            <set name="hd">d10</set>
        </setters>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_MEDIUM_ARMOR" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_SHIELDS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" requirements="!ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_MULTICLASS_WARDEN" />

            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_WISDOM" requirements="!ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_MULTICLASS_WARDEN" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_STRENGTH" requirements="!ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_MULTICLASS_WARDEN" />
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency (Warden)" number="2" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ANIMALHANDLING|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ATHLETICS|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ARCANA|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INTIMIDATION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INVESTIGATION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_NATURE|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SURVIVAL" requirements="!ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_MULTICLASS_WARDEN" />

            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_COMBAT_DISCIPLINE" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_NATURAL_AWARENESS" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_NATURAL_POWER" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_GLAMOUR" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_SOURCE_MAGIC" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_PRIME_ELEMENT" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_ABILITY_SCORE_INCREASE" level="4" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_EXTRA_ATTACK" level="5" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_PRIME_ELEMENTAL_SHIELD" level="7" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_NATURE_SENSE" level="10" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_PRIMEVAL_MAGIC" level="11" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_CHANNEL_POWER" level="15" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_MASTER_OF_ELEMENTS" level="20" />
        </rules>
        <multiclass id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_MULTICLASS_WARDEN">
            <prerequisite>Strength or Dexterity 13, and Wisdom 13</prerequisite>
            <requirements>([str:13]||[dex:13]),[wis:13]</requirements>
            <setters>
                <set name="multiclass proficiencies"></set>
            </setters>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS" />
            </rules>
        </multiclass>
    </element>
    <element name="Combat Discipline" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_COMBAT_DISCIPLINE">
        <description>
            <p>At 1st level, you’ve completed your training in a certain combat specialty of your choice: Guardian, Fanatic, or Sage, each of which is detailed at the end of the class description. Your choice grants you features at 1st level, and again at 6th, 10th, and 14th level.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Archetype" name="Combat Discipline" supports="Warden Combat Discipline" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Natural Awareness" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_NATURAL_AWARENESS">
        <description>
            <p>Also at 1st level, the time you have spent in nature learning your craft and honing your skills has given you an acute sense of danger.</p>
            <p class="indent">You have advantage on perception checks while in a natural environment (such as a forest or a cave, but not a city or dungeon.) Also, you can identify if natural phenomena (such as tremors, eruptions, magma flows, thunderstorms, and similar) are natural or unnatural.</p>
            <p class="indent">Starting at 18th level, you also gain a bonus to your initiative equal to your Wisdom modifier and whenever you are in an entirely natural environment, you make initiative checks with advantage.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You have advantage on perception checks while in a natural environment (such as a forest or a cave, but not a city or dungeon.) Also, you can identify if natural phenomena (such as tremors, eruptions, magma flows, thunderstorms, and similar) are natural or unnatural.</description>
            <description level="18">You have advantage on perception checks while in a natural environment (such as a forest or a cave, but not a city or dungeon.) Also, you can identify if natural phenomena (such as tremors, eruptions, magma flows, thunderstorms, and similar) are natural or unnatural. You also have a bonus to your initiative of {{wisdom:modifier}} and whenever you are in an entirely natural environment, you make initiative checks with advantage.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="initiative" value="wisdom:modifier" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Natural Power" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_NATURAL_POWER">
        <description>
            <p>All wardens can pull from a well of innate power that allows them to channel the elements into their strikes.</p>
            <p class="indent">The Warden table shows how many power dice you have, as well as what die size to roll when using them.</p>
            <p class="indent">When you hit with a weapon attack, you can expend a power die to add the result to the attack’s damage roll. The damage type of the additional damage is acid, bludgeoning, cold, fire, lightning, or thunder (your choice.) This damage is magical.</p>
            <p class="indent">You regain all expended power die when you finish a long rest, or half your total amount when you finish a short rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You have {{natural-power:power-dice}}d{{natural-power:die-type}} power dice. When you hit with a weapon attack, you can expend a power die to add the result to the attack’s damage roll. The damage type of the additional damage is acid, bludgeoning, cold, fire, lightning, or thunder (your choice.) This damage is magical. You regain all expended power die when you finish a long rest, or half your total amount when you finish a short rest.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="natural-power:power-dice" value="4" level="1" />
            <stat name="natural-power:power-dice" value="1" level="5" />
            <stat name="natural-power:power-dice" value="1" level="9" />
            <stat name="natural-power:power-dice" value="1" level="13" />
            <stat name="natural-power:power-dice" value="1" level="17" />
            <stat name="natural-power:die-type" value="4" bonus="base" level="1" />
            <stat name="natural-power:die-type" value="6" bonus="base" level="5" />
            <stat name="natural-power:die-type" value="8" bonus="base" level="11" />
            <stat name="natural-power:die-type" value="10" bonus="base" level="17" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Glamour" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_GLAMOUR">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 2nd level, you can create a harmless elemental sensory effect originating from your body. This may be in the form of water dripping from your hands, a fiery glow in your eyes, or for your skin to appear mottled and earthen.</p>
            <p class="indent">When making a Charisma check, you can expend a power die and add the result to your roll.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can create a harmless elemental sensory effect originating from your body. This may be in the form of water dripping from your hands, a fiery glow in your eyes, or for your skin to appear mottled and earthen. When making a Charisma check, you can expend a power die and add the result to your roll.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Source Magic" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_SOURCE_MAGIC">
        <description>
            <p>At 2nd level, you’ve unlocked your natural born affinity with the elements in the form of spellcasting. See chapter 10 of the Player’s Handbook for the general rules of spellcasting. The warden spell list will be provided at the end of this document.</p>
            <h5>SPELL SLOTS</h5>
            <p>The Warden table shows how many spell slots you have. The table also shows what the level of those slots is; all of your spell slots are the same level. To cast one of your warden spells of 1st level or higher, you must expend a spell slot. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            <p class="indent">For example, when you are 5th level, you have two 2nd-level spell slots. To cast the 1st-level spell thunderwave, you must spend one of those slots, and you cast it as a 2nd-level spell.</p>
            <h5>SPELLS KNOWN OF 1ST LEVEL AND HIGHER</h5>
            <p>At 2nd level, you know two 1st level spells of your choice from the warden spell list.</p>
            <p class="indent">The Spells Known column of the Warden table shows when you learn more warden spells of your choice of 1st level and higher. A spell you choose must be of a level no higher than what’s shown in the table’s Slot Level column for your level. When you reach 9th level, for example, you learn a new warden spell, which can be of 1st, 2nd, or 3rd level.</p>
            <p class="indent">Additionally, when you gain a level in this class, you can choose one of your warden spells you know and replace it with another spell from the warden spell list, which also must be of a level for which you have spell slots.</p>
            <h5>SPELLCASTING ABILITY</h5>
            <p>Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for your warden spells, so you use your Wisdom whenever a spell references your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Wisdom modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a warden spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b>Spell save DC</b> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier</p>
            <p class="indent"><b>Spell attack modifier</b> = your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <spellcasting name="Warden" ability="Wisdom" prepare="false" allowReplace="true">
            <list>Warden</list>
        </spellcasting>
        <setters>
            <set name="spellcaster">true</set>
            <set name="spellcastingAbility">Wisdom</set>
        </setters>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS_SPELLCASTING_SLOTS_SOLO" requirements="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS"/>

            <stat name="warden:spellcasting:slots:count" value="1" level="2"/>
            <stat name="warden:spellcasting:slots:count" value="1" level="5"/>
            <stat name="warden:spellcasting:slots:count" value="1" level="13"/>

            <stat name="warden:spellcasting:slot" value="1" level="2" />
            <stat name="warden:spellcasting:slot" value="1" level="5" />
            <stat name="warden:spellcasting:slot" value="1" level="13" />
            
            <!-- negative count to remove slots -->
            <stat name="warden:spellcasting:slots:1" value="warden:spellcasting:slots:count" level="2" />
            <stat name="warden:spellcasting:slots:1" value="-warden:spellcasting:slots:count" level="5" />
            <stat name="warden:spellcasting:slots:2" value="warden:spellcasting:slots:count" level="5" />
            <stat name="warden:spellcasting:slots:2" value="-warden:spellcasting:slots:count" level="9" />
            <stat name="warden:spellcasting:slots:3" value="warden:spellcasting:slots:count" level="9" />
            <stat name="warden:spellcasting:slots:3" value="-warden:spellcasting:slots:count" level="13" />
            <stat name="warden:spellcasting:slots:4" value="warden:spellcasting:slots:count" level="13" />
            <stat name="warden:spellcasting:slots:4" value="-warden:spellcasting:slots:count" level="17" />
            <stat name="warden:spellcasting:slots:5" value="warden:spellcasting:slots:count" level="17" />
      
            <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Warden)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="2" number="2" spellcasting="Warden"/>
            <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Warden)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="5" spellcasting="Warden"/>
            <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Warden)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="7" spellcasting="Warden"/>
            <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Warden)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="9" spellcasting="Warden"/>
            <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Warden)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="11" spellcasting="Warden"/>
            <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Warden)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="13" spellcasting="Warden"/>
            <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Warden)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="15" spellcasting="Warden"/>
            <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Warden)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="17" spellcasting="Warden"/>
            <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Warden)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="19" spellcasting="Warden"/>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Prime Element" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_PRIME_ELEMENT">
        <description>
            <p>At 3rd level, your application of your elemental abilities encourages a specialized discipline of ability. You gain one of the following features of your choice. This choice is used by features you gain at later levels.</p>
            <h5>Earthen Bulwark</h5>
            <p>You learn the <i>magic stone<sup>XGtE</sup></i>, <i>mold earth<sup>EE</sup></i> and <i>thorn whip</i> cantrips.</p>
            <p class="indent">When you spend a power die to deal additional bludgeoning damage on an attack, the target must succeed on a Strength saving throw equal to your spell save DC, or become grappled by the ground around it if the attack was made with a melee weapon or have their movement speed halved until the start of their next turn if the attack was made with a ranged weapon.</p>
            <p class="indent">Whenever a creature moves to within 5 feet of you, you can use your reaction an expend a power die to shove them away. You make a Strength (Athletics) check contested by the target’s Strength (Athletics) or Dexterity (Acrobatics) check, adding the result of your power die to your roll. If you win the contest, you push the target back 10 feet and its movement becomes 0 until the end of its turn.</p>
            <h5>Flaming Bravery</h5>
            <p>You learn the <i>control flames<sup>EE</sup></i>, <i>firebolt</i> and <i>produce flame</i> cantrips.</p>
            <p class="indent">When you spend a power die to deal additional fire damage on an attack, the target takes additional fire damage equal to your power die at the start of its next turn.</p>
            <p class="indent">Whenever a creature makes an attack roll against you, you can use your reaction and expend a power die to add the number rolled to your AC. You can choose to do this after the creature has rolled to attack, but must decide before the DM says whether the roll hits or misses. If you choose to expend this die and the attack misses, the attacking creature takes fire damage equal your Wisdom modifier + the result of your power die.</p>
            <h5>Putrid Corrosion</h5>
            <p>You learn the <i>acid splash</i>, <i>infestation<sup>XGtE</sup></i>, and <i>primal savagery<sup>XGtE</sup></i> cantrips.</p>
            <p class="indent">When you spend a power die to deal additional acid damage on an attack, the target is unable to add their Strength or Dexterity modifier to weapon attack and damage rolls they make until the end of their next turn.</p>
            <p class="indent">Whenever you cast a spell that forces a creature to make a saving throw, you can expend a power die and add a corrosive element to the spell. Any creature affected by this spell that fails their saving throw also suffers the following effect. At the beginning of each of its turns, this creature must make a Constitution saving throw against your spell save DC. On a failed save, this creature takes acid damage equal to the result on your power die. On a successful save, or after 1 minute, the effect ends.</p>
            <h5>Stoic Chill</h5>
            <p>You learn the <i>frostbite<sup>XGtE</sup></i>, <i>ray of frost</i>, and <i>shape water<sup>XGtE</sup></i> cantrips.</p>
            <p class="indent">When you spend a power die to deal additional cold damage on an attack, the target has disadvantage on the next weapon attack it makes before the start of your next turn.</p>
            <p class="indent">Whenever you must make a saving throw, you can use your reaction and expend a power die to add that die roll to your total. You may choose to do this after you have rolled the saving throw, but must decide before the DM says whether the roll succeeds or fails. If you choose to expend a die this way and succeed on the saving throw, all surfaces in a 10-foot radius of you become covered in enchanted ice which is difficult terrain. Any creature (other than you) in this area when the ice forms must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw against your spell save DC, or fall prone. This effect lasts until the end of your next turn.</p>
            <h5>Unrelenting Storm</h5>
            <p>You learn the <i>gust<sup>EE</sup></i>, <i>lightning lure<sup>SCAG</sup></i> and <i>shocking grasp</i> cantrips.</p>
            <p class="indent">When you spend a power die to deal additional lightning or thunder damage on an attack, the target takes damage of the same type equal to your power die + your Wisdom modifier if it moves willingly before the start of your next turn.</p>
            <p class="indent">Whenever you make an attack roll with a weapon attack, you can expend a power die and add that number to your attack roll. You may choose to do this after you have rolled to attack, but must decide before the DM says whether the roll hits or misses. If this attack roll hits, all creatures within 5 feet of you or the target of your attack must make a Constitution saving throw against your spell save DC, being knocked back 5 feet on a failed saving throw.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Prime Element" supports="Warden Prime Element" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Ability Score Increase" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_ABILITY_SCORE_INCREASE">
        <description>
            <p>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Warden 4)" supports="Improvement Option,Warden,4" level="4" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Warden 8)" supports="Improvement Option,Warden,8" level="8" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Warden 12)" supports="Improvement Option,Warden,12" level="12" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Warden 16)" supports="Improvement Option,Warden,16" level="16" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Warden 19)" supports="Improvement Option,Warden,19" level="19" />
        </rules>
    </element>

    <!-- Prime Elements -->
        <!-- Earthen Bulwark -->
            <element name="Earthen Bulwark" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_PRIME_ELEMENT_EARTHEN_BULWARK">
                <supports>Warden Prime Element</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>You learn the <i>magic stone<sup>XGtE</sup></i>, <i>mold earth<sup>EE</sup></i> and <i>thorn whip</i> cantrips.</p>
                    <p class="indent">When you spend a power die to deal additional bludgeoning damage on an attack, the target must succeed on a Strength saving throw equal to your spell save DC, or become grappled by the ground around it if the attack was made with a melee weapon or have their movement speed halved until the start of their next turn if the attack was made with a ranged weapon.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Whenever a creature moves to within 5 feet of you, you can use your reaction an expend a power die to shove them away. You make a Strength (Athletics) check contested by the target’s Strength (Athletics) or Dexterity (Acrobatics) check, adding the result of your power die to your roll. If you win the contest, you push the target back 10 feet and its movement becomes 0 until the end of its turn.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>When you spend a power die to deal additional bludgeoning damage on an attack, the target must succeed on a Strength saving throw (save DC {{spellcasting:dc:wis}}), or become grappled by the ground if the attack was made with a melee weapon or have their movement speed halved until the start of their next turn if the attack was made with a ranged weapon. </description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_MAGIC_STONE" spellcasting="Warden" known="true" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_MOLD_EARTH" spellcasting="Warden" known="true" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_THORN_WHIP" spellcasting="Warden" known="true" />
                    <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_PRIME_ELEMENT_EARTHEN_BULWARK_2" />
                    <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_PRIME_ELEMENT_EARTHEN_BULWARK_ELEMENTAL_SHIELD" level="7" />
                    <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_EARTHEN_BULWARK_MASTER_OF_ELEMENTS" level="20" />
                </rules>
            </element>
                <element name="Earthen Bulwark" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_PRIME_ELEMENT_EARTHEN_BULWARK_2">
                    <description />
                    <sheet action="Reaction">
                        <description>Whenever a creature moves to within 5 feet of you, you can expend a power die to shove them away. You make a Strength (Athletics) check contested by the target’s Strength (Athletics) or Dexterity (Acrobatics) check, adding the result of your power die to your roll. If you win the contest, you push the target back 10 feet and its movement becomes 0 until the end of its turn.</description>
                    </sheet>
                </element>
                <element name="Prime Elemental Shield" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_PRIME_ELEMENT_EARTHEN_BULWARK_ELEMENTAL_SHIELD">
                    <description />
                    <sheet action="Reaction" alt="Elemental Shield">
                        <description>When a creature makes a ranged attack against you or you are subjected to an effect that allows you to make a Dexterity saving throw, you can kick up a cloud of dust and rocks to provide you half cover against that attack or effect.</description>
                    </sheet>
                </element>
                <element name="Master of Elements" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_EARTHEN_BULWARK_MASTER_OF_ELEMENTS">
                    <description />
                    <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                        <description>You can cast investiture of stone without expending a spell slot.</description>
                    </sheet>
                    <rules>
                        <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_INVESTITURE_OF_STONE" />
                    </rules>
                </element>

        <!-- Flaming Bravery -->
            <element name="Flaming Bravery" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_PRIME_ELEMENT_FLAMING_BRAVERY">
                <supports>Warden Prime Element</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>You learn the <i>control flames<sup>EE</sup></i>, <i>firebolt</i> and <i>produce flame</i> cantrips.</p>
                    <p class="indent">When you spend a power die to deal additional fire damage on an attack, the target takes additional fire damage equal to your power die at the start of its next turn.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Whenever a creature makes an attack roll against you, you can use your reaction and expend a power die to add the number rolled to your AC. You can choose to do this after the creature has rolled to attack, but must decide before the DM says whether the roll hits or misses. If you choose to expend this die and the attack misses, the attacking creature takes fire damage equal to your Wisdom modifier + the result of your power die.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>When you spend a power die to deal additional fire damage on an attack, the target takes additional fire damage equal to your power die at the start of its next turn.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_CONTROL_FLAMES" spellcasting="Warden" known="true" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIRE_BOLT" spellcasting="Warden" known="true" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PRODUCE_FLAME" spellcasting="Warden" known="true" />
                    <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_PRIME_ELEMENT_FLAMING_BRAVERY_2" />
                    <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_PRIME_ELEMENT_FLAMING_BRAVERY_ELEMENTAL_SHIELD" level="7" />
                    <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_FLAMING_BRAVERY_MASTER_OF_ELEMENTS" level="20" />
                </rules>
            </element>
                <element name="Flaming Bravery" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_PRIME_ELEMENT_FLAMING_BRAVERY_2">
                    <description />
                    <sheet action="Reaction">
                        <description>Whenever a creature makes an attack roll against you, you can use your reaction and expend a power die to add the number rolled to your AC. You can choose to do this after the creature has rolled to attack, but must decide before the DM says whether the roll hits or misses. If you choose to expend this die and the attack misses, the attacking creature takes fire damage equal to {{wisdom:modifier}} + the result of your power die.</description>
                    </sheet>
                </element>
                <element name="Prime Elemental Shield" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_PRIME_ELEMENT_FLAMING_BRAVERY_ELEMENTAL_SHIELD">
                    <description />
                    <sheet action="Reaction">
                        <description>When a creature forces you to save against being grappled, shoved, or knocked prone you can make that save with advantage, causing your body to suddenly flare up in energy.</description>
                    </sheet>
                </element>
                <element name="Master of Elements" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_FLAMING_BRAVERY_MASTER_OF_ELEMENTS">
                    <description />
                    <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                        <description>You can cast investiture of flame without expending a spell slot.</description>
                    </sheet>
                    <rules>
                        <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_INVESTITURE_OF_FLAME" />
                    </rules>
                </element>

        <!-- Putrid Corrosion -->
            <element name="Putrid Corrosion" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_PRIME_ELEMENT_PUTRID_CORROSION">
                <supports>Warden Prime Element</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>You learn the <i>acid splash</i>, <i>infestation<sup>XGtE</sup></i>, and <i>primal savagery<sup>XGtE</sup></i> cantrips.</p>
                    <p class="indent">When you spend a power die to deal additional acid damage on an attack, the target is unable to add their Strength or Dexterity modifier to weapon attack and damage rolls they make until the end of their next turn.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Whenever you cast a spell that forces a creature to make a saving throw, you can expend a power die and add a corrosive element to the spell. Any creature affected by this spell that fails their saving throw also suffers the following effect. At the beginning of each of its turns, this creature must make a Constitution saving throw against your spell save DC. On a failed save, this creature takes acid damage equal to the result on your power die. On a successful save, or after 1 minute, the effect ends.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>When you spend a power die to deal additional acid damage on an attack, the target is unable to add their Strength or Dexterity modifier to weapon attack and damage rolls they make until the end of their next turn.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ACID_SPLASH" spellcasting="Warden" known="true" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_INFESTATION" spellcasting="Warden" known="true" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_PRIMAL_SAVAGERY" spellcasting="Warden" known="true" />
                    <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_PRIME_ELEMENT_PUTRID_CORROSION_2" />
                    <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_PRIME_ELEMENT_PUTRID_CORROSION_ELEMENTAL_SHIELD" level="7" />
                    <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_PUTRID_CORROSION_MASTER_OF_ELEMENTS" level="20" />
                </rules>
            </element>
                <element name="Putrid Corrosion" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_PRIME_ELEMENT_PUTRID_CORROSION_2">
                    <description />
                    <sheet>
                        <description>Whenever you cast a spell that forces a creature to make a saving throw, you can expend a power die and add a corrosive element to the spell. Any creature affected by this spell that fails their saving throw also suffers the following effect. At the beginning of each of its turns, this creature must make a Constitution saving throw (save DC {{spellcasting:dc:wis}}). On a failed save, this creature takes acid damage equal to the result on your power die. On a successful save, or after 1 minute, the effect ends.</description>
                    </sheet>
                </element>
                <element name="Prime Elemental Shield" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_PRIME_ELEMENT_PUTRID_CORROSION_ELEMENTAL_SHIELD">
                    <description />
                    <sheet action="Reaction">
                        <description>When a creature hits you with a melee attack with a metal weapon, you can weaken their weapon. Whenever that creature makes an attack with that weapon until the start of their next turn, that attack is made with disadvantage and can’t benefit from advantage.</description>
                    </sheet>
                </element>
                <element name="Master of Elements" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_PUTRID_CORROSION_MASTER_OF_ELEMENTS">
                    <description />
                    <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                        <description>You can cast investiture of corruption without expending a spell slot.</description>
                    </sheet>
                    <rules>
                        <grant type="Spell" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_SPELL_INVESTITURE_OF_CORRUPTION" />
                    </rules>
                </element>

        <!-- Stoic Chill -->
            <element name="Stoic Chill" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_PRIME_ELEMENT_STOIC_CHILL">
                <supports>Warden Prime Element</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>You learn the <i>frostbite<sup>XGtE</sup></i>, <i>ray of frost</i>, and <i>shape water<sup>XGtE</sup></i> cantrips.</p>
                    <p class="indent">When you spend a power die to deal additional cold damage on an attack, the target has disadvantage on the next weapon attack it makes before the start of your next turn.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Whenever you must make a saving throw, you can use your reaction and expend a power die to add that die roll to your total. You may choose to do this after you have rolled the saving throw, but must decide before the DM says whether the roll succeeds or fails. If you choose to expend a die this way and succeed on the saving throw, all surfaces in a 10-foot radius of you become covered in enchanted ice which is difficult terrain. Any creature (other than you) in this area when the ice forms must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw against your spell save DC, or fall prone. This effect lasts until the end of your next turn.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>When you spend a power die to deal additional cold damage on an attack, the target has disadvantage on the next weapon attack it makes before the start of your next turn.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_FROSTBITE" spellcasting="Warden" known="true" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RAY_OF_FROST" spellcasting="Warden" known="true" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_SHAPE_WATER" spellcasting="Warden" known="true" />
                    <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_PRIME_ELEMENT_STOIC_CHILL_2" />
                    <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_PRIME_ELEMENT_STOIC_CHILL_ELEMENTAL_SHIELD" level="7" />
                    <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_STOIC_CHILL_MASTER_OF_ELEMENTS" level="20" />
                </rules>
            </element>
                <element name="Stoic Chill" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_PRIME_ELEMENT_STOIC_CHILL_2">
                    <description />
                    <sheet action="Reaction">
                        <description>Whenever you must make a saving throw, you can expend a power die to add that die roll to your total. You may choose to do this after you have rolled the saving throw, but must decide before the DM says whether the roll succeeds or fails. If you choose to expend a die this way and succeed on the saving throw, all surfaces in a 10-foot radius of you become covered in enchanted ice which is difficult terrain. Any creature (other than you) in this area when the ice forms must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw (save DC {{spellcasting:dc:wis}}), or fall prone. This effect lasts until the end of your next turn.</description>
                    </sheet>
                </element>
                <element name="Prime Elemental Shield" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_PRIME_ELEMENT_STOIC_CHILL_ELEMENTAL_SHIELD">
                    <description />
                    <sheet action="Reaction">
                        <description>Immediately after a creature has successfully hits you with a melee weapon, you can have that creature make a Constitution saving throw (save DC {{spellcasting:dc:wis}}). On a failed roll, you freeze their weapon, causing it to become impossibly heavy and rendered unusable. The weapon remains in a deep freeze and until the end of the attacking creature’s turn.</description>
                    </sheet>
                </element>
                <element name="Master of Elements" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_STOIC_CHILL_MASTER_OF_ELEMENTS">
                    <description />
                    <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                        <description>You can cast investiture of ice without expending a spell slot.</description>
                    </sheet>
                    <rules>
                        <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_INVESTITURE_OF_ICE" />
                    </rules>
                </element>

        <!-- Unrelenting Storm -->
            <element name="Unrelenting Storm" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_PRIME_ELEMENT_UNRELENTING_STORM">
                <supports>Warden Prime Element</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>You learn the <i>gust<sup>EE</sup></i>, <i>lightning lure<sup>SCAG</sup></i> and <i>shocking grasp</i> cantrips.</p>
                    <p class="indent">When you spend a power die to deal additional lightning or thunder damage on an attack, the target takes damage of the same type equal to your power die + your Wisdom modifier if it moves willingly before the start of your next turn.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Whenever you make an attack roll with a weapon attack, you can expend a power die and add that number to your attack roll. You may choose to do this after you have rolled to attack, but must decide before the DM says whether the roll hits or misses. If this attack roll hits, all creatures within 5 feet of you or the target of your attack must make a Constitution saving throw against your spell save DC, being knocked back 5 feet on a failed saving throw.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>When you spend a power die to deal additional lightning or thunder damage on an attack, the target takes damage of the same type equal to your power die + {{wisdom:modifier}} if it moves willingly before the start of your next turn.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_GUST" spellcasting="Warden" known="true" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_SCAG_SPELL_LIGHTNING_LURE" spellcasting="Warden" known="true" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHOCKING_GRASP" spellcasting="Warden" known="true" />
                    <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_PRIME_ELEMENT_UNRELENTING_STORM_2" />
                    <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_PRIME_ELEMENT_UNRELENTING_STORM_ELEMENTAL_SHIELD" level="7" />
                    <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_UNRELENTING_STORM_MASTER_OF_ELEMENTS" level="20" />
                </rules>
            </element>
                <element name="Unrelenting Storm" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_PRIME_ELEMENT_UNRELENTING_STORM_2">
                    <description />
                    <sheet>
                        <description>Whenever you make an attack roll with a weapon attack, you can expend a power die and add that number to your attack roll. You may choose to do this after you have rolled to attack, but must decide before the DM says whether the roll hits or misses. If this attack roll hits, all creatures within 5 feet of you or the target of your attack must make a Constitution saving throw (save DC {{spellcasting:dc:wis}}), being knocked back 5 feet on a failed saving throw.</description>
                    </sheet>
                </element>
                <element name="Prime Elemental Shield" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_PRIME_ELEMENT_UNRELENTING_STORM_ELEMENTAL_SHIELD">
                    <description />
                    <sheet action="Reaction">
                        <description>Anytime a creature hits you or an ally within 5 feet of you with a ranged weapon attack, you can create a buffet of air that dampens the impact of the projectile, reducing the damage dealt by {{wisdom:modifier}}.</description>
                    </sheet>
                </element>
                <element name="Master of Elements" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_UNRELENTING_STORM_MASTER_OF_ELEMENTS">
                    <description />
                    <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                        <description>You can cast  without expending a spell slot.</description>
                    </sheet>
                    <rules>
                        <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_INVESTITURE_OF_WIND" />
                    </rules>
                </element>

    <element name="Extra Attack" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_EXTRA_ATTACK">
        <description>
            <p>Beginning at 5th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="extra attack:count" value="2" level="5" bonus="extra attack" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Prime Elemental Shield" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_PRIME_ELEMENTAL_SHIELD">
        <description>
            <p>At 7th level, you can use your reaction to produce one the following effects, depending on the prime element you’ve chosen.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Earthen Bulwark.</i></b> When a creature makes a ranged attack against you or you are subjected to an effect that allows you to make a Dexterity saving throw, you can kick up a cloud of dust and rocks as a reaction to provide you half cover against that attack or effect.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Flaming Bravery.</i></b> When a creature forces you to save against being grappled, shoved, or knocked prone you can use your reaction to make that save with advantage, causing your body to suddenly flare up in energy.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Putrid Corrosion.</i></b> When a creature hits you with a melee attack with a metal weapon, you can use your reaction to weaken their weapon. Whenever that creature makes an attack with that weapon until the start of their next turn, that attack is made with disadvantage and can’t benefit from advantage.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Stoic Chill.</i></b> Immediately after a creature has successfully hits you with a melee weapon, you can use your reaction to have that creature make a Constitution saving throw equal to your spell save DC. On a failed roll, you freeze their weapon, causing it to become impossibly heavy and rendered unusable. The weapon remains in a deep freeze and until the end of the attacking creature’s turn.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Unrelenting Storm.</i></b> Anytime a creature hits you or an ally within 5 feet of you with a ranged weapon attack, you can use your reaction to create a buffet of air that dampens the impact of the projectile, reducing the damage dealt by the attack by an amount equal to your Wisdom modifier.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Nature Sense" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_NATURE_SENSE">
        <description>
            <p>Beginning at 10th level, you can channel nature to extend your senses.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can spend 1 minute touching a natural surface and focusing on it, after which you can shift your perspective as if your senses were originating from a point on that surface up to 100 feet away, and you are blinded and deafened to your own senses. You can maintain this vantage point for up to 10 minutes if you don’t move, and can choose to end it at any time (no action required.)</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can spend 1 minute touching a natural surface and focusing on it, after which you can shift your perspective as if your senses were originating from a point on that surface up to 100 feet away, and you are blinded and deafened to your own senses. You can maintain this vantage point for up to 10 minutes if you don’t move, and can choose to end it at any time (no action required.)</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Primeval Magic" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_PRIMEVAL_MAGIC">
        <description>
            <p>Beginning at 11th level, when you use your action to cast a cantrip, you can make one weapon attack as a bonus action.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Bonus Action">
            <description>When you use your action to cast a cantrip, you can make one weapon attack as a bonus action.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Channel Power" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_CHANNEL_POWER">
        <description>
            <p>Beginning at 15th level, your natural power can benefit your spellcasting further. You can sacrifice your power dice to cast an additional spell.</p>
            <p class="indent">As a bonus action, you can expend four power dice to regain a single spell slot. Once you have used this feature, you must finish a long rest before you can do so again.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>You can expend four power dice to regain a single spell slot.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Master of Elements" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARDEN_MASTER_OF_ELEMENTS">
        <description>
            <p>At 20th level, your mastery of your prime element has granted you access to its most powerful form.</p>
            <p class="indent">You gain one of the following 6th-level spells depending on your prime element choice. You can cast this spell once without expending a spell slot, and this spell requires no concentration to maintain when you cast it this way. Once you have used this feature, you must finish a long rest before you can do so again.</p>
            <ul>
                <li>Earthen Bulwark: <i>investiture of stone<sup>XGtE</sup></i></li>
                <li>Flaming Bravery: <i>investiture of flame<sup>XGtE</sup></i></li>
                <li>Putrid Corrosion: <i>investiture of corruption</i></li>
                <li>Stoic Chill: <i>investiture of ice<sup>XGtE</sup></i></li>
                <li>Unrelenting Storm: <i>investiture of wind<sup>XGtE</sup></i></li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
    </element>


    <!-- Combat Disciplines -->
        <element name="Guardian" type="Archetype" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_WARDEN_GUARDIAN">
            <supports>Warden Combat Discipline</supports>
            <description>
                <p>Your focus of combat training has been on the utilization of martial weapons to combat your foes and defend nature. By focusing your training on weaponry, you have sharpened the edge of your resolve and found balance between nature and steel.</p>
                <div element="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_GUARDIAN_GUARDIAN_SPELLS" />
                <div element="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_GUARDIAN_COMBAT_TRAINING" />
                <div element="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_GUARDIAN_STRENGTH_OF_THE_ELEMENTS" />
                <div element="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_GUARDIAN_SHIELDING_AURA" />
                <div element="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_GUARDIAN_NATURES_FURY" />
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_GUARDIAN_GUARDIAN_SPELLS" level="1" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_GUARDIAN_COMBAT_TRAINING" level="1" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_GUARDIAN_STRENGTH_OF_THE_ELEMENTS" level="6" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_GUARDIAN_SHIELDING_AURA" level="10" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_GUARDIAN_NATURES_FURY" level="14" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Guardian Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_GUARDIAN_GUARDIAN_SPELLS">
                <description>
                    <p>You learn an additional spell when you reach certain levels in this archetype, as shown in the Guardian Spells table. The spell counts as a warden spell for you, but it doesn’t count against the number of warden spells you know.</p>
                    <h5>GUARDIAN SPELLS</h5>
                    <table>
                        <thead>
                            <tr><td>Spell Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                        </thead>
                        <tr><td>1st</td><td><i>ensnaring strike</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>2nd</td><td><i>maximilian’s earthen graspXGE</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>3rd</td><td><i>elemental weapon</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>4th</td><td><i>stoneskin</i></td></tr>
                    </table>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENSNARING_STRIKE" spellcasting="Warden" known="true" level="2" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_MAXIMILIANS_EARTHEN_GRASP" spellcasting="Warden" known="true" level="5" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ELEMENTAL_WEAPON" spellcasting="Warden" known="true" level="9" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_STONESKIN" spellcasting="Warden" known="true" level="13" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Combat Training" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_GUARDIAN_COMBAT_TRAINING">
                <description>
                    <p>Your training has been with a variety of styles suited to your tastes and the needs of the situation.</p>
                    <p class="indent">You gain proficiency in all martial weapons and heavy armor. In addition, choose one of the following fighting style options. You can’t take the same Fighting Style option more than once, even if you get to choose again.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Archery. </i></b>You gain a +2 bonus to attack rolls you make with ranged weapons.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Great Weapon Fighting. </i></b>When you roll a 1 or 2 on a damage die for an attack you make with a melee weapon that you are wielding with two hands, you can reroll the die and must use the new roll, even if the new roll is a 1 or 2. The weapon must have the two-handed or versatile property for you to gain this benefit.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b><i>Protection. </i></b>When a creature you can see attacks a target other than you that is within 5 feet of you, you can use your reaction to impose disadvantage on the attack roll. You must be wielding a shield.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_MARTIAL_WEAPONS" />
                    <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_HEAVY_ARMOR" />
                    <select type="Class Feature" name="Fighting Style" supports="Fighting Style, Warden" />
                    <!-- potentially add fighting maneuvers rules here...-->
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Strength of the Elements" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_GUARDIAN_STRENGTH_OF_THE_ELEMENTS">
                <description>
                    <p>Starting at 6th level, when you spend a power die to deal additional damage to a creature, you can choose to use the maximum result on that die, instead of rolling it. If the attack is a critical hit, you add double the maximum result if you use this feature.</p>
                    <p class="indent">You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier (a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a short or long rest.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="{{strength-of-elements:uses}}/Short Rest">
                    <description>When you spend a power die to deal additional damage to a creature, you can choose to use the maximum result on that die, instead of rolling it. If the attack is a critical hit, you add double the maximum result if you use this feature.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="strength-of-elements:uses" value="1" bonus="base" />
                    <stat name="strength-of-elements:uses" value="wisdom:modifier" bonus="base" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Shielding Aura" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_GUARDIAN_SHIELDING_AURA">
                <description>
                    <p>Starting at 10th level, if you or an ally you can see within 30 feet take acid, fire, cold, lightning, or thunder damage, you can spend your reaction to reduce the damage to that creature by half.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet action="Reaction">
                    <description>If you or an ally you can see within 30 feet take acid, fire, cold, lightning, or thunder damage, you can spend reduce the damage to that creature by half.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Nature’s Fury" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_GUARDIAN_NATURES_FURY">
                <description>
                    <p>At 14th level, your mastery of combat has enabled you to tap into your elemental affinity to strike true.</p>
                    <p class="indent">When you make a weapon attack, you can expend a power die to grant yourself advantage on that attack. For each d20 that is part of the attack roll that would hit the creature, you deal additional damage equal to the result of your power die. The damage type of this additional damage is bludgeoning, acid, cold, fire, lightning, or thunder (your choice.)</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>When you make a weapon attack, you can expend a power die to grant yourself advantage on that attack. For each d20 that is part of the attack roll that would hit the creature, you deal additional damage equal to the result of your power die. The damage type of this additional damage is bludgeoning, acid, cold, fire, lightning, or thunder (your choice.)</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>

        <element name="Fanatic" type="Archetype" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_WARDEN_FANATIC">
            <supports>Warden Combat Discipline</supports>
            <description>
                <p></p>
                <p class="indent"></p>
                <div element="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_FANATIC_FANATIC_SPELLS" />
                <div element="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_FANATIC_PUGILIST" />
                <div element="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_FANATIC_BURST_OF_POWER" />
                <div element="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_FANATIC_EXTENSION_STANCE" />
                <div element="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_FANATIC_EXPLODING_ELEMENTS" />
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_FANATIC_FANATIC_SPELLS" level="1" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_FANATIC_PUGILIST" level="1" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_FANATIC_BURST_OF_POWER" level="6" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_FANATIC_EXTENSION_STANCE" level="10" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_FANATIC_EXPLODING_ELEMENTS" level="14" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Fanatic Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_FANATIC_FANATIC_SPELLS">
                <description>
                    <p>You learn an additional spell when you reach certain levels in this archetype, as shown in the Fanatic Spells table. The spell counts as a warden spell for you, but it doesn’t count against the number of warden spells you know.</p>
                    <h5>FANATIC SPELLS</h5>
                    <table>
                        <thead>
                            <tr><td>Spell Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                        </thead>
                        <tr><td>1st</td><td><i>absorb elementsXGE</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>2nd</td><td><i>earthbindXGE</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>3rd</td><td><i>haste</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>4th</td><td><i>fire shield</i></td></tr>
                    </table>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ABSORB_ELEMENTS" spellcasting="Warden" known="true" level="2" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_EARTHBIND" spellcasting="Warden" known="true" level="5" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HASTE" spellcasting="Warden" known="true" level="9" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIRE_SHIELD" spellcasting="Warden" known="true" level="13" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Pugilist" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_FANATIC_PUGILIST">
                <description>
                    <p>Foregoing all need for weapons, you’ve focused your training on turning your fists into a force of nature. You gain the following benefits:</p>
                    <ul>
                        <li>You can roll a d4 in place of the normal damage of your unarmed strike. This die changes as you gain warden levels, as shown in the Power Die column of the Warden table.</li>
                        <li>You can use Wisdom instead of Strength for the attack and damage rolls of your unarmed strikes.</li>
                        <li>When you take the Attack action to make an unarmed strike, you can make another unarmed strike as a bonus action.</li>
                    </ul>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>Your unarmed strikes do 1d{{pugilist:die-type}} damage. You can use Wisdom instead of Strength for your unarmed strikes’ attack and damage. When you take the Attack action to make an unarmed strike, you can make another unarmed strike as a bonus action.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="pugilist:die-type" value="4" bonus="base" level="1" />
                    <stat name="pugilist:die-type" value="6" bonus="base" level="5" />
                    <stat name="pugilist:die-type" value="8" bonus="base" level="11" />
                    <stat name="pugilist:die-type" value="10" bonus="base" level="17" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Burst of Power" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_FANATIC_BURST_OF_POWER">
                <description>
                    <p>Starting at 6th level, your patience has allowed you to enhance the boons granted to you by your innate power. When you spend a power die to deal additional damage to a creature with an unarmed strike, you can roll the power die an additional time and add its result to the damage.</p>
                    <p class="indent">You can do this a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier (a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="{{burst-of-power:uses}}/Long Rest">
                    <description>When you spend a power die to deal additional damage to a creature with an unarmed strike, you can roll the power die an additional time and add its result to the damage.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="burst-of-power:uses" value="1" bonus="base" />
                    <stat name="burst-of-power:uses" value="wisdom:modifier" bonus="base" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Extension Stance" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_FANATIC_EXTENSION_STANCE">
                <description>
                    <p>Beginning at 10th level, your blend of hand to hand and the elements has extended your range of influence.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Your reach with unarmed strikes is increased to 15 feet as long as both hands are empty. If you have a single creature grappled by an attack made within this reach, it does not occupy your hands and is instead grappled by your extended elements.</p>
                    <p class="indent">If a spell you cast has a range of touch, you can deliver it to any creature within range of your unarmed strikes.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>Your reach with unarmed strikes is increased to 15 feet as long as both hands are empty. If you have a single creature grappled by an attack made within this reach, it does not occupy your hands and is instead grappled by your extended elements. If a spell you cast has a range of touch, you can deliver it to any creature within range of your unarmed strikes.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Exploding Elements" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_FANATIC_EXPLODING_ELEMENTS">
                <description>
                    <p>Starting at 14th level, the elements coursing through you can be expelled as an explosive burst. When you spend a power die to deal additional damage on an attack, you can choose to have that damage dealt to all creatures within 5 feet of your target, excluding you.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>When you spend a power die to deal additional damage on an attack, you can choose to have that damage dealt to all creatures within 5 feet of your target, excluding you.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>

        <element name="Sage" type="Archetype" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_WARDEN_SAGE">
            <supports>Warden Combat Discipline</supports>
            <description>
                <p>Your elemental affinity and natural power has been so strong since it manifested that you’ve dedicated yourself entirely to your innate abilities. Compared to other wardens, your ability to command spells is unmatched.</p>
                <div element="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_SAGE_SAGE_SPELLS" />
                <div element="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_SAGE_NATURAL_ARMAMENTS" />
                <div element="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_SAGE_INNATE_POTENTIAL" />
                <div element="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_SAGE_PRIMAL_DANCE" />
                <div element="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_SAGE_DUALITY" />
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_SAGE_SAGE_SPELLS" level="1" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_SAGE_NATURAL_ARMAMENTS" level="1" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_SAGE_INNATE_POTENTIAL" level="6" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_SAGE_PRIMAL_DANCE" level="10" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_SAGE_DUALITY" level="14" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Sage Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_SAGE_SAGE_SPELLS">
                <description>
                    <p>You learn an additional spell when you reach certain levels in this archetype, as shown in the Sage Spells table. The spell counts as a warden spell for you, but it doesn’t count against the number of warden spells you know.</p>
                    <h5>SAGE SPELLS</h5>
                    <table>
                        <thead>
                            <tr><td>Spell Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                        </thead>
                        <tr><td>1st</td><td><i>faerie fire</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>2nd</td><td><i>moonbeam</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>3rd</td><td><i>protection from energy</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>4th</td><td><i>polymorph</i></td></tr>
                    </table>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FAERIE_FIRE" spellcasting="Warden" known="true" level="2" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MOONBEAM" spellcasting="Warden" known="true" level="5" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PROTECTION_FROM_ENERGY" spellcasting="Warden" known="true" level="9" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_POLYMORPH" spellcasting="Warden" known="true" level="13" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Natural Armaments" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_SAGE_NATURAL_ARMAMENTS">
                <description>
                    <p>Your ability to harness magic has granted you a unique way to defend yourself and those around you.</p>
                    <p class="indent">You gain the shillelagh cantrip. In addition, you’ve shrouded yourself in a magical energy. Your AC cannot be lower than 16.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>You’ve shrouded yourself in a magical energy. Your AC cannot be lower than 16.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHILLELAGH" spellcasting="Warden" known="true" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Innate Potential" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_SAGE_INNATE_POTENTIAL">
                <description>
                    <p>At 6th level, your potential in spellcasting manifests itself through your being, but you must tap into your pool of natural power to harness it effectively.</p>
                    <p class="indent">You can cast one of the following spells, as a 1st-level spell by expending two power dice: <i>burning hands</i>, <i>earth tremorXGE</i>, <i>ice knifeXGE</i>, or <i>thunderwave</i>. You add the result of your power die to one damage roll of the spell cast.</p>
                    <p class="indent">These spells are also added to your Spells Known and can be cast using Warden spell slots. If you already know any of these spells you may replace them with another spell you have the spell slots to cast when you gain this feature.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>You can cast one of the following spells, as a 1st-level spell by expending two power dice: burning hands, earth tremor, ice knife, or thunderwave. You add the result of your power die to one damage roll of the spell cast.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BURNING_HANDS" spellcasting="Warden" known="true" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_EARTH_TREMOR" spellcasting="Warden" known="true" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ICE_KNIFE" spellcasting="Warden" known="true" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_THUNDERWAVE" spellcasting="Warden" known="true" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Primal Dance" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_SAGE_PRIMAL_DANCE">
                <description>
                    <p>Beginning at 10th level, you’ve learned to predict the movements of your enemies through their disturbance in the air around you. Whenever a hostile creature moves within 15 feet of you, as a reaction, you can move up to your speed.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet action="Reaction">
                    <description>Whenever a hostile creature moves within 15 feet of you, you can move up to your speed.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Duality" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARDEN_SAGE_DUALITY">
                <description>
                    <p>Starting at 14th level, your spell mastery has extended to your Prime Element and granted you talent with a second element.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Choose a second element as described in the Prime Element class feature. You gain the benefits of having both elements and any features that produce an effect based on the element you’ve chosen allow you access to either benefit but any limitations still apply. You may not choose the same element more than once.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <select type="Class Feature" name="Secondary Element (Duality)" supports="Warden Prime Element" />
                </rules>
            </element>

    <!-- Spell -->
        <element name="Investiture of Corruption" type="Spell" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_LAYHNET_RDDT_UA_SPELL_INVESTITURE_OF_CORRUPTION">
            <supports>Druid, Sorcere, Warlock</supports>
            <description>
                <p>Until the spell ends, a noxious and acrid miasma surrounds your body, and you gain the following benefits:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>You have resistance to acid and poison damage, and are immune to the poisoned condition.</li>
                    <li>The air in a 10-foot radius around you is toxic, creatures that must breath begin to suffocate.</li>
                    <li>You can use your action to blow a puff of noxious gas in a 15-foot cone originating from your mouth. Creatures affected by this must succed on a Constitution saving throw or become poisoned. They can repeat this saving throw at the start of their turn, ending the effect on a successful save.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="keywords"></set>
                <set name="level">6</set>
                <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
                <set name="time">1 action</set>
                <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 10 minutes</set>
                <set name="range">Self</set>
                <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
                <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
                <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
                <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            </setters>
        </element>

    <!-- Warden Spells -->
      <!-- 1st Level Spells -->
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BURNING_HANDS">
            <supports>Warden</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CHROMATIC_ORB">
            <supports>Warden</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COLOR_SPRAY">
            <supports>Warden</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CREATE_OR_DESTROY_WATER">
            <supports>Warden</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_POISON_AND_DISEASE">
            <supports>Warden</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_EARTH_TREMOR">
            <supports>Warden</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENTANGLE">
            <supports>Warden</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ICE_KNIFE">
            <supports>Warden</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SLEEP">
            <supports>Warden</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_THUNDERWAVE">
            <supports>Warden</supports>
        </append>

      <!-- 2nd Level Spells-->
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_AGANAZZARS_SCORCHER">
            <supports>Warden</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONTINUAL_FLAME">
            <supports>Warden</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_DUST_DEVIL">
            <supports>Warden</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HEAT_METAL">
            <supports>Warden</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INVISIBILITY">
            <supports>Warden</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LEVITATE">
            <supports>Warden</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LOCATE_ANIMALS_OR_PLANTS">
            <supports>Warden</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_PYROTECHNICS">
            <supports>Warden</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPIKE_GROWTH">
            <supports>Warden</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_WARDING_WIND">
            <supports>Warden</supports>
        </append>

      <!-- 3rd Level Spells -->
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CALL_LIGHTNING">
            <supports>Warden</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CREATE_FOOD_AND_WATER">
            <supports>Warden</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DAYLIGHT">
            <supports>Warden</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ERUPUTING_EARTH">
            <supports>Warden</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIREBALL">
            <supports>Warden</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MELD_INTO_STONE">
            <supports>Warden</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PLANT_GROWTH">
            <supports>Warden</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SLEET_STORM">
            <supports>Warden</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_PLANTS">
            <supports>Warden</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_THUNDER_STEP">
            <supports>Warden</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_TIDAL_WAVE">
            <supports>Warden</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_WALL_OF_SAND">
            <supports>Warden</supports>
        </append>

      <!-- 4th Level Spells -->
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONTROL_WATER">
            <supports>Warden</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DOMINATE_BEAST">
            <supports>Warden</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ELEMENTAL_BANE">
            <supports>Warden</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GRASPING_VINE">
            <supports>Warden</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_STONE_SHAPE">
            <supports>Warden</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_STORM_SPHERE">
            <supports>Warden</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_VITRIOLIC_SPHERE">
            <supports>Warden</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WALL_OF_FIRE">
            <supports>Warden</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_WATERY_SPHERE">
            <supports>Warden</supports>
        </append>

      <!-- 5th Level Spells -->
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CLOUDKILL">
            <supports>Warden</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONE_OF_COLD">
            <supports>Warden</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_CONTROL_WINDS">
            <supports>Warden</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_DAWN">
            <supports>Warden</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FLAME_STRIKE">
            <supports>Warden</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_IMMOLATION">
            <supports>Warden</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_MAELSTROM">
            <supports>Warden</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_TRANSMUTE_ROCK">
            <supports>Warden</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WALL_OF_STONE">
            <supports>Warden</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_WRATH_OF_NATURE">
            <supports>Warden</supports>
        </append>

    <!-- Warden Fighting Styles -->
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_ARCHERY">
        <supports>Warden</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_DEFENSE">
        <supports>Warden</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_DUELING">
        <supports>Warden</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_GREAT_WEAPON_FIGHTING">
        <supports>Warden</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_TWOWEAPON_FIGHTING">
        <supports>Warden</supports>
    </append>

</elements>