<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Witch</name>
        <description>EinarTheRed’s Witch updated by EinarTheRed</description>
        <update version="0.0.6">
            <file name="class-witch-einar.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/classes/class-witch-einar.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>

    <element name="EinarTheRed’s Witch" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_EINARTHERED_GM_BINDER_SOURCE_WITCH">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p>A guide to binding, using, and abusing spirits.</p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation"></set>
            <set name="url">https://www.gmbinder.com/share/-M1IoVDLix7WD09px8S5</set>
            <set name="image">https://www.gmbinder.com/images/uBdzeFa.jpg</set>
            <set name="author" url="https://www.reddit.com/user/EinarTheRed">u/EinarTheRed</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20200330</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <!-- Witch Class -->
    <element name="Witch" type="Class" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_CLASS_WITCH">
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">A tattooed elf, veiled and cloaked, draws his obsidian dagger across the sand, calling forth from the lines a ghostly apparition to help him and his allies find their way. A trio of halfling hermits gather among candles and incense, chanting words of power to bait spirits from the shadows. The bejeweled human, dressed in exotic garb and golden chains bellows a spell which echoes with the voices of an army of lost souls, a fiendish glint in his eyes as blood drips from his palm.</p>
            <p class="indent">Unlike shamans who pray to the spirits of nature, witches bind the transient souls of intelligent beings lost betwixt the realm of the living and the beyond. As a witch, you learn to summon these souls and bind them to your will, gaining protection from them as well as the power to debilitate your enemies. As you attain higher levels, the covenant you choose to live by grants you further abilities which extend the utility and power of these bonds in different ways.</p>
            <h4>THE POWER OF THE SPIRIT</h4>
            <p>Witches may or may not have a level of respect for the spirits they bind, though one could say they should. Some witches tap into the residual energies of long-departed souls, while others use extant spiritual beings as conduits for their spellcasting. Either way and whether or not they wish, witches bind part of their own soul to those that surround them.</p>
            <p class="indent">Witch spells mostly deal with manipulation of spiritual energies (both living and dead) and protections against the beings which supply those energies. As part of their connection to the spiritual world, they are also privy to information and secrets normally not meant for mortal minds. As such, witches are often powerful enchanters, abjurers, and diviners.</p>
            <h4>BONDS OF THE SOUL</h4>
            <p>Witches acknowledge that there is a spiritual connection between all things -- forces that inexplicably and randomly bind beings and happenings together in a shared fate or destiny. They see other witches as brothers and sisters, and other classes as close cousins. As a consequence, witches are often fond of forming alliances. One kind of alliance is the circle that a witch belongs to.</p>
            <p class="indent">The covenant that a witch joins is the manifestation of a philosophy regarding the nature of spirits. Some, like the covenant of unity, believe in a supreme energy that extends beyond the physical world, weaving together magic and the collective conscience of all living things. Others, from the covenant of blood for example, believe in a more intimate connection between the physical world and the other side. In this philosophy, each soul is tied to something close to it in the physical world -- a body, an object, or location that was important to it when it was alive.</p>
            <h4>CREATING A WITCH</h4>
            <p>When deciding on the witch class, think about what led your character to tap into the spirit world. Maybe witchcraft is a tradition in the area, or your character comes from an area rife with a ghostly past. Superstition is also a good trigger for a fascination with spirits. What is your relationship with spirits? Is there a measure of mutual respect? Perhaps your character feels more like a servant to the spirit than the other way around, or maybe they possess the entitlement to dominate and extort spiritual beings.</p>
            <p class="indent">How did your character come to be an adventurer? It could be that he or she was a pariah in their community due to contact with the other side, cast out and forced to fend for him or herself. Perhaps your character is even haunted by a particular spirit and seeks away to control or be rid of it.</p>
            <h5>QUICK BUILD</h5>
            <p>You can make a witch quickly by following these suggestions. First, Charisma should be your highest ability score, followed by Constitution. Second, select the Hermit background. Third, select the chill touch, guidance, and light cantrips along with the following 1st level spells: <em>charm person</em>, <em>detect magic</em>, <em>healing word</em>, and <em>witch bolt</em>.</p>
            <h3>CLASS FEATURES</h3>
            <p>As a witch, you gain the following class features.</p>
            <h5>HIT POINTS</h5>
            <p>
                <span class="emphasis">Hit Dice:</span>1d8 per witch level<br/>
                <span class="emphasis">Hit Points at 1st Level:</span>8 + your Constitution modifier<br/>
                <span class="emphasis">Hit Points at Higher Levels:</span>1d8 (or 5) + your Constitution modifier per witch level after first<br/>
            </p>
            <h5>PROFICIENCIES</h5>
            <p>
                <b>Armor: </b>Light armor<br/>
                <b>Weapons:</b>Simple weaponse<br/>
                <b>Tools:</b>Herbalism kit<br/>
                <b>Saving Throws:</b>Intelligence, Wisdom<br/>
                <b>Skills:</b>Choose two from Arcana, Animal Handling, History, Insight, Medicine, Nature, and Religion<br/>
            </p>
            <h5>EQUIPMENT</h5>
            <p>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</p>
            <ul>
                <lem><em>(a)</em> a light crossbow and 20 bolts or <em>(b)</em> any simple weapon</lem>
                <lem><em>(a)</em> a component pouch or <em>(b)</em> an anthame used as an arcane focus</lem>
                <lem><em>(a)</em> a priest’s pack or <em>(b)</em> an scholar’s pack</lem>
                <lem>Any simple weapon and two daggers</lem>
            </ul>
            <p class="indent">Or, you start with 2d4 x 10 gp</p>
			<h5 class="caption">THE WITCH</h5>
            <table class="class-features">
                    <thead>
                            <tr><th class="col-5">Level</th><th class="col-10">Proficiency Bonus</th><th class="col-5">Bonds</th><th class="left">Features</th><th class="col-10">Cantrips</th><th class="col-10">Spells Known</th><th class="col-5">1st</th><th class="col-5">2nd</th><th class="col-5">3rd</th><th class="col-5">4th</th><th class="col-5">5th</th><th class="col-5">6th</th><th class="col-5">7th</th><th class="col-5">8th</th><th class="col-5">9th</th></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                            <tr><td>1st</td><td>+2</td><td>-</td><td class="left">Quickening, Spellcasting</td><td>3</td><td>4</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                            <tr><td>2nd</td><td>+2</td><td>1</td><td class="left">Witch Covenant, Binding Rites</td><td>3</td><td>5</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                            <tr><td>3rd</td><td>+2</td><td>1</td><td class="left">Spirit Ward</td><td>3</td><td>6</td><td>4</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                            <tr><td>4th</td><td>+2</td><td>1</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>4</td><td>7</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                            <tr><td>5th</td><td>+3</td><td>1</td><td class="left">—</td><td>4</td><td>8</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                            <tr><td>6th</td><td>+3</td><td>2</td><td class="left">Covenant Feature</td><td>4</td><td>9</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                            <tr><td>7th</td><td>+3</td><td>2</td><td class="left">Spiritual Spellcasting</td><td>4</td><td>10</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>1</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                            <tr><td>8th</td><td>+3</td><td>2</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>4</td><td>10</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                            <tr><td>9th</td><td>+4</td><td>2</td><td class="left">—</td><td>4</td><td>11</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>1</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                            <tr><td>10th</td><td>+4</td><td>3</td><td class="left">Covenant Feature</td><td>5</td><td>11</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                            <tr><td>11th</td><td>+4</td><td>3</td><td class="left">Channel Spell</td><td>5</td><td>12</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                            <tr><td>12th</td><td>+4</td><td>3</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>5</td><td>12</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                            <tr><td>13th</td><td>+5</td><td>3</td><td class="left">—</td><td>5</td><td>13</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                            <tr><td>14th</td><td>+5</td><td>4</td><td class="left">Covenant feature</td><td>5</td><td>13</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                            <tr><td>15th</td><td>+5</td><td>4</td><td class="left">Strength of Spirit</td><td>5</td><td>14</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>—</td></tr>
                            <tr><td>16th</td><td>+5</td><td>4</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>5</td><td>14</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>—</td></tr>
                            <tr><td>17th</td><td>+6</td><td>4</td><td class="left">—</td><td>5</td><td>15</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>1</td></tr>
                            <tr><td>18th</td><td>+6</td><td>5</td><td class="left">Familiar Spirit</td><td>5</td><td>15</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>1</td></tr>
                            <tr><td>19th</td><td>+6</td><td>5</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>5</td><td>16</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>1</td></tr>
                            <tr><td>20th</td><td>+6</td><td>5</td><td class="left">Ghostly Step</td><td>5</td><td>16</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>1</td></tr>
                    </tbody>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_SPELLCASTING_WITCH" />
            <div element="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_SPELL_HELP" />
            <div element="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_QUICKENING" />
            <div element="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_ANCIENT_COVEN" />
            <div element="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_BINDING_RITES" />
            <div element="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT_WITCH" />
            <div element="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_TRADITIONAL_MEDICINE" />
            <div element="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_SPIRITUAL_SPELLCASTING" />
            <div element="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_OMENS" />
            <!--
            <div element="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_STRENGTH_OF_SPIRIT" />
            -->
            <div element="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_FAMILIAR_SPIRIT" />
            <div element="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_SOUL_CONDUIT" />
            <h4>WITCH MULTICLASSING</h4>
            <h5 class="caption">MULTICLASSING PREREQUISITES</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Class</td><td>Ability Score Minimum</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>Witch</td><td>Wisdom 13</td></tr>
            </table>
            <h5 class="caption">MULTICLASSING PROFICIENCIES</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Class</td><td>Proficiencies Gained</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>Witch</td><td>Light armor, simple weapons, Herbalism kit</td></tr>
            </table>
            <h3>THIS IS YOUR LIFE</h3>
            <p>To aid you in the creation of a witch, you may use the following tables to help you decide on your character’s backstory and goals.</p>
            <h4>COVEN INITIATION</h4>
            <p>At some point in a witch’s life they might have found or joined a coven of witches. Such a coven might be located in a small settlement buried in a forest or mountain, maybe they discovered an abandoned or tower, or even within a large city manipulating things from the shadows.</p>
            <p class="indent">Regardless of where they might be found, consider how you were brought to them. What were your thoughts upon meeting them? Did they force you to stay, or even join? Or did you make that decision on your own?</p>
            <h5 class="caption">Coven Initiations</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d6</td><td>Initiation</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>You were born with magic and would have been killed, but your family gave you to the coven to protect you.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>Your parents and family are part of the coven.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>You were kidnapped as a child and forced to join.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>You were a prepared sacrifice who was saved by the spirits.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>You were discovered lost and alone near their settlement and were taken in for your protection.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>You were summoned by the coven during a mishap in a ritual.</td></tr>
            </table>
            <h4>SPIRITUAL BOND</h4>
            <p>Few creatures in the world understand or perhaps even believe in spirits. A farmer might at some point come to understand that a ghost or a wraith is a monster that can terrorize the world. An elf might have knowledge of a banshee and how to defeat one. But a witch is not so limited on their view. A spirit may be able to take a more tangible, visible, form into the world but such an event does not speak to the endless flow of spirits that are hidden behind the thin, weak, veil. A veil that can be opened and used by one who knows how.</p>
            <p class="indent">Often one who learns this lesson, came to this knowledge through a particular event. The meeting of a spirit can prove dangerous as they are little more than power and emotion unchained by small things like morals.</p>
            <p class="indent">Consider how you came to know of spirits and their power. Did it leave you so amazed that you had to seek more? Perhaps you were horrified but seek to conquer that fear. Also think about how this effects your view of spirits themselves. Are they dangerous or misguided? Can they be trusted? Befriended? Must they be enslaved and be made a weapon?</p>
            <h5 class="caption">Spiritual Bonds</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d6</td><td>Bond</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>You were possessed by a spirit to enact some task it sought to complete.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>Part of your soul was ripped from your body and you linger somewhere between worlds.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>A banshee’s scream nearly killed you, and you still hear its wail today.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>You could always see the spirits of others who have passed, silently watching the world around them.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>You had an imaginary friend for a part of your life, which aided you through the darkest moments, and you later found out it was a spirit.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>A powerful wayward spirit drew you into the Ethereal Plane for a time and your very soul was altered by it.</td></tr>
            </table>
            <h4>DEPARTURE</h4>
            <p>A coven is often a close gathering of witches that hold an understanding that strength in numbers is an asset for survival. This usually means that covens can be as close as a family. Even in an internal conflict, a coven rarely seeks a death of its members, instead punishing them in other ways.</p>
            <p class="indent">With such a close group, it is rare for one to leave the coven. Consider as to why you had to leave the coven. How was your life in the coven until now? Did you hate it? Will you miss members of the coven or have you cast such notions away? How does your character deal without the coven nearby?</p>
            <h5 class="caption">Departures</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d6</td><td>Departure</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>You were banished for an alleged crime to the coven.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>You were sent to locate powerful magical relics.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>You left to complete your coming of age trials and come back a full-fledged member of the coven.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>You sought to see the outside world with your own eyes, rather than just stories.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>You were tasked with hunting down and eliminating a great threat to the coven.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>You were sent to establish mercantile, political, religious, or magical ties with a foreign power</td></tr>
            </table>
            <h4>CLASS TRAINING</h4>
            <p>If you chose to become a witch, here is a section to help you decide how to your character became one. Roll a d6 and find the number you rolled on the appropriate table in this section, which describes how you came to be a witch.</p>
            <p class="indent">The above sections in this chapter have further story suggestions, which you can use in concert with the material here.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">Witch</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d6</td><td>I became a witch because...</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>I seek unimaginable power.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>I was hunted and nearly killed for having the magic and sought a means of survival.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>I seek to meet the expectations placed upon me by my coven.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>I wish to keep our power, ancient magics, and rituals from disappearing to history.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>Spirits whispered to me of things forgotten by the most.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>It was foretold by another witch.</td></tr>
            </table>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description>A spellcaster that relies on binding spirits and using their power.</description>
        </sheet>
        <setters>
            <set name="short">A spellcaster that relies on binding spirits and using those spirits’ power.</set>
            <set name="hd">d8</set>
        </setters>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" requirements="!ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_MULTICLASS_WITCH" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" requirements="!ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_MULTICLASS_WITCH" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_WISDOM" requirements="!ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_MULTICLASS_WITCH" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_INTELLIGENCE" requirements="!ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_MULTICLASS_WITCH" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_HERBALISM_KIT" requirements="!ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_MULTICLASS_WITCH" />
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency (Witch)" supports="Skill,EinarTheRed Witch" number="2" requirements="!ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_MULTICLASS_WITCH" />

            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_SPELLCASTING_WITCH" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_SPELL_HELP" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_QUICKENING" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_ANCIENT_COVEN" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_BINDING_RITES" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT_WITCH" level="4" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_TRADITIONAL_MEDICINE" level="5" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_SPIRITUAL_SPELLCASTING" level="7" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_OMENS" level="10" />
            <!--
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_STRENGTH_OF_SPIRIT" level="15" />
            -->
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_FAMILIAR_SPIRIT" level="18" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_SOUL_CONDUIT" level="20" />

            <select type="List" name="Initiation">
                <item id="1">You were born with magic and would have been killed, but your family gave you to the coven to protect you.</item>
                <item id="2">Your parents and family are part of the coven.</item>
                <item id="3">You were kidnapped as a child and forced to join.</item>
                <item id="4">You were a prepared sacrifice who was saved by the spirits.</item>
                <item id="5">You were discovered lost and alone near their settlement and were taken in for your protection.</item>
                <item id="6">You were summoned by the coven during a mishap in a ritual.</item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="Bond">
                <item id="1">You were possessed by a spirit to enact some task it sought to complete.</item>
                <item id="2">Part of your soul was ripped from your body and you linger somewhere between worlds.</item>
                <item id="3">A banshee’s scream nearly killed you, and you still hear its wail today.</item>
                <item id="4">You could always see the spirits of others who have passed, silently watching the world around them.</item>
                <item id="5">You had an imaginary friend for a part of your life, which aided you through the darkest moments, and you later found out it was a spirit.</item>
                <item id="6">A powerful wayward spirit drew you into the Ethereal Plane for a time and your very soul was altered by it.</item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="Departure">
                <item id="1">You were banished for an alleged crime to the coven.</item>
                <item id="2">You were sent to locate powerful magical relics.</item>
                <item id="3">You left to complete your coming of age trials and come back a full-fledged member of the coven.</item>
                <item id="4">You sought to see the outside world with your own eyes, rather than just stories.</item>
                <item id="5">You were tasked with hunting down and eliminating a great threat to the coven.</item>
                <item id="6">You were sent to establish mercantile, political, religious, or magical ties with a foreign power</item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="I became a witch because...">
                <item id="1">I seek unimaginable power.</item>
                <item id="2">I was hunted and nearly killed for having the magic and sought a means of survival.</item>
                <item id="3">I seek to meet the expectations placed upon me by my coven.</item>
                <item id="4">I wish to keep our power, ancient magics, and rituals from disappearing to history.</item>
                <item id="5">Spirits whispered to me of things forgotten by the most.</item>
                <item id="6">It was foretold by another witch.</item>
            </select>
        </rules>
        <multiclass id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_MULTICLASS_WITCH">
            <prerequisite>Wisdom 13</prerequisite>
            <requirements>[wis:13]</requirements>
            <setters>
                <set name="multiclass proficiencies">Light armor, simple weapons, Herbalism kit</set>
            </setters>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_HERBALISM_KIT" />
            </rules>
        </multiclass>
    </element>

    <element name="Spellcasting" type="Class Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_SPELLCASTING_WITCH">
        <supports>ID_INTERNAL_SUPPORT_SPELLCASTING,Witch</supports>
        <requirements />
        <description>
            <p>Your contact with the spirit world and intuitive knowledge of the magic sustains it grants you the use of spells.</p>
            <h5>CANTRIPS</h5>
            <p>You know three cantrips of your choice from the witch spell list. You learn additional witch cantrips of your choice at higher levels, as shown in the Cantrips Known column of the Witch table.</p>
            <h5>SPELL SLOTS</h5>
            <p>The Witch table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your spells of 1st level and higher. To cast one of these witch spells, you must expend a slot of the spell’s level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.</p>
            <p class="indent">For example, if you know the 1st-level spell <em>cure wounds</em> and have a 1st-level and a 2nd-level spell slot available, you can cast <em>cure wounds</em> using either slot.</p>
            <h5>SPELLS KNOWN OF 1ST LEVEL AND HIGHER</h5>
            <p>You know four 1st-level spells of your choice from the witch spell list.</p>
            <p class="indent">The Spells Known column of the Witch table shows when you learn more witch spells of your choice. Each of these spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots. For instance, when you reach 3rd level in this class, you can learn one new spell of 1st or 2nd level.</p>
            <p class="indent">Additionally, when you gain a level in this class, you can choose one of the witch spells you know and replace it with another spell from the witch spell list, which also must be of a level for which you have spell slots.</p>
            <h5>SPELLCASTING ABILITY</h5>
            <p>Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for your witch spells, since the power of your magic relies on your ability to project your will into the world. You use your Wisdom whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Wisdom modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a witch spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.</p>
            <p class="indent">Spell save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier</p>
            <p class="indent">Spell attack modifier = your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier</p>
            <div class="sidebar">
                <h5 class="caption">MYRIAD WAYS TO WITCH</h5>
                <p>Consider asking your DM if you can use Intelligence or Charisma as your spellcasting ability. If they agree to it, then use the chosen ability in place of Wisdom wherever Wisdom appears for this class, excepting your Saving Throw proficiency.</p>
            </div>
            <h5>RITUAL CASTING</h5>
            <p>You can cast a witch spell as a ritual if that spell has the ritual tag.</p>
            <h5>SPELLCASTING FOCUS</h5>
            <p>You can use an athame as a spellcasting focus for your witch spells.</p>
            <p class="indent">Alternatively, choose a focus that you feel would suit your character.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Witch Spellcasting Ability" supports="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_SPELLCASTING_WITCH_WISDOM|ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_SPELLCASTING_WITCH_INTELLIGENCE|ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_SPELLCASTING_WITCH_CHARISMA" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Spellcasting: Wisdom" type="Class Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_SPELLCASTING_WITCH_WISDOM">
            <compendium display="false" />
            <description>
                <h5>SPELLCASTING ABILITY</h5>
                <p>Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for your witch spells, since the power of your magic relies on your ability to project your will into the world. You use your Wisdom whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Wisdom modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a witch spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.</p>
                <p class="indent">Spell save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier</p>
                <p class="indent">Spell attack modifier = your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false" />
            <spellcasting name="Witch" ability="Wisdom" allowReplace="true">
                <list>EinarTheRed Witch</list>
            </spellcasting>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS_SPELLCASTING_SLOTS_FULL" requirements="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS" />

                <stat name="spellcasting:ability-string" inline="true" value="Wisdom" />
                <stat name="spellcasting:ability-modifier" value="wisdom:modifier" />
                <stat name="spellcasting:saving-throw-dc" value="spellcasting:dc:wis" />

                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:1" value="2" level="1" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="2" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="3" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:2" value="2" level="3" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:2" value="1" level="4" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:3" value="2" level="5" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:3" value="1" level="6" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="7" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="8" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="9" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:5" value="1" level="9" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:5" value="1" level="10" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:5" value="1" level="18" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:6" value="1" level="11" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:6" value="1" level="19" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:7" value="1" level="13" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:7" value="1" level="20" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:8" value="1" level="15" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:9" value="1" level="17" />
            
                <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Witch)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),0" level="1" number="3" spellcasting="Witch" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Witch)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),0" level="4" spellcasting="Witch"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Witch)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),0" level="10" spellcasting="Witch"/>
                
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Witch)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="1" number="4" spellcasting="Witch"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Witch)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="2" spellcasting="Witch"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Witch)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="3" spellcasting="Witch"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Witch)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="4" spellcasting="Witch"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Witch)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="5" spellcasting="Witch"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Witch)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="6" spellcasting="Witch"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Witch)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="7" spellcasting="Witch"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Witch)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="9" spellcasting="Witch"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Witch)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="9" spellcasting="Witch"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Witch)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="11" spellcasting="Witch"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Witch)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="13" spellcasting="Witch"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Witch)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="15" spellcasting="Witch"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Witch)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="17" spellcasting="Witch"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Witch)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="19" spellcasting="Witch"/>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Spellcasting: Intelligence" type="Class Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_SPELLCASTING_WITCH_INTELLIGENCE">
            <compendium display="false" />
            <description>
                <h5>SPELLCASTING ABILITY</h5>
                <p>Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for your witch spells, since the power of your magic relies on your ability to project your will into the world. You use your Intelligence whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Intelligence modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a witch spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.</p>
                <p class="indent">Spell save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier</p>
                <p class="indent">Spell attack modifier = your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false" />
            <spellcasting name="Witch" ability="Intelligence" allowReplace="true">
                <list>EinarTheRed Witch</list>
            </spellcasting>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS_SPELLCASTING_SLOTS_FULL" requirements="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS" />

                <stat name="spellcasting:ability-string" inline="true" value="Intelligence" />
                <stat name="spellcasting:ability-modifier" value="intelligence:modifier" />
                <stat name="spellcasting:saving-throw-dc" value="spellcasting:dc:int" />

                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:1" value="2" level="1" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="2" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="3" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:2" value="2" level="3" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:2" value="1" level="4" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:3" value="2" level="5" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:3" value="1" level="6" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="7" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="8" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="9" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:5" value="1" level="9" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:5" value="1" level="10" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:5" value="1" level="18" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:6" value="1" level="11" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:6" value="1" level="19" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:7" value="1" level="13" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:7" value="1" level="20" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:8" value="1" level="15" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:9" value="1" level="17" />
            
                <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Witch)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),0" level="1" number="3" spellcasting="Witch" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Witch)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),0" level="4" spellcasting="Witch"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Witch)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),0" level="10" spellcasting="Witch"/>
                
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Witch)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="1" number="4" spellcasting="Witch"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Witch)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="2" spellcasting="Witch"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Witch)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="3" spellcasting="Witch"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Witch)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="4" spellcasting="Witch"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Witch)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="5" spellcasting="Witch"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Witch)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="6" spellcasting="Witch"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Witch)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="7" spellcasting="Witch"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Witch)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="9" spellcasting="Witch"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Witch)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="9" spellcasting="Witch"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Witch)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="11" spellcasting="Witch"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Witch)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="13" spellcasting="Witch"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Witch)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="15" spellcasting="Witch"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Witch)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="17" spellcasting="Witch"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Witch)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="19" spellcasting="Witch"/>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Spellcasting: Charisma" type="Class Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_SPELLCASTING_WITCH_CHARISMA">
            <compendium display="false" />
            <description>
                <h5>SPELLCASTING ABILITY</h5>
                <p>Charisma is your spellcasting ability for your witch spells, since the power of your magic relies on your ability to project your will into the world. You use your Charisma whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Charisma modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a witch spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.</p>
                <p class="indent">Spell save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier</p>
                <p class="indent">Spell attack modifier = your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false" />
            <spellcasting name="Witch" ability="Charisma" allowReplace="true">
                <list>EinarTheRed Witch</list>
            </spellcasting>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS_SPELLCASTING_SLOTS_FULL" requirements="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS" />

                <stat name="spellcasting:ability-string" inline="true" value="Charisma" />
                <stat name="spellcasting:ability-modifier" value="charisma:modifier" />
                <stat name="spellcasting:saving-throw-dc" value="spellcasting:dc:cha" />

                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:1" value="2" level="1" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="2" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="3" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:2" value="2" level="3" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:2" value="1" level="4" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:3" value="2" level="5" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:3" value="1" level="6" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="7" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="8" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="9" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:5" value="1" level="9" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:5" value="1" level="10" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:5" value="1" level="18" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:6" value="1" level="11" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:6" value="1" level="19" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:7" value="1" level="13" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:7" value="1" level="20" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:8" value="1" level="15" />
                <stat name="witch:spellcasting:slots:9" value="1" level="17" />
            
                <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Witch)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),0" level="1" number="3" spellcasting="Witch" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Witch)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),0" level="4" spellcasting="Witch"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Witch)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),0" level="10" spellcasting="Witch"/>
                
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Witch)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="1" number="4" spellcasting="Witch"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Witch)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="2" spellcasting="Witch"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Witch)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="3" spellcasting="Witch"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Witch)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="4" spellcasting="Witch"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Witch)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="5" spellcasting="Witch"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Witch)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="6" spellcasting="Witch"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Witch)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="7" spellcasting="Witch"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Witch)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="9" spellcasting="Witch"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Witch)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="9" spellcasting="Witch"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Witch)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="11" spellcasting="Witch"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Witch)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="13" spellcasting="Witch"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Witch)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="15" spellcasting="Witch"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Witch)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="17" spellcasting="Witch"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Witch)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="19" spellcasting="Witch"/>
            </rules>
        </element>
    <element name="Spell Help" type="Class Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_SPELL_HELP">
        <description>
            <p>Witches are adept at casting spells in groups, and as such, can use the Help action to aid another spell caster. When you’re within 30 feet of an ally that can cast spells, you can use your Help action to assist them with their spellcasting.</p>
            <p class="indent">Until the beginning of your next turn, when the selected ally casts a spell, you can choose one of the effects below to occur. Once an effect occurs, this feature cannot be used again until the beginning of your next turn.</p>
            <ul>
                <li>If the ally’s spell requires an attack roll, they may make the first attack roll at advantage.</li>
                <li>If the ally’s spell requires a DC saving throw, the one creature targeted by the spell has the DC increased by an amount equal to half your spellcasting ability modifier (rounded down, minimum 1).</li>
                <li>If the ally’s spell includes a damage roll, then they may maximize a number of dice equal to half your spellcasting ability modifier (rounded down, minimum 1).</li>
                <li>If the ally’s spell has a maximum range to choose a target creature or target point, the range is increased by an additional number of feet equal to 10 times your spellcasting ability modifier (rounded down, minimum 1).</li>
                <li>If the ally’s spell requires concentration, you can both make a DC 15 concentration check. If you both succeed, you begin concentrating on the spell instead of the target. The spell then uses your spellcasting ability and DC instead of the ally’s. The ally can refuse to do so; if they do, then select a different effect to occur.</li>
                <li>If the ally’s spell requires concentration, until the beginning of your next turn they have a bonus to concentration checks for that spell, equal to half your spellcasting modifier (rounded down, minimum 1).</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Action">
            <description>You can use the Help action to aid another spellcaster within 30 feet. Until the beginning of your next turn, when the selected ally casts a spell, you can choose one of the effects to occur. Once an effect occurs, this feature cannot be used again until the beginning of your next turn.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Quickening" type="Class Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_QUICKENING">
        <description>
            <p>At 1st level, you gain the ability to enter a trance known as the witch’s quickening, letting you see beyond the borders of the material world. Entering the trance is a bonus action and allows you to see into the Ethereal Plane up to 60 feet for up to one minute. You also gain insight into the emotional energy surrounding you, letting you know if and what spirits are bound within 60 feet, as well as granting you advantage to Wisdom (Insight) checks. While in your quickening, if you cast a spell that deals necrotic damage you can substitute that damage with psychic damage instead. The quickening requires concentration for the duration and may be maintained for up to a minute.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can use this ability a number of times equal to 1 + your spellcasting ability modifier. When you finish a long rest, you regain all expended uses.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="{{quickening:count}}/Long Rest" action="Bonus Action">
            <description>You can enter your witch’s quickening trance. You can see into the Ethereal Plane up to 60 feet for up to one minute. You also get advantage to Insight checks. During the quickening, if you cast a spell that does necrotic damage, you can substitute psychic damage. The quickening requires concentration for the duration and may be maintained for up to a minute.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="quickening:count" value="1" />
            <stat name="quickening:count" value="spellcasting:ability-modifier" />
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Ancient Coven" type="Class Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_ANCIENT_COVEN">
        <description>
            <p>At 2nd level you commit yourself to a spiritual philosophy known as a witch’s coven: the Coven of Blood, the Coven of Charms, the Coven of Ruin, the Coven of Shadows, the Coven of Symbiosis, or the Coven of Unity, detailed at the end of the class description. Your choice grants you features at 2nd level and again at 6th, 10th, and 14th level.</p>
            <p>Additionally, you know the <em>find familiar</em> spell and it does not count against your spells known. You gain the ability to cast <em>find familiar</em> once per long rest without providing material components.</p>
            <h5>COVEN SPELLS</h5>
            <p>Each coven has a list of spells-its coven spells-that you gain at the witch levels noted in the coven description. Each spell counts as a witch spell for you, but it doesn’t count against the number of witch spells you know. These spells can’t be replaced when you gain a level in this class. If you have a coven spell that doesn’t appear on the witch spell list, the spell is nonetheless a witch spell for you.</p>
            <p class="indent">You only have access to these spells so long as you have a familiar.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>You can cast <em>find familiar</em> without providing material components.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Archetype" name="Ancient Coven" supports="Ancient Coven" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIND_FAMILIAR" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" />
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Binding Rites" type="Class Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_BINDING_RITES">
        <description>
            <p>At 2nd level you can bind spirits to your service. Binding a spirit is much like casting a ritual spell and takes 10 minutes of uninterrupted meditation. During this time, the witch speaks the invocations required to summon the spirit forth and enacts the rite of binding depending on which philosophy the witch belongs to. A blood witch might utilize a bone fragment to bind the spirit, while a shadow witch might bargain with the summoned spirit, exchanging a secret for the spirit’s service. You have one spirit bond. You gain additional bonds as you reach higher levels, as shown in the Spirit Bonds column of the Witch table.</p>
            <p class="indent">When you choose a spirit to bind from the list at the end of this class description, you fill one of your available spell slots with the spirit. The spell slot used is no longer available for casting spells, and it remains unavailable for as long as the spirit filling it remains bound to you. The spirit is said to be of a level equal to the spell slot filled to bind it. Thus, a Spirit of Passion occupying a 6th level spell slot is a level 6 spirit. You cannot have more than one spirit with the same name bound at one time. Depending on the type of spirit, you gain certain benefits while the spirit remains bound and an additional effect when you release the spirit, as detailed in the Binding Rites section. The passive benefits the spirit grants while bound increase as you gain levels in this class.</p>
            <p class="indent">Releasing a spirit is a bonus action, unless otherwise stated. Once a spirit has been released, it no longer provides its passive effect and the spell slot it occupied is considered expended. The effect of the release is instantaneous, unless otherwise stated.</p>
            <p class="indent">A witch may exchange any spirit they have bound for another spirit by performing the ritual as described above.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description level="2">You may bind up to 1 spirit into an unused spell slot. The spirit level is equal to the spell slot to which it is bound. The binding ritual takes 10 minutes. You can release a spirit as a bonus action.</description> 
            <description level="6">You may bind up to 2 spirits into unused spell slots. The spirit level is equal to the spell slot to which it is bound. The binding ritual takes 10 minutes. You can release a spirit as a bonus action.</description> 
            <description level="10">You may bind up to 3 spirits into unused spell slots. The spirit level is equal to the spell slot to which it is bound. The binding ritual takes 10 minutes. You can release a spirit as a bonus action.</description> 
            <description level="14">You may bind up to 4 spirits into unused spell slots. The spirit level is equal to the spell slot to which it is bound. The binding ritual takes 10 minutes. You can release a spirit as a bonus action.</description> 
            <description level="18">You may bind up to 5 spirits into unused spell slots. The spirit level is equal to the spell slot to which it is bound. The binding ritual takes 10 minutes. You can release a spirit as a bonus action.</description> 
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_BINDING_RITES_WISDOM" level="2" requirements="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_SPELLCASTING_WITCH_WISDOM" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_BINDING_RITES_INTELLIGENCE" level="2" requirements="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_SPELLCASTING_WITCH_INTELLIGENCE" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_BINDING_RITES_CHARISMA" level="2" requirements="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_SPELLCASTING_WITCH_CHARISMA" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_WITCH_SPIRIT_AGONY" spellcasting="Spirit Binding" known="true" prepared="false" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_WITCH_SPIRIT_CONNECTION" spellcasting="Spirit Binding" known="true" prepared="false" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_WITCH_SPIRIT_DESIRE" spellcasting="Spirit Binding" known="true" prepared="false" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_WITCH_SPIRIT_EMPATHY" spellcasting="Spirit Binding" known="true" prepared="false" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_WITCH_SPIRIT_ENVY" spellcasting="Spirit Binding" known="true" prepared="false" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_WITCH_SPIRIT_FORTUNE" spellcasting="Spirit Binding" known="true" prepared="false" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_WITCH_SPIRIT_GLUTTONY" spellcasting="Spirit Binding" known="true" prepared="false" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_WITCH_SPIRIT_GREED" spellcasting="Spirit Binding" known="true" prepared="false" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_WITCH_SPIRIT_GUILT" spellcasting="Spirit Binding" known="true" prepared="false" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_WITCH_SPIRIT_HOPE" spellcasting="Spirit Binding" known="true" prepared="false" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_WITCH_SPIRIT_JUSTICE" spellcasting="Spirit Binding" known="true" prepared="false" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_WITCH_SPIRIT_PASSION" spellcasting="Spirit Binding" known="true" prepared="false" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_WITCH_SPIRIT_PRIDE" spellcasting="Spirit Binding" known="true" prepared="false" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_WITCH_SPIRIT_PROTECTION" spellcasting="Spirit Binding" known="true" prepared="false" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_WITCH_SPIRIT_SLOTH" spellcasting="Spirit Binding" known="true" prepared="false" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_WITCH_SPIRIT_SORROW" spellcasting="Spirit Binding" known="true" prepared="false" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_WITCH_SPIRIT_TERROR" spellcasting="Spirit Binding" known="true" prepared="false" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_WITCH_SPIRIT_TRUST" spellcasting="Spirit Binding" known="true" prepared="false" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_WITCH_SPIRIT_VENGEANCE" spellcasting="Spirit Binding" known="true" prepared="false" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_WITCH_SPIRIT_WONDER" spellcasting="Spirit Binding" known="true" prepared="false" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_WITCH_SPIRIT_WRATH" spellcasting="Spirit Binding" known="true" prepared="false" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Binding Rites: Wisdom" type="Class Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_BINDING_RITES_WISDOM">
        <compendium display="false" />
        <description />
        <sheet display="false" />
        <spellcasting name="Spirit Binding" ability="Wisdom" prepare="true">
            <list known="true">Einar Witch Binding Rites</list>
        </spellcasting>
        <rules>
            <stat name="spirit binding:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="2" />
            <stat name="spirit binding:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="6" />
            <stat name="spirit binding:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="10" />
            <stat name="spirit binding:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="14" />
            <stat name="spirit binding:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="18" />
			<stat name="spirit binding:spellcasting:prepare" value="1" level="2" />
			<stat name="spirit binding:spellcasting:prepare" value="1" level="6" />
			<stat name="spirit binding:spellcasting:prepare" value="1" level="10" />
			<stat name="spirit binding:spellcasting:prepare" value="1" level="14" />
			<stat name="spirit binding:spellcasting:prepare" value="1" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Binding Rites: Intelligence" type="Class Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_BINDING_RITES_INTELLIGENCE">
        <compendium display="false" />
        <description />
        <sheet display="false" />
        <spellcasting name="Spirit Binding" ability="Intelligence" prepare="true">
            <list known="true">Einar Witch Binding Rites</list>
        </spellcasting>
        <rules>
            <stat name="spirit binding:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="2" />
            <stat name="spirit binding:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="6" />
            <stat name="spirit binding:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="10" />
            <stat name="spirit binding:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="14" />
            <stat name="spirit binding:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="18" />
			<stat name="spirit binding:spellcasting:prepare" value="1" level="2" />
			<stat name="spirit binding:spellcasting:prepare" value="1" level="6" />
			<stat name="spirit binding:spellcasting:prepare" value="1" level="10" />
			<stat name="spirit binding:spellcasting:prepare" value="1" level="14" />
			<stat name="spirit binding:spellcasting:prepare" value="1" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Binding Rites: Charisma" type="Class Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_BINDING_RITES_CHARISMA">
        <compendium display="false" />
        <description />
        <sheet display="false" />
        <spellcasting name="Spirit Binding" ability="Charisma" prepare="true">
            <list known="true">Einar Witch Binding Rites</list>
        </spellcasting>
        <rules>
            <stat name="spirit binding:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="2" />
            <stat name="spirit binding:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="6" />
            <stat name="spirit binding:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="10" />
            <stat name="spirit binding:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="14" />
            <stat name="spirit binding:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="18" />
			<stat name="spirit binding:spellcasting:prepare" value="1" level="2" />
			<stat name="spirit binding:spellcasting:prepare" value="1" level="6" />
			<stat name="spirit binding:spellcasting:prepare" value="1" level="10" />
			<stat name="spirit binding:spellcasting:prepare" value="1" level="14" />
			<stat name="spirit binding:spellcasting:prepare" value="1" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>

  <!--
    <element name="Spirit Ward" type="Class Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_SPIRIT_WARD">
        <description>
            <p>At 3rd level, you learn a rite that offers protection against spirits who wish you or your allies harm. As an action, you can create a spirit ward with a radius of 30 feet, centered on your location. The ward lasts 1 minute and is stationary for the duration. While inside the ward, friendly creatures (yourself included) cannot be charmed, frightened, or possessed by undead and have resistance to all damage from incorporeal undead sources. Additionally, if a friendly creature is reduced to 0 hit points within the ward but is not killed outright, the creature becomes stable.</p>
            <p>ou can use this feature 3 times. You regain expended uses when you finish a long rest. When you reach 9th level, you regain expended uses when you finish a short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="3/Long Rest" action="Action">
            <description>You can create a stationary spirit ward with a radius of 30 feet that lasts one minute. While inside the ward you and friendly creatures cannot be charmed, frightened, or possessed by undead and you have resistance to all damage from incorporeal undead sources. Friendly creatures within the ward reduced to 0 hit points but not killed outright become stable.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
  -->
    
    <element name="Ability Score Improvement (Witch)" type="Class Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT_WITCH">
        <description>
            <p>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Witch 4)" supports="Improvement Option,Witch,4" level="4" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Witch 8)" supports="Improvement Option,Witch,8" level="8" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Witch 12)" supports="Improvement Option,Witch,12" level="12" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Witch 16)" supports="Improvement Option,Witch,16" level="16" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Witch 19)" supports="Improvement Option,Witch,19" level="19" />
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Traditional Medicine" type="Class Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_TRADITIONAL_MEDICINE">
        <description>
            <p>Upon reaching 5th level, you have become proficient with Alchemy Supplies. Additionally, you can still brew potions even without Alchemy Supplies, so long as you have a cauldron.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Bonus Action">
            <description>You can still brew potions even without Alchemy Supplies, so long as you have a cauldron.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_ALCHEMISTS_SUPPLIES" />
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Spiritual Spellcasting" type="Class Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_SPIRITUAL_SPELLCASTING">
        <description>
            <p>At 7th level you may call upon the spirits you have bound to help you cast your spells. You may dismiss a spirit as a bonus action to recover the spell slot that the spirit occupied. The release effect of the spirit you dismissed is not activated.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Bonus Action">
            <description>You may release a bound spirit to recover the spell slot of the bound spirit. The release effect is not activated.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules />
    </element>
    
    <element name="Omens" type="Class Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_OMENS">
        <description>
            <p>Upon reaching the 10th level, you can draw objects of a creature together and draw information about that creature. Should you have three objects belonging to a person, such as hair, blood, a beloved sword, or an important religious symbol, you can brew them in a cauldron for a day and at the end, you cast the spell <em>scrying</em> with that person as the target of the spell.</p>
            <div class="reference">
                <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_SCRYING" />
            </div>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Should you have three objects belonging to a person, such as hair, blood, a beloved sword, or an important religious symbol, you can brew them in a cauldron for a day and at the end, you cast the spell scry with that person as the target of the spell.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SCRYING" />
        </rules>
    </element>

  <!--
    <element name="Strength of Spirit" type="Class Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_STRENGTH_OF_SPIRIT">
        <description>
            <p>At 15th level, you learn to sap additional fortitude from the spirits you bind. When you finish a long rest, you gain temporary hit points equal to 5 times the highest-level spirit you have bound.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>You gain temporary hit points equal to 5 times the highest-level spirit you have bound when you finish a long rest.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules />
    </element>
  -->

    <element name="Familiar Spirit" type="Class Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_FAMILIAR_SPIRIT">
        <description>
            <p>At 18th level, when cast <em>find familiar</em> or if you already have a familiar, you can awaken spiritual energy within the animal as part of an additional ritual taking 10 minutes. Once complete, you choose one spirit from the list at the end of the class description. Its level is equal to your spellcasting ability modifier.</p>
            <p class="indent">Your familiar provides you with the spirit’s passive effect as long as your familiar is within 100 feet of you. If the familiar dies, the spirit you initially chose produces its release effect if you can see any valid targets within range of the familiar when it dies.</p>
            <p class="indent">Additionally, if your familiar is the sole target of an effect that deals damage while it Bound with a spirit and within 100 feet of you can choose to take that damage instead.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can bind a spirit to your familiar. The spirit’s level is {{familiar spirit:level}}. You gain the passive effect while your familiar is within 100 feet of you. If your familiar dies, the spirit is released and the release effect is triggered. If your familiar is the sole target of an effect that deals damage while it Bound with a spirit and within 100 feet of you can choose to take that damage instead.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="familiar spirit:level" value="spellcasting:ability-modifier" />
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Soul Conduit" type="Class Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_CLASS_FEATURE_WITCH_SOUL_CONDUIT">
        <description>
            <p>At 20th level you gain the ability to draw power from all your spirits to empower your spells. When you cast a spell you can increase the spell save DC by an amount equal to the number of spirits you have bound. Your Familiar Spirit cannot be added to this amount.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you have used this ability you cannot do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>When you cast a spell you can increase the spell save DC by an amount equal to the number of spirits you have bound. Your Familiar Spirit cannot be added to this amount.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules />
    </element>
    
    <!-- Witch Covenants -->
    <element name="Coven of Blood" type="Archetype" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COVEN_OF_BLOOD">
        <supports>Ancient Coven</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Witches of the Coven of Blood believe in strong connections between the physical world and the spiritual one. Spirits are connected to the physical world through objects that were important to them while they were alive. This knowledge allows a witch to bind spirits to their power more easily –– as long as they know a bit about the spirit’s life.</p>
            <p class="indent">Though not always, witches from the covenant of blood tend to dominate the spirits under their control. They generally take care to leave spirits intact and in a state no worse than before they were bound, but nevertheless are capable of using a spirit’s weaknesses against them, taking advantage of their connections to the physical world in order to gain power over them.</p>
            <div element="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COB_COVEN_SPELLS" />
            <div element="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COB_AWAKEN_THE_BLOOD" />
            <div element="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COB_SYMPATHETIC_MAGIC" />
            <div element="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COB_BLOOD_BINDING" />
            <div element="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COB_WEAKNESS_OF_FLESH" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COB_COVEN_SPELLS" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COB_SPIRIT_OF_CONNECTION" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COB_AWAKEN_THE_BLOOD" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COB_SYMPATHETIC_MAGIC" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COB_BLOOD_BINDING" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COB_WEAKNESS_OF_FLESH" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Coven Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COB_COVEN_SPELLS">
            <description>
                <p>As long as you have a familiar, you may also add the following spells to your spells known list.</p>
                <h5 class="caption">Coven of Blood Spells</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Witch Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>hold person, locate object</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>remove curse, vampiric touch</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>7th</td><td><em>locate creature, polymorph</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><em>awaken, greater restoration</em></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>As long as you have a familiar, you may add covenant spells to your known spells list.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HOLD_PERSON" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LOCATE_OBJECT" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_REMOVE_CURSE" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_VAMPIRIC_TOUCH" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LOCATE_CREATURE" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" level="7" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_POLYMORPH" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" level="7" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AWAKEN" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GREATER_RESTORATION" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" level="9" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Spirit of Connection" type="Archetype Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COB_SPIRIT_OF_CONNECTION">
            <description>
                <p>Witches of the Coven of Blood excel in merging the physical and the spiritual realms, and sometimes they have help from the other side. You gain the ability to bond a unique spirit: The Spirit of Connection.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Awaken the Blood" type="Archetype Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COB_AWAKEN_THE_BLOOD">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 2nd level, when you release a spirit, you can use the energy from the spiritual bonds to repair corporeal bodies. When you release a spirit, you and a creature you can touch regain hit points equal to 3 times the level of the spirit.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you release a spirit, you and a creature you can touch regain 3 times the level of the spirit in hit points.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Sympathetic Magic" type="Archetype Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COB_SYMPATHETIC_MAGIC">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, you gain the power to cast spells on targets over vast distances beyond what the spell may ordinarily allow. If you have an article (blood, hair, clothing) from a creature on the same plane of existence, your spells of 5th level or lower that target only one creature may target that creature. When you cast a spell that affects a creature this way, the article you have from the target is consumed.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>If you have an article from a creature on the same plane of existence, your spells of 5th level and lower that target only one creature may target that creature.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Blood Binding" type="Archetype Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COB_BLOOD_BINDING">
            <description>
                <p>At 10th level, if a hostile living creature dies within 30 feet of you, you may bind its soul as a reaction.</p>
                <p class="indent">You bind a spirit type of your choice to an unused spell slot, as long as you meet the prerequisites of that spirit type. This binding expires after 24 hours or whenever you use this ability again.</p>
                <p class="indent">For the duration of the binding, the creature who provided the soul cannot be resurrected by any means short of a <em>true resurrection</em> or <em>wish</em> spell. Once you use this feature, you must finish a long rest before you can use it again.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Reaction" usage="1/Long Rest"> 
                <description>If a hostile creature dies within 30 feet of you, you may bind its soul as a spirit type of your choice to an unused spell slot. For the duration of the binding, the creature who provided the soul cannot be resurrected by any means short of a true resurrection or wish spell.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Weakness of Flesh" type="Archetype Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COB_WEAKNESS_OF_FLESH">
            <description>
                <p>At 14th level, you gain the ability to force the weakness of flesh and bone of the physical realm on to a creature. As an action you force a creature within 60 feet must succeed at a Constitution saving throw or be cursed and weakened. When the curse successfully takes root, you can choose to remove a creature’s resistance to one type of damage and remove its immunities to the grappled, restrained, and prone conditions if it has any. The creature instead has advantage on saving throws against those conditions. Finally, if the creature has incorporeal movement it loses that trait. These effects last for 1 minute.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you have used this ability you cannot do so again until you finish a short rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Short Rest"> 
                <description>You force a creature within 60 feet must succeed at a Constitution saving throw or be cursed and weakened. When the curse successfully takes root, you can choose to remove a creature’s resistance to one type of damage and remove its immunities to the grappled, restrained, and prone conditions if it has any. The creature instead has advantage on saving throws against those conditions. Finally, if the creature has incorporeal movement it loses that trait. These effects last for 1 minute.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    <element name="Coven of Charms" type="Archetype" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COVEN_OF_CHARMS">
        <supports>Ancient Coven</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Witches of the Coven of Charms tap deep into the emotions which govern lingering spirits’ behaviors. They use these emotions as signposts and guides to manipulate the desires and shape the aspirations of the living. They believe that although lingering spirits are echoes of the past, they hold the key to individual futures. By harnessing the raw emotional energy of the beyond, one can gain absolute control over the hearts and minds of those around him or her.</p>
            <p class="indent">Witches of this philosophy vary in their treatment of spirits. Some befriend and learn from the spirits they bind, using that knowledge to further their own ends. Others take only cursory notice of the spirits they enslave – an attitude that often carries over into their living interactions, manipulating and charming those they will, without any true regard for the desires of those they meet.</p>
            <div element="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COC_COVEN_SPELLS" />
            <div element="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COC_SPIRIT_OF_DESIRE" />
            <div element="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COC_SPIRIT_TOKEN" />
            <div element="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COC_IN_PERFECT_TRUST" />
            <div element="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COC_OF_ONE_HEART" />
            <div element="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COC_CRUX_OF_DESIRE" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COC_COVEN_SPELLS" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COC_SPIRIT_OF_DESIRE" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COC_SPIRIT_TOKEN" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COC_IN_PERFECT_TRUST" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COC_OF_ONE_HEART" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COC_CRUX_OF_DESIRE" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Coven Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COC_COVEN_SPELLS">
            <description>
                <p>As long as you have a familiar, you may also add the following spells to your spells known list.</p>
                <h5 class="caption">Coven of Charms Spells</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Witch Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>detect thoughts, suggestion</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>hypnotic pattern, tongues</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>7th</td><td><em>hallucinatory terrain, phatasmal killer</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><em>dream, modify memory</em></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>As long as you have a familiar, you may add covenant spells to your known spells list.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_THOUGHTS" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SUGGESTION" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HYPNOTIC_PATTERN" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TONGUES" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HALLUCINATORY_TERRAIN" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" level="7" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PHANTASMAL_KILLER" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" level="7" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DREAM" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MODIFY_MEMORY" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" level="9" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Spirit of Desire" type="Archetype Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COC_SPIRIT_OF_DESIRE">
            <description>
                <p>Witches of the Coven of Charms have discovered many ways of bending a creature’s emotions. They can even be so convincing as to enlist spirits from the other side to whisper to a target’s very soul. You gain the ability to bond a unique spirit: The Spirit of Desire.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Spirit Token" type="Archetype Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COC_SPIRIT_TOKEN">
            <description>
                <p>At 2nd level, you gain the ability to share the emotional energy of the spirits you bind. You may tie one of your spirits you already have bound to a small object as an action.</p>
                <p class="indent">The spirit still counts towards your maximum bonds while attached to the object. When you create a token, you also choose a recipient. As long as the recipient is in possession of the token, the spirit provides its passive effect as though the spirit were bound by the recipient (even if the holder of the token is not a witch). In either case, the magic holding the spirit to the object expires after 24 hours where it returns to your control or when you take a long rest. If the token is returned to you, you can break this magic sooner as a bonus action. Breaking this returns the spirit to you.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>You may use your action to tie one of your bound spirits to a small object. You choose a recipient to whom the token bears significance and the recipient gains the passive effect of the spirit. You can break the tie as a bonus action, otherwise the bond lasts for 24 hours.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="In Perfect Trust" type="Archetype Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COC_IN_PERFECT_TRUST">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, you have grown attuned to the hearts and minds of those around you. While in your quickening, you may add your proficiency bonus to Charisma (Deception) and Charisma (Persuasion) checks, or twice your proficiency bonus if you are already proficient.</p>
                <p class="indent">In addition, during your quickening, you gain the ability peer into the heart of a creature within 60 feet. Much like the <em>detect thoughts</em> spell, you may use an action to force the target to make a Wisdom saving throw against your spell save DC. If it fails, you gain insight into its emotional state and something that is currently influencing this state such as something it worries over, desires, loves, or hates. If the target succeeds on its saving throw, nothing happens. Unlike <em>detect thoughts</em>, the target does not become aware of the intrusion. Constructs and creatures immune to being charmed are not affected.</p>
                <p class="indent">You may attempt to peer into the heart of a creature once per long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest" action="Action">
                <description>You may force a target within 60 feet of you to make a Wisdom saving throw against your spell save DC (save DC = {{spellcasting:saving-throw-dc}}). If it fails, you gain insight into its emotional state and something influencing this state. The target is not aware of the intrustion. Constructs and creatures immune to charm are not affected.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Of One Heart" type="Archetype Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COC_OF_ONE_HEART">
            <description>
                <p>At 10th level, foes charmed by you are also considered charmed by allies you designate. Additionally, whenever you trigger a spirit’s release effect, allies within 60 feet may damage charmed foes on their next turn without breaking the charm. Once a creature has been affected by this, it cannot be affected again for 24 hours.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, when you use your quickening, you gain further insight into a creature. You can study an enemy for 1 minute in or out of combat. Doing so gives you information about their abilities. The DM can tell you if the following enemy abilities are equal to, stronger, or weaker than your own:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Intelligence ability score</li>
                    <li>Wisdom ability score</li>
                    <li>Charisma ability score</li>
                    <li>AC</li>
                    <li>Current HP</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Foes charmed by you are also considered charmed by your allies. Additionally, whenever you trigger a spirit’s release effect, allies within 60 feet may damage charmed foes until the end of their next turn without breaking the charm. Once a creature has been affected by this, it cannot be affected again for 24 hours. Additionally, when you use your quickening, you gain further insight into a creature. You can study an enemy for 1 minute in or out of combat.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Crux of Desire" type="Archetype Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COC_CRUX_OF_DESIRE">
            <description>
                <p>At 14th level, your spells and spirits which can charm creatures affect those with immunity to being charmed. When you cast a spell that forces a creature to make a saving throw against or become charmed, you may strip their defenses against your magic as part of that spell. Creatures that are immune to the charm condition instead gain advantage on all saving throws to resist or break free of the effect. A creature who is not immune to being charmed now has disadvantage against being charmed by you.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can use this ability 3 times and regain expended uses when you finish a long rest.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, you gain immunity to the charmed condition.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="3/Long Rest">
                <description>When you cast a spell that forces a creature to make a saving throw against or become charmed, you may strip their defenses against your magic as part of that spell. Creatures that are immune to the charm condition instead gain advantage on all saving throws to resist or break free of the effect. A creature who is not immune to being charmed now has disadvantage against being charmed by you. You are immune to being charmed.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    <element name="Coven of Fates" type="Archetype" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COVEN_OF_FATES">
        <supports>Ancient Coven</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Witches of the Coven of Fates have an unusual connection with the pulse of the universe. Some call it karma, luck, destiny, or fate. Whatever the case may be a witch of this coven is hard to pin down as luck always seems to be on their side, enabling them to do better or causing their enemies to do worse. Often finding themselves worshiped as oracles or prophets.</p>
            <p class="indent">Witches of this coven do not have much bias toward the spirits they bind, simply seeing it as fate that this spirit answered their call. How they treat the spirit once it has been called depends entirely on the witch as taking an active hand with fate, no matter the kindness or brutality show, is always acceptable for the coven.</p>
            <div element="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COF_COVEN_SPELLS" />
            <div element="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COF_SPIRIT_OF_FORTUNE" />
            <div element="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COF_JINX_NUMBERS" />
            <div element="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COF_BOUNDLESS_LUCK" />
            <div element="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COF_HEXWEAVER" />
            <div element="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COF_FORTUNES_FAVORITE" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COF_COVEN_SPELLS" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COF_SPIRIT_OF_FORTUNE" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COF_JINX_NUMBERS" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COF_BOUNDLESS_LUCK" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COF_HEXWEAVER" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COF_FORTUNES_FAVORITE" level="14" />
         </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Coven Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COF_COVEN_SPELLS">
            <description>
                <p>As long as you have a familiar, you may also add the following spells to your spells known list.</p>
                <h5 class="caption">Coven of Fates Spells</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Witch Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>detect evil and good, speak with animals</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>detect thoughts, locate object</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>7th</td><td><em>clairvoyance, locate creature</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><em>divination, commune with nature</em></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>As long as you have a familiar, you may add covenant spells to your known spells list.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_EVIL_AND_GOOD" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_ANIMALS" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_THOUGHTS" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LOCATE_OBJECT" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CLAIRVOYANCE" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" level="7" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LOCATE_CREATURE" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" level="7" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DIVINATION" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMMUNE_WITH_NATURE" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" level="9" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Spirit of Fortune" type="Archetype Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COF_SPIRIT_OF_FORTUNE">
            <description>
                <p>Witches of the Coven of Fates have learned that one can bind particularly lucky souls and use it for themselves. You gain the ability to bond a unique spirit: The Spirit of Fortune.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Jinx Numbers" type="Archetype Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COF_JINX_NUMBERS">
            <description>
                <p>Starting when you choose this coven at 2nd level, you gain a Jinx die. When you finish a long rest you can roll the Jinx die (a d20) and record the result. When you release a spirit, select a creature within 60 feet of you. The creature must make a Wisdom saving throw and on a fail that creature becomes cursed. Whenever the cursed creature rolls the same number on a d20 as your Jinx die, their roll instead is treated as if they rolled a 1.</p>
                <p class="indent">At 10th level, you gain a second Jinx die. If the cursed creature rolls either number from your Jinx dice their roll instead is treated as if they rolled a 1. If you roll the same number twice, you can roll one of the dice and must use the new result.</p>
                <p class="indent">For example, you have rolled a 13 on your Jinx die and cursed an enemy. Whenever that enemy rolls a d20, like on an ability check, attack roll, or saving throw, and they roll a 13 that roll instead acts as a critical fail.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you finish a long rest you can roll the Jinx die (a d20) and record the result. When you release a spirit, select a creature within 60 feet of you. The creature must make a Wisdom saving throw and on a fail that creature becomes cursed. Whenever the cursed creature rolls the same number on a d20 as your Jinx die, their roll instead is treated as if they rolled a 1.</description>
                <description level="10">When you finish a long rest you can roll two Jinx dice (d20) and record the results. When you release a spirit, select a creature within 60 feet of you. The creature must make a Wisdom saving throw and on a fail that creature becomes cursed. If the cursed creature rolls either number from your Jinx dice their roll instead is treated as if they rolled a 1. If you roll the same number twice, you can roll one of the dice and must use the new result.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Boundless Luck" type="Archetype Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COF_BOUNDLESS_LUCK">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 6th level, when you release a spirit that effects an ally, the ally becomes blessed with luck. The next ability check, attack roll, or saving throw they make that rolls a 9 or lower becomes a 10 instead.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you release a spirit that effects an ally, the ally becomes blessed with luck. The next ability check, attack roll, or saving throw they make that rolls a 9 or lower becomes a 10 instead.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Hexweaver" type="Archetype Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COF_HEXWEAVER">
            <description>
                <p>Upon reaching 10th level, certain spells you cast become empowered. You can cast the <em>hex</em> spell with a 4th level spell slot or higher. It gains one of the following additions:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>You can target a second creature within range of the spell and both suffer the effects.</li>
                    <li>One ally of your choice, within 30 feet of you when you cast the spell, deals an extra 1d6 necrotic damage whenever they hit the creature with an attack.</li>
                    <li>You can select a number of ability scores equal to half your proficiency modifier (rounded down). The target has disadvantage on ability checks made with the chosen abilities.</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, you know the bless and bane spells and the spells do not count against your Spells Known. You can cast the spells at a 4th level spell slot or higher, gaining the following benefit:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>The dice rolled on the spell becomes a d6 instead of a d4.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can cast the hex spell with a 4th level spell slot or higher. It gains one of the following additions: you can target a second creature; one ally within 30 feet deals an extra 1d6 necrotic damage; you can select up to {{proficiency:half}} ability scores for which the target has disadvantage. In addition, the die for bless or bane becomes a d6.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLESS" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BANE" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Fortune’s Favorite" type="Archetype Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COF_FORTUNES_FAVORITE">
            <description>
                <p>At 14th level luck always seems to surround you. As a reaction whenever you make a roll at advantage you roll an additional 1d20 and take the highest number. Additionally, as a reaction when enemies makes an attack roll at disadvantage against you they roll an additional 1d20 and take the lowest number.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Reaction">
                <description>As a reaction whenever you make a roll at advantage you roll an additional 1d20 and take the highest number. Additionally, as a reaction when enemies makes an attack roll at disadvantage against you they roll an additional 1d20 and take the lowest number.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    <element name="Coven of Ruin" type="Archetype" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COVEN_OF_RUIN">
        <supports>Ancient Coven</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The Coven of Ruin has less respect for spirits than the other covens. Witches who bind these spirits utilize their magic to torture and pressure spirits in order to extract power from them. Their philosophy revolves around invoking ruin and causing as much damage as possible.</p>
            <p class="indent">Though good witches of this coven are rare, they are not unknown. Good witches who share this coven’s ideology typically aim to bind evil spirits, turning these beings into weapons for good against their will (though this can hardly be considered to be completely benign). These witches often claim this is for the greater good — using evil to combat evil.</p>
            <div element="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COR_COVEN_SPELLS" />
            <div element="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COR_SPIRIT_OF_SORROW" />
            <div element="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COR_DOOM" />
            <div element="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COR_DEVASTATING_RELEASE" />
            <div element="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COR_ABSOLUTE_RUIN" />
            <div element="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COR_RITE_OF_EXORCISM" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COR_COVEN_SPELLS" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COR_SPIRIT_OF_SORROW" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COR_DOOM" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COR_DEVASTATING_RELEASE" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COR_ABSOLUTE_RUIN" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COR_RITE_OF_EXORCISM" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Coven Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COR_COVEN_SPELLS">
            <description>
                <p>As long as you have a familiar, you may also add the following spells to your spells known list.</p>
                <h5 class="caption">Coven of Ruin Spells</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Witch Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td>crown of madness, shatter</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td>bestow curse, call lightning</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>7th</td><td>confusion, ice storm</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td>cloudkill, destructive wave</td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>As long as you have a familiar, you may add covenant spells to your known spells list.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CROWN_OF_MADNESS" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHATTER" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BESTOW_CURSE" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CALL_LIGHTNING" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONFUSION" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" level="7" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ICE_STORM" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" level="7" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CLOUDKILL" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DESTRUCTIVE_WAVE" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" level="9" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Spirit of Sorrow" type="Archetype Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COR_SPIRIT_OF_SORROW">
            <description>
                <p>Witches of the Coven of Ruin have, in their extensive abuse of spirits, discovered a unique spirit whose unearthly wails weaken the mind and body. You gain the ability to bond a unique spirit: The Spirit of Sorrow.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Doom" type="Archetype Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COR_DOOM">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning when you choose this coven at 2nd level, hostile creatures who are the target of any of your spirits’ release effects are given a penalty on their next ability check or attack roll, your choice. This penalty is equal to 1/3 your witch level (rounded down, minimum of 1). If multiple creatures can be affected by this feature, choose one to take the penalty.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Hostile creatures who are the target of any of your spirits’ release effects have a penalty on their next ability check or attack roll of 1/3 your witch level (rounded down, minimum of 1). If multiple creatures can be affected by this feature, choose one to take the penalty.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Devastating Release" type="Archetype Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COR_DEVASTATING_RELEASE">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, spirits you release erupt with energy as their bonds are broken, causing harm to those around you. When you release a spirit, enemies within 30 feet of you must make a Wisdom saving throw against your spellcasting DC. Those that fail are dealt 1d4 psychic damage for each level you have in the Witch class. Those who take fail also hear wails and screams as the spirit is released, and feel a rush of sorrow and discomfort.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you release a spirit, enemies within 30 feet of you must make a Wisdom saving throw against your spellcasting DC. Those that fail are dealt 1d4 psychic damage for each level you have in the Witch class. Those who take fail also hear wails and screams as the spirit is released, and feel a rush of sorrow and discomfort.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Absolute Ruin" type="Archetype Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COR_ABSOLUTE_RUIN">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 10th level, you can now choose to give enemies the penalty on their next saving throws with your Doom feature.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Beginning at 10th level, you can now choose to give enemies the penalty on their next saving throws with your Doom feature.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Rite of Exorcism" type="Archetype Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COR_RITE_OF_EXORCISM">
            <description>
                <p>At 14th level, you can attempt to exorcise a living creature’s own soul as an action. If a creature within 30 feet fails a Charisma save against your spell save DC, they are dealt 5d6 psychic damage and 5d6 necrotic damage as their soul is torn from their body. The creature is also stunned until your next turn. A successful save means the creature takes half damage and is not stunned. You may use this ability 3 times. Expended uses recover after a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="3/Long Rest">
                <description>If a creature within 30 feet fails a Charisma save against your spell save DC, they are dealt 5d6 psychic damage and 5d6 necrotic damage as their soul is torn from their body. The creature is also stunned until your next turn. A successful save means the creature takes half damage and is not stunned.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    <element name="Coven of Shadows" type="Archetype" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COVEN_OF_SHADOWS">
        <supports>Ancient Coven</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The Coven of Shadows subscribes to the belief that everything that exists, both physically and metaphysically, is like a shadow cast by that which came before it. Shadows are windows into worlds beyond the material plane — as one world becomes dimmer, others become brighter and easier to see by comparison.</p>
            <p class="indent">There is reason to be wary of the dark. Witches from this coven are more cautious dealing with spirits. They know that dangers lurk in the shadows, and they are careful with their dealings lest the spirits they bind show their dark side.</p>
            <div element="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COS_COVEN_SPELLS" />
            <div element="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COS_SPIRIT_OF_TERROR" />
            <div element="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COS_THE_SHADOWS_HAVE_EYES" />
            <div element="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COS_BLINDING_SHACKLES" />
            <div element="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COS_SPIRITS_IN_THE_SHADOWS" />
            <div element="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COS_HAUNTING_SHADES" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COS_COVEN_SPELLS" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COS_SPIRIT_OF_TERROR" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COS_THE_SHADOWS_HAVE_EYES" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COS_BLINDING_SHACKLES" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COS_SPIRITS_IN_THE_SHADOWS" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COS_HAUNTING_SHADES" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Coven Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COS_COVEN_SPELLS">
        <description>
            <p>As long as you have a familiar, you may also add the following spells to your spells known list.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">Coven of Shadows Spells</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Witch Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>3rd</td><td>darkness, pass without trace</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5th</td><td>fear, invisibility</td></tr>
                <tr><td>7th</td><td>dimension door, greater invisibility</td></tr>
                <tr><td>9th</td><td>mislead, seeming</td></tr>
            </table>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>As long as you have a familiar, you may add covenant spells to your known spells list.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DARKNESS" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" level="3" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PASS_WITHOUT_TRACE" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" level="3" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FEAR" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" level="5" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INVISIBILITY" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" level="5" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DIMENSION_DOOR" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" level="7" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GREATER_INVISIBILITY" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" level="7" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MISLEAD" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" level="9" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SEEMING" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" level="9" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Spirit of Terror" type="Archetype Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COS_SPIRIT_OF_TERROR">
            <description>
                <p>Witches of the Coven of Shadows have learned to command the darkness and unknown, and nothing is more terrifying. You gain the ability to bond a unique spirit: The Spirit of Terror.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="The Shadows Have Eyes" type="Archetype Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COS_THE_SHADOWS_HAVE_EYES">
            <description>
                <p>You can use the spirits which dwell in the darkness to see. Beginning at 2nd level, you can see in magical and nonmagical darkness up to 120 feet as long as you have at least 1 spirit bound, and you have advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks in dim light or darkness.</p>
                <p class="indent">At 6th level, you can see through magical darkness.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>If you have a spirit bound, you can see in nonmagical darkness up to 120 feet. You also have advantage on Perception checks in dim light or darkness.</description>
                <description level="6">If you have a spirit bound, you can see in magical and nonmagical darkness up to 120 feet. You also have advantage on Perception checks in dim light or darkness.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Blinding Shackles" type="Archetype Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COS_BLINDING_SHACKLES">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, hostile targets that are affected by any of your spirits’ release effects must make a Constitution saving throw or be blinded for a number of rounds equal to the level of the spirit released. This ability cannot affect creatures who do not use light to see.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Creatures affected by your spirits’ release effects must make a Constitution saving throw (save DC {{spellcasting:saving-throw-dc}}) or be blinded by one round per level of spirit released.  This ability cannot affect creatures who do not use light to see.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Spirits in the Shadows" type="Archetype Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COS_SPIRITS_IN_THE_SHADOWS">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 10th level, the shadows hide many mysteries that are open to you. When you release a spirit, you can remove the somatic or verbal component from the next spell you cast. Additionally, you may force an enemy to make a Wisdom saving throw instead of a Constitution saving throw against your Blinding Shackles. If you use Blinding Shackles in this manner and the creature fails it’s saving throw, you are considered invisible to it.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you release a spirit, you can remove the somatic or verbal component from the next spell you cast. Additionally, you may force an enemy to make a Wisdom saving throw instead of a Constitution saving throw against your Blinding Shackles. If you use Blinding Shackles in this manner and the creature fails it’s saving throw, you are considered invisible to it.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Haunting Shades" type="Archetype Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COS_HAUNTING_SHADES">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 14th level, when you release a spirit that targets a hostile creature, you may choose for the spirit to haunt that creature for a number of rounds equal to the level of the spirit, requiring your concentration as if on a spell. The passive effect of the spirit continues to aid you even while it haunts the targeted creature.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, the target’s attack rolls made against you are at disadvantage as the spirit interferes. When the minute expires or you lose concentration, the spirit’s release effect activates again.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you must finish a long rest before you can use it again.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>When you release a spirit that targets a hostile creature, you may have the spirit haunt that creature for a number of rounds equal to the level of the spirit, requiring your concentration as if on a spell.. The passive effect continues but uses the haunted creature as the origin. Additionally, the target’s attack rolls made against you are at disadvantage as the spirit interferes. When the minute expires or you lose concentration, the spirit’s release effect activates again.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    <element name="Coven of Symbiosis" type="Archetype" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COVEN_OF_SYMBIOSIS">
        <supports>Ancient Coven</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Those of the Coven of Symbiosis take on the role of guide and hand for those beyond the grave. Often thought of as the very spirit of vengeance, witches of this coven taken in their souls in a more intimate way. Becoming the host to a legion of souls, the witch acts as the final messenger for the spirit’s next of kin and loved ones, or the final terrifying reckoning to a hated foe.</p>
            <p class="indent">The witch can do this out of kindness, but there is always a price. The witch gains brief glimpses into the spirit’s memories and skills, gaining powers and abilities beyond natural understanding.</p>
            <div element="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COSY_COVEN_SPELLS" />
            <div element="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COSY_FRAGMENTED_SPIRITS" />
            <div element="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COSY_LEGION" />
            <div element="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COSY_KNOWLEDGE_OF_THE_GRAVE" />
            <div element="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COSY_SPIRITBOUND_WARRIOR" />
            <div element="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COSY_HOST_OF_SOULS" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COSY_COVEN_SPELLS" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COSY_FRAGMENTED_SPIRITS" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COSY_LEGION" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COSY_KNOWLEDGE_OF_THE_GRAVE" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COSY_SPIRITBOUND_WARRIOR" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COSY_HOST_OF_SOULS" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Coven Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COSY_COVEN_SPELLS">
            <description>
                <p>As long as you have a familiar, you may also add the following spells to your spells known list.</p>
                <h5 class="caption">Coven of Symbiosis Spells</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Witch Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>see invisibility, spiritual Weapon</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>phantom steed, spirit guardians</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>7th</td><td><em>death ward, phantasmal killer</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><em>animate objects, geas</em></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>As long as you have a familiar, you may add covenant spells to your known spells list.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SEE_INVISIBILITY" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPIRITUAL_WEAPON" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PHANTOM_STEED" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPIRIT_GUARDIANS" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DEATH_WARD" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" level="7" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PHANTASMAL_KILLER" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" level="7" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANIMATE_OBJECTS" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GEAS" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" level="9" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Fragmented Spirits" type="Archetype Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COSY_FRAGMENTED_SPIRITS">
            <description>
                <p>Witches of the Coven of Symbiosis have become so attuned with the spirits they draw in, that they can combine small fragments of spirits into a single functioning spirit. When you bind a spirit, you may replace the release effect of the spirit with a different spirit’s release effect.</p>
                <p class="indent">You cannot use a spirit’s passive effect or release effect if you do not meet the prerequisites for that spirit type.</p>
                <p class="indent">For example, you may bind a Spirit of Wrath’s Passive effect with the Spirit of Passion’s Release effect. You may not bind a Passive effect or Release effect more than once. For example, you may not have a Spirit of Protection’s Passive effect combined with a Spirit of Wrath’s Release effect and have the Spirit of Protection’s Passive effect combined with the Spirit of Guilt’s Release effect. In this example, the Spirit of Protection’s Passive effect has already been used.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you bind a spirit, you may replace the release effect of the spirit with a different spirit’s release effect. You cannot use a spirit’s passive effect or release effect if you do not meet the prerequisites for that spirit type.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Legion" type="Archetype Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COSY_LEGION">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 2nd level, you have become a host to a legion of souls. When you bind a spirit choose one armor, language, skill, tool, or individual weapon that you are not proficient in and gain that proficiency. When the spirit is released or replaced you lose that proficiency.</p>
                <h5 class="caption">Legion Quirks</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>d4</td><td>Quirk</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1</td><td>You only refer to yourself in "we" and "us" terms.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>2</td><td>Your voice changes between sounding feminine or masculine and deep or high pitched every day.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3</td><td>You take on different habits that may be unusual, such as sharpening weapons or whether you sit with your legs crossed.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>4</td><td>You refer to yourself by a different name each day.</td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you bind a spirit choose one armor, language, skill, tool, or individual weapon that you are not proficient in and gain that proficiency. When the spirit is released or replaced you lose that proficiency.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Knowledge of the Grave" type="Archetype Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COSY_KNOWLEDGE_OF_THE_GRAVE">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 6th level, the knowledge of the spirits you bind has empowered your body magic with unnatural power. When you bind your first spirit each day you choose one of the following effects:</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong>Extra Attack.</strong> You can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong>Potent Spellcasting.</strong> You add your Spellcasting Ability modifier to the damage you deal with any witch cantrips.</p>
                <p class="indent">This effect lasts so long as you have at least one spirit bound to you.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you bind your first spirit each day you choose one of the following effects: Extra Attack or Potent Spellcasting. This effect lasts so long as you have at least one spirit bound to you.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Spiritbound Warrior" type="Archetype Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COSY_SPIRITBOUND_WARRIOR">
            <description>
                <p>At 10th level, your spirits can further aid you in combat. When you use your action to release a spirit you can use your bonus action to cast a cantrip.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you use your action to release a spirit you can use your bonus action to cast a cantrip.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Host of Souls" type="Archetype Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COSY_HOST_OF_SOULS">
            <description>
                <p>Upon reaching 14th level, your spirits guide your strikes and bolster your defenses. You can add +1 to saving throws and attack rolls for each spirit you have bound. Additionally, your AC cannot be less than 10 + the number of spirits you have bound.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can add +1 to saving throws and attack rolls for each spirit you have bound. Additionally, your AC cannot be less than 10 + the number of spirits you have bound.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    <element name="Coven of Unity" type="Archetype" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COVEN_OF_UNITY">
        <supports>Ancient Coven</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The Coven of Unity subscribes to a philosophy that all spiritual entities are connected by a collective consciousness. They use this knowledge to surmount power over the spiritual realm itself. In other words, these witches gain their abilities by harnessing the secrets which govern the very basis of spiritual existence, rather than focusing on the relationships between the metaphysical and the material world.</p>
            <p class="indent">The Coven of Unity is perhaps a little more sympathetic to the spirits these witches bind. Witches of this coven tend to see spirits more as allies. They trust the spirits they bind enough to allow their power to grow under their command with the purpose of sharing this power.</p>
            <div element="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COU_COVEN_SPELLS" />
            <div element="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COS_SPIRIT_OF_TRUST" />
            <div element="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COU_SPIRIT_LINK" />
            <div element="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COU_FORCEFUL_PRESENCE" />
            <div element="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COU_POWERFUL_BONDS" />
            <div element="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COU_SIMULACRUM" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COU_COVEN_SPELLS" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COS_SPIRIT_OF_TRUST" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COU_SPIRIT_LINK" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COU_FORCEFUL_PRESENCE" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COU_POWERFUL_BONDS" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COU_SIMULACRUM" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Coven Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COU_COVEN_SPELLS">
            <description>
                <p>As long as you have a familiar, you may also add the following spells to your spells known list.</p>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Witch Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td>blur, calm emotions</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td>feign death, spirit guardians</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>7th</td><td>death ward, freedom of movement</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td>commune, legend lore</td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>As long as you have a familiar, you may add covenant spells to your known spells list.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLUR" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CALM_EMOTIONS" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FEIGN_DEATH" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPIRIT_GUARDIANS" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DEATH_WARD" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" level="7" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FREEDOM_OF_MOVEMENT" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" level="7" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMMUNE" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LEGEND_LORE" spellcasting="Witch" known="true" level="9" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Spirit of Trust" type="Archetype Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COS_SPIRIT_OF_TRUST">
            <description>
                <p>Witches of the Coven of Unity protect both physical and spiritual realms to such a degree that they have earned the favor of a unique spirit. You gain the ability to bond a unique spirit: The Spirit of Trust.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Spirit Link" type="Archetype Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COU_SPIRIT_LINK">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 2nd level, you can bind the soul of an ally using one of your Binding Rites. To perform this, you must spend the time it would take to bind a spirit normally, but does not require a spellslot. Allies bound in this way gain the following benefits so long as they are within 30 feet of you:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>When you release a spirit, your ally may add your Spellcasting Ability modifier to their next attack roll.</li>
                    <li>When you cast a spell of 1st level or higher, your ally gains advantage on their next attack roll.</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">If multiple allies can be affected by this ability, you choose who gains the benefit. A spirit bound in this way can be released an action when the bound ally is within 5 feet of you.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>You can bind the soul of an ally using one of your Binding Rites. To perform this, you must spend the time it would take to bind a spirit normally, but does not require a spellslot. Allies bound in this way gain the following benefits so long as they are within 30 feet of you: when you release a spirit, your ally may add your Spellcasting Ability modifier to their next attack roll; when you cast a spell of 1st level or higher, your ally gains advantage on their next attack roll. If multiple allies can be affected by this ability, you choose who gains the benefit. A spirit bound in this way can be released an action when the bound ally is within 5 feet of you.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Forceful Presence" type="Archetype Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COU_FORCEFUL_PRESENCE">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 6th level, you can retain control over a spirit after it produces its release effect so that it remains bound and ready to be released again.</p>
                <p class="indent">However, once you have released the spirit the first time, it cannot be regained as a spell slot.</p>
                <p class="indent">You may use this ability a number of times equal to half your proficiency bonus (rounded down). You regain all expended uses after you have finished a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="{{forceful presence:uses}}/Long Rest">
                <description>You maintain control of a spirit after it produces its release effect and remains bound until released again. However, once you have released the spirit the first time, it cannot be regained as a spell slot.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="forceful presence:uses" value="1" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="forceful presence:uses" value="proficiency:half" bonus="base" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Powerful Bonds" type="Archetype Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COU_POWERFUL_BONDS">
            <description>
                <p>At 10th level, your body and soul develop the ability to contain more powerful spirits. When you release a spirit, the release effect is considered 1 spell level higher, to a maximum of 9th level.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, you can link yourself to the souls of others, gaining knowledge of them. While in your quickening you can use your action to know whether a creature you can see has greater or fewer hit points than yourself and all conditions it currently suffers from.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>The level of spirits you bind are considered 1 higher than the spell slot you use to bind them. Additionally, you can link yourself to the souls of others, gaining knowledge of them. While in your quickening you can use your action to know whether a creature you can see has greater or fewer hit points than yourself and all conditions it currently suffers from.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Simulacrum" type="Archetype Feature" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COU_SIMULACRUM">
            <description>
                <p>At 14th level, should you be reduced to 0 hit points but not killed outright, your body becomes possessed by a spirit you control and you may continue to act for 1 round per level of the highest level spirit you have in your power. You cannot use this ability if you do not have any spirits bound. During this time, your hit points remain at 0 and you continue to make death saving throws.</p>
                <p class="indent">Onlookers notice a strangeness in your movements, eyes, and voice while you remain possessed. While possessed, you can use your action on your turn to activate the release power of one of the spirits you have bound and have it remain bound. This does not count against the uses of the Forceful Presence ability.</p>
                <p class="indent">Should you be healed under the possession (including by yourself), you awaken from the possession, conscious. Otherwise, when the duration expires, your body collapses.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you are reduced to 0 hit points but not killed outright, you may continue to act for 1 round per level of the highest level spirit you have in your power. Your hit points remain at 0 and you continue to make death saving throws. You can use your action to activate the release power of one spirit and have it remain bound (without counting as a use of Forceful Presence). Should you be healed under the possession (including by yourself), you awaken from the possession, conscious. Otherwise, when the duration expires, your body collapses.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    <!-- Witch Skills-->
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ARCANA">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ANIMALHANDLING">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_MEDICINE">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_NATURE">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_RELIGION">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SURVIVAL">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>


    <!-- Witch Spell List -->
    <!-- Witch Cantrips-->
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ACID_SPLASH">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLADE_WARD">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CHILL_TOUCH">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DANCING_LIGHTS">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FRIENDS">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLADE_WARD">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_SCAG_SPELL_GREEN_FLAME_BLADE">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GUIDANCE">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_GUST">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_INFESTATION">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LIGHT">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGE_HAND">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MENDING">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MINOR_ILLUSION">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_MOLD_EARTH">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_POISON_SPRAY">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RAY_OF_FROST">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RESISTANCE">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_THAUMATURGY">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_THUNDERCLAP">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_TOLL_THE_DEAD">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TRUE_STRIKE">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>

    <!-- Witch First Level Spells -->
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ABSORB_ELEMENTS">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANIMAL_FRIENDSHIP">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CHARM_PERSON">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CHROMATIC_ORB">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CURE_WOUNDS">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_MAGIC">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_POISON_AND_DISEASE">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENTANGLE">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FALSE_LIFE">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FAERIE_FIRE">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIND_FAMILIAR">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FOG_CLOUD">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HEALING_WORD">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HEX">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_IDENTIFY">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LONGSTRIDER">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGE_ARMOR">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGIC_MISSILE">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PROTECTION_FROM_EVIL_AND_GOOD">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PURIFY_FOOD_AND_DRINK">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SANCTUARY">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SILENT_IMAGE">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_ANIMALS">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WITCH_BOLT">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>

    <!-- Witch Second Level Spells -->
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ALTER_SELF">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AUGURY">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BARKSKIN">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLINDNESS_DEAFNESS">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLUR">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CROWN_OF_MADNESS">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DARKNESS">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DARKVISION">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_THOUGHTS">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENHANCE_ABILITY">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENLARGE_REDUCE">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENTHRALL">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FEIGN_DEATH">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GENTLE_REPOSE">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HOLD_PERSON">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LESSER_RESTORATION">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LEVITATE">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LOCATE_ANIMALS_OR_PLANTS">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LOCATE_OBJECT">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MIRROR_IMAGE">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MISTY_STEP">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MOONBEAM">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PASS_WITHOUT_TRACE">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PHANTASMAL_FORCE">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PROTECTION_FROM_POISON">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RAY_OF_ENFEEBLEMENT">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_SHADOW_BLADE">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPIKE_GROWTH">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SUGGESTION">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WARDING_BOND">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WEB">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>

    <!-- Witch Third Level Spells -->
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BESTOW_CURSE">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CLAIRVOYANCE">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONJURE_ANIMALS">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COUNTERSPELL">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DAYLIGHT">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISPEL_MAGIC">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ENEMIES_ABOUND">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FEAR">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FLY">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HASTE">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGIC_CIRCLE">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAJOR_IMAGE">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PHANTOM_STEED">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PROTECTION_FROM_ENERGY">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_REMOVE_CURSE">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_REVIVIFY">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SLEET_STORM">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SLOW">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_DEAD">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPIRIT_GUARDIANS">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_SUMMON_LESSER_DEMONS">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TONGUES">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_VAMPIRIC_TOUCH">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WATER_WALK">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>

    <!-- Witch Fourth Level Spells -->
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ARCANE_EYE">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BANISHMENT">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLIGHT">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_CHARM_MONSTER">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONFUSION">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DEATH_WARD">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DIMENSION_DOOR">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DIVINATION">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DOMINATE_BEAST">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_EVARDS_BLACK_TENTACLES">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FREEDOM_OF_MOVEMENT">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GIANT_INSECT">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GRASPING_VINE">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GREATER_INVISIBILITY">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HALLUCINATORY_TERRAIN">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ICE_STORM">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LOCATE_CREATURE">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MORDENKAINENS_PRIVATE_SANCTUM">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PHANTASMAL_KILLER">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_POLYMORPH">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_SICKENING_RADIANCE">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_SUMMON_GREATER_DEMON">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_VIRTIOLIC_SPHERE">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WALL_OF_FIRE">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>

    <!-- Witch Fifth Level Spells -->
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANIMATE_OBJECTS">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANTILIFE_SHELL">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AWAKEN">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMMUNE">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONE_OF_COLD">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONJURE_ELEMENTAL">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONTACT_OTHER_PLANE">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONTAGION">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_DANSE_MACABRE">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DOMINATE_PERSON">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DREAM">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ENERVATION">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GEAS">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GREATER_RESTORATION">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HALLOW">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HOLD_MONSTER">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_INFERNAL_CALLING">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INSECT_PLAGUE">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LEGEND_LORE">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MASS_CURE_WOUNDS">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MISLEAD">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MODIFY_MEMORY">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_NEGATIVE_ENERGY_FLOOD">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PLANAR_BINDING">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_REINCARNATE">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SCRYING">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TELEPORTATION_CIRCLE">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TREE_STRIDE">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>

    <!-- Witch Sixth Level Spells -->
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ARCANE_GATE">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CIRCLE_OF_DEATH">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONJURE_FEY">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONTINGENCY">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_CREATE_HOMUNCULUS">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CREATE_UNDEAD">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DRAWMIJS_INSTANT_SUMMONS">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_DRUID_GROVE">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_EYEBITE">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIND_THE_PATH">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GLOBE_OF_INVULNDERABILITY">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HEAL">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_INVESTITURE_OF_FLAME">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_INVESTITURE_OF_ICE">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_INVESTITURE_OF_STONE">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_INVESTITURE_OF_WIND">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGIC_JAR">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MASS_SUGGESTION">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_MENTAL_PRISON">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_OTILUKES_FREEZING_SPHERE">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_OTTOS_IRRESISTIBLE_DANCE">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_SOUL_CAGE">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SUNBEAM">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_TENSERS_TRANSFORMATION">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TRANSPORT_VIA_PLANTS">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TRUE_SEEING">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WALL_OF_ICE">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>

    <!-- Witch Seventh Level Spells -->
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ETHEREALNESS">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FINGER_OF_DEATH">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MIRAGE_ARCANE">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MORDENKAINENS_MAGNIFICENT_MANSION">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PLANE_SHIFT">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_POWER_WORD_PAIN">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PRISMATIC_SPRAY">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PROJECT_IMAGE">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_REGENERATE">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SEQUESTER">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SIMULACRUM">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SYMBOL">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>

    <!-- Witch Eighth Level Spells-->
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANIMAL_SHAPES">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANTIMAGIC_FIELD">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANTIPATHY_SYMPATHY">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CLONE">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DEMIPLANE">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DOMINATE_MONSTER">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FEEBLEMIND">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ILLUSORY_DRAGON">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_MADDENING_DARKNESS">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAZE">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_MIGHTY_FORTRESS">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MIND_BLANK">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_POWER_WORD_STUN">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SUNBURST">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TRAP_THE_SOUL">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>

    <!-- Witch Ninth Level Spells -->
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ASTRAL_PROJECTION">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FORESIGHT">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GATE">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_INVULNERABILITY">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_MASS_POLYMORPH">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_POWER_WORD_KILL">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PRISMATIC_WALL">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHAPECHANGE">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TRUE_POLYMORPH">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TRUE_RESURRECTION">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WEIRD">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WISH">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
    </append>

  <!-- Witch Spirits -->
    <element name="Spirit of Agony" type="Spell" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_WITCH_SPIRIT_AGONY">
        <supports>Einar Witch Binding Rites</supports>
        <description>
            <p>In the presence of a spirit of Agony, foes’ wounds continue to bleed, and fires continue to burn. When agony is bound choose a damage type. When you deal damage of your chosen type with a spell of 1st level or higher and roll a 1 a damage dice you can reroll the die and must use the new roll, even if the new roll is a 1. When Agony is bound using a 6th level spell slot or higher this increases to a 1 or 2 on a damage die and you must keep the new roll even if it is a 1 or 2.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Release.</em></strong> You may release Agony as part of any attack or spell which deals damage. In addition to the damage, you may roll an extra number of equivalent dice equal to the level of the spirit. If the attack or spell uses more than one type of die, choose the largest. This extra damage is psychic damage. Additionally, all 1s are treated as the maximum value for each die.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Binding Rite</set>
            <set name="time">10 minutes</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">Until released (Bonus Action)</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Spirit of Connection" type="Spell" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_WITCH_SPIRIT_CONNECTION">
        <supports>Einar Witch Binding Rites</supports>
        <requirements>ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COVEN_OF_BLOOD</requirements>
        <prerequisite>Coven of Blood</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Coven of Blood</p>
            <p>Spirits of Connection are always willing to make sacrifices for those who bind them with good intentions. You cast a spell of 1st level or higher that heals an ally, restore an additional 1 hit point. This bonus increases by 1 when you Connection is bound in a 4th through 6th level spell slot (+2) and again when Connection is bound in a 7th level spell slot or higher (+3).</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Release.</em></strong> You can release Connection as part of an action or bonus action when you cast a spell that targets allies. The spell’s range increases by 5 times the spirit level and allies can receive the benefit even if they cannot be seen, cannot hear you.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Binding Rite</set>
            <set name="time">10 minutes</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">Until released (Bonus Action)</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Spirit of Desire" type="Spell" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_WITCH_SPIRIT_DESIRE">
        <supports>Einar Witch Binding Rites</supports>
        <requirements>ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COVEN_OF_CHARMS</requirements>
        <prerequisite>Coven of Charms</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Coven of Charms</p>
            <p>Spirits of Desire impress your desires onto others and enhance their own. As a reaction when a charmed enemy creature makes a Wisdom saving throw, they take a -1 penalty to the save. When Desire is bound in a 6th level or higher spell slot the penalty the enemy creature receives increases by 1 when you bind the spirit with a 6th level spell slot or higher (-2). Once an affected creature succeeds on a Wisdom saving throw against one of your spells, that creature is immune to this spirit’s effect for 24 hours.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Release.</em></strong> When you release this spirit as a bonus action, a number of target creatures up to the spirit level within 30ft become charmed if they fail a Wisdom saving throw against one of your spells. This effect lasts one minute. The effect ends prematurely if you or your allies damage the creature. The spirit’s level also determines what kind of creature can be charmed. At 3rd level and below, only humanoids and animals can be affected. At 4th level and above, all creatures can be affected.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Binding Rite</set>
            <set name="time">10 minutes</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">Until released (Bonus Action)</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Spirit of Empathy" type="Spell" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_WITCH_SPIRIT_EMPATHY">
        <supports>Einar Witch Binding Rites</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Spirits of Empathy force your enemies to share your pain. While Empathy is bound, when an ally creature within 30 feet of you takes damage you can use your reaction to reduce that damage by 2, taking the damage yourself instead. This increases by 2 when Empathy is bound in a 4th through 6th level spell slot (4), and again when Empathy is bound in a 7th level spell slot or higher (6).</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Release.</em></strong> You can release Empathy as a reaction when an ally takes damage from a creature. When an ally within 30 feet of you takes damage, you can use your reaction to reduce the damage they take by 5 times the spirit’s level.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Binding Rite</set>
            <set name="time">10 minutes</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">Until released (Bonus Action)</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Spirit of Envy" type="Spell" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_WITCH_SPIRIT_ENVY">
        <supports>Einar Witch Binding Rites</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Spirits of Envy take from others what they covet for themselves – life. Whenever you deal damage with a spell of 1st level or higher or spirit effect to a hostile creature while Envy is bound, you can use your reaction to regain 1d4 hit points. When Envy is bound with a 4th level spell slot or lower this healing is increased by 1d4 (2d4). This increases by 1d4 again when Envy is bound in a 7th level spell slot or higher.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Release.</em></strong> You may release Envy as a bonus action to grant yourself or an ally within 30 feet temporary hit points equal to 5 times the spirit level. Additionally, select one hostile creature within 30 feet of the spirit’s target. It must make a Wisdom saving throw or become envious of the spirit’s target. As long as these temporary hit points remain, that enemy has disadvantage on attack rolls against creatures other than the spirit’s target.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Binding Rite</set>
            <set name="time">10 minutes</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">Until released (Bonus Action)</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Spirit of Fortune" type="Spell" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_WITCH_SPIRIT_FORTUNE">
        <supports>supports</supports>
        <requirements>ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COVEN_OF_FATES</requirements>
        <prerequisite>Coven of Fates</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Coven of Fates</p>
            <p>The Spirit of Fortune is the embodiment of chance. When Fortune is bound you gain 1 charge. You can use this charge as a reaction when you fail a saving throw and reroll the save. This increases by 1 charge when Fortune is bound in a 4th through 6th level spell slot (2) and again when Fortune is bound in a 7th level spell slot or higher (3).</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Release.</em></strong> The Spirit of Fortune can be released as a bonus action. Roll 1d4. If the number rolled is even then every creature within 60 feet of you gains a bonus to their next attack roll equal to the level of the spirit. If the number rolled is odd then every creature within 60 feet of you receives a penalty to their next attack roll equal to the level of the spirit.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Binding Rite</set>
            <set name="time">10 minutes</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">Until released (Bonus Action)</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <!--
    <element name="Spirit of Generosity" type="Spell" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_WITCH_SPIRIT_GENEROSITY">
        <supports>Einar Witch Binding Rites</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Spirits of Generosity are always willing to make sacrifices for those who bind them with good intentions. Your spells that heal restore an additional 1d4 hit points per level of the spirit. If the spell heals more than one creature each creature is instead healed an extra number of hit points equal to the spirit level.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Release.</em></strong> You may release Generosity as a bonus action and gift the spirit to an ally within 30 feet. The spirit protects the ally, granting them temporary hit points equal to 5 times the spirit level. These temporary hit points last 10 minutes.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Binding Rite</set>
            <set name="time">10 minutes</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">Until released (Bonus Action)</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    -->
    <element name="Spirit of Gluttony" type="Spell" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_WITCH_SPIRIT_GLUTTONY">
        <supports>Einar Witch Binding Rites</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Spirits of Gluttony held an unending hunger for some aspect of life, be it knowledge, power, or something else. When you are forced to make a saving throw against a spell or magical effect that deals damage to you, that damage is reduced by 1. This penalty increases by 1 when Gluttony is bound in a 4th through 6th level spell slot (-2), and again when Glutton is bound in a 7th level spell spot or higher.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Release.</em></strong> You can release gluttony as a reaction when you must make a save against a spell that effects only you. You cast the counterspell spell at a level equal to the spirit level, and if the counterspell is successful, you gain a number of temporary hit points equal to three times the spirit level.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Binding Rite</set>
            <set name="time">10 minutes</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">Until released (Bonus Action)</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Spirit of Greed" type="Spell" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_WITCH_SPIRIT_GREED">
        <supports>Einar Witch Binding Rites</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Spirits of Greed were once being a that held a need to own everything, or everyone. When Greed is bound you gain a bonus of +2 to your Charisma (Deception) and Charisma (Persuasion) checks. This bonus increases by +2 when Greed is bound in a 4th through 6th level spell slot, and again when Greed is bound in a 7th level or higher spell slot.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Release.</em></strong> You can release Greed as an action. You cast the dispel magic spell at a level equal to the spirit level against a creature within range that is under the effects of a spell. If the dispel magic is successful, you gain the benefits of the spell cast by the creature. If the spell requires concentration, you may choose to begin concentrating on the spell or let the effect end immediately.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Binding Rite</set>
            <set name="time">10 minutes</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">Until released (Bonus Action)</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Spirit of Guilt" type="Spell" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_WITCH_SPIRIT_GUILT">
        <supports>Einar Witch Binding Rites</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Spirits of Guilt cause your enemies hesitation in acts that would wrong you. While Guilt is bound, when an ally within 30 feet of you is the target of an attack roll you can use your reaction to reduce the attack roll by 1. The penalty the enemy creature receives increases by 2 when Guild is bound in a 3rd level through 5th level spell slot (-4) and again when Guilt is bound in a 6th level spell slot or higher (-6). The creature’s attacks cannot be affected again for 1 minute.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Release.</em></strong> When you release Guilt from your power as a bonus action, choose a creature within 30 feet of you. That creature must make a Wisdom saving throw to make an attack against an ally of yours. On a failure, the attack is lost. This lasts until the creature has made number of attack rolls equal to the spirit’s level.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Binding Rite</set>
            <set name="time">10 minutes</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">Until released (Bonus Action)</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <!--
    <element name="Spirit of Hate" type="Spell" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_WITCH_SPIRIT_HATE">
        <supports>Einar Witch Binding Rites</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Spirits of Hate inspire a ferocity in you. When you are damaged by a creature, you gain advantage on attack rolls against that creature until the end of your next turn.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Release.</em></strong> When you are hit by an attack or spell, you can use your reaction to make an attack or cast a spell with a casting time of 1 action and an attack roll against the creature who struck you. The creature is dealt additional psychic damage equal to 1d6 per spirit level regardless of whether you hit.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Binding Rite</set>
            <set name="time">10 minutes</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">Until released (Bonus Action)</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Spirit of Hunger" type="Spell" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_WITCH_SPIRIT_HUNGER">
        <supports>Einar Witch Binding Rites</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Spirits of Hunger both sustain their friends and deprive their enemies of energy. While Hunger is bound to you, you require no food or water to survive.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Release.</em></strong> You may release Hunger as a bonus action to impart one level of exhaustion on a number of creatures within 30 feet equal to the spirit’s level. The creature cannot be affected by a Spirit of Hunger again for 24 hours.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Binding Rite</set>
            <set name="time">10 minutes</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">Until released (Bonus Action)</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    -->
    <element name="Spirit of Hope" type="Spell" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_WITCH_SPIRIT_HOPE">
        <supports>Einar Witch Binding Rites</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Spirits of Hope come from those who strove to be a beacon in dark times. While Hope is bound, you gain a +2 bonus to your death saving throws. This increases by 2 when Hope is bound in a 4th through 6th level spell slot (+4) and again when Hope is bound in a 7th level spell slot or higher (+6).</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Release.</em></strong> You can release Hope as a reaction when an ally within 30 feet of you makes a death saving throw. That ally gains advantage on their death saving throw and an additional bonus to the saving throw equal to level of the spirit. If the total for the save is greater than 20, your ally immediately regains 1 hit point and a number of temporary hit points equal to the level of the spirit.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Binding Rite</set>
            <set name="time">10 minutes</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">Until released (Bonus Action)</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Spirit of Justice" type="Spell" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_WITCH_SPIRIT_JUSTICE">
        <supports>Einar Witch Binding Rites</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Spirits of Justice were exemplars of law and order, denouncing crime and lies. While Justice is bound, you gain +2 to your Wisdom (Insight) and Intelligence (Investigation) rolls. When Justice is bound with a 4th through 6th level spell slot this bonus increases by 2 (+4) and again when it is bound in a 7th level spell slot or higher (+6).</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Release.</em></strong> You can release Justice as an action. A zone of influence is created around you in a 30 ft radius. Enemies creatures must make a Wisdom saving throw against your spell save DC or be unable to tell a lie.</p>
            <p class="indent">However, on a success, they take psychic damage equal to the spirit level when they tell a lie. This damage is considered non-lethal. The zone is centered on you, moving as you move and lasts for 1 minute.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Binding Rite</set>
            <set name="time">10 minutes</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">Until released (Bonus Action)</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>


    <element name="Spirit of Passion" type="Spell" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_WITCH_SPIRIT_PASSION">
        <supports>Einar Witch Binding Rites</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Spirits of Passion give those who bind them the power to push themselves and others further in order to accomplish a task. When this spirit is bound you gain 2 bonus dice. These dice are d4s. You may choose to roll one of these dice and add the result to any attack roll, ability check, or saving throw you make. You lose all remaining dice when you release Passion. The amount of bonus dice you have increases to 4 when Passion is bound in a 4th through 6th level spell slot, and 6 when Passion is bound in a 7th level spell slot or higher.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Release.</em></strong> You may release Passion as part of an attack roll, ability check, or saving throw. You make this roll with advantage. In addition, you can roll a d4 as a reaction and add the number rolled to any attack roll, ability check, or saving throw made by any creature within 30 feet for a number of rounds equal to the spirit’s level.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Binding Rite</set>
            <set name="time">10 minutes</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">Until released (Bonus Action)</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Spirit of Pride" type="Spell" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_WITCH_SPIRIT_PRIDE">
        <supports>Einar Witch Binding Rites</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Spirits of Pride were once mighty beings who thought themselves better than others and became arrogant. When Pride is bound you can attempt to reroll 1 saving throw. The amount of times you can attempt a reroll increases by 1 when Pride is bound in 6th level spell slot or higher.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Release.</em></strong> You can release Pride as a reaction when an ally within 30 feet of you falls to 0 hit points. The ally regains hit points equal to twice the level of the spirit instead. If Pride is still bound when you fall to 0 hit points, Pride automatically releases with you as the target. You regain twice the level of the spirit hit point instead.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Binding Rite</set>
            <set name="time">10 minutes</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">Until released (Bonus Action)</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Spirit of Protection" type="Spell" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_WITCH_SPIRIT_PROTECTION">
        <supports>Einar Witch Binding Rites</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Spirits of Protection shield you from harm. While Protection is bound to you, you gain resistance to your choice of bludgeoning, piercing, or slashing damage, which you decide upon binding the spirit. When Protection is bound in a 6th level spell slot or higher you can choose 2 of the damage types to resist.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Release.</em></strong> When you release Protection from your power as a bonus action, you may create a spirit ward with a radius of 30 feet, centered on your location. The ward lasts 1 minute and is stationary for the duration. While inside the ward, a number of friendly creatures equal to the spell level cannot be charmed, frightened, or possessed. Should a friendly creature already be under one of these effects and within the Spirit of Protections radius, they may immediately make a save against this effect at advantage. Additionally, if a friendly creature is reduced to 0 hit points within the ward but is not killed outright, the creature becomes stable.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Binding Rite</set>
            <set name="time">10 minutes</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">Until released (Bonus Action)</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <!--
    <element name="Spirit of Serenity" type="Spell" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_WITCH_SPIRIT_SERENITY">
        <supports>Einar Witch Binding Rites</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Spirits of Serenity bring peace and clarity of thought to those who bind them. You require only half the time worth of sleep or rest as long as Serenity remains bound. You still require 8 hours to gain the full benefits of a long rest. Additionally, when you or an ally within 30 feet roll a Hit Die to regain hit points, you regain an additional amount equal to the spirit level.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Release.</em></strong> When you release Serenity from your power as a reaction when you would suffer from the following conditions, you may avoid being afflicted, or else end their effect as long as you retain your reaction: Blinded, Deafened, Frightened, Paralyzed, Poisoned, and Stunned.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Binding Rite</set>
            <set name="time">10 minutes</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">Until released (Bonus Action)</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    -->
    <element name="Spirit of Sloth" type="Spell" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_WITCH_SPIRIT_SLOTH">
        <supports>Einar Witch Binding Rites</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Spirits of Sloth inspire sluggishness and laziness of thought and action around you. While Sloth is bound, spaces within 10 feet of you count as difficult terrain. This increases by 10 feet when Sloth is bound in a 4th through 7th level spell slot and again when Sloth is bound in an 8th level spell slot or higher (30 feet).</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Release.</em></strong> When Sloth is released as a bonus action, a number of creature’s you choose up to an amount equal to your spirit’s level within 30 feet loses their reaction until your next turn.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Binding Rite</set>
            <set name="time">10 minutes</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">Until released (Bonus Action)</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Spirit of Sorrow" type="Spell" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_WITCH_SPIRIT_SORROW">
        <supports>Einar Witch Binding Rites</supports>
        <requirements>ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COVEN_OF_RUIN</requirements>
        <prerequisite>Coven of Ruin</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Coven of Ruin</p>
            <p>The failures of your enemies continue to haunt them in the presence of a spirit of Sorrow. While Sorrow is bound to you, enemies within 30 feet who fail a saving throw against a spell of 1st level or higher cast by you or an ally are dealt psychic damage equal to the spirit’s level.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Release.</em></strong> When Sorrow is released as a bonus action, choose a creature within 30 feet. That creature has disadvantage on its next saving throw, ability check, or attack roll. Should this roll fail, they are dealt 1d6 psychic damage and this spirit’s release effect triggers again on the same creature. Once this damage has been dealt a number of times equal to the spirit level, it is no longer renewed.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Binding Rite</set>
            <set name="time">10 minutes</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">Until released (Bonus Action)</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Spirit of Terror" type="Spell" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_WITCH_SPIRIT_TERROR">
        <supports>Einar Witch Binding Rites</supports>
        <requirements>ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COVEN_OF_SHADOWS</requirements>
        <prerequisite>Coven of Shadows</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Coven of Shadows</p>
            <p>Spirits of Terror bring nightmares to life. While Terror is bound, you gain +2 to your Charisma (Intimidation) checks. When Terror is bound with a 4th level through 6th level spell slot this bonus increases by 2 (+4) and again when it is bound with a 7th level spell slot or higher (+6).</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Release.</em></strong> When Terror is released from its bonds as a bonus action, a number of creatures equal to the spirit level within 30 feet make a Wisdom save or be frightened for 1 minute. Each creature affected is allowed a Wisdom saving throw to end the effect at the beginning of their turn.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Binding Rite</set>
            <set name="time">10 minutes</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">Until released (Bonus Action)</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Spirit of Trust" type="Spell" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_WITCH_SPIRIT_TRUST">
        <supports>Einar Witch Binding Rites</supports>
        <requirements>ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_ARCHETYPE_COVEN_OF_UNITY</requirements>
        <prerequisite>Coven of Unity</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="indent">Prerequisite: Coven of Unity</p>
            <p>While emboldened by a spirit of trust, you can help your allies through cooperative spellcasting, or protect them from harmful spellcasting effects from other allies. While Trust is bound, you can use your reaction to aid an ally within 30 feet to cast a spell, giving them advantage on an attack roll or ability check made with that spell. Alternatively, if that spell requires a saving throw, the spell save DC is increased by 1. Finally, you can also use your reaction to render a single ally within 30 feet immune to the harmful effects of any ally’s spells until your next turn.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Release.</em></strong> When trust is released as part of your Help action, you impart a bonus to the spell save DC of a single ally within 30 feet for the next spell they cast before your next turn. This bonus is equal to the level of this spirit. If the spell forces more than one creature to make a saving throw, only one creature is affected by the increased DC.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Binding Rite</set>
            <set name="time">10 minutes</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">Until released (Bonus Action)</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <!--
    <element name="Spirit of Valor" type="Spell" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_WITCH_SPIRIT_VALOR">
        <supports>Einar Witch Binding Rites</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Spirits of Valor give those who bind them the power to pull through with confidence against poor odds. While Valor is bound, you and allies within 5 feet of you have advantage on saves against being frightened. Additionally, when you have line of sight to a hostile creature, you may use an action to inspire an ally within 30 feet, granting them temporary hit points equal to the spirit’s level. These temporary hit points leave when the hostile creature leaves an ally’s line of sight.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Release.</em></strong> When you release this spirit as a bonus action, one creature per spirit level within 30 feet is no longer frightened and may immediately make a saving throw to end any other effect or condition afflicting them which would normally allow saving throws.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Binding Rite</set>
            <set name="time">10 minutes</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">Until released (Bonus Action)</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    -->
    <element name="Spirit of Vengeance" type="Spell" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_WITCH_SPIRIT_VENGEANCE">
        <supports>Einar Witch Binding Rites</supports>
        <requirements>[level:witch:5]</requirements>
        <prerequisite>5th Level</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 5th Level</p>
            <p>Spirits of Vengeance are those who fell in life with vengeance in their hearts yet unfulfilled. While Vengeance is bound, whenever you are dealt damage from a living or undead source within 30 feet of you, you may use your reaction to deal the creature psychic damage equal to half your witch level (rounded down). If Vengeance is bound in a 5th level spell slot or higher, the damage increases to your full witch level.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Release.</em></strong> You can release the spirit of Vengeance as an action, letting it loose unto the world. Various stats of the Spirit of Vengeance are determined based off the spirit level. Once summoned the Spirit of Vengeance acts immediately after you and can be commanded to move to a location it can reach, requiring no action by you. The Spirit of Vengeance lasts until either it dies or 1 hour passes.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Binding Rite</set>
            <set name="time">10 minutes</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">Until released (Bonus Action)</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Spirit of Wonder" type="Spell" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_WITCH_SPIRIT_WONDER">
        <supports>Einar Witch Binding Rites</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You radiate an aura of awe when a spirit of Wonder is bound to you. While Wonder is bound, you can use your reaction to impose a -2 penalty on a Wisdom (Insight) or Wisdom (Perception) check made by a creature within 60 feet. This penalty increases by 2 when you Wonder is bound in a 4th through 6th level spell slot (-4) and again when Wonder is bound in a 7th level spell slot or higher (-6).</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Release.</em></strong> When Wonder is released from its bonds as a reaction when a creature within 30 feet of you fails a saving throw against one of your spells. If the target fails the save by more than 10 - your spirit’s level, the creature is stunned until the end of your next turn.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Binding Rite</set>
            <set name="time">10 minutes</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">Until released (Bonus Action)</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Spirit of Wrath" type="Spell" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_WITCH_SPIRIT_WRATH">
        <supports>Einar Witch Binding Rites</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Spirits of Wrath inspire a ferocity in you. You gain an increase on damage rolls against the last creature to damage you before the start of your turn. This increase starts at +2 and increases by 2 when Wrath is bound in a 4th through 6th level spell slot (+4) and again when Wrath is bound in a 7th level spell slot or higher (+6).</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Release.</em></strong> When you hit a creature with a spell or attack you may release Wrath as a reaction and deal necrotic damage equal to 1d6 per spirit level.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Binding Rite</set>
            <set name="time">10 minutes</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">Until released (Bonus Action)</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>


    <!-- Witch only spells -->
    <element name="Evil Eye of Annihilation" type="Spell" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_SPELL_EVIL_EYE_OF_ANNIHILATION">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You turn a vile gaze toward a creature of your choice within range that you can see. Your gaze begins to wither away the creature’s body, physically destroying it. The enemy creature must make a Constitution saving throw or take 4d6 necrotic damage at the end of their turn. If a creature dies as a result of this spell their body disintegrates.</p>
            <p class="indent">A disintegrated creature and everything it is wearing and carrying, except magic items, are reduced to a pile of fine gray dust. The creature can be restored to life only by means of a true resurrection or a wish spell.</p>
            <p class="indent">The spell also ends if the target is ever outside the spell’s range or if it has total cover from you.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">5</set>
            <set name="school">necromancy</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 Action</set>
            <set name="range">120 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Evil Eye of Chains" type="Spell" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_SPELL_EVIL_EYE_OF_CHAINS">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You turn a vile gaze toward a creature of your choice within range that you can see. A creature caught in your gaze believes they are ensnared by chains and must make a Wisdom saving throw or be restrained and take 1d6 psychic damage as they struggle against their imagined bonds. They may repeat this saving throw at the end of each of their turns, ending the effect on a success.</p>
            <p class="indent">The spell also ends if the target is ever outside the spell’s range or if it has total cover from you.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">necromancy</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 Action</set>
            <set name="range">120 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Evil Eye of Control" type="Spell" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_SPELL_EVIL_EYE_OF_CONTROL">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You turn a vile gaze toward a creature of your choice within range that you can see. An creature caught in your gaze must make a Wisdom saving throw or you can control it like a puppet as a bonus action causing it to either make a single melee weapon attack against a creature within range, or to have disadvantage on an attack rolls until the end of its next turn. The creature may remake this saving throw at the end of its turn.</p>
            <p class="indent">The spell also ends if the target is ever outside the spell’s range or if it has total cover from you.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">enchantment</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 Action</set>
            <set name="range">120 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Evil Eye of Greater Sight Thievery" type="Spell" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_SPELL_EVIL_EYE_OF_GREATER_SIGHT_THIEVERY">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You turn a vile gaze toward a creature of your choice within range that you can see. A creature caught in your gaze begins to lose it’s senses. The creature must make a Charisma saving throw or lose any special Senses that it might have such as Blindsight, Darkvision, or Truesight and be affected by the blinded condition. Additionally, if the creature lost at least one Sense from this spell you gain that Sense. The creature may repeat this saving throw at the end of its turn, ending the effect on a success.</p>
            <p class="indent">The spell also ends if the target is ever outside the spell’s range or if it has total cover from you.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">8</set>
            <set name="school">necromancy</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 Action</set>
            <set name="range">120 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Evil Eye of Lesser Sight Thievery" type="Spell" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_SPELL_EVIL_EYE_OF_LESSER_SIGHT_THIEVERY">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You turn a vile gaze toward a creature of your choice within range that you can see. A creature caught in your gaze begins to lose it’s senses. The creature must make a Charisma or lose any Darkvision it had and you gain Darkvision out to that range. The creature may repeat this saving throw at the end of its turn, ending the effect on a success.</p>
            <p class="indent">The spell also ends if the target is ever outside the spell’s range or if it has total cover from you.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">4</set>
            <set name="school">necromancy</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 Action</set>
            <set name="range">120 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Evil Eye of Malformation" type="Spell" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_SPELL_EVIL_EYE_OF_MALFORMATION">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You turn a vile gaze toward a creature of your choice within range that you can see. Your gaze curses the creature with horrific deformities. The creature must make a Charisma saving throw or become cursed. Their body becomes physically disfigured and they suffer the following conditions:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>Their speed is halved.</li>
                <li>They have disadvantage on attack rolls, ability checks, and saving throws based on Strength, Dexterity, or Constitution.</li>
            </ul>
            <p class="indent">They may repeat this saving throw once every 24 hours.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">7</set>
            <set name="school">necromancy</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 Action</set>
            <set name="range">120 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Evil Eye of Petrification" type="Spell" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_SPELL_EVIL_EYE_OF_PETRIFICATION">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You turn a vile gaze toward a creature of your choice within range that you can see. Your gaze it like that of Medusa and begins to turn a creature to stone. The Creature must make a Constitution saving throw or begin to become petrified.</p>
            <p class="indent">On a failed saving throw the creature’s movement speed is reduced by 10 feet. If the creature fails the saving grow by 5 or more it’s movement speed is reduced by 20 feet.</p>
            <p class="indent">On a success, the creature regains 10 feet of movement. If the creature succeeds by 5 or more it regains 20 feet of movement speed. The creature repeats this saving throw at the end of each of its turns.</p>
            <p class="indent">If a creature reaches 0 movement speed, they become petrified. The petrification lasts until it is freed by the greater restoration spell or other magic.</p>
            <p class="indent">The spell also ends if the target is ever outside the spell’s range or if it has total cover from you and the creature’s movement speed is restored at the end of it’s next turn.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">6</set>
            <set name="school">necromancy</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 Action</set>
            <set name="range">120 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Evil Eye of Terror" type="Spell" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_SPELL_EVIL_EYE_OF_TERROR">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You turn a vile gaze toward a creature of your choice within range that you can see. Your gaze instills a sense of dread and horror in the target. A construct or an undead is immune to this effect. The target must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or become frightened of you until the spell ends. The frightened target can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.</p>
            <p class="indent">The spell also ends if the target is ever outside the spell’s range or if it has total cover from you.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">necromancy</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 Action</set>
            <set name="range">120 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Evil Eye of Weakness" type="Spell" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_SPELL_EVIL_EYE_OF_WEAKNESS">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You turn a vile gaze toward a creature of your choice within range that you can see. The creature must make a Constitution saving throw or feel weakened and move slower. On a failure, roll 1d6 at the start of your turn. The enemy creature receives a penalty to their attack rolls and ability checks based on Strength or Dexterity equal to the number rolled that turn. The creature may repeat this saving throw at the end of it’s turn.</p>
            <p class="indent">The spell also ends if the target is ever outside the spell’s range or if it has total cover from you.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">necromancy</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 Action</set>
            <set name="range">120 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Evil Eye of Weight" type="Spell" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_SPELL_EVIL_EYE_OF_WEIGHT">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You turn a vile gaze toward a creature of your choice within range that you can see. Your gaze causes enemies to feel as if they are being crushed by immense weight. The creature must make a Wisdom saving throw or move they move as if they are in difficult terrain.</p>
            <p class="indent">The spell also ends if the target is ever outside the spell’s range or if it has total cover from you.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">necromancy</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 Action</set>
            <set name="range">120 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Witch Sight" type="Spell" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_SPELL_WITCH_SIGHT">
        <supports>EinarTheRed Witch</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You can see the true form of any Shapechanger or creature concealed by Illusion or Transmutation magic while the creature is within 120 feet of you and within line of sight.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">5</set>
            <set name="school">necromancy</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 Action</set>
            <set name="range">120 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">An ointment for the eyes that costs 5 gp; is made from herbal powder and blood; and is consumed by the spell</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>


  <!-- Witch Items -->
	<element name="Athame" type="Weapon" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_WEAPON_DAGGER">
		<supports>ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_MELEE, ID_INTERNAL_DAMAGE_TYPE_PIERCING, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_FINESSE, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_LIGHT, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_THROWN</supports>
		<description>
			<p>An athame is a ritual dagger used by spellcasters and witches.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">2</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="range">20/60</set>
			<set name="damage" type="piercing">1d4</set>
			<set name="container">Arcane Focus</set>
			<set name="proficiency">ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_DAGGER</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Spirit Bound Athame +1" type="Magic Item" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_MAGIC_ITEM_SPIRIT_BOUND_ATHAME_1">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</p>
			<p class="indent">While holding this athame, you gain a bonus to spell attack rolls determined by the athame’s rarity.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can use this athame as a spellcasting focus for your witch spells.</p>
			<p class="indent">Additionally, you may spend ten minutes calling a spirit to the dagger. The level of this spirit depends on your max spell slot level, up to level 5 for the spirit. The spirit does not count against your max spirits bound. Once the bonding is complete, the spirit functions as if bound to you.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">athame</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="athame">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a witch">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">athame</set>
			<set name="name-format">Spirit Bound Athame +1</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Spirit Bound Athame +2" type="Magic Item" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_MAGIC_ITEM_SPIRIT_BOUND_ATHAME_2">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</p>
			<p class="indent">While holding this athame, you gain a bonus to spell attack rolls determined by the athame’s rarity.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can use this athame as a spellcasting focus for your witch spells.</p>
			<p class="indent">Additionally, you may spend ten minutes calling a spirit to the dagger. The level of this spirit depends on your max spell slot level, up to level 5 for the spirit. The spirit does not count against your max spirits bound. Once the bonding is complete, the spirit functions as if bound to you.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">athame</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="athame">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a witch">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">2</set>
			<set name="weapon">athame</set>
			<set name="name-format">Spirit Bound Athame +2</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Spirit Bound Athame +3" type="Magic Item" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_MAGIC_ITEM_SPIRIT_BOUND_ATHAME_3">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</p>
			<p class="indent">While holding this athame, you gain a bonus to spell attack rolls determined by the athame’s rarity.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can use this athame as a spellcasting focus for your witch spells.</p>
			<p class="indent">Additionally, you may spend ten minutes calling a spirit to the dagger. The level of this spirit depends on your max spell slot level, up to level 5 for the spirit. The spirit does not count against your max spirits bound. Once the bonding is complete, the spirit functions as if bound to you.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">athame</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="athame">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a witch">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
			<set name="weapon">athame</set>
			<set name="name-format">Spirit Bound Athame +3</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

    <element name="Witch’s Hat" type="Magic Item" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_MAGIC_ITEM_WITCHES_HAT">
        <description>
            <p>You can use the hat as a spellcasting focus for your witch spells.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can try to cast a cantrip that you don’t know. The cantrip must be on the witch spell list, and you must make a DC 10 Intelligence (Arcana) check. If the check succeeds, you cast the spell. If the check fails, so does the spell, and the action used to cast the spell is wasted. In either case, you can’t use this property again until you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="slot">head</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a witch">true</set>
            <set name="rarity">Common</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Lantern of the First Circle: Dormant" type="Magic Item" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_MAGIC_ITEM_LANTERN_OF_THE_FIRST_CIRCLE_DORMANT">
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Witch Level 4-9</p>
            <p>The spirit trapped within the lantern claims that it taught the first magic casters how to bind their power together, forming the first circle. Other legends state that the first circle of witches formed to bind this powerful spirit forever to the lantern. By appearance, the lantern is built of dark metal with a sickly green glow emanating between the housing. Upon closer inspection one can make out the spirit that dwells within, but few descriptions of it line up.</p>
            <h4>DORMANT</h4>
            <p>You gain a +1 bonus to spell attack rolls.</p>
            <h5>SPIRIT OF POWER</h5>
            <p>While attuned to the lantern, you have the Spirit of Power bound to you, and it does not count against your maximum number of spirits bound. While Power is bound, you gain a +1 bonus to the saving throw DCs of your witch spells.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Release.</em></strong> The spirit refuses to be released.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Sentient.</em></strong> The spirit that dwells within the lantern yet retains its capacity to think. With a chaotic neutral alignment and an Intelligence of 12, a Wisdom of 16, and a Charisma of 15. It has hearing and lifesense for 30 feet.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Personality.</em></strong> The spirit is manipulative and patient, willing to play a long game to see its goal fulfilled. That goal is yet unknown, but doesn’t appear to care about being freed from its prison.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a witch">true</set>
            <set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
        </setters>
        <rules>
			<stat name="spellcasting:attack" value="1" />
			<stat name="spellcasting:dc" value="1" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Lantern of the First Circle: Awakened" type="Magic Item" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_MAGIC_ITEM_LANTERN_OF_THE_FIRST_CIRCLE_AWAKENED">
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Witch Level 10-14</p>
            <p>The spirit trapped within the lantern claims that it taught the first magic casters how to bind their power together, forming the first circle. Other legends state that the first circle of witches formed to bind this powerful spirit forever to the lantern. By appearance, the lantern is built of dark metal with a sickly green glow emanating between the housing. Upon closer inspection one can make out the spirit that dwells within, but few descriptions of it line up.</p>
            <h4>AWAKENED</h4>
            <p>You gain a +2 bonus to spell attack rolls.</p>
            <h5>SPIRIT OF POWER</h5>
            <p>While attuned to the lantern, you have the Spirit of Power bound to you, and it does not count against your maximum number of spirits bound. While Power is bound, you gain a +2 bonus to the saving throw DCs of your witch spells.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Release.</em></strong> When Power is released from its bonds as an action, it strips the enemy of its supposed protections. You may target one enemy within 30 feet of you. Regardless of resistances or immunities, that enemy is vulnerable to all damage received until the start of your next turn. Once released Power does not reform in the lantern until a long rest has been completed.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Sentient.</em></strong> The spirit that dwells within the lantern yet retains its capacity to think. With a chaotic neutral alignment and an Intelligence of 12, a Wisdom of 16, and a Charisma of 15. It has hearing and lifesense for 30 feet.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Personality.</em></strong> The spirit is manipulative and patient, willing to play a long game to see its goal fulfilled. That goal is yet unknown, but doesn’t appear to care about being freed from its prison.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a witch">true</set>
            <set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
        </setters>
        <rules>
			<stat name="spellcasting:attack" value="2" />
			<stat name="spellcasting:dc" value="2" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Lantern of the First Circle: Exalted" type="Magic Item" source="EinarTheRed’s Witch" id="ID_EINARTHERED_WITCH_MAGIC_ITEM_LANTERN_OF_THE_FIRST_CIRCLE_EXALTED">
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Witch Level 15-20</p>
            <p>The spirit trapped within the lantern claims that it taught the first magic casters how to bind their power together, forming the first circle. Other legends state that the first circle of witches formed to bind this powerful spirit forever to the lantern. By appearance, the lantern is built of dark metal with a sickly green glow emanating between the housing. Upon closer inspection one can make out the spirit that dwells within, but few descriptions of it line up.</p>
            <h4>EXALTED</h4>
            <p>You gain a +3 bonus to spell attack rolls.</p>
            <h5>SPIRIT OF POWER</h5>
            <p>While attuned to the lantern, you have the Spirit of Power bound to you, and it does not count against your maximum number of spirits bound. While Power is bound, you gain a +3 bonus to the saving throw DCs of your witch spells.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Release.</em></strong> When Power is released from its bonds as ab action, it strips the enemy of its supposed protections. You may target one enemy within 30 feet of you. Regardless of resistances or immunities, that enemy is vulnerable to all damage received until the start of your next turn. Once released Power does not reform in the lantern until a long rest has been completed.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Sentient.</em></strong> The spirit that dwells within the lantern yet retains its capacity to think. With a chaotic neutral alignment and an Intelligence of 12, a Wisdom of 16, and a Charisma of 15. It has hearing and lifesense for 30 feet.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Personality.</em></strong> The spirit is manipulative and patient, willing to play a long game to see its goal fulfilled. That goal is yet unknown, but doesn’t appear to care about being freed from its prison.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Spirit’s Call.</em></strong> The spirit can cast spirit guardians and healing spirit once per day. It decides when to cast the spell and maintains concentration on them so that you don’t have to. You may use your bonus action to request that the spirit move the Healing Spirit to a location within 30 feet of you.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a witch">true</set>
            <set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
        </setters>
        <rules>
			<stat name="spellcasting:attack" value="3" />
			<stat name="spellcasting:dc" value="3" />
        </rules>
    </element>
</elements>
