<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Death Knight Class</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="class-death-knight-kb.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/classes/class-death-knight-kb.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="The Death Knight" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_KYLENBLAISE_GMBINDER_SOURCE_The Death Knight">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation">TDK</set>
            <set name="url">https://www.gmbinder.com/share/-Ln4qu88tNDwBKVrxrAt/-MHnbCxmyBXESD5mSg16</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" abbreviation="KB" url="https://www.gmbinder.com/profile/kylenblaise">KylenBlaise</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20201002</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Death Knight" type="Class" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_DEATH_KNIGHT">
        <description>
            <p>An elf in half-plate strides toward an orc warchief. His spear lashes out and keeps the orc distracted while his mount, a great wyrm of lightless scales, flies down to take the orc from behind.</p>
            <p class="indent">A brass dragonborn sits in meditation as she focuses upon inscribing a new rune upon her warhammer, which will grant her the edge in her upcoming battle.</p>
            <p class="indent">Two heavily armored knights face off: one a half-orc bound by a Solar, the other an aasimar assassin of Asmodeus. Their weapons glow with runes of green fire, which flare with flashes of energy as they clash, each intent on their opponent’s doom.</p>
            <p class="indent">Death knights are attuned to death in an intimate manner. Each death knight has died, then been brought back to life by their patron. Sometimes these resurrections were part of a bargain struck, sometimes an act of necessity, sometimes as spite, and on rare occasions the long deceased are brought back to serve a new purpose. The ritual used to create death knights is taxing upon the patron, but each one is a powerful avatar, whether they are willing or not.</p>
            <h4>RETURNED FROM DEATH</h4>
            <p>The experience of being brought back to life is often a difficult one. Some suffered in their final moments, and the thought of reliving it can break some, resulting in an insane weapon for their patron to wield. Others have been returned from another era, and they must learn of the world that has passed them by as they lay in the ground. Whatever the cause of their death, one thing remains certain: a death knight is changed from their first life.</p>
            <h4>WARRIORS OF THEIR PATRON</h4>
            <p>Death knights are created when an entity needs a hitman. Whether they bargained for it or were forced into it, death knights serve as the hand of their patron. When there is a threat, they strike out. When there is an insult, a blade of necrotic magics corrects the slight.</p>
            <p class="indent">Death knights are rare and meeting another is rarer still, but often, when two meet, it is with weapons drawn and spells ready. This is due to the wide range of patrons who create death knights. Oftentimes, the purpose of one is counter to the other, so it is rare for both parties to walk away unscathed from even a casual meeting.</p>
            <h4>DISCIPLINED AND PATIENT</h4>
            <p>As ones who have experienced death and usher others into its embrace, death knights learn that being at peace with one’s lot is important. The purest expression of this attribute is their rune-scribing. The focus and time needed to properly write a single rune is both soothing and demanding. The trance they enter to attune their focus and imbue their inks with the energy needed to inscribe a rune of power brings a tranquility that lets them cope with their nearness to death.</p>
            <h4>CREATING A DEATH KNIGHT</h4>
            <p>As you design a death knight, contemplate how they became a servant of their patron. Was it a mutual agreement? Was it for revenge? Or was it a deception? Consider how they act on their patron’s behalf. Do they act as a proper knight, or are they a scoundrel, doing as they wish until their next target?</p>
            <h5>QUICK BUILD</h5>
            <p>You can make a death knight quickly by following these suggestions, First, Strength should be your highest ability score, followed by Charisma. Second, choose the soldier background</p>
            <h5>PATRON</h5>
            <p>Each death knight has a patron; they determine the goals and targets for their death knight.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">PATRONS TABLE</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d6</td><td>Patron</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>Fiend</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>Fey</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>Celestial</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>Great Old One</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>Deity</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>Dragon</td></tr>
            </table>
            <h5>MANNER OF DEATH, CIRCUMSTANCES OF RESURRECTION</h5>
            <p>The variety of ways beings can die is staggering. Each one unique in time and circumstance, and it can cause their return to life to be complicated. This can be as simple as getting used to a new era, or as complicated as dealing with the consequences of your previous lifetime.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">MANNER OF DEATH, CIRCUMSTANCES OF RESURRECTION TABLE</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d6</td><td>Manner of Death, Circumstances of Resurrection</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>You were executed as a traitor to your country, and you were returned to life to save it, though they could very well kill you again.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>Once a war hero who died in battle, you have returned after more than a century and feel out of place.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>You made a bargain to become a death knight and chose to drift into servitude with a cup of nightshade tea. You awaken moments later filled with new power.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>You were murdered by a corrupt lord, and your patron granted you the ability to seek justice.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>You were a paladin in life, but were returned to serve your archnemesis. You cannot refuse, but you seek to take them down.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>You were a criminal brought to the noose. Now, you are a criminal with powers from beyond the grave. You shall have your vengeance.</td></tr>
            </table>
            <h5>RIVAL</h5>
            <p>Death knights rarely live long without creating enemies. It is part of the job, but some become more than an enemy. They may be a thorn in your side or perhaps a tool to measure your own growth.</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d6</td><td>Rival</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>A paladin who feels they must constantly try to thwart you.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>A fellow death knight serving your patron’s arch nemesis. You will never have peace as long as they draw breath.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>A noble escaped you and is constantly sending assassins to kill you while they hide.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>A warrior of unmatched skill bested you. You now seek to surpass him, not to kill them, but to prove to them and yourself that you are the better fighter.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>A mage, who aided in your demise so your patron could have you, reminds you of their power at every opportunity.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>An assassin who intentionally tries to kill your targets before you, and they do so just to get on your nerves.</td></tr>
            </table>
            <h2>CLASS FEATURES</h2>
            <p>As an death knight, you gain the following class features.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">HIT POINTS</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Hit Dice:</strong> 1d10 per death knight level</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at 1st Level:</strong> 10 + your Constitution modifier</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at Higher Levels:</strong> 1d10 (or 6) + your Constitution modifier per death knight level after 1st</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">PROFICIENCIES</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled mb">
                <li><strong>Armor:</strong> All armor, shields</li>
                <li><strong>Weapons:</strong> Simple and Martial weapons</li>
                <li><strong>Tools:</strong> Calligrapher’s supplies</li>
            </ul>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Saving Throws:</strong> Constitution, Charisma</li>
                <li><strong>Skills:</strong> Choose two from Arcana, Athletics, Animal Handling, Deception, Intimidation, Persuasion, Survival</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">EQUIPMENT</h5>
            <p>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>(a) A martial weapon and a shield, or (b) two martial weapons</li>
                <li>(a) leather armor, or (b) scale mail, or (c) chain mail</li>
                <li>(a) Dungeoneer’s pack, or (b) Explorer’s pack</li>
                <li>Calligrapher’s supplies and 4 javelins</li>
            </ul>
            <h2>MULTICLASSING</h2>
            <p><b><i>Prerequisites.</i></b> To multiclass into or out of the death knight class, you must meet these prerequisites: Strength 13 and Charisma 13</p>
            <p><b><i>Proficiencies.</i></b> When you multiclass into the death knight class, you gain the following proficiencies: light and medium armor, shields, all simple and martial weapons, and calligrapher’s supplies.</p>
            <p><b><i>Pact Magic.</i></b> If you multiclass into or out of Warlock, you calculate your spell slots using the method below:</p>
            <p class="indent">Your Pact Magic is not split, instead you add your death knight levels and half of your death knight levels (rounded down), the total combined level is then used to determine spell slots as written on the death knight class table.</p>
        <!-- class table here -->
            <div element="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DEATH_KNIGHT_RUNE_WEAPON" />
            <div element="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DEATH_KNIGHT_KNIGHTLY_ORDER" />
            <div element="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DEATH_KNIGHT_FIGHTING_STYLE" />
            <div element="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DEATH_KNIGHT_PACT_MAGIC" />
            <div element="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DEATH_KNIGHT_NECROTIC_STRIKE" />
            <div element="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DEATH_KNIGHT_RUNE_SCRIBE" />
            <div element="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DEATH_KNIGHT_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" />
            <div element="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DEATH_KNIGHT_EXTRA_ATTACK" />
            <div element="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DEATH_KNIGHT_KNIGHTLY_DISCERNMENT" />
            <div element="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DEATH_KNIGHT_GREATER_NECROTIC_STRIKE" />
            <div element="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DEATH_KNIGHT_DISCIPLINED_MIND_AND_BODY" />
            <div element="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DEATH_KNIGHT_AVATAR_OF_DEATH" />
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="hd">d10</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_MEDIUM_ARMOR" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_HEAVY_ARMOR" requirements="!ID_KB_TDK_MULTICLASS_DEATH_KNIGHT" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_SHIELDS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_MARTIAL_WEAPONS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_CALLIGRAPHERS_SUPPLIES" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CONSTITUTION" requirements="!ID_KB_TDK_MULTICLASS_DEATH_KNIGHT" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CHARISMA" requirements="!ID_KB_TDK_MULTICLASS_DEATH_KNIGHT" />
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency, Death Knight" supports="Skill, KB Death Knight" number="2" requirements="!ID_KB_TDK_MULTICLASS_DEATH_KNIGHT" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DEATH_KNIGHT_RUNE_WEAPON" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DEATH_KNIGHT_KNIGHTLY_ORDER" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DEATH_KNIGHT_FIGHTING_STYLE" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DEATH_KNIGHT_PACT_MAGIC" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DEATH_KNIGHT_NECROTIC_STRIKE" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DEATH_KNIGHT_RUNE_SCRIBE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DEATH_KNIGHT_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" level="4" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DEATH_KNIGHT_EXTRA_ATTACK" level="5" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DEATH_KNIGHT_KNIGHTLY_DISCERNMENT" level="7" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DEATH_KNIGHT_GREATER_NECROTIC_STRIKE" level="11" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DEATH_KNIGHT_DISCIPLINED_MIND_AND_BODY" level="14" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DEATH_KNIGHT_AVATAR_OF_DEATH" level="20" />
        </rules>
        <multiclass id="ID_KB_TDK_MULTICLASS_DEATH_KNIGHT">
            <prerequisite>Strength 13 and Charisma 13</prerequisite>
            <requirements>[str:13],[cha:13]</requirements>
            <setters>
                <set name="multiclass proficiencies">When you multiclass into the death knight class, you gain the following proficiencies: light and medium armor, shields, all simple and martial weapons, and calligrapher’s supplies.</set>
            </setters>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS" />
            </rules>
        </multiclass>
    </element>
        <element name="Rune Weapon" type="Class Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DEATH_KNIGHT_RUNE_WEAPON">
            <description>
                <p>As a death knight, your weapon is your calling card. No matter its form, you can imbue it with a measure of your power, which in turn empowers yourself. Over the course of a short rest, you can inscribe runes of necrotic energy upon up to two weapons. The runes glow with a green-white fire and mark it as your own.</p>
                <p class="indent">While wielding a rune weapon, you cannot be disarmed unless you are incapacitated, and as long as you have at least one rune weapon, you age at the rate of 1 year for every 10 years that passes. Additionally, if the weapon is on the same plane of existence, you can summon it to your hand as a bonus action.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can have up to two rune weapons at once. If you imbue a third rune weapon, you must choose one of the other two to lose its power.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Over the course of a short rest, you can inscribe runes of necrotic energy upon up to two weapons. While wielding a rune weapon, you cannot be disarmed unless you are incapacitated. Additionally, if the weapon is on the same plane of existence, you can summon it to your hand as a bonus action.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Knightly Order" type="Class Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DEATH_KNIGHT_KNIGHTLY_ORDER">
            <description>
                <p>Upon becoming a Death Knight, you join an order of knights that shape your methodology for handling situations in and out of combat. You may choose the order that best fits your philosophy on matters of conflicts. Each order has an extraplanar place to train in the art of being a death knight.</p>
                <p class="indent">Your order grants features at 1st level, and again at 6th, 10th, 15th, and 18th level.</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Order of Cavaliers</li>
                    <li>Order of Destroyers</li>
                    <li>Order of Ebon Blades</li>
                    <li>Order of Magi</li>
                    <li>Order of Rune Warden</li>
                    <li>Order of Fallen Paladins (Appendix B)</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Archetype" name="Knightly Order" supports="KB Death Knight Knightly Order" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Fighting Style" type="Class Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DEATH_KNIGHT_FIGHTING_STYLE">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 2nd level, you adopt a particular fighting style as your specialty. Choose one of the following options. You can’t take a Fighting Style more than once, even if you later get to choose again.</p>
                <h5>DEFENSE</h5>
                <p>While you are wearing armor, you gain a +1 bonus to AC.</p>
                <h5>DUELING</h5>
                <p>When you are wielding a melee weapon in one hand and no other weapons, you gain a +2 bonus to damage rolls with that weapon.</p>
                <h5>GREAT WEAPON FIGHTING</h5>
                <p>When you roll a 1 or 2 on a damage die for an Attack you make with a melee weapon that you are wielding with two hands, you can reroll the die and must use the new roll, even if the new roll is a 1 or a 2. The weapon must have the Two-Handed or Versatile property for you to gain this benefit.</p>
                <h5>TWO-WEAPON FIGHTING</h5>
                <p>When you engage in two-weapon fighting, you can add your ability modifier to the damage of the second Attack.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Fighting Style" supports="Fighting Style, KB Death Knight" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Pact Magic" type="Class Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DEATH_KNIGHT_PACT_MAGIC">
            <description>
                <p>By 2nd level, your patron’s hand in returning you to life grants you pact magic and allows you to cast death knight spells.</p>
                <h5>SPELL SLOTS</h5>
                <p>The death knight leveling table shows how many spell slots you have. The table also shows what the level of those slots is; all of your spell slots are the same level. To cast one of your death knight spells of 1st level or higher, you must expend a spell slot. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a short or long rest.</p>
                <h5>SPELLS KNOWN OF 1ST LEVEL AND HIGHER</h5>
                <p>At 1st level, you know two 1st level spells of your choice from death knight spell list. The Spells Known column of the death knight table shows when you learn more death knight spells of your choice of 1st level and higher. A spell you choose must be of a level no higher than what’s shown in the table’s Slot Level column for your level.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, when you take a long rest you can choose to sacrifice hit dice that you would regain in order to remove a spell you know and replace it with another spell from the death knight spell list, which also must be of a level for which you have spell slots. Spells cost 1 hit die per level to replace them; the cost is based on the new spell known.</p>
                <h5>SPELLCASTING ABILITY</h5>
                <p>Charisma is your spellcasting ability for your death knight spells. You use your Charisma whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Charisma modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a death knight spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.</p>
                <p style="text-align: center;"><b>Spell Save DC</b> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier</p>
                <p style="text-align: center;"><b>Spell attack modifier</b> = your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier</p>
                <h5>SPELLCASTING FOCUS</h5>
                <p>You use your rune weapon as a spellcasting focus for your spells.</p>
            </description>
            <spellcasting name="Death Knight" ability="Charisma" prepare="false">
                <list>KB Death Knight</list>
            </spellcasting>
            <sheet>
                <description>when you take a long rest you can choose to sacrifice hit dice that you would regain in order to remove a spell you know and replace it with another spell from the death knight spell list, which also must be of a level for which you have spell slots. Spells cost 1 hit die per level to replace them; the cost is based on the new spell known.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
    			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS_SPELLCASTING_SLOTS_SOLO" requirements="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS"/>
    			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_INTERNAL_PROFICIENCY_SPELLFOCUS_GROUP_RUNE_WEAPON_FOCUS" />
                <stat name="death knight:spellcasting:slots:count" value="1" level="1"/>
                <stat name="death knight:spellcasting:slots:count" value="1" level="2"/>

                <stat name="death knight:spellcasting:slot" value="1" level="2" />
                <stat name="death knight:spellcasting:slot" value="1" level="3" />

                <!-- negative count to remove slots -->
                <stat name="death knight:spellcasting:slots:1" value="death knight:spellcasting:slots:count" level="2" />
                <stat name="death knight:spellcasting:slots:1" value="-death knight:spellcasting:slots:count" level="5" />
                <stat name="death knight:spellcasting:slots:2" value="death knight:spellcasting:slots:count" level="5" />
                <stat name="death knight:spellcasting:slots:2" value="-death knight:spellcasting:slots:count" level="9" />
                <stat name="death knight:spellcasting:slots:3" value="death knight:spellcasting:slots:count" level="9" />
                <stat name="death knight:spellcasting:slots:3" value="-death knight:spellcasting:slots:count" level="13" />
                <stat name="death knight:spellcasting:slots:4" value="death knight:spellcasting:slots:count" level="13" />
                <stat name="death knight:spellcasting:slots:4" value="-death knight:spellcasting:slots:count" level="17" />
                <stat name="death knight:spellcasting:slots:5" value="death knight:spellcasting:slots:count" level="17" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Pact Magic (Death Knight)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" spellcasting="Death Knight" known="true" level="2" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Pact Magic (Death Knight)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" spellcasting="Death Knight" known="true" level="3" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Pact Magic (Death Knight)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" spellcasting="Death Knight" known="true" level="5" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Pact Magic (Death Knight)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" spellcasting="Death Knight" known="true" level="7" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Pact Magic (Death Knight)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" spellcasting="Death Knight" known="true" level="9" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Pact Magic (Death Knight)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" spellcasting="Death Knight" known="true" level="11" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Pact Magic (Death Knight)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" spellcasting="Death Knight" known="true" level="13" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Pact Magic (Death Knight)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" spellcasting="Death Knight" known="true" level="15" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Pact Magic (Death Knight)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" spellcasting="Death Knight" known="true" level="17" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Pact Magic (Death Knight)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" spellcasting="Death Knight" known="true" level="19" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Necrotic Strike" type="Class Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DEATH_KNIGHT_NECROTIC_STRIKE">
            <description>
                <p>At 2nd level, you can wreath your weapon with deadly power drawn from your runes. When you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack using a rune weapon, you can cause green-white fire to erupt, dealing an additional 1d10 necrotic damage. You can use this feature twice per long rest. The damage dealt and number of uses per long rest increase with your death knight level as shown on the Necrotic Strike Damage (Uses) column of the death knight table.</p>
                <p class="indent">You regain all uses of Necrotic Strike at the end of a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="{{necrotic-strike:uses}}/Long Rest">
                <description>When you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack using a rune weapon, you can cause green-white fire to erupt, dealing an additional {{necrotic-strike:damage-dice}}d10 necrotic damage.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="necrotic-strike:uses" value="2" level="2" />
                <stat name="necrotic-strike:uses" value="1" level="5" />
                <stat name="necrotic-strike:uses" value="1" level="9" />
                <stat name="necrotic-strike:uses" value="1" level="13" />
                <stat name="necrotic-strike:uses" value="1" level="17" />
                <stat name="necrotic-strike:damage-dice" value="1" level="2" />
                <stat name="necrotic-strike:damage-dice" value="1" level="5" />
                <stat name="necrotic-strike:damage-dice" value="1" level="11" />
                <stat name="necrotic-strike:damage-dice" value="1" level="17" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Rune Scribe" type="Class Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DEATH_KNIGHT_RUNE_SCRIBE">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 3rd level, you learn to ritualistically imbue your weapons and armor with runes of power. These special runes add unique features allowing death knights to be more adaptable. The ritual takes two hours per rune of power inscribed, and you can change a previously inscribed rune to a different one over the course of one hour. Once a rune of power has been inscribed, you must complete a long rest in order for the magic to take effect, and only you can benefit from inscribed runes.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can only have a number of inscribed runes equal to the amount shown on the Inscribed Runes column of the death knight table. A list of runes is provided at the end of this document.</p>
                <p class="indent">By 6th level, your rune scribed weapons are infused with enough magic to act as a magical weapon. If you break your connection with a rune scribed weapon, the runes of power fade, and, if it was a non-magical weapon, it ceases to act as one.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can inscribe your weapons and armor with runes of power over the course of a 2-hour ritual per rune. You must finish a long rest in order for the magic to take effect. You can have a single inscribed rune.</description>
                <description level="6">You can inscribe your weapons and armor with runes of power over the course of a 2-hour ritual per rune. Your rune scribed weapons are infused with enough magic to act as a magical weapon. If you break your connection with a rune scribed weapon, the runes of power fade, and, if it was a non-magical weapon, it ceases to act as one. You must finish a long rest in order for the magic to take effect. You can have up to {{rune-scribe:runes}} inscribed runes.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="rune-scribe:runes" value="1" level="3" />
                <stat name="rune-scribe:runes" value="1" level="6" />
                <stat name="rune-scribe:runes" value="1" level="11" />
                <stat name="rune-scribe:runes" value="1" level="16" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Death Knight Rune, Rune Forged" supports="KB Death Knight Rune" allowReplace="true" level="3" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Death Knight Rune, Rune Forged" supports="KB Death Knight Rune" allowReplace="true" level="6" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Death Knight Rune, Rune Forged" supports="KB Death Knight Rune" allowReplace="true" level="11" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Death Knight Rune, Rune Forged" supports="KB Death Knight Rune" allowReplace="true" level="16" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Ability Score Improvement" type="Class Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DEATH_KNIGHT_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Death Knight 4)" supports="Improvement Option,Death Knight,4" level="4" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Death Knight 8)" supports="Improvement Option,Death Knight,8" level="8" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Death Knight 12)" supports="Improvement Option,Death Knight,12" level="12" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Death Knight 16)" supports="Improvement Option,Death Knight,16" level="16" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Death Knight 19)" supports="Improvement Option,Death Knight,19" level="19" />     
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Extra Attack" type="Class Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DEATH_KNIGHT_EXTRA_ATTACK">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 5th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="extra attack:count" value="2" level="5" bonus="extra attack" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Knightly Discernment" type="Class Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DEATH_KNIGHT_KNIGHTLY_DISCERNMENT">
            <description>
                <p>At 7th level, the magics granted by your raw personality can be focused to give you clarity. When you make a Wisdom (Insight) or Wisdom (Perception) check, you can add your Charisma modifier to the total.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can add {{charisma:modifier}} when you make an Insight or Perception check.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Greater Necrotic Strike" type="Class Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DEATH_KNIGHT_GREATER_NECROTIC_STRIKE">
            <description>
                <p>At 11th level, you are capable of drawing out more power from your rune weapon. The damage dealt by necrotic strike ignores resistance to Necrotic damage and treats immunity as resistance by drawing energy off of such beings rather than directly damaging them.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, once per long rest, when you roll initiative and have no uses of necrotic strike, you regain 1 use.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>When you roll initiative and have no uses of necrotic strike, you regain 1 use. Additionally, the damage dealt by necrotic strike always ignores resistance to Necrotic damage and treats immunity as resistance by drawing energy off of such beings rather than directly damaging them.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Disciplined Mind and Body" type="Class Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DEATH_KNIGHT_DISCIPLINED_MIND_AND_BODY">
            <description>
                <p>At 14th level, you have transcended the need for extensive sleep. You only need to sleep for half the time to benefit from a long rest and may spend the rest of the time doing light activity such as reading, keeping watch, or rune scribing.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You only need to sleep for half the time to benefit from a long rest and may spend the rest of the time doing light activity such as reading, keeping watch, or rune scribing.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Avatar of Death" type="Class Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DEATH_KNIGHT_AVATAR_OF_DEATH">
            <description>
                <p>At 20th level, once per long rest, as an action, you can become an Avatar of Death for one minute. While in this form, you gain resistance to all damage types, and you cannot be charmed or frightened. Your movement speed is doubled, and you are unaffected by both magical and non-magical difficult terrain.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You can become an Avatar of Death for one minute. While in this form, you gain resistance to all damage types, and you cannot be charmed or frightened. Your movement speed is doubled, and you are unaffected by both magical and non-magical difficult terrain.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>

  <!-- Knightly Orders -->
    <element name="Order of Cavaliers" type="Archetype" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_DEATH_KNIGHT_ORDER_OF_CAVALIERS">
        <supports>KB Death Knight Knightly Order</supports>
        <description>
            <p>In Ysgard, the cavaliers train to become warriors of honor and valor. The Mithril Citadel, the sprawling castle of the cavaliers, is the center of their training. Here they learn to bond with the beasts they can summon and are trained in the best tactics to employ with their loyal ally.</p>
            <div element="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CAVALIER_ORDER_BOUND_MOUNT" />
            <div element="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CAVALIER_ORDER_KNIGHTLY_DEMEANOR" />
            <div element="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CAVALIER_ORDER_SKILLED_RIDER" />
            <div element="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CAVALIER_ORDER_COURTLY_APTITUDE" />
            <div element="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CAVALIER_ORDER_COMBAT_INSTINCTS" />
            <div element="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DRAGONKIN_MOUNT" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CAVALIER_ORDER_BOUND_MOUNT" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CAVALIER_ORDER_KNIGHTLY_DEMEANOR" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CAVALIER_ORDER_SKILLED_RIDER" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CAVALIER_ORDER_COURTLY_APTITUDE" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CAVALIER_ORDER_COMBAT_INSTINCTS" level="15" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DRAGONKIN_MOUNT" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Bound Mount" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CAVALIER_ORDER_BOUND_MOUNT">
            <description>
                <p>When you become a cavalier, as a 1 hour ritual, you can summon a mount. While you ride your mount, you can take the Dash action as a bonus action. If you are not riding your mount in combat, it moves on your turn, and you can spend a bonus action to command it to take an action.</p>
                <p class="indent">Your mount has the statistics of a riding horse or another CR 1/4 creature that can be ridden (at your DM’s discretion), though it is a celestial, fey, or undead (your choice) instead of its normal type, and if your mount has an Intelligence of 5 or less, its Intelligence becomes 6, and it gains the ability to understand any language that you speak; you can also communicate with it telepathically as long as it is on the same plane of existence as you.</p>
                <p class="indent">Your mount also uses your proficiency bonus instead of its own, and it has a bonus to its Hit Points equal to twice your death knight level. Additionally, while on your mount, you can make any spell you cast that targets only you also target your mount.</p>
                <p class="indent">At 5th level you can alter its form and statistics to that of a war horse or another creature of CR 1/2 or less that can be ridden. The limit increases to CR 1 at 9th level and CR 2 at 13th level.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>As a 1-hour ritual, you can summon a mount of CR 1/4 or less. While you ride your mount, you can take the Dash action as a bonus action. If you are not riding your mount in combat, it moves on your turn, and you can spend a bonus action to command it to take an action. Your mount also uses your proficiency bonus instead of its own, and it has a bonus {{bound-mount:hp}} hit points. Additionally, while on your mount, you can make any spell you cast that targets only you also target your mount.</description>
                <description level="5">As a 1-hour ritual, you can summon a mount of CR 1/2 or less. While you ride your mount, you can take the Dash action as a bonus action. If you are not riding your mount in combat, it moves on your turn, and you can spend a bonus action to command it to take an action. Your mount also uses your proficiency bonus instead of its own, and it has a bonus {{bound-mount:hp}} hit points. Additionally, while on your mount, you can make any spell you cast that targets only you also target your mount.</description>
                <description level="9">As a 1-hour ritual, you can summon a mount of CR 1 or less. While you ride your mount, you can take the Dash action as a bonus action. If you are not riding your mount in combat, it moves on your turn, and you can spend a bonus action to command it to take an action. Your mount also uses your proficiency bonus instead of its own, and it has a bonus {{bound-mount:hp}} hit points. Additionally, while on your mount, you can make any spell you cast that targets only you also target your mount.</description>
                <description level="13">As a 1-hour ritual, you can summon a mount of CR 2 or less. While you ride your mount, you can take the Dash action as a bonus action. If you are not riding your mount in combat, it moves on your turn, and you can spend a bonus action to command it to take an action. Your mount also uses your proficiency bonus instead of its own, and it has a bonus {{bound-mount:hp}} hit points. Additionally, while on your mount, you can make any spell you cast that targets only you also target your mount.</description>
                <description level="18">As a 1-hour ritual, you can summon shadow wyrm or a mount of CR 3 or less. While you ride your mount, you can take the Dash action as a bonus action. If you are not riding your mount in combat, it moves on your turn, and you can spend a bonus action to command it to take an action. Your mount also uses your proficiency bonus instead of its own, and it has a bonus {{bound-mount:hp}} hit points. Additionally, while on your mount, you can make any spell you cast that targets only you also target your mount.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="bound-mount:hp" value="level:death knight" />
                <stat name="bound-mount:hp" value="level:death knight" />
                <select type="Companion" name="Bound Mount" supports="1/4" level="1" requirements="![level:death knight:5]" />
                <select type="Companion" name="Bound Mount" supports="(1/4||1/2)" level="5" requirements="![level:death knight:9]" />
                <select type="Companion" name="Bound Mount" supports="(1/4||1/2||1)" level="9" requirements="![level:death knight:13]" />
                <select type="Companion" name="Bound Mount" supports="(1/4||1/2||1||2)" level="13" requirements="![level:death knight:18]" />
                <select type="Companion" name="Bound Mount" supports="(1/4||1/2||1||2||3)" level="18" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Knightly Demeanor" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CAVALIER_ORDER_KNIGHTLY_DEMEANOR">
            <description>
                <p>At 1st level, your training as a cavalier imparts a refined air to your countenance.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can give yourself advantage on Charisma (Intimidation) checks a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier per long rest. You regain all uses of this feature at the end of a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="{{charisma:modifier}}/Long Rest">
                <description>You can give yourself advantage on Intimidation checks.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Skilled Rider" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CAVALIER_ORDER_SKILLED_RIDER">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, you become a dangerous foe to face while mounted. While you are mounted and are not incapacitated, you gain the following benefits:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>While mounted, you have immunity to the surprised condition.</li>
                    <li>You gain proficiency with Animal Handling, or if you are already proficient, you can choose a skill from the death knight skill list and gain proficiency with it.</li>
                    <li>You have advantage on checks to stay mounted against non-magical and magical effects.</li>
                </ul>
                <div class="sidebar">
                    <h5>CAVALIER VARIANT RULES</h5>
                    <h5 class="caption">SKILLED RIDER VARIANT</h5>
                    <p>If your campaign does not allow feats, you can choose to gain the following benefits instead of the normal Skilled Rider features:</p>
                    <ul>
                        <li>You have advantage on melee attack rolls against any unmounted creature that is smaller than your mount.</li>
                        <li>You can force an attack targeted at your mount to target you instead.</li>
                        <li>If your mount is subjected to an effect that allows it to make a Dexterity saving throw to take only half damage, it instead takes no damage if it succeeds on the saving throw, and only half damage if it fails.</li>
                    </ul>
                    <h5 class="caption">ALTERNATE MOUNTS</h5>
                    <p>If your DM approves, instead of summoning a creature, you can attempt to tame a creature you meet in your travels. The DM can choose to require Animal Handling checks to succeed. In this case, you must complete an hour long bonding ritual with the creature. Creatures bonded in this way could potentially exceed the standard CR limits at the DM’s discretion.</p>
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>While mounted, you have immunity to the surprised condition. You gain proficiency with Animal Handling, or if you are already proficient, you can choose a skill from the death knight skill list and gain proficiency with it. You have advantage on checks to stay mounted against non-magical and magical effects.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Courtly Aptitude" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CAVALIER_ORDER_COURTLY_APTITUDE">
            <description>
                <p>At 10th level, your extensive experience has made you a superior diplomat. When you make a Charisma (Persuasion) check or an Intelligence (History) check, your proficiency bonus is doubled.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
			    <stat name="persuasion:proficiency" value="proficiency" bonus="double" />
			    <stat name="history:proficiency" value="proficiency" bonus="double" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Combat Instincts" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CAVALIER_ORDER_COMBAT_INSTINCTS">
            <description>
                <p>Upon reaching 15th level, your summoned mount has become just as much of a force on the battlefield as you have. Any of your bound mounts gain instincts honed to the point that you have advantage on initiative rolls atop your mount.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, you can now telepathically direct your mounts to take actions (no action required).</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You have advantage on initiative rolls atop your mount. Additionally, you can now telepathically direct your mounts to take actions (no action required).</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Dragonkin Mount" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DRAGONKIN_MOUNT">
            <description>
                <p>At 18th level, when you use your bound mount feature, you can now summon a Shadow Wyrm Mount (stats at the end of the list of runes). Alternately, you can summon a Nightmare or another CR 3 creature that can be ridden.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you use your bound mount feature, you can now summon a Shadow Wyrm Mount (stats at the end of the list of runes). Alternately, you can summon a Nightmare or another CR 3 creature that can be ridden.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>

    <element name="Order of Destroyers" type="Archetype" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_DEATH_KNIGHT_ORDER_OF_DESTROYERS">
        <supports>KB Death Knight Knightly Order</supports>
        <description>
            <p>One of two sister orders, the destroyers have the entrance to their headquarters in Avalas, first layer of the plane Acheron. Through a rift accessible only to death knights and their patrons, lies the Adamant Bastion where the destroyers become truly terrifying warriors that focus on strength above all else.</p>
            <div element="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DESTROYER_ORDER_EVOKE_FEAR" />
            <div element="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DESTROYER_ORDER_CLOSE_THE_GAP" />
            <div element="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DESTROYER_ORDER_SAVAGE_TECHNIQUES" />
            <div element="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DESTROYER_ORDER_IMBUED_PHYSIQUE" />
            <div element="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DESTROYER_ORDER_IMPROVED_SAVAGE_TECHNIQUES" />
            <div element="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DESTROYER_ORDER_CHANNELED_POWER" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DESTROYER_ORDER_EVOKE_FEAR" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DESTROYER_ORDER_CLOSE_THE_GAP" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DESTROYER_ORDER_SAVAGE_TECHNIQUES" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DESTROYER_ORDER_IMBUED_PHYSIQUE" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DESTROYER_ORDER_IMPROVED_SAVAGE_TECHNIQUES" level="15" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DESTROYER_ORDER_CHANNELED_POWER" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Evoke Fear" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DESTROYER_ORDER_EVOKE_FEAR">
            <description>
                <p>Your training as a destroyer has imparted the ability to cause even the most stalwart to cower before you. You can give yourself advantage on Charisma (Intimidation) checks a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier per long rest and regain all uses of this feature at the end of a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="{{charisma:modifier}}/Long Rest">
                <description>You can give yourself advantage on Intimidation checks.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Close the Gap" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DESTROYER_ORDER_CLOSE_THE_GAP">
            <description>
                <p>At 1st level, when you take the attack action, you gain an additional 5 feet of movement. You can use this movement before or after making your first attack.</p>
                <p class="indent">The additional movement increases to 10 feet at 6th level and 15 feet at 15th level.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you take the attack action, you gain an additional {{close-the-gap:speed}} feet of movement. You can use this movement before or after making your first attack.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="close-the-gap:speed" value="5" level="1" />
                <stat name="close-the-gap:speed" value="5" level="6" />
                <stat name="close-the-gap:speed" value="5" level="15" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Savage Techniques" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DESTROYER_ORDER_SAVAGE_TECHNIQUES">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, when you hit with a melee weapon attack using your Strength modifier, you can attempt to brutalize an opponent and beat them down with power and fear. You can use savage techniques a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier per long rest.</p>
                <ul class="unstyled">
                    <li><b>Batter.</b> The target creature must make a Strength saving throw against your Spell Save DC or be knocked prone.</li>
                    <li><b>Battle Cry.</b> You let loose a primal scream and strike fear into your opponent. The target creature must make a Wisdom saving throw against your Spell Save DC. On a failure, they become frightened of you until the end of its next turn.</li>
                    <li><b>Break the Gate.</b> The target creature must make a Constitution saving throw against your Spell Save DC. On a failure, the target creature has -2 penalty to its AC until the end of it’s next turn. Break the Gate does not stack.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="{{charisma:modifier}}/Long Rest">
                <description>When you hit with a melee weapon attack using your Strength modifier, you can use a savage technique.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DESTROYER_ORDER_SAVAGE_TECHNIQUES_BATTER" level="6" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DESTROYER_ORDER_SAVAGE_TECHNIQUES_BATTLE_CRY" level="6" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DESTROYER_ORDER_SAVAGE_TECHNIQUES_BREAK_THE_GATE" level="6" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DESTROYER_ORDER_IMPROVED_SAVAGE_TECHNIQUES_WAR_CRY" level="15" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DESTROYER_ORDER_IMPROVED_SAVAGE_TECHNIQUES_SHATTER_THE_GATE" level="15" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DESTROYER_ORDER_IMPROVED_SAVAGE_TECHNIQUES_OVERWHELM" level="15" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Batter" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DESTROYER_ORDER_SAVAGE_TECHNIQUES_BATTER">
                <description>
                    <p>The target creature must make a Strength saving throw against your Spell Save DC or be knocked prone.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Savage Technique">
                    <description>The target creature must make a Strength saving throw against your Spell Save DC or be knocked prone.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Battle Cry" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DESTROYER_ORDER_SAVAGE_TECHNIQUES_BATTLE_CRY">
                <description>
                    <p>You let loose a primal scream and strike fear into your opponent. The target creature must make a Wisdom saving throw against your Spell Save DC. On a failure, they become frightened of you until the end of its next turn.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Savage Technique">
                    <description>The target creature must make a Wisdom saving throw against your Spell Save DC. On a failure, they become frightened of you until the end of its next turn.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Break the Gate" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DESTROYER_ORDER_SAVAGE_TECHNIQUES_BREAK_THE_GATE">
                <description>
                    <p>The target creature must make a Constitution saving throw against your Spell Save DC. On a failure, the target creature has -2 penalty to its AC until the end of it’s next turn. Break the Gate does not stack.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Savage Technique">
                    <description>The target creature must make a Constitution saving throw against your Spell Save DC. On a failure, the target creature has -2 penalty to its AC until the end of it’s next turn. Break the Gate does not stack.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
        <element name="Imbued Physique" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DESTROYER_ORDER_IMBUED_PHYSIQUE">
            <description>
                <p>At 10th level, your training grants you enhanced physical capabilities and a more sinister aspect. When you make a Strength (Athletics) or Charisma (Intimidation) check, your proficiency bonus is doubled.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
			    <stat name="athletics:proficiency" value="proficiency" bonus="double" />
			    <stat name="intimidation:proficiency" value="proficiency" bonus="double" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Improved Savage Techniques" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DESTROYER_ORDER_IMPROVED_SAVAGE_TECHNIQUES">
            <description>
                <p>By 15th level, you have learned to perform superior versions of your Savage Techniques.</p>
                <ul class="unstyled">
                    <li><b>War Cry.</b> Creatures targeted by Battle Cry make the Wisdom saving throw at disadvantage.</li>
                    <li><b>Shatter the Gate.</b> Break the Gate now causes them to have a -2 penalty to all saving throws until the end of their next turn.</li>
                    <li><b>Overwhelm.</b> When the target of Batter is one size larger than you or smaller, they are knocked prone and cannot make a save against it.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="War Cry" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DESTROYER_ORDER_IMPROVED_SAVAGE_TECHNIQUES_WAR_CRY">
                <description>
                    <p>Creatures targeted by Battle Cry make the Wisdom saving throw at disadvantage.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Savage Technique">
                    <description>Creatures targeted by Battle Cry make the Wisdom saving throw at disadvantage.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Shatter the Gate" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DESTROYER_ORDER_IMPROVED_SAVAGE_TECHNIQUES_SHATTER_THE_GATE">
                <description>
                    <p>Break the Gate now causes them to have a -2 penalty to all saving throws until the end of their next turn.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Savage Technique">
                    <description>Break the Gate now causes them to have a -2 penalty to all saving throws until the end of their next turn.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Overwhelm" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DESTROYER_ORDER_IMPROVED_SAVAGE_TECHNIQUES_OVERWHELM">
                <description>
                    <p>When the target of Batter is one size larger than you or smaller, they are knocked prone and cannot make a save against it.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Savage Technique">
                    <description>When the target of Batter is one size larger than you or smaller, they are knocked prone and cannot make a save against it.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
        <element name="Channeled Power" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DESTROYER_ORDER_CHANNELED_POWER">
            <description>
                <p>At 18th level, you learn to temporarily enhance your muscles with magic. As a bonus action, you can increase your Strength score by an amount equal to your Charisma modifier for 1 minute. This enhancement can take your strength above 20, but it cannot exceed 30. If your Strength score is set by a Magic Item, this feature does increase the set amount, instead increasing your natural Strength score, and you use whichever is higher.</p>
                <p class="indent">While your channeled power is active, you can use your Savage Technique feature once per turn without expending a use.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can use this feature once per long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You can increase your Strength score by {{charisma:modifier}} (maximum of 30) for 1 minute. While your channeled power is active, you can use your Savage Technique feature once per turn without expending a use.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>

    <element name="Order of Ebon Blades" type="Archetype" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_DEATH_KNIGHT_ORDER_OF_EBON_BLADES">
        <supports>KB Death Knight Knightly Order</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The second sister order, the ebon blades have the entrance to their headquarters in the first layer of the plane Acheron, Avalas. Through a rift accessible only to death knights and their patrons, lies the Adamant Bastion where ebon blades undergo their transformation from a mere swordsman to a swordmaster whose skill is unrivaled.</p>
            <div element="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_EBON_BLADE_EMPOWERED_ACROBAT" />
            <div element="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_EBON_BLADE_EBON_ARMAMENTS" />
            <div element="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_EBON_BLADE_WEAPON_ARTS" />
            <div element="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_EBON_BLADE_SUPERIOR_AWARENESS" />
            <div element="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_EBON_BLADE_IMPROVED_WEAPON_ARTS" />
            <div element="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_EBON_BLADE_UNDYING_SWORDSMAN" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_EBON_BLADE_EMPOWERED_ACROBAT" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_EBON_BLADE_EBON_ARMAMENTS" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_EBON_BLADE_WEAPON_ARTS" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_EBON_BLADE_SUPERIOR_AWARENESS" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_EBON_BLADE_IMPROVED_WEAPON_ARTS" level="15" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_EBON_BLADE_UNDYING_SWORDSMAN" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Empowered Acrobat" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_EBON_BLADE_EMPOWERED_ACROBAT">
            <description>
                <p>Your training as an ebon blade has imparted the ability to perform greater feats of acrobatics. When you make a Dexterity (Acrobatics) check you can give yourself advantage a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier per long rest and regain all uses of this feature at the end of a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="{{charisma:modifier}}/Long Rest">
                <description>When you make an Acrobatics check you can give yourself advantage.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Ebon Armaments" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_EBON_BLADE_EBON_ARMAMENTS">
            <description>
                <p>At 1st level, you learn to use weapons with skill beyond the grasp of others. Choose up to two melee weapons to become ebon armaments, you can use Dexterity for attack and damage rolls while using them, even if it does not have the finesse property.</p>
                <p class="indent">At 10th and 15th level, you can select an additional weapon to become an ebon armament.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Choose up to {{ebon-armaments:count}} melee weapons to become ebon armaments, you can use Dexterity for attack and damage rolls while using them, even if it does not have the finesse property.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="ebon-armaments:count" value="2" level="1" />
                <stat name="ebon-armaments:count" value="1" level="10" />
                <stat name="ebon-armaments:count" value="1" level="15" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Weapon Arts" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_EBON_BLADE_WEAPON_ARTS">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, you gain an additional way to use your ebon armaments. You learn the following weapon arts, and can use them when you wield the appropriate weapon. You can use weapon arts a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier per long rest.</p>
                <ul class="unstyle">
                    <li><b>Blade Swarm.</b> When you miss an attack using an ebon armament when engaging in two-weapon fighting, you can make a second attack as part of the same bonus action.</li>
                    <li><b>Cripple.</b> When you hit with an attack while wielding an ebon armament in one hand and no other weapons, you can attempt to slow an enemy. The target creature must make a Constitution saving throw against your Spell Save DC. On a failure, the target creature’s movement speed is reduced by half until the end of its next turn.</li>
                    <li><b>Reaping Swipe.</b> Before you make an attack with a two-handed ebon armament, you can choose to make it a cleaving attack. Make a single attack roll against a target creature, if the total is greater than or equal to the AC of a second creature within your melee attack range, the second creature takes damage equal to half the damage dealt to the first creature.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="{{charisma:modifier}}/Long Rest">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Blade Swarm" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_EBON_BLADE_WEAPON_ARTS_BLADE_SWARM">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>When you miss an attack using an ebon armament when engaging in two-weapon fighting, you can make a second attack as part of the same bonus action.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Weapon Arts">
                    <description>When you miss an attack using an ebon armament when engaging in two-weapon fighting, you can make a second attack as part of the same bonus action.</description>
                    <description level="15">When you miss an attack using an ebon armament when engaging in two-weapon fighting, you can make a second attack as part of the same bonus action. You have advantage on the second attack.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Cripple" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_EBON_BLADE_WEAPON_ARTS_CRIPPLE">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>When you hit with an attack while wielding an ebon armament in one hand and no other weapons, you can attempt to slow an enemy. The target creature must make a Constitution saving throw against your Spell Save DC. On a failure, the target creature’s movement speed is reduced by half until the end of its next turn.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Weapon Arts">
                    <description>When you hit with an attack while wielding an ebon armament in one hand and no other weapons, you can attempt to slow an enemy. The target creature must make a Constitution saving throw against your Spell Save DC. On a failure, the target creature’s movement speed is reduced by half until the end of its next turn.</description>
                    <description level="15">When you hit with an attack while wielding an ebon armament in one hand and no other weapons, you can attempt to slow an enemy. The target creature must make a Constitution saving throw against your Spell Save DC. On a failure, the target creature is knocked prone.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Reaping Swipe" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_EBON_BLADE_WEAPON_ARTS_REAPING_SWIPE">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>Before you make an attack with a two-handed ebon armament, you can choose to make it a cleaving attack. Make a single attack roll against a target creature, if the total is greater than or equal to the AC of a second creature within your melee attack range, the second creature takes damage equal to half the damage dealt to the first creature.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Weapon Arts">
                    <description>Before you make an attack with a two-handed ebon armament, you can choose to make it a cleaving attack. Make a single attack roll against a target creature, if the total is greater than or equal to the AC of a second and third creature within your melee attack range, the second and third creature takes damage equal to half the damage dealt to the first creature.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
        <element name="Superior Awareness" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_EBON_BLADE_SUPERIOR_AWARENESS">
            <description>
                <p>At 10th level, your training results in a state of pure physical and mental focus, ensuring you do not get surprised. When you make a Dexterity (Acrobatics) check or a Wisdom (Perception) check, your proficiency bonus is doubled.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
			    <stat name="acrobatics:proficiency" value="proficiency" bonus="double" />
			    <stat name="perception:proficiency" value="proficiency" bonus="double" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Improved Weapon Arts" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_EBON_BLADE_IMPROVED_WEAPON_ARTS">
            <description>
                <p>At 15th level, you have improved upon your skills with weapons.</p>
                <ul class="unstyled">
                    <li><b>Improved Blade Swarm.</b> When you use this feature to make a second attack, you gain advantage on the second strike.</li>
                    <li><b>Improved Cripple.</b> When you use this feature, on a failed save, the target creature is knocked prone.</li>
                    <li><b>Improved Reaping Swipe.</b> When you use this feature, you can target a third creature.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Undying Swordsman" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_EBON_BLADE_UNDYING_SWORDSMAN">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 18th level, if you take damage that would reduce you to 0 hit points but does not kill you outright, you can move up to your walking speed and make a single melee weapon attack. If you hit, you regain hit points equal to the damage dealt.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can use this feature once per long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>If you take damage that would reduce you to 0 hit points but does not kill you outright, you can move up to your walking speed and make a single melee weapon attack. If you hit, you regain hit points equal to the damage dealt.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>

    <element name="Order of Magi" type="Archetype" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_DEATH_KNIGHT_ORDER_OF_MAGI">
        <supports>KB Death Knight Knightly Order</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The Umbra Spire, headquarters of the magi located in the Shadowfel, is a place of arcane learning and deadly intrigue. The location within the Shadowfel is ever shifting, and part of one’s initiation is to find it before the natives find you, and of those who do only those of great wit can survive the machinations of the masters and students of the spire.</p>
            <div element="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MAGI_ORDER_KEEPER_OF_SECRETS" />
            <div element="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MAGI_ORDER_EXPANDED_SPELL_LIST" />
            <div element="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MAGI_ORDER_MAGE_ADEPT" />
            <div element="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MAGI_ORDER_INITIATE_NECROMANCER" />
            <div element="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MAGI_ORDER_FORBIDDEN_LORE" />
            <div element="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MAGI_ORDER_ADEPT_NECROMANCER" />
            <div element="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MAGI_ORDER_MASTER_NECROMANCER" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MAGI_ORDER_KEEPER_OF_SECRETS" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MAGI_ORDER_EXPANDED_SPELL_LIST" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MAGI_ORDER_MAGE_ADEPT" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MAGI_ORDER_INITIATE_NECROMANCER" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MAGI_ORDER_FORBIDDEN_LORE" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MAGI_ORDER_ADEPT_NECROMANCER" level="15" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MAGI_ORDER_MASTER_NECROMANCER" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Keeper of Secrets" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MAGI_ORDER_KEEPER_OF_SECRETS">
            <description>
                <p>At 1st level, as a result of your training, hiding the truth has become second nature. You can give yourself advantage on Charisma (Deception) checks a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier per long rest. You regain all uses of this feature at the end of a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="{{charisma:modifier}}/Long Rest">
                <description>You can give yourself advantage on Deception checks.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Expanded Spell list" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MAGI_ORDER_EXPANDED_SPELL_LIST">
            <description>
                <p>You learn additional spells when you reach certain levels in this class, as shown in the Magi Spells table. The spell counts as a death knight spell for you, but it doesn’t count against the number of death knight spells you know.</p>
                <h5 class="caption">MAGI SPELLS</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Death Knight Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>2nd</td><td><em>false life, ray of sickness</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>blindness/deafness, ray of enfeeblement</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><em>life transference, vampiric touch</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>13th</td><td><em>blight, shadow of Moil</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>17th</td><td><em>danse macabre, negative energy flood</em></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FALSE_LIFE" spellcasting="Death Knight" known="true" level="2" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RAY_OF_SICKNESS" spellcasting="Death Knight" known="true" level="2" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLINDNESS_DEAFNESS" spellcasting="Death Knight" known="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RAY_OF_ENFEEBLEMENT" spellcasting="Death Knight" known="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_LIFE_TRANSFERENCE" spellcasting="Death Knight" known="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_VAMPIRIC_TOUCH" spellcasting="Death Knight" known="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLIGHT" spellcasting="Death Knight" known="true" level="13" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_SHADOW_OF_MOIL" spellcasting="Death Knight" known="true" level="13" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_DANSE_MACABRE" spellcasting="Death Knight" known="true" level="17" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_NEGATIVE_ENERGY_FLOOD" spellcasting="Death Knight" known="true" level="17" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Mage Adept" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MAGI_ORDER_MAGE_ADEPT">
            <description>
                <p>When you choose this order at 1st level, you can learn cantrips from the Magi Spell list. At 1st level, you choose two cantrips. At 10th level you can learn one additional cantrip.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, you can cast the spell <i>find familiar</i> as a ritual, but you can only use it to create a crawling claw. This spell does not count toward your spells known.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can cast the spell find familiar as a ritual, but you can only use it to create a crawling claw.</description>
            </sheet>
            <spellcasting name="Death Knight" extend="true">
                <extend>ID_SCAG_SPELL_BOOMING_BLADE</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_CHILL_TOUCH</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_DANCING_LIGHTS</extend>
                <extend>ID_SCAG_SPELL_GREEN_FLAME_BLADE</extend>
                <extend>ID_SCAG_SPELL_LIGHTNING_LURE</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_POISON_SPRAY</extend>
                <extend>ID_SCAG_SPELL_SWORD_BURST</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_SPARE_THE_DYING</extend>
                <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_THAUMATURGY</extend>
                <extend>ID_XGTE_SPELL_TOLL_THE_DEAD</extend>
            </spellcasting>
            <rules>
                <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Death Knight)" spellcasting="Death Knight" supports="$(spellcasting:list),0" number="2" known="true" level="1" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Death Knight)" spellcasting="Death Knight" supports="$(spellcasting:list),0" known="true" level="10" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIND_FAMILIAR" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Initiate Necromancer" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MAGI_ORDER_INITIATE_NECROMANCER">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, once per long rest, you can cast the spell <i>animate dead</i> at 3rd level without expending a spell slot.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, undead you control use your proficiency bonus.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You can cast the spell animate dead at 3rd level without expending a spell slot. Additionally, undead you control use your proficiency bonus.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANIMATE_DEAD" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Forbidden Lore" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MAGI_ORDER_FORBIDDEN_LORE">
            <description>
                <p>At 10th level, you have unlocked many secrets of the multiverse. When you make an Intelligence (Arcana) check or an Intelligence (Religion) check, your proficiency bonus is doubled.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
			    <stat name="arcana:proficiency" value="proficiency" bonus="double" />
			    <stat name="religion:proficiency" value="proficiency" bonus="double" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Adept Necromancer" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MAGI_ORDER_ADEPT_NECROMANCER">
            <description>
                <p>At 15th level, undead you create gain the following benefits:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Your undead minions are created with temporary hit points equal to your death knight level.</li>
                    <li>Your undead minions weapon attacks score a critical hit on a roll of 19 or 20.</li>
                    <li>Your undead minions weapon attacks deal additional necrotic damage equal to your proficiency bonus.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Undead you create gain the following benefits: {{level:death knight}} temporary hit points; their weapon attacks score a critical hit on a 19 or 20; their weapon attacks deal +{{proficiency}} necrotic damage.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Master Necromancer" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MAGI_ORDER_MASTER_NECROMANCER">
            <description>
                <p>At 18th level, once per long rest, you can cast create undead at 6th level without expending a spell slot.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You can cast create undead at 6th level without expending a spell slot</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CREATE_UNDEAD" />
            </rules>
        </element>

    <element name="Rune Warden" type="Archetype" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_DEATH_KNIGHT_RUNE_WARDEN">
        <supports>KB Death Knight Knightly Order</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Rune Wardens learn their arts deep within the Feywild. There they learn to empower not just their weapons, but their body. They tattoo runes and artistic ley lines upon themselves to attune their bodies to runic energy more thoroughly than the members of any other order.</p>
            <div element="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RUNE_WARDEN_RUNE_FORGED" />
            <div element="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RUNE_WARDEN_RUNE_GIVER" />
            <div element="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RUNE_WARDEN_IMPROVED_RUNE_WEAPON" />
            <div element="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RUNE_WARDEN_RUNE_LORE" />
            <div element="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RUNE_WARDEN_IMPROVED_RUNE_SCRIBE" />
            <div element="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RUNE_WARDEN_GREATER_RUNE_GIVER" />
            <div element="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RUNE_WARDEN_RUNIC_RECHARGE" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RUNE_WARDEN_RUNE_FORGED" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RUNE_WARDEN_RUNE_GIVER" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RUNE_WARDEN_IMPROVED_RUNE_WEAPON" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RUNE_WARDEN_RUNE_LORE" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RUNE_WARDEN_IMPROVED_RUNE_SCRIBE" level="15" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RUNE_WARDEN_GREATER_RUNE_GIVER" level="15" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RUNE_WARDEN_RUNIC_RECHARGE" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Rune Forged" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RUNE_WARDEN_RUNE_FORGED">
            <description>
                <p>As a rune warden, you have undergone a ritualistic tattooing that has permanently altered your body, and you can choose one rune from the list of runes to be tattooed upon your back. This rune does not count against your number of inscribed runes, but it can only be changed when you gain a level in the death knight class.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Death Knight Rune, Rune Forged" supports="KB Death Knight Rune" allowReplace="true" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Rune Giver" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RUNE_WARDEN_RUNE_GIVER">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, you learn to temporarily grant an ally a rune. During a long rest, you can spend 2 hours to rune scribe an ally’s weapon. Choose a rune from the death knight rune list that does not have a level or subclass prerequisite to scribe onto an ally’s weapon. If the rune normally has more than one use, it only has one use when inscribed this way, and it only lasts until the end of the next long rest.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can only use this feature once per long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>During a long rest, you can spend 2 hours to rune scribe an ally’s weapon. Choose a rune from the death knight rune list that does not have a level or subclass prerequisite to scribe onto an ally’s weapon. If the rune normally has more than one use, it only has one use when inscribed this way, and it only lasts until the end of the next long rest.</description>
                <description level="15">During a long rest, you can spend 2 hours to rune scribe you allies’ weapons. You can give up to two runes to one ally or one rune to two allies. Choose a rune from the death knight rune list that does not have a level or subclass prerequisite to scribe onto an ally’s weapon. If the rune normally has more than one use, it only has one use when inscribed this way, and it only lasts until the end of the next long rest.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Improved Rune Weapon" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RUNE_WARDEN_IMPROVED_RUNE_WEAPON">
            <description>
                <p>By 10th level, you can use a bonus action to will your rune weapons to give off bright light for 20 feet and dim light for another 20 feet. Objects and creatures within the bright light are seen as if under the effects of <i>detect magic</i>. You can dismiss the light at will. If your rune weapon leaves your hand, it will cease to give off the light.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>You can will your rune weapons to give off bright light for 20 feet and dim light for another 20 feet. Objects and creatures within the bright light are seen as if under the effects of detect magic.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Rune Lore" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RUNE_WARDEN_RUNE_LORE">
            <description>
                <p>At 10th level, your study of runes has resulted in anexpanded knowledge of ancient civilizations. When you make an Intelligence (History) check, your proficiency bonus is doubled.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
			    <stat name="history:proficiency" value="proficiency" bonus="double" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Improved Rune Scribe" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RUNE_WARDEN_IMPROVED_RUNE_SCRIBE">
            <description>
                <p>By 15th level, you have learned to half the time it takes to rune scribe, including the time it takes for your rune giver feature.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>It takes you half the time to inscribe any rune.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Greater Rune Giver" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RUNE_WARDEN_GREATER_RUNE_GIVER">
            <description>
                <p>At 15th level, when you use your rune giver feature, you can give up to two runes to one ally or one rune to two allies.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description>When you use your rune giver feature, you can give up to two runes to one ally or one rune to two allies.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Runic Recharge" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RUNE_WARDEN_RUNIC_RECHARGE">
            <description>
                <p>At 18th level, you can use an action to recharge a single use of a rune that you have expended.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can do so once per long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You can recharge a single use of a rune that you have expended.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>

    <element name="Order of Fallen Paladins" type="Archetype" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_DEATH_KNIGHT_ORDER_OF_FALLEN_PALADINS">
        <supports>KB Death Knight Knightly Order</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The order of the fallen paladins is unique among the knightly orders. It is the only one whose members have no patron, and it cannot be chosen, rather one dies into it. Oath Breakers that have committed atrocities of the highest order resurrect as one of these. Only upon finding atonement and redemption can they find rest.</p>
            <h5>RESTRICTION: EVIL ALIGNMENT ONLY</h5>
            <p>This subclass is designed to be a template for antagonists, similar to the Oathbreaker (DMG page 97). As such, it is imbalanced for player characters, and it will need tweaking for that purpose. Speak with your DM about this before making a character using this subclass.</p>
            <div element="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FALLEN_PALADIN_WITHERING_TOUCH" />
            <div element="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FALLEN_PALADIN_AURA_OF_DESOLATION" />
            <div element="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FALLEN_PALADIN_AURA_OF_TERROR" />
            <div element="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FALLEN_PALADIN_SCHADENFREUDE" />
            <div element="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FALLEN_PALADIN_GREATER_AURAS" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FALLEN_PALADIN_WITHERING_TOUCH" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FALLEN_PALADIN_AURA_OF_DESOLATION" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FALLEN_PALADIN_AURA_OF_TERROR" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FALLEN_PALADIN_SCHADENFREUDE" level="15" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FALLEN_PALADIN_GREATER_AURAS" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Withering Touch" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FALLEN_PALADIN_WITHERING_TOUCH">
            <description>
                <p>As a fallen paladin, you are unable to heal, instead your hands take life. You have a pool of necrotic energy that replenishes when you take a long rest. With that pool, you can deal necrotic damage to a target creature’s equal to your death knight level × 5.</p>
                <p class="indent">As an action, you can make a melee weapon attack. On a hit you can deal necrotic damage to that creature, up to the maximum amount remaining in your pool.</p>
                <p class="indent">If you kill a creature with this feature, you gain temporary hit points equal to either half of the damage dealt (rounded down, minimum of 1) or half of the creature’s maximum hit points (rounded down, minimum of 1), whichever is less.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="{{withering-touch:hp-pool}}/Long Rest" action="Action">
                <description>You can make a melee weapon attack. On a hit you can deal necrotic damage to that creature, up to the maximum amount remaining in your pool. If you kill a creature with this feature, you gain temporary hit points equal to either half of the damage dealt (rounded down, minimum of 1) or half of the creature’s maximum hit points (rounded down, minimum of 1), whichever is less.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="withering-touch:hp-pool" value="level:death knight" />
                <stat name="withering-touch:hp-pool" value="level:death knight" />
                <stat name="withering-touch:hp-pool" value="level:death knight" />
                <stat name="withering-touch:hp-pool" value="level:death knight" />
                <stat name="withering-touch:hp-pool" value="level:death knight" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Aura of Desolation" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FALLEN_PALADIN_AURA_OF_DESOLATION">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, death oozes from your very being, drawing life from those around you. Creatures you choose that enter for the first time or start their turn within 10 feet of you, lose a number of hit points equal to your Charisma modifier.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Creatures you choose that enter for the first time or start their turn within 10 feet of you, lose {{aura-of-desolation:hp-damage}} hit points.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="aura-of-desolation:hp-damage" value="charisma:modifier" level="6" />
                <stat name="aura-of-desolation:hp-damage" value="charisma:modifier" level="18" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Aura of Terror" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FALLEN_PALADIN_AURA_OF_TERROR">
            <description>
                <p>At 10th level, your presence insights fear in your foes. Creatures you choose that enter or start their turn within 10 feet of you must make a Wisdom saving throw against your death knight spell save, or they become frightened of you for 1 minute.</p>
                <p class="indent">The creature can repeat this save at the end of each of their turns. Once a creature succeeds, it becomes immune to this effect for 24 hours.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Creatures you choose that enter or start their turn within 10 feet of you must make a Wisdom saving throw (DC {{spellcasting:dc:cha}}), or they become frightened of you for 1 minute.</description>
                <description level="18">Creatures you choose that enter or start their turn within 10 feet of you must make a Wisdom saving throw (DC {{spellcasting:dc:cha}}), or they become frightened of you for 1 minute. Creatures that are immune to the frightened condition can be frightened by your aura, but they make the saving throw with advantage. Creatures not immune to being frightened have disadvantage on the initial saving throw; if they are frightened, the subsequent saves are made without disadvantage.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Schadenfreude" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FALLEN_PALADIN_SCHADENFREUDE">
            <description>
                <p>At 15th level, you learn to transfer the effects of spells from your self to another. As an action, you can end one spell on yourself. You can then use a reaction to cause another creature within 30 feet to be affected by the spell instead.</p>
                <p class="indent">The creature can make a Wisdom saving throw, or the effect is transferred to them. A creature can choose to not make the save and automatically receive the effects of the spell.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>You can end one spell on yourself. You can then use a reaction to cause another creature within 30 feet to be affected by the spell instead. The creature can make a Wisdom saving throw (DC {{spellcasting:dc:cha}}), or the effect is transferred to them. A creature can choose to not make the save and automatically receive the effects of the spell.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Greater Auras" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FALLEN_PALADIN_GREATER_AURAS">
            <description>
                <p>At 18th level, instead of expanding the effects of your auras, you concentrate them into the same area for greater effect:</p>
                <ul class="unstyled">
                    <li><b>Greater Aura of Desolation.</b> The amount of hit points lost is now equal to twice your Charisma modifier.</li>
                    <li><b>Greater Aura of Terror.</b> Your aura is so suffocating that it causes even the most stalwart beings to feel fear. Creatures that are immune to the frightened condition can be frightened by your aura, but they make the saving throw with advantage. Creatures not immune to being frightened have disadvantage on the initial saving throw; if they are frightened, the subsequent saves are made without disadvantage.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>


  <!-- Death Knight Skills -->
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ARCANA">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ATHLETICS">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ANIMALHANDLING">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_DECEPTION">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INTIMIDATION">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERSUASION">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SURVIVAL">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>

  <!-- Fighting Styles -->
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_DEFENSE">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_DUELING">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_GREAT_WEAPON_FIGHTING">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_TWOWEAPON_FIGHTING">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_MARINER">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_RSQUARED_BLACKGUARD_CLASS_FEATURE_BLACKGUARD_FIGHTINGSTYLE_REPRISAL">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_VDP_VARIANT_FIGHTER_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTING_STYLE_MANEUVERS_RANGER_PALADIN">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_DEVIKYN_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTING_STYLE_DUAL_WIELDING">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_DEVIKYN_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTING_STYLE_SWITCH_FIGHTING">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_THEARENAGUY_RDDTUA_CLASS_FEATURE_SHIELD_BASHING">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTING_STYLE_BLIND_FIGHTING">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTING_STYLE_SUPERIOR_TECHNIQUE">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>

    <element name="Rune Weapon Focus" type="Spellcasting Focus Group" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_SPELLFOCUS_GROUP_SPIRITUAL_FOCUS">
        <description>
            <p>As a death knight, you use your rune weapon as a spellcasting focus for your spells..</p>
        </description>
    </element>
    <element name="Spellcasting Focus Group (Rune Weapon Focus)" type="Proficiency" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_INTERNAL_PROFICIENCY_SPELLFOCUS_GROUP_RUNE_WEAPON_FOCUS">
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>

  <!-- Background Features -->
    <element name="Feature: Patron" type="Background Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_PATRON">
        <description>
            <p>Each death knight has a patron; they determine the goals and targets for their death knight.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet alt="Patron">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="list" name="Patron">
                <item id="1">Fiend</item>
                <item id="2">Fey</item>
                <item id="3">Celestial</item>
                <item id="4">Great Old One</item>
                <item id="5">Deity</item>
                <item id="6">Dragon</item>
            </select>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Feature: Manner of Death, Circumstances of Resurrection" type="Background Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_MANNER_OF_DEATH">
        <description>
            <p>The variety of ways beings can die is staggering. Each one unique in time and circumstance, and it can cause their return to life to be complicated. This can be as simple as getting used to a new era, or as complicated as dealing with the consequences of your previous lifetime.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet alt="Manner of Death, Circumstances of Resurrection">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="list" name="Manner of Death, Circumstances of Resurrection">
                <item id="1">You were executed as a traitor to your country, and you were returned to life to save it, though they could very well kill you again.</item>
                <item id="2">Once a war hero who died in battle, you have returned after more than a century and feel out of place.</item>
                <item id="3">You made a bargain to become a death knight and chose to drift into servitude with a cup of nightshade tea. You awaken moments later filled with new power.</item>
                <item id="4">You were murdered by a corrupt lord, and your patron granted you the ability to seek justice.</item>
                <item id="5">You were a paladin in life, but were returned to serve your archnemesis. You cannot refuse, but you seek to take them down.</item>
                <item id="6">You were a criminal brought to the noose. Now, you are a criminal with powers from beyond the grave. You shall have your vengeance.</item>
            </select>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Feature: Rival" type="Background Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_RIVAL">
        <description>
            <p>Death knights rarely live long without creating enemies. It is part of the job, but some become more than an enemy. They may be a thorn in your side or perhaps a tool to measure your own growth.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet alt="Rival">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="list" name="Rival">
                <item id="1">A paladin who feels they must constantly try to thwart you.</item>
                <item id="2">A fellow death knight serving your patron’s arch nemesis. You will never have peace as long as they draw breath.</item>
                <item id="3">A noble escaped you and is constantly sending assassins to kill you while they hide.</item>
                <item id="4">A warrior of unmatched skill bested you. You now seek to surpass him, not to kill them, but to prove to them and yourself that you are the better fighter.</item>
                <item id="5">A mage, who aided in your demise so your patron could have you, reminds you of their power at every opportunity.</item>
                <item id="6">An assassin who intentionally tries to kill your targets before you, and they do so just to get on your nerves.</item>
            </select>
        </rules>
    </element>

  <!-- Death Knight Spells -->
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ARMOR_OF_AGATHYS">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ARMS_OF_HADAR">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BANE">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_CAUSE_FEAR">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMMAND">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMPELLED_DUEL">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_EVIL_AND_GOOD">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISSONANT_WHISPERS">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FALSE_LIFE">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HEROISM">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RAY_OF_SICKNESS">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SEARING_SMITE">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_THUNDEROUS_SMITE">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WRATHFUL_SMITE">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CROWN_OF_MADNESS">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DARKNESS">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENTHRALL">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GENTLE_REPOSE">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HOLD_PERSON">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGIC_WEAPON">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_MIND_SPIKE">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PHANTASMAL_FORCE">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PROTECTION_FROM_POISON">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RAY_OF_ENFEEBLEMENT">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHATTER">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BESTOW_CURSE">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ELEMENTAL_WEAPON">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ENEMIES_ABOUND">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FEAR">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FEIGN_DEATH">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HUNGER_OF_HADAR">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_LIFE_TRANSFERENCE">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_REMOVE_CURSE">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_REVIVIFY">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_DEAD">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WATER_WALK">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLIGHT">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONFUSION">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DEATH_WARD">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FREEDOM_OF_MOVEMENT">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_SHADOW_OF_MOIL">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_SICKENING_RADIANCE">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_STAGGERING_SMITE">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BANISHING_SMITE">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONTAGION">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GEAS">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HOLD_MONSTER">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INSECT_PLAGUE">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_NEGATIVE_ENERGY_FLOOD">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RAISE_DEAD">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_STEEL_WIND_STRIKE">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
    </append>

  <!-- Rune Class Features -->
    <element name="Rune of the Arcanist" type="Class Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DK_RUNE_OF_THE_ARCANIST">
        <supports>KB Death Knight Rune</supports>
        <requirements>ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_DEATH_KNIGHT_ORDER_OF_MAGI</requirements>
        <prerequisite>Order of Magi</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Order of Magi</p>
            <p>You can add your Charisma modifier to the damage you deal with any magi cantrip, and you can learn one additional magi cantrip.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can add {{charisma:modifier}} to the damage you deal with any magi cantrip.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Death Knight)" spellcasting="Death Knight" supports="$(spellcasting:list),0" known="true" level="10" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Rune of the Clouds" type="Class Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DK_RUNE_OF_THE_CLOUDS">
        <supports>KB Death Knight Rune</supports>
        <description>
            <p>This rune allows you to draw a shrouding mist around yourself. As an action, you create a 10ft radius circle of fog centered on yourself that follows you. The area around you is treated as heavily obscured, but you can see through it. The fog lasts for 1 minute, or until you dismiss it as a bonus action.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can use this feature once per short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Short Rest" action="Action">
            <description>You create a 10ft radius circle of fog centered on yourself that follows you. The area around you is treated as heavily obscured, but you can see through it. The fog lasts for 1 minute, or until you dismiss it as a bonus action.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Rune of the Crusader" type="Class Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DK_RUNE_OF_THE_CRUSADER">
        <supports>KB Death Knight Rune</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You can use the necrotic energy of your runes to heal yourself. When you hit with a rune weapon while necrotic strike is active, you can roll a number of hit dice equal to your Charisma modifier and heal for the total rolled.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can only use this rune once per short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
            <description>When you hit with a rune weapon while necrotic strike is active, you can roll {{charisma:modifier}} hit dice and heal for the total rolled.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Rune of the Death Ward" type="Class Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DK_RUNE_OF_THE_DEATH_WARD">
        <supports>KB Death Knight Rune</supports>
        <requirements>[level:death knight:13]</requirements>
        <prerequisite>13th level</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 13th level</p>
            <p>When you take damage that would reduce you to 0 hit points, you instead drop to 1 hit point.</p>
            <p class="indent">This rune can only be activated once per long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>When you take damage that would reduce you to 0 hit points, you instead drop to 1 hit point.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Rune of Defense" type="Class Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DK_RUNE_OF_DEFENSE">
        <supports>KB Death Knight Rune</supports>
        <requirements>[level:death knight:13]</requirements>
        <prerequisite>13th level</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 13th level</p>
            <p>Whenever you must make a saving throw, you gain a bonus to the saving throw equal to your Charisma modifier (with a minimum bonus of +1).</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Whenever you must make a saving throw, you gain a +{{rune-of-defense:save-bonus}} bonus to the saving throw.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="rune-of-defense:save-bonus" value="1" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="rune-of-defense:save-bonus" value="charisma:modifier" bonus="base" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Rune of the Frozen Grasp" type="Class Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DK_RUNE_OF_THE_FROZEN_GRASP">
        <supports>KB Death Knight Rune</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Once on each of your turns, when you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack, you can reduce that creature’s speed by 10 feet until the end of your next turn.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Once on each of your turns, when you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack, you can reduce that creature’s speed by 10 feet until the end of your next turn.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Rune of the Gargoyle" type="Class Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DK_RUNE_OF_THE_GARGOYLE">
        <supports>KB Death Knight Rune</supports>
        <requirements>ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_DEATH_KNIGHT_ORDER_OF_DESTROYERS</requirements>
        <prerequisite>Order of Destroyers</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Order of Destroyers</p>
            <p>When you take damage, you can use your reaction to roll a d12. Add your Constitution modifier to the number rolled, and reduce the damage by that total.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can use this rune once per short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Short Rest" action="Reaction">
            <description>When you take damage, you can roll a d12 + {{constitution:modifier}}. Reduce the damage by that total.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Rune of Hellfire" type="Class Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DK_RUNE_OF_HELLFIRE">
        <supports>KB Death Knight Rune</supports>
        <requirements>[level:death knight:17]</requirements>
        <prerequisite>17th level</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 17th level</p>
            <p>This rune allows you to hurl a magical ball of fire fueled with energies derived from your rune weapon.</p>
            <p class="indent">As an action, you choose a point you can see within 120 feet. Each creature in a 20-foot-radius sphere centered on that point must make a Dexterity saving throw. The sphere spreads around corners. A creature takes 6d6 fire damage and 6d6 necrotic damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can use this rune once per long rest</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>you choose a point you can see within 120 feet. Each creature in a 20-foot-radius sphere centered on that point must make a Dexterity saving throw. The sphere spreads around corners. A creature takes 6d6 fire damage and 6d6 necrotic damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Rune of the Inquisitor" type="Class Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DK_RUNE_OF_THE_INQUISITOR">
        <supports>KB Death Knight Rune</supports>
        <requirements>ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_DEATH_KNIGHT_RUNE_WARDEN, [level:death knight:9]</requirements>
        <prerequisite>Order of Rune Wardens, 9th level</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Order of Rune Wardens, 9th level</p>
            <p>This rune allows you to gain insights into what you see. As an action, you can cast <i>identify</i>. You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Charisma Modifier.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Action" usage="{{charisma:modifier}}/Long Rest">
            <description>You can cast identify.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Rune of the Legendary Mount" type="Class Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DK_RUNE_OF_THE_LEGENDARY_MOUNT">
        <supports>KB Death Knight Rune</supports>
        <requirements>ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_DEATH_KNIGHT_ORDER_OF_CAVALIERS, [level:death knight:13]</requirements>
        <prerequisite>Order of Cavaliers, 13th level</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Order of Cavaliers, 13th level</p>
            <p>This rune grants any creature created using your bound mount feature resistance to all damage, and when it deals damage, you can add your proficiency bonus to the damage dealt.</p>
            <p class="indent">The additional damage is of the same type as the mount’s attack, if the attack deals more than one type of damage, the damage bonus is applied to only one type. You choose which type.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>This rune grants any creature created using your bound mount feature resistance to all damage, and when it deals damage, you can add your proficiency bonus to the damage dealt.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Rune of Lethality" type="Class Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DK_RUNE_OF_LETHALITY">
        <supports>KB Death Knight Rune</supports>
        <requirements>[level:death knight:17]</requirements>
        <prerequisite>17th level</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 17th level</p>
            <p>This rune lets you cause your enemies to whither under the effects of necrotic energy. You can use your reaction to cause a target creature to become vulnerable to a single instance of necrotic damage.</p>
            <p class="indent">This rune can only be used once per short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Short Rest" action="Reaction">
            <description>You can use your reaction to cause a target creature to become vulnerable to a single instance of necrotic damage.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Rune of the Lightning Mount" type="Class Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DK_RUNE_OF_THE_LIGHTNING_MOUNT">
        <supports>KB Death Knight Rune</supports>
        <requirements>ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_DEATH_KNIGHT_ORDER_OF_CAVALIERS, [level:death knight:9]</requirements>
        <prerequisite>Order of Cavaliers, 9th level</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Order of Cavaliers, 9th level</p>
            <p>While mounted, you can use your action to cast <i>haste</i> on yourself and your mount without expending a spell slot.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can use this rune once per long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest" action="Action">
            <description>You can cast haste on yourself and your mount without expending a spell slot.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Rune of Necrosis" type="Class Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DK_RUNE_OF_NECROSIS">
        <supports>KB Death Knight Rune</supports>
        <requirements>ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_DEATH_KNIGHT_RUNE_WARDEN, [level:death knight:13]</requirements>
        <prerequisite>Order of Rune Wardens, 13th level</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Order of Rune Wardens, 13th level</p>
            <p>This rune imbues your weapon with more necrotic energy. You gain 1 additional use of your Necrotic Strike feature per long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="necrotic-strike:uses" value="1" level="13" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Rune of Necrotic Strike Mastery" type="Class Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DK_RUNE_OF_NECROTIC_STRIKE_MASTERY">
        <supports>KB Death Knight Rune</supports>
        <description>
            <p>When you use necrotic strike, and you roll a 1 or 2 for necrotic damage, you can reroll the dice once and take the second roll.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you use necrotic strike, and you roll a 1 or 2 for necrotic damage, you can reroll the dice once and take the second roll.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Rune of Retribution" type="Class Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DK_RUNE_OF_RETRIBUTION">
        <supports>KB Death Knight Rune</supports>
        <description>
            <p>While this rune is inscribed, when you take damage from a creature within 60 feet of you, you can use your reaction to deal 3d10 necrotic damage to the creature that damaged you.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can use this rune a number of times equal to a third of your death knight level (rounded down) per long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Reaction" usage="{{rune-of-retribution:uses}}/Long Rest">
            <description>While this rune is inscribed, when you take damage from a creature within 60 feet of you, you can use your reaction to deal 3d10 necrotic damage to the creature that damaged you.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="rune-of-retribution:uses" value="1" level="1" />
            <stat name="rune-of-retribution:uses" value="1" level="6" />
            <stat name="rune-of-retribution:uses" value="1" level="9" />
            <stat name="rune-of-retribution:uses" value="1" level="12" />
            <stat name="rune-of-retribution:uses" value="1" level="15" />
            <stat name="rune-of-retribution:uses" value="1" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Rune of the Owl" type="Class Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DK_RUNE_OF_THE_OWL">
        <supports>KB Death Knight Rune</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You gain darkvision and can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can’t discern color in darkness, only shades of gray. If you already have darkvision, then your darkvision intervals increase by 60 feet.</p>
            <p class="indent">You also have advantage on Stealth checks while in darkness.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You have advantage on Stealth checks while in darkness.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_DARKVISION_OR_INCREASE_60" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Rune of Parrying" type="Class Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DK_RUNE_OF_PARRYING">
        <supports>KB Death Knight Rune</supports>
        <requirements>ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_DEATH_KNIGHT_ORDER_OF_EBON_BLADES</requirements>
        <prerequisite>Order of Ebon Blades</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Order of Ebon Blades</p>
            <p>You can add your proficiency bonus to your AC against one melee attack that would hit you. To do so, you must see the attacker and be wielding a melee weapon.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can add your proficiency bonus to your AC against one melee attack that would hit you. To do so, you must see the attacker and be wielding a melee weapon.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Rune of Skill" type="Class Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DK_RUNE_OF_SKILL">
        <supports>KB Death Knight Rune</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You can use this rune to add your proficiency bonus to a skill you do not have proficiency in. This feature can be used before or after the roll, but it must be used before you know if it succeeds or fails.</p>
            <p class="indent">This rune can only be used a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier per long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="{{charisma:modifier}}/Long Rest">
            <description>You can use this rune to add your proficiency bonus to a skill you do not have proficiency in. This feature can be used before or after the roll, but it must be used before you know if it succeeds or fails.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Rune of the Slayer" type="Class Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DK_RUNE_OF_THE_SLAYER">
        <supports>KB Death Knight Rune</supports>
        <requirements>ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_DEATH_KNIGHT_ORDER_OF_DESTROYERS, [level:death knight:13]</requirements>
        <prerequisite>Order of Destroyers or Ebon Blades, 13th level</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Order of Destroyers or Ebon Blades, 13th level</p>
            <p>This rune lets you channel the death of an opponent into a surge of adrenaline. Once per turn, when you reduce an enemy creature to 0 hit points or score a critical hit, you can make an additional attack as part of that attack action.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Once per turn, when you reduce an enemy creature to 0 hit points or score a critical hit, you can make an additional attack as part of that attack action.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Rune of Spellbinding" type="Class Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DK_RUNE_OF_SPELLBINDING">
        <supports>KB Death Knight Rune</supports>
        <requirements>ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_DEATH_KNIGHT_ORDER_OF_MAGI, [level:death knight:13]</requirements>
        <prerequisite>Order of Magi, 13th level</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Order of Magi, 13th level</p>
            <p>This rune channels additional magical energy that can be used to fuel your powers. You gain 1 additional spell slot equal to the level of your other death knight spell slots.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="death knight:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="13" />
            <stat name="death knight:spellcasting:slots:4" value="-1" level="17" />
            <stat name="death knight:spellcasting:slots:5" value="1" level="17" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Rune of Spellbreaking" type="Class Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DK_RUNE_OF_SPELLBREAKING">
        <supports>KB Death Knight Rune</supports>
        <requirements>[level:death knight:9]</requirements>
        <prerequisite>9th level</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 9th level</p>
            <p>You can use this rune to attempt to disrupt a spell. As a reaction to a creature within 30 feet of you casting a spell, you can cast counterspell without expending a spell slot, but regardless of the spell’s level, you must make an ability check using your spellcasting ability. The DC equals 10 + the spell’s level. On a success, the creature’s spell fails and has no effect.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can use this rune twice per long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="2/Long Rest" action="Reaction">
            <description>As a reaction to a creature within 30 feet of you casting a spell, you can cast counterspell without expending a spell slot, but regardless of the spell’s level, you must make an ability check using your spellcasting ability. The DC equals 10 + the spell’s level. On a success, the creature’s spell fails and has no effect.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Rune of Spellstriking" type="Class Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DK_RUNE_OF_SPELLSTRIKING">
        <supports>KB Death Knight Rune</supports>
        <requirements>ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_DEATH_KNIGHT_ORDER_OF_MAGI, [level:death knight:9]</requirements>
        <prerequisite>Order of Magi, 9th level</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Order of Magi, 9th level</p>
            <p>When you cast a spell, you can use a bonus action to make a spell attack with advantage, or you can impose disadvantage on the saving throw of a single creature affected by that spell.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can use this rune a number of times equal to a quarter of your death knight level (rounded down) per long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="{{rune-of-spellstriking:uses}}/Long Rest">
            <description>When you cast a spell, you can use a bonus action to make a spell attack with advantage, or you can impose disadvantage on the saving throw of a single creature affected by that spell.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="rune-of-spellstriking:uses" value="2" level="8" />
            <stat name="rune-of-spellstriking:uses" value="1" level="12" />
            <stat name="rune-of-spellstriking:uses" value="1" level="16" />
            <stat name="rune-of-spellstriking:uses" value="1" level="20" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Rune of the Summoner" type="Class Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DK_RUNE_OF_THE_SUMMONER">
        <supports>KB Death Knight Rune</supports>
        <requirements>ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_DEATH_KNIGHT_ORDER_OF_CAVALIERS</requirements>
        <prerequisite>Order of Cavaliers</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Order of Cavaliers</p>
            <p>You can use this rune to instantly bring your Bound Mount to your location. You can decide whether it appears next to you, or if it appears under you, allowing you to become instantly mounted.</p>
            <p class="indent">If there is not enough room for your mount, the summoning fails and your mount takes 4d6 force damage.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can use this rune once per short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
            <description>You can use this rune to instantly bring your Bound Mount to your location. You can decide whether it appears next to you, or if it appears under you, allowing you to become instantly mounted. If there is not enough room for your mount, the summoning fails and your mount takes 4d6 force damage.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Rune of the True Warden" type="Class Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DK_RUNE_OF_THE_TRUE_WARDEN">
        <supports>KB Death Knight Rune</supports>
        <requirements>ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_DEATH_KNIGHT_RUNE_WARDEN</requirements>
        <prerequisite>Order of Rune Wardens</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Order of Rune Wardens</p>
            <p>This rune activates the leylines in your body to create a matrix of defensive energies around you. While you are not wearing any armor, your armor class equals 10 + your Dexterity modifier + your Charisma modifier. You can use a shield and still gain this benefit.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>While you are not wearing any armor, your armor class equals {{ac:unarmored defense rune}}. You can use a shield and still gain this benefit.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
			<stat name="ac:unarmored defense rune:base" value="10" />
			<stat name="ac:unarmored defense rune:dexterity" value="dexterity:modifier" />
			<stat name="ac:unarmored defense rune:charisma" value="charisma:modifier" />
			<stat name="ac:unarmored defense rune" value="ac:unarmored defense rune:base" />
			<stat name="ac:unarmored defense rune" value="ac:unarmored defense rune:dexterity" />
			<stat name="ac:unarmored defense rune" value="ac:unarmored defense rune:charisma" />
			<stat name="ac:calculation" value="ac:unarmored defense rune" bonus="calculation" equipped="[armor:none]" alt="Unarmored Defense (Rune Warden)" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Rune of Unbridled Savagery" type="Class Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DK_RUNE_OF_UNBRIDLED_SAVAGERY">
        <supports>KB Death Knight Rune</supports>
        <requirements>ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_DEATH_KNIGHT_ORDER_OF_DESTROYERS, [level:death knight:9]</requirements>
        <prerequisite>Order of Destroyers, 9th level</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Order of Destroyers, 9th level</p>
            <p>You regain all uses of your savage techniques on a short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You regain all uses of your savage techniques on a short or long rest.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Rune of the Weapon Master" type="Class Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DK_RUNE_OF_THE_WEAPON_MASTER">
        <supports>KB Death Knight Rune</supports>
        <requirements>ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_DEATH_KNIGHT_ORDER_OF_EBON_BLADES, [level:death knight:9]</requirements>
        <prerequisite>Order of Ebon Blades, 9th level</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Order of Ebon Blades, 9th level</p>
            <p>You regain all uses of your weapon arts on a short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You regain all uses of your weapon arts on a short or long rest.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Rune of Lingering Protection" type="Class Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DK_RUNE_OF_LINGERING_PROTECTION">
        <supports>KB Death Knight Rune</supports>
        <requirements>ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_DEATH_KNIGHT_ORDER_OF_FALLEN_PALADINS</requirements>
        <prerequisite>Order of the Fallen Paladins</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Order of the Fallen Paladins</p>
            <p>While this rune is active, you have immunity to disease, the frightened condition, and you have advantage against charm effects.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>While this rune is active, you have immunity to disease, the frightened condition, and you have advantage against charm effects.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Rune of Necrotic Smite" type="Class Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DK_RUNE_OF_NECROTIC_SMITE">
        <supports>KB Death Knight Rune</supports>
        <requirements>ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_DEATH_KNIGHT_ORDER_OF_FALLEN_PALADINS,[level:death knight:13]</requirements>
        <prerequisite>Order of the Fallen Paladins, 13th level</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Order of the Fallen Paladins, 13th level</p>
            <p>When you hit with a melee weapon attack using a rune weapon, you can expend one spell slot to channel necrotic energy into your rune weapon and deal additional necrotic damage to the target, in addition to the weapon’s damage. The extra damage is 2d8 for a 1st-level spell slot, plus 1d8 for each spell level higher than 1st, to a maximum of 5d8.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you hit with a melee weapon attack using a rune weapon, you can expend one spell slot to deal additional necrotic damage to the target, in addition to the weapon’s damage. The extra damage is 2d8 for a 1st-level spell slot, plus 1d8 for each spell level higher than 1st, to a maximum of 5d8.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Rune of the Retained Divine" type="Class Feature" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_CLASS_FEATURE_DK_RUNE_OF_THE_RETAINED_DIVINE">
        <supports>KB Death Knight Rune</supports>
        <requirements>ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_DEATH_KNIGHT_ORDER_OF_FALLEN_PALADINS,[level:death knight:9]</requirements>
        <prerequisite>Order of the Fallen Paladins, 9th level</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Order of the Fallen Paladins, 9th level</p>
            <p>You can learn additional spells from the paladin spell list. The number of spells you can learn are equal to to a third of your death knight level (rounded down). These spells do not count against your total spells known.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Rune of the Retained Divine)" spellcasting="Death Knight" known="true" supports="Paladin,$(spellcasting:slots)" level="3" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Rune of the Retained Divine)" spellcasting="Death Knight" known="true" supports="Paladin,$(spellcasting:slots)" level="6" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Rune of the Retained Divine)" spellcasting="Death Knight" known="true" supports="Paladin,$(spellcasting:slots)" level="9" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Rune of the Retained Divine)" spellcasting="Death Knight" known="true" supports="Paladin,$(spellcasting:slots)" level="12" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Rune of the Retained Divine)" spellcasting="Death Knight" known="true" supports="Paladin,$(spellcasting:slots)" level="15" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Rune of the Retained Divine)" spellcasting="Death Knight" known="true" supports="Paladin,$(spellcasting:slots)" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>

  <!-- Death Knight Runes as Gifts -->
    <element name="Rune of the Arcanist" type="Magic Item" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_MAGIC_ITEM_DK_RUNE_OF_THE_ARCANIST">
        <prerequisite>Order of Magi</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Order of Magi</p>
            <p>You can add your Charisma modifier to the damage you deal with any magi cantrip, and you can learn one additional magi cantrip.</p>
        </description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Death Knight Rune</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
		</setters>
        <rules>
            <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Death Knight)" spellcasting="Death Knight" supports="$(spellcasting:list),0" known="true" level="10" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Rune of the Clouds" type="Magic Item" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_MAGIC_ITEM_DK_RUNE_OF_THE_CLOUDS">
        <description>
            <p>This rune allows you to draw a shrouding mist around yourself. As an action, you create a 10ft radius circle of fog centered on yourself that follows you. The area around you is treated as heavily obscured, but you can see through it. The fog lasts for 1 minute, or until you dismiss it as a bonus action.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can use this feature once per short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Death Knight Rune</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
		</setters>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Rune of the Crusader" type="Magic Item" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_MAGIC_ITEM_DK_RUNE_OF_THE_CRUSADER">
        <description>
            <p>You can use the necrotic energy of your runes to heal yourself. When you hit with a rune weapon while necrotic strike is active, you can roll a number of hit dice equal to your Charisma modifier and heal for the total rolled.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can only use this rune once per short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Death Knight Rune</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
		</setters>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Rune of the Death Ward" type="Magic Item" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_MAGIC_ITEM_DK_RUNE_OF_THE_DEATH_WARD">
        <prerequisite>13th level</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 13th level</p>
            <p>When you take damage that would reduce you to 0 hit points, you instead drop to 1 hit point.</p>
            <p class="indent">This rune can only be activated once per long rest.</p>
        </description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Death Knight Rune</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
		</setters>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Rune of Defense" type="Magic Item" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_MAGIC_ITEM_DK_RUNE_OF_DEFENSE">
        <prerequisite>13th level</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 13th level</p>
            <p>Whenever you must make a saving throw, you gain a bonus to the saving throw equal to your Charisma modifier (with a minimum bonus of +1).</p>
        </description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Death Knight Rune</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
		</setters>
        <rules>
            <stat name="rune-of-defense:save-bonus" value="1" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="rune-of-defense:save-bonus" value="charisma:modifier" bonus="base" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Rune of the Frozen Grasp" type="Magic Item" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_MAGIC_ITEM_DK_RUNE_OF_THE_FROZEN_GRASP">
        <description>
            <p>Once on each of your turns, when you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack, you can reduce that creature’s speed by 10 feet until the end of your next turn.</p>
        </description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Death Knight Rune</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
		</setters>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Rune of the Gargoyle" type="Magic Item" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_MAGIC_ITEM_DK_RUNE_OF_THE_GARGOYLE">
        <prerequisite>Order of Destroyers</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Order of Destroyers</p>
            <p>When you take damage, you can use your reaction to roll a d12. Add your Constitution modifier to the number rolled, and reduce the damage by that total.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can use this rune once per short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Death Knight Rune</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
		</setters>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Rune of Hellfire" type="Magic Item" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_MAGIC_ITEM_DK_RUNE_OF_HELLFIRE">
        <prerequisite>17th level</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 17th level</p>
            <p>This rune allows you to hurl a magical ball of fire fueled with energies derived from your rune weapon.</p>
            <p class="indent">As an action, you choose a point you can see within 120 feet. Each creature in a 20-foot-radius sphere centered on that point must make a Dexterity saving throw. The sphere spreads around corners. A creature takes 6d6 fire damage and 6d6 necrotic damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can use this rune once per long rest</p>
        </description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Death Knight Rune</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
		</setters>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Rune of the Inquisitor" type="Magic Item" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_MAGIC_ITEM_DK_RUNE_OF_THE_INQUISITOR">
        <prerequisite>Order of Rune Wardens, 9th level</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Order of Rune Wardens, 9th level</p>
            <p>This rune allows you to gain insights into what you see. As an action, you can cast <i>identify</i>. You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Charisma Modifier.</p>
        </description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Death Knight Rune</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
		</setters>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Rune of the Legendary Mount" type="Magic Item" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_MAGIC_ITEM_DK_RUNE_OF_THE_LEGENDARY_MOUNT">
        <prerequisite>Order of Cavaliers, 13th level</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Order of Cavaliers, 13th level</p>
            <p>This rune grants any creature created using your bound mount feature resistance to all damage, and when it deals damage, you can add your proficiency bonus to the damage dealt.</p>
            <p class="indent">The additional damage is of the same type as the mount’s attack, if the attack deals more than one type of damage, the damage bonus is applied to only one type. You choose which type.</p>
        </description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Death Knight Rune</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
		</setters>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Rune of Lethality" type="Magic Item" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_MAGIC_ITEM_DK_RUNE_OF_LETHALITY">
        <prerequisite>17th level</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 17th level</p>
            <p>This rune lets you cause your enemies to whither under the effects of necrotic energy. You can use your reaction to cause a target creature to become vulnerable to a single instance of necrotic damage.</p>
            <p class="indent">This rune can only be used once per short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Death Knight Rune</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
		</setters>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Rune of the Lightning Mount" type="Magic Item" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_MAGIC_ITEM_DK_RUNE_OF_THE_LIGHTNING_MOUNT">
        <prerequisite>Order of Cavaliers, 9th level</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Order of Cavaliers, 9th level</p>
            <p>While mounted, you can use your action to cast <i>haste</i> on yourself and your mount without expending a spell slot.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can use this rune once per long rest.</p>
        </description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Death Knight Rune</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
		</setters>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Rune of Necrosis" type="Magic Item" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_MAGIC_ITEM_DK_RUNE_OF_NECROSIS">
        <prerequisite>Order of Rune Wardens, 13th level</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Order of Rune Wardens, 13th level</p>
            <p>This rune imbues your weapon with more necrotic energy. You gain 1 additional use of your Necrotic Strike feature per long rest.</p>
        </description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Death Knight Rune</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
		</setters>
        <rules>
            <stat name="necrotic-strike:uses" value="1" level="13" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Rune of Necrotic Strike Mastery" type="Magic Item" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_MAGIC_ITEM_DK_RUNE_OF_NECROTIC_STRIKE_MASTERY">
        <description>
            <p>When you use necrotic strike, and you roll a 1 or 2 for necrotic damage, you can reroll the dice once and take the second roll.</p>
        </description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Death Knight Rune</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
		</setters>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Rune of Retribution" type="Magic Item" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_MAGIC_ITEM_DK_RUNE_OF_RETRIBUTION">
        <description>
            <p>While this rune is inscribed, when you take damage from a creature within 60 feet of you, you can use your reaction to deal 3d10 necrotic damage to the creature that damaged you.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can use this rune a number of times equal to a third of your death knight level (rounded down) per long rest.</p>
        </description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Death Knight Rune</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
		</setters>
        <rules>
            <stat name="rune-of-retribution:uses" value="1" level="1" />
            <stat name="rune-of-retribution:uses" value="1" level="6" />
            <stat name="rune-of-retribution:uses" value="1" level="9" />
            <stat name="rune-of-retribution:uses" value="1" level="12" />
            <stat name="rune-of-retribution:uses" value="1" level="15" />
            <stat name="rune-of-retribution:uses" value="1" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Rune of the Owl" type="Magic Item" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_MAGIC_ITEM_DK_RUNE_OF_THE_OWL">
        <description>
            <p>You gain darkvision and can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can’t discern color in darkness, only shades of gray. If you already have darkvision, then your darkvision intervals increase by 60 feet.</p>
            <p class="indent">You also have advantage on Stealth checks while in darkness.</p>
        </description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Death Knight Rune</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
		</setters>
        <rules>
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_DARKVISION_OR_INCREASE_60" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Rune of Parrying" type="Magic Item" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_MAGIC_ITEM_DK_RUNE_OF_PARRYING">
        <prerequisite>Order of Ebon Blades</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Order of Ebon Blades</p>
            <p>You can add your proficiency bonus to your AC against one melee attack that would hit you. To do so, you must see the attacker and be wielding a melee weapon.</p>
        </description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Death Knight Rune</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
		</setters>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Rune of Skill" type="Magic Item" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_MAGIC_ITEM_DK_RUNE_OF_SKILL">
        <description>
            <p>You can use this rune to add your proficiency bonus to a skill you do not have proficiency in. This feature can be used before or after the roll, but it must be used before you know if it succeeds or fails.</p>
            <p class="indent">This rune can only be used a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier per long rest.</p>
        </description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Death Knight Rune</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
		</setters>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Rune of the Slayer" type="Magic Item" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_MAGIC_ITEM_DK_RUNE_OF_THE_SLAYER">
        <prerequisite>Order of Destroyers or Ebon Blades, 13th level</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Order of Destroyers or Ebon Blades, 13th level</p>
            <p>This rune lets you channel the death of an opponent into a surge of adrenaline. Once per turn, when you reduce an enemy creature to 0 hit points or score a critical hit, you can make an additional attack as part of that attack action.</p>
        </description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Death Knight Rune</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
		</setters>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Rune of Spellbinding" type="Magic Item" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_MAGIC_ITEM_DK_RUNE_OF_SPELLBINDING">
        <prerequisite>Order of Magi, 13th level</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Order of Magi, 13th level</p>
            <p>This rune channels additional magical energy that can be used to fuel your powers. You gain 1 additional spell slot equal to the level of your other death knight spell slots.</p>
        </description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Death Knight Rune</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
		</setters>
        <rules>
            <stat name="death knight:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="13" />
            <stat name="death knight:spellcasting:slots:4" value="-1" level="17" />
            <stat name="death knight:spellcasting:slots:5" value="1" level="17" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Rune of Spellbreaking" type="Magic Item" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_MAGIC_ITEM_DK_RUNE_OF_SPELLBREAKING">
        <prerequisite>9th level</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 9th level</p>
            <p>You can use this rune to attempt to disrupt a spell. As a reaction to a creature within 30 feet of you casting a spell, you can cast counterspell without expending a spell slot, but regardless of the spell’s level, you must make an ability check using your spellcasting ability. The DC equals 10 + the spell’s level. On a success, the creature’s spell fails and has no effect.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can use this rune twice per long rest.</p>
        </description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Death Knight Rune</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
		</setters>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Rune of Spellstriking" type="Magic Item" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_MAGIC_ITEM_DK_RUNE_OF_SPELLSTRIKING">
        <prerequisite>Order of Magi, 9th level</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Order of Magi, 9th level</p>
            <p>When you cast a spell, you can use a bonus action to make a spell attack with advantage, or you can impose disadvantage on the saving throw of a single creature affected by that spell.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can use this rune a number of times equal to a quarter of your death knight level (rounded down) per long rest.</p>
        </description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Death Knight Rune</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
		</setters>
        <rules>
            <stat name="rune-of-spellstriking:uses" value="2" level="8" />
            <stat name="rune-of-spellstriking:uses" value="1" level="12" />
            <stat name="rune-of-spellstriking:uses" value="1" level="16" />
            <stat name="rune-of-spellstriking:uses" value="1" level="20" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Rune of the Summoner" type="Magic Item" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_MAGIC_ITEM_DK_RUNE_OF_THE_SUMMONER">
        <prerequisite>Order of Cavaliers</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Order of Cavaliers</p>
            <p>You can use this rune to instantly bring your Bound Mount to your location. You can decide whether it appears next to you, or if it appears under you, allowing you to become instantly mounted.</p>
            <p class="indent">If there is not enough room for your mount, the summoning fails and your mount takes 4d6 force damage.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can use this rune once per short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Death Knight Rune</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
		</setters>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Rune of the True Warden" type="Magic Item" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_MAGIC_ITEM_DK_RUNE_OF_THE_TRUE_WARDEN">
        <prerequisite>Order of Rune Wardens</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Order of Rune Wardens</p>
            <p>This rune activates the leylines in your body to create a matrix of defensive energies around you. While you are not wearing any armor, your armor class equals 10 + your Dexterity modifier + your Charisma modifier. You can use a shield and still gain this benefit.</p>
        </description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Death Knight Rune</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
		</setters>
        <rules>
			<stat name="ac:unarmored defense rune:base" value="10" />
			<stat name="ac:unarmored defense rune:dexterity" value="dexterity:modifier" />
			<stat name="ac:unarmored defense rune:charisma" value="charisma:modifier" />
			<stat name="ac:unarmored defense rune" value="ac:unarmored defense rune:base" />
			<stat name="ac:unarmored defense rune" value="ac:unarmored defense rune:dexterity" />
			<stat name="ac:unarmored defense rune" value="ac:unarmored defense rune:charisma" />
			<stat name="ac:calculation" value="ac:unarmored defense rune" bonus="calculation" equipped="[armor:none]" alt="Unarmored Defense (Rune Warden)" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Rune of Unbridled Savagery" type="Magic Item" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_MAGIC_ITEM_DK_RUNE_OF_UNBRIDLED_SAVAGERY">
        <prerequisite>Order of Destroyers, 9th level</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Order of Destroyers, 9th level</p>
            <p>You regain all uses of your savage techniques on a short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Death Knight Rune</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
		</setters>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Rune of the Weapon Master" type="Magic Item" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_MAGIC_ITEM_DK_RUNE_OF_THE_WEAPON_MASTER">
        <prerequisite>Order of Ebon Blades, 9th level</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Order of Ebon Blades, 9th level</p>
            <p>You regain all uses of your weapon arts on a short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Death Knight Rune</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
		</setters>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>

 <!-- Death Knight New Spells -->
    <element name="Crypt Fangs" type="Spell" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_SPELL_CRYPT_FANGS">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You reach down and place your palm against the ground, causing spires of shadow to pierce the ground. Creatures you choose within 40 feet of you must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw, or they take 4d10 necrotic damage and become frightened until the end of your next turn. On a successful save they only take half damage, and they are not frightened.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 6th level or higher, the damage reduction increases by 1d10 for each slot level above 5th.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">5</set>
            <set name="school">conjuration</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 Action</set>
            <set name="range">self (40 foot radius)</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Grave Hammer" type="Spell" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_SPELL_GRAVE_HAMMER">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
        <description>
            <p>As part of the action used to cast this spell, you must make a melee attack with a weapon against one creature within the spell’s range, otherwise the spell fails. On a hit, the target suffers the attack’s normal effects, and they cannot use their reaction until the end of your current turn.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> At 5th level, the melee attack deals extra necrotic damage equal to 1d8. The damage increases by 1d8 at 11th level (2d8) and 17th level (3d8).</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">0</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 Action</set>
            <set name="range">5 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a weapon</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Hoarfrost Chains" type="Spell" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_SPELL_HOARFROST_CHAINS">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You conjure a writhing mass of chains made of ice. When you cast this spell, you can direct the chains to wrap around any number of creatures within 30 feet of you that you can see. That creature must succeed on a Strength saving throw or you and the targeted are unable to move further than 30 feet from you. A creature bound in this way can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of their turns. Additionally, creatures chained in this way make Dexterity saving throws at disadvantage.</p>
            <p class="indent">If your movement would cause a creature to be further than 30 feet from you, you can either release them (no action required), or you can move at a cost of an additional 1 foot of movement per creature per 1 foot moved. Creatures you leave chained while you move in this way causes them to move with you. You may also use a bonus action on your turn to attempt to chain an additional creature that is within 30 feet.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">4</set>
            <set name="school">conjuration</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 Action</set>
            <set name="range">30 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">four iron chain links</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Life Ward" type="Spell" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_SPELL_LIFE_WARD">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You can protect a creature within 30 feet or yourself from harm. When a creature or yourself would take damage from any source that can be reduced, you can use your reaction to reduce the damage by 1d8.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the damage reduction increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 1st.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">abjuration</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 Reaction</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a miniature shield pendant</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Necroblast" type="Spell" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_SPELL_NECROBLAST">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You launch a sphere of sickly green-black fire at a creature or object within range. Make a ranged spell attack against the target. On a hit, the target takes 1d4 fire damage and 1d4 necrotic damage. A flammable object hit by this spell ignites if it isn’t being worn or carried.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> This spell’s fire and necrotic damage each increase by 1d4 when you reach 5th level (2d4 and 2d4), 11th level (3d4 and 3d4), and 17th level (4d4 and 4d4).</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">0</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">120 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Virulent Sickness" type="Spell" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_SPELL_VIRULENT_SICKNESS">
        <supports>KB Death Knight</supports>
        <description>
            <p>After a rapid incantation, you cause a sickness to infect a target creature. The creature must succeed on a Constitution saving throw, or they are affected by one of the diseases you choose from the list below. If a creature is immune to disease, they automatically succeed.</p>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><b>Rot:</b> the affected creature cannot gain temporary hit points and only heals for half of the amount (rounded down).</li>
                <li><b>Agony:</b> the affected creature takes 1d6 psychic damage at the beginning of each turn for the spell’s duration.</li>
                <li><b>Leg Palsy:</b> the affected creature’s movement speed is halved, and they cannot take the dash or disengage action.</li>
                <li><b>Erratic Nerves:</b> the affected creature must roll a d6 before each weapon or spell attack roll. On a 1 or 2, they take 2d6 lightning and the attack roll is made with disadvantage.</li>
            </ul>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th or higher, the number of targets you can affect increases. For each spell slot higher than 3rd level, you can target one additional creature in range.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">necromancy</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 Action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">1 minute</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

  <!-- Shadow Wyrm Mount -->
    <element name="Shadow Wyrm" type="Companion" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_COMPANION_SHADOW_WYRM">
        <requirements>ID_KB_TDK_ARCHETYPE_DEATH_KNIGHT_ORDER_OF_CAVALIERS,[level:death knight:18]</requirements>
        <description />
        <setters>
            <set name="strength">19</set>
            <set name="dexterity">14</set>
            <set name="constitution">17</set>
            <set name="intelligence">6</set>
            <set name="wisdom">12</set>
            <set name="charisma">6</set>
            <set name="ac">17 (natural armor)</set>
            <set name="hp">58 (5d10 + 15)</set>
            <set name="speed">30 ft., fly 30 ft.</set>
            <set name="languages">Can understand any language spoken by its master</set>
            <set name="saves">Str +7, Dex +5, Con +6</set>
            <set name="skills">Perception +5, Stealth +2</set>
            <set name="immunities">Necrotic</set>
            <set name="senses">Blindsight 10 ft., Darkvision 120 ft., Passive Perception 17</set>
            <set name="type">Dragon</set>
            <set name="size">Large</set>
            <set name="alignment">unaligned</set>
            <set name="challenge">3</set>
            <set name="traits">ID_KB_TDK_COMPANION_TRAIT_SHADOW_WYRM_ONE_WITH_SHADOW, ID_KB_TDK_COMPANION_TRAIT_SHADOW_WYRM_SHADOW_STEALTH</set>
            <set name="actions">ID_anthem_source_COMPANION_ACTION_SHADOW_WYRM_MULTIATTACK, ID_anthem_source_COMPANION_ACTION_SHADOW_WYRM_BITE, ID_anthem_source_COMPANION_ACTION_SHADOW_WYRM_CLAW, ID_anthem_source_COMPANION_ACTION_SHADOW_WYRM_SHADOW_BREATH</set>
        </setters>
        <rules>
            <stat name="companion:ac" value="17" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="companion:hp:max" value="65" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="companion:speed" value="30" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="companion:speed:fly" value="30" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="companion:stealth:proficiency" value="proficiency" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="companion:perception:proficiency" value="proficiency" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="companion:strength:save:proficiency" value="companion:proficiency" bonus="proficiency" />
            <stat name="companion:dexterity:save:proficiency" value="companion:proficiency" bonus="proficiency" />
            <stat name="companion:dexterity:save:proficiency" value="companion:proficiency" bonus="proficiency" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="One with Shadow" type="Companion Trait" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_COMPANION_TRAIT_SHADOW_WYRM_ONE_WITH_SHADOW">
            <description>
                <p>When in dim light or darkness, this creature has advantage on stealth checks.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When in dim light or darkness, this creature has advantage on stealth checks.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Shadow Stealth" type="Companion Trait" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_KB_TDK_COMPANION_TRAIT_SHADOW_WYRM_SHADOW_STEALTH">
            <description>
                <p>While in dim light or darkness, the dragon can take the Hide action as a bonus action.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>While in dim light or darkness, the dragon can take the Hide action as a bonus action.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Multiattack" type="Companion Action" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_anthem_source_COMPANION_ACTION_SHADOW_WYRM_MULTIATTACK">
            <description>
                <p>The dragon makes two attacks: one with its bite and one with its claws.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>The dragon makes two attacks: one with its bite and one with its claws.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Bite" type="Companion Action" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_anthem_source_COMPANION_ACTION_SHADOW_WYRM_BITE">
            <description>
                <p>Melee Weapon Attack: +7 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 9 (1d10 + 4) piercing damage and 2 (1d4) necrotic damage.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Melee Weapon Attack: +7 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 9 (1d10 + 4) piercing damage and 2 (1d4) necrotic damage.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Claw" type="Companion Action" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_anthem_source_COMPANION_ACTION_SHADOW_WYRM_CLAW">
            <description>
                <p>Melee Weapon Attack: +7 to hit, reach 5ft., one target. Hit 7 (1d6 + 4).</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Melee Weapon Attack: +7 to hit, reach 5ft., one target. Hit 7 (1d6 + 4).</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Shadow Breath" type="Companion Action" source="The Death Knight" id="ID_anthem_source_COMPANION_ACTION_SHADOW_WYRM_SHADOW_BREATH">
            <description>
                <p>The dragon exhales shadowy fire in a 20-foot cone. Each creature in that area must make a DC 16 Dexterity saving throw, taking 33 (6d10) necrotic damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>The dragon exhales shadowy fire in a 20-foot cone. Each creature in that area must make a DC 16 Dexterity saving throw, taking 33 (6d10) necrotic damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

</elements>