<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>The Minstrel Class</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="class-minstrel.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/classes/class-minstrel.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="The Minstrel Class" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_SHEMULATOR_GMBINDER_SOURCE_The Minstrel Class">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation">TTC</set>
            <set name="url">https://www.gmbinder.com/share/-MQ5Qn9W4M3sL3Ne7k2r</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" abbreviation="SHEM" url="https://www.gmbinder.com/profile/shemulator">Shemulator</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20200118</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Minstrel" type="Class" source="The Minstrel Class" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_CLASS_MINSTREL">
        <description>
            <p>A lyrist’s fingers glide across her instrument as her allies face the terrible dragon before them. The melody rumbles deeply in their ears as they steel themselves for the great battle to come.</p>
            <p class="indent">Chanting a song of strength, an orc summons a deep well of courage within his brothers and sisters—inspiring them to charge ahead.</p>
            <p class="indent">A halfling strikes his drum, pulling on the threads of magic that erupt from his instrument to weave together healing relief for his injured companion.</p>
            <p class="indent">Neither wizards or bards of long past, minstrels are talented musicians, performers, and speakers. By combining song, dance, music, and arcane power, minstrels to create wondrous magic like no other.</p>
            <h4>THE POWER OF MUSIC</h4>
            <p>Many are the magic practitioners across the land. However, few of them see through the veil of arcana like minstrels do. Sounds and words, hold vast and innumerable power. And minstrels are the select few who have learned to harness and weave that power. What a simple plucked string or the boom of a drum is to some people is raw, craftable, and reachable magic to a minstrel—song and dance are their paintbrushes and the world is their canvas.</p>
            <p class="indent">In the chaos of battle, minstrels can be seen on the outer edges of the fray: bolstering their allies with their powerful songspells. Some minstrels, however, seek the heat of battle themselves and willingly charge into a fight—eagerly bellowing chants of fire and steel alongside their companions. Wherever you might see one—a minstrel is always a welcome comrade on the field.</p>
            <h4>THE SOUND OF ADVENTURE</h4>
            <p>One would be quick to assume that minstrels travel the land in search of the next legendary deed to write ballads over or the next great world changing event to solidify their place in history with. While some, in fact, do, many minstrels do not chase fame or heroic pinings.</p>
            <p class="indent">Some minstrels line themselves up as caravan guards, using their musical repertoire to aid their fellow guardsman in whatever threats they might meet along the road. Other minstrels earn their keep as mercenaries and freelancers—offering their spectacular gifts in exchange for some coin. Minstrels are even found among dangerous, specialized excursions deep into untold lands: a beacon of comfort and reassurance in the face of the black dirges of the unknown.</p>
            <h4>CREATING A MINSTREL</h4>
            <p>As you create a minstrel, think of where your character learned their musical gifts. Did they study under a kingdom famous musical genius? A warm, neighborly old woman who once played for the king? Perhaps your character is self taught—a prodigy of natural art just waiting for her moment to shine upon the land.</p>
            <p class="indent">What caused you to leave hearth and home? Were you called upon by a special request in favor of your musical abilities? Are you a wanderer and traveler constantly seeking bed and bread in exchange for tune? Or perhaps you’re a writer: constantly seeking the “spark” that will become the greatest ode in all of the land?</p>
            <h5>QUICK BUILD</h5>
            <p>You can make a minstrel quickly by following these suggestions. First, Charisma should be your highest ability score, followed by Constitutuon. Second, choose the entertainer background.</p>
            <h2>CLASS FEATURES</h2>
            <p>As an minstrel, you gain the following class features.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">HIT POINTS</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Hit Dice:</strong> 1d8 per minstrel level</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at 1st Level:</strong> 8 + your Constitution modifier</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at Higher Levels:</strong> 1d8 (or 5) + your Constitution modifier per minstrel level after 1st</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">PROFICIENCIES</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled mb">
                <li><strong>Armor:</strong> Light armor, medium armor</li>
                <li><strong>Weapons:</strong> Simple weapons, hand crossbows, longswords, rapiers, shortswords</li>
                <li><strong>Tools:</strong> Three musical instruments of your choice</li>
            </ul>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Saving Throws:</strong> Dexterity, Charisma</li>
                <li><strong>Skills:</strong> Performance and any two other skills</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">EQUIPMENT</h5>
            <p>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>(a) a rapier, (b) a longsword, or (c) any simple weapon</li>
                <li>(a) a diplomat’s pack or (b) an entertainer’s pack</li>
                <li>(a) a lute or (b) any other musical instrument</li>
                <li>Leather armor and a dagger</li>
            </ul>
        <!-- class table here -->
            <h5 class="caption">THE MINSTREL</h5>
            <table class="class-features">
                <thead>
                    <tr><td class="col-5">Level</td><td class="col-10">Proficiency Bonus</td><td class="col-60 left">Features</td><td class="col-10">Songs Known</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td> 1st</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Born Performer, Songcraft</td><td>1</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 2nd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Musical Style, Aficionado</td><td>1</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 3rd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Musical Style feature</td><td>2</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 4th</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>2</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 5th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Key Change</td><td>3</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 6th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Musical Style feature</td><td>3</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 7th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">─</td><td>4</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 8th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>4</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 9th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Greater Songcraft</td><td>4</td></tr>
                <tr><td>10th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Expertise</td><td>4</td></tr>
                <tr><td>11th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Epic Transition</td><td>5</td></tr>
                <tr><td>12th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>5</td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">─</td><td>6</td></tr>
                <tr><td>14th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Musical Style feature</td><td>6</td></tr>
                <tr><td>15th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">─</td><td>7</td></tr>
                <tr><td>16th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>7</td></tr>
                <tr><td>17th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">─</td><td>8</td></tr>
                <tr><td>18th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Master Songcraft</td><td>8</td></tr>
                <tr><td>19th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>8</td></tr>
                <tr><td>20th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Encore</td><td>8</td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_SHEM_TTC_CLASS_FEATURE_MINSTREL_BORN_PERFORMER" />
            <div element="ID_SHEM_TTC_CLASS_FEATURE_MINSTREL_SONGCRAFT" />
            <div element="ID_SHEM_TTC_CLASS_FEATURE_MINSTREL_MUSICAL_STYLE" />
            <div element="ID_SHEM_TTC_CLASS_FEATURE_MINSTREL_AFICIONADO" />
            <div element="ID_SHEM_TTC_CLASS_FEATURE_MINSTREL_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" />
            <div element="ID_SHEM_TTC_CLASS_FEATURE_MINSTREL_KEY_CHANGE" />
            <div element="ID_SHEM_TTC_CLASS_FEATURE_MINSTREL_GREATER_SONGCRAFT" />
            <div element="ID_SHEM_TTC_CLASS_FEATURE_MINSTREL_EXPERTISE" />
            <div element="ID_SHEM_TTC_CLASS_FEATURE_MINSTREL_EPIC_TRANSITION" />
            <div element="ID_SHEM_TTC_CLASS_FEATURE_MINSTREL_MASTER_SONGCRAFT" />
            <div element="ID_SHEM_TTC_CLASS_FEATURE_MINSTREL_ENCORE" />
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="hd">d8</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_MEDIUM_ARMOR" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_CROSSBOW_HAND" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_LONGSWORD" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_RAPIER" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SHORTSWORD" />
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Musical Instrument (Minstrel)" supports="Musical Instrument" number="3" />
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency (Minstrel)" supports="Skill" number="2" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERFORMANCE" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_DEXTERITY" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CHARISMA" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_CLASS_FEATURE_MINSTREL_BORN_PERFORMER" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_CLASS_FEATURE_MINSTREL_SONGCRAFT" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_CLASS_FEATURE_MINSTREL_MUSICAL_STYLE" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_CLASS_FEATURE_MINSTREL_AFICIONADO" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_CLASS_FEATURE_MINSTREL_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" level="4" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_CLASS_FEATURE_MINSTREL_KEY_CHANGE" level="5" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_CLASS_FEATURE_MINSTREL_GREATER_SONGCRAFT" level="9" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_CLASS_FEATURE_MINSTREL_EXPERTISE" level="10" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_CLASS_FEATURE_MINSTREL_EPIC_TRANSITION" level="11" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_CLASS_FEATURE_MINSTREL_MASTER_SONGCRAFT" level="18" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_CLASS_FEATURE_MINSTREL_ENCORE" level="20" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Born Performer" type="Class Feature" source="The Minstrel Class" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_CLASS_FEATURE_MINSTREL_BORN_PERFORMER">
            <description>
                <p>At 1st level, you have a natural knack for motivating and inspiring others to greater action whether through words or music. Your proficiency bonus is doubled for Charisma (Performance) checks.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false" />
            <rules>
                <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_EXPERTISE_SKILL_PERFORMANCE" level="1" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Songcraft" type="Class Feature" source="The Minstrel Class" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_CLASS_FEATURE_MINSTREL_SONGCRAFT">
            <description>
                <p>Unlike the bards of old, your songs rally those around you to greater feats of action. You pull on the threads of magic to fuel your music with powerful effects called songspells.</p>
                <h5>CASTING A SONGSPELL</h5>
                <p>You can play a number of songspells equal to your Charisma modifier. To play a known songspell, you expend one use of your songcraft as an action. A songspell and its effects end at the beginning of your next turn but can be maintained until the beginning of the following turn as a bonus action until your concentration is broken (as if concentrating on a spell). A songspell has a maximum duration of 1 minute, at which you spend another use of songcraft to continue its effect. You regain any expended uses during a short or long rest.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can only have one songspell active at any time. Changing a songspell from one effect to another requires you to stop the previous performance and start a new one as an action.</p>
                <h5>SONGSPELL FOCUS</h5>
                <p>You can use an instrument as a spellcasting focus for your songspells.</p>
                <h5>SONGS KNOWN OF 1ST LEVEL AND HIGHER</h5>
                <p>At 1st level, you know one songspell of your choice from the songspell list. The Songs Known column of the Minstrel table shows when you learn more songspells of your choice.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, when you gain a level in this class, you can choose one of the songspells you know and replace it with another songspell that you could learn at that level.</p>
                <p class="indent">If a songspell has prerequisites, you must meet them to learn it. You can learn the songspell at the same time that you meet its prerequisites. A level prerequisite refers to your level in this class.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can change your known songspells when you finish a long rest. Memorizing new songspells requires time spent practicing the music and magic required to cast the songspell: at least 1 minute per songspell.</p>
                <p class="indent">Some of your songspells require your target to make a saving throw to resist the feature’s effects. You use your Charisma modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a songspell you use and when making a spell attack roll with one.</p>
                <p style="text-align: center;"><b>Songspell Save DC</b> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier</p>
                <p style="text-align: center;"><b>Songspell attack modifier</b> = your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="{{charisma:modifier}}/Short Rest" action="Action">
                <description>You can cast songspells. You can memorize up to {{minstrel:spellcasting:prepare}} songspells during a long rest.</description>
            </sheet>
            <spellcasting name="Minstrel" ability="Charisma" prepare="true">
                <list known="true">Minstrel Songspell</list>
            </spellcasting>
            <rules>
                <stat name="minstrel:spellcasting:slots:1" value="charisma:modifier" level="1" />
                <stat name="minstrel:spellcasting:prepare" value="1" level="1" />
                <stat name="minstrel:spellcasting:prepare" value="1" level="3" />
                <stat name="minstrel:spellcasting:prepare" value="1" level="5" />
                <stat name="minstrel:spellcasting:prepare" value="1" level="7" />
                <stat name="minstrel:spellcasting:prepare" value="1" level="11" />
                <stat name="minstrel:spellcasting:prepare" value="1" level="13" />
                <stat name="minstrel:spellcasting:prepare" value="1" level="15" />
                <stat name="minstrel:spellcasting:prepare" value="1" level="17" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Musical Style" type="Class Feature" source="The Minstrel Class" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_CLASS_FEATURE_MINSTREL_MUSICAL_STYLE">
            <description>
                <p>No minstrel is like another. Music of the land continues to evolve throughout history, yet there are a few integrations of magic and song that have stood strong against the sands of time. Though every minstrel displays a unique style and identity, their magic through music tends to manifest in a multitude of recognizable ways.</p>
                <p class="indent">At 2nd level, you have started to develop your own rhythm when using your songcraft. Choose the Battle Dancer, Precentor, String Marstra, or Rhythm Knight, all detailed at the end of the class description. Your choice grants you features at 2nd level and again at 3rd, 6th, and 14th level.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Archetype" name="Musical Style" supports="Musical Style" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Aficionado" type="Class Feature" source="The Minstrel Class" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_CLASS_FEATURE_MINSTREL_AFICIONADO">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 2nd level, you can double your proficiency bonus when rolling Intelligence checks to recognize written or oral songs, poems, or other verse. If the piece in question is in a language you do not understand, you can still understand the base emotion, feeling, and intention of it even if you cannot translate it directly.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can double your proficiency bonus when rolling Intelligence checks to recognize written or oral songs, poems, or other verse. If the piece in question is in a language you do not understand, you can still understand the base emotion, feeling, and intention of it even if you cannot translate it directly.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Ability Score Improvement" type="Class Feature" source="The Minstrel Class" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_CLASS_FEATURE_MINSTREL_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
				<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Minstrel 4)" supports="Improvement Option,Minstrel,4" level="4" />
				<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Minstrel 8)" supports="Improvement Option,Minstrel,8" level="8" />
				<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Minstrel 12)" supports="Improvement Option,Minstrel,12" level="12" />
				<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Minstrel 16)" supports="Improvement Option,Minstrel,16" level="16" />
				<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Minstrel 19)" supports="Improvement Option,Minstrel,19" level="19" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Key Change" type="Class Feature" source="The Minstrel Class" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_CLASS_FEATURE_MINSTREL_KEY_CHANGE">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 5th level, you can use your reaction to immediately play a new songspell that you know in place of a currently active songspell without expending a use of Songcraft. You can use this feature twice at 5th level, and three times at 15th level.</p>
                <p class="indent">You regain uses of this feature after a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Reaction" usage="{{key-change:uses}}/Short Rest">
                <description>You can immediately play a new songspell that you know in place of a currently active songspell without expending a use of Songcraft.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="key-change:uses" value="2" level="5" />
                <stat name="key-change:uses" value="1" level="15" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Greater Songcraft" type="Class Feature" source="The Minstrel Class" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_CLASS_FEATURE_MINSTREL_GREATER_SONGCRAFT">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 9th level, you can have up to two songspells active simultaneously. You can spend an action activating a second songspell, at which a second songspell effects are applied simultaneously, and you cannot choose a songspell that is already active.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can continue to use your bonus action on subsequent turns to maintain your songspell and both songspell effects are maintained in this way. If your concentration is broken, you lose both effects immediately.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>You can spend an action activating a second songspell, at which a second songspell effects are applied simultaneously, and you cannot choose a songspell that is already active. You can continue to use your bonus action on subsequent turns to maintain your songspell and both songspell effects are maintained in this way. If your concentration is broken, you lose both effects immediately.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Expertise" type="Class Feature" source="The Minstrel Class" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_CLASS_FEATURE_MINSTREL_EXPERTISE">
            <description>
                <p>At 10th Level, choose two of your skill proficiencies besides Charisma (Performance). Your proficiency bonus is doubled for any ability check you make that uses either of the chosen proficiencies.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Expertise, Minstrel" supports="Expertise,Skill" number="2" level="10" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Epic Transition" type="Class Feature" source="The Minstrel Class" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_CLASS_FEATURE_MINSTREL_EPIC_TRANSITION">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 11th level, you can expend one use of your songcraft to have your next songspell affect all allies within 30 feet of you as a bonus action.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="Songcraft">
                <description>You can expend one use of your songcraft to have your next songspell affect all allies within 30 feet of you.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Master Songcraft" type="Class Feature" source="The Minstrel Class" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_CLASS_FEATURE_MINSTREL_MASTER_SONGCRAFT">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 18th level, you can have up to three songspells active simultaneously.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can have up to three songspells active simultaneously.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Encore" type="Class Feature" source="The Minstrel Class" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_CLASS_FEATURE_MINSTREL_ENCORE">
            <description>
                <p>At 20th level, you are a maestro of music. Your Charisma score increases by 4. Your maximum for that score is now 24. Additionally, when you roll for initiative and have no uses of Songcraft remaining, you regain 1 use of it.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you roll for initiative and have no uses of Songcraft remaining, you regain 1 use of it.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="charisma:max" value="4" />
                <stat name="charisma" value="4" />
            </rules>
        </element>

    <!-- Musical Styles-->
    <element name="Battle Dancer" type="Archetype" source="The Minstrel Class" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_ARCHETYPE_MINSTREL_BATTLE_DANCER">
        <supports>Musical Style</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Many cultures share a need for warriors. And many warriors feed off of the adrenaline that comes from the pounding of drums, the chants of their comrades, and the rhythms of their battle cries. Battle dancers are fighters, lovers, and powerful allies.</p>
            <div element="ID_SHEM_TTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BATTLE_DANCER_WARDANCING" />
            <div element="ID_SHEM_TTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BATTLE_DANCER_BATTLE_CHANT" />
            <div element="ID_SHEM_TTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BATTLE_DANCER_EXTRA_ATTACK" />
            <div element="ID_SHEM_TTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BATTLE_DANCER_EXPLOSIVE_FINALE" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BATTLE_DANCER_WARDANCING" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BATTLE_DANCER_BATTLE_CHANT" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BATTLE_DANCER_EXTRA_ATTACK" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BATTLE_DANCER_EXPLOSIVE_FINALE" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Wardancing" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Minstrel Class" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BATTLE_DANCER_WARDANCING">
            <description>
                <p>At 2nd level, you gain proficiency with martial weapons, chakrams, and war fans.</p>
                <p class="indent">While you have at least one songspell active, being within 5 feet of a hostile creature doesn’t impose disadvantage on your ranged attack rolls with thrown weapons and attacks made by a thrown weapon ignores half cover and three-quarters cover. Additionally, while you have at least one songspell active, thrown weapons return to you at the end of your turn if you miss an attack with them.</p>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Special Weapons</td><td>Cost</td><td>Damage</td><td>Weight</td><td>Properties</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>Chakram</td><td>30 gp</td><td>1d6 slashing</td><td>1 lb.</td><td>Finesse, light, thrown (range 20/60)</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>War fan</td><td>10 gp</td><td>1d6 slashing or bludgeoning</td><td>1 lb.</td><td>Finesse, light, deflecting</td></tr>
                </table>
                <p class="indent">Deflecting</p>
                <p class="indent">A weapon with this property gains a +1 to AC against ranged weapon attacks. This bonus does not stack if you wield a second deflecting weapon.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>While you have at least one songspell active, being within 5 feet of a hostile creature doesn’t impose disadvantage on your ranged attack rolls with thrown weapons and attacks made by a thrown weapon ignores half cover and three-quarters cover. Additionally, while you have at least one songspell active, thrown weapons return to you at the end of your turn if you miss an attack with them.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_MARTIAL_WEAPONS" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_CHAKRAM" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_WAR_FAN" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Battle Chant" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Minstrel Class" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BATTLE_DANCER_BATTLE_CHANT">
            <description>
                <p>At 3rd level, you perform an aggressive and vigorous warcry that makes your foes cower before you. As an action, all creatures you choose within 30 feet of you must make a Charisma saving throw. The DC for this saving throw is equal to 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier. The DC increases by an additional +1 for every songspell you have active when you perform your battle chant.</p>
                <p class="indent">Creatures who fail this saving throw are shaken and receive a -1 penalty to their AC.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>All creatures you choose within 30 feet of you must make a Charisma saving throw (DC {{spellcasting:dc:cha}}) +1 per active songspell. Creatures who fail this saving throw are shaken and receive a -1 penalty to their AC.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Extra Attack" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Minstrel Class" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BATTLE_DANCER_EXTRA_ATTACK">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 6th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="extra attack:count" value="2" level="6" bonus="extra attack" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Explosive Finale" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Minstrel Class" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BATTLE_DANCER_EXPLOSIVE_FINALE">
            <description>
                <p>At 14th level, you can cause the magic of your songspells to explode—causing everything within vicinity of them to go up in flames.</p>
                <p class="indent">As an action, all creatures you choose within 30 feet of you must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, each target takes 4d8 fire damage for each songspell you have active, or half as much damage on a successful one.</p>
                <p class="indent">The fire spreads around corners. It ignites flammable objects in the area that aren’t being worn or carried.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can perform this feature a number of times equal to you Charisma modifier, regaining uses on a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="{{charisma:modifier}}/Long Rest">
                <description>All creatures you choose within 30 feet of you must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, each target takes 4d8 fire damage for each songspell you have active, or half as much damage on a successful one.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>

    <element name="Precentor" type="Archetype" source="The Minstrel Class" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_ARCHETYPE_MINSTREL_PRECENTOR">
        <supports>Musical Style</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Speakers, motivators—precentors are more than simple wordsmiths. Their voices drip with authority, power, influence, and meaning. Precentors do not waste words: for every breath and tongue holds secret power.</p>
            <div element="ID_SHEM_TTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PRECENTOR_BOLD_WORDS" />
            <div element="ID_SHEM_TTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PRECENTOR_BOLSTERING_PHRASE" />
            <div element="ID_SHEM_TTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PRECENTOR_TRUE_TONGUE" />
            <div element="ID_SHEM_TTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PRECENTOR_COUNTER_MELODY" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PRECENTOR_BOLD_WORDS" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PRECENTOR_BOLSTERING_PHRASE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PRECENTOR_TRUE_TONGUE" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PRECENTOR_COUNTER_MELODY" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Bold Words" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Minstrel Class" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PRECENTOR_BOLD_WORDS">
            <description>
                <p>Things you say are more than mere words and phrases. Beginning at 2nd level when you choose this style, you double your proficiency bonus when making Charisma (Persuasion and Intimidation) checks.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You double your proficiency bonus when making Persuasion and Intimidation checks.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="intimidation:proficiency" value="proficiency" bonus="double" />
                <stat name="persuasion:proficiency" value="proficiency" bonus="double" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Bolstering Phrase" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Minstrel Class" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PRECENTOR_BOLSTERING_PHRASE">
            <description>
                <p>At 3rd level, you can inspire your allies in remarkable ways. As a reaction, whenever a friendly creature within 60 feet of you makes an attack roll, ability check, or saving throw, you may grant them an additional d20 to roll. You can use this feature after the original roll, but before the outcome is revealed.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Reaction" usage="1/Short Rest">
                <description>As a reaction, whenever a friendly creature within 60 feet of you makes an attack roll, ability check, or saving throw, you may grant them an additional d20 to roll.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="True Tongue" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Minstrel Class" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PRECENTOR_TRUE_TONGUE">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 6th level, you hear and understand the songs of all tongues and understand all spoken Languages. Moreover, any creature that can understand a language can understand what you say.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You hear and understand the songs of all tongues and understand all spoken Languages. Moreover, any creature that can understand a language can understand what you say.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Counter Melody" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Minstrel Class" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PRECENTOR_COUNTER_MELODY">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 14th level, you can perform a musical phrase that negates certain magical effects. You can cast <i>counterspell</i> at will a number of times per day equal to your Charisma modifier. You regain uses of this feature after a long rest.</p>
                <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_COUNTERSPELL" />
            </description>
            <sheet usage="{{charisma:modifier}}/Long Rest">
                <description>You can cast counterspell.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COUNTERSPELL" />
            </rules>
        </element>

    <element name="String Maestra" type="Archetype" source="The Minstrel Class" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_ARCHETYPE_MINSTREL_STRING_MAESTRA">
        <supports>Musical Style</supports>
        <description>
            <p>String maestras have mastered the art of instruments such as the lute, vielle, or harp. Like their instruments, string maestras glide around the battlefield—constantly frustrating their opponents in their dance-like combat movements.</p>
            <div element="ID_SHEM_TTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STRING_MAESTRA_STRING_SLIDE" />
            <div element="ID_SHEM_TTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STRING_MAESTRA_SUSPENSEFUL_RISE" />
            <div element="ID_SHEM_TTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STRING_MAESTRA_NO_STRINGS_ON_ME" />
            <div element="ID_SHEM_TTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STRING_MAESTRA_MULTI_CHORD" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STRING_MAESTRA_STRING_SLIDE" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STRING_MAESTRA_SUSPENSEFUL_RISE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STRING_MAESTRA_NO_STRINGS_ON_ME" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STRING_MAESTRA_MULTI_CHORD" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="String Slide" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Minstrel Class" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STRING_MAESTRA_STRING_SLIDE">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your body to slip and glide like your fingers on strings. You can take a bonus action on each of your turns in combat. This action can be used only to take the Dash, Disengage, or Hide action.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>You can Dash, Disengage, or Hide.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Suspenseful Rise" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Minstrel Class" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STRING_MAESTRA_SUSPENSEFUL_RISE">
            <description>
                <p>At 3rd level, you can play a haunting sound with your instrument that elicits fear and nervousness in a creature. As an action, choose one target within 60 feet. The target must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or become frightened of you for 1 minute. The frightened target can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success. A construct or an undead is immune to this effect.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Short Rest">
                <description>Choose one target within 60 feet. The target must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or become frightened of you for 1 minute. The frightened target can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success. A construct or an undead is immune to this effect.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="No Strings on Me" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Minstrel Class" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STRING_MAESTRA_NO_STRINGS_ON_ME">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 6th level, you gain advantage on checks and saving throws to avoid being grappled, paralyzed, or restrained.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You have advantage on checks and saving throws to avoid being grappled, paralyzed, or restrained.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Multi Chord" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Minstrel Class" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STRING_MAESTRA_MULTI_CHORD">
            <description>
                <p>At 14th level, you can play each of your strings on your instrument and fire a magical ray of power. You can cast <i>prismatic spray</i> at will. Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a long rest.</p>
                <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_PRISTMATIC_SPRAY" />
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can cast prismatic spray.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PRISTMATIC_SPRAY" />
            </rules>
        </element>

    <element name="Rhythm Knight" type="Archetype" source="The Minstrel Class" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_ARCHETYPE_MINSTREL_RHYTHM_KNIGHT">
        <supports>Musical Style</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Wartime drummers have marched their way throughout much of the land’s history. But no simple drummer plays like a rhythm knight—for these warriors bring the thirst for combat and battle with them into the marches of war.</p>
            <div element="ID_SHEM_TTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RHYTHM_KNIGHT_INTO_BATTLE" />
            <div element="ID_SHEM_TTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RHYTHM_KNIGHT_FEEL_THE_RHYTHM" />
            <div element="ID_SHEM_TTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RHYTHM_KNIGHT_WAR_MARCH" />
            <div element="ID_SHEM_TTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RHYTHM_KNIGHT_THUNDER_SHEET" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RHYTHM_KNIGHT_INTO_BATTLE" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RHYTHM_KNIGHT_FEEL_THE_RHYTHM" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RHYTHM_KNIGHT_WAR_MARCH" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RHYTHM_KNIGHT_THUNDER_SHEET" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Into Battle" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Minstrel Class" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RHYTHM_KNIGHT_INTO_BATTLE">
            <description>
                <p>At 2nd level, you gain proficiency in heavy armor. In addition, you gain resistance to thunder and bludgeoning damage.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false" />
            <rules>
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_HEAVY_ARMOR" />
                <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_THUNDER" />
                <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_BLUDGEONING" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Feel the Rhythm" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Minstrel Class" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RHYTHM_KNIGHT_FEEL_THE_RHYTHM">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 3rd level, you gain tremorsense and can detect and pinpoint the origin of vibrations within 30 feet, provided that you and the source of the vibrations are in contact with the same ground or substance.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You have tremorsense and can detect and pinpoint the origin of vibrations within 30 feet, provided that you and the source of the vibrations are in contact with the same ground or substance.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="War March" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Minstrel Class" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RHYTHM_KNIGHT_WAR_MARCH">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning 6th level, you can play a battle march that brings confidence and power to your allies. You can cast <i>crusader’s mantle</i> at will with your instrument.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can perform this feature a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier and regain uses after a long rest.</p>
                <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_CRUSADERS_MANTLE" />
            </description>
            <sheet usage="{{charisma:modifier}}/Long Rest">
                <description>You can cast crusader’s mantle at will with your instrument.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CRUSADERS_MANTLE" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Thunder Sheet" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Minstrel Class" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RHYTHM_KNIGHT_THUNDER_SHEET">
            <description>
                <p>At 14th level, as an action, you can strike your instrument to create a thundering pillar of sound. Each creature in a 10-foot wide and 120-foot long line in a direction you choose must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save a creature takes 10d8 thunder damage and is deafened for 10 minutes. On a successful save, it takes half as much damage and is deafened until the end of your next turn.</p>
                <p class="indent">A creature deafened by this spell makes another Constitution saving throw at the end of each of its turns. On a successful save, it is no longer deafened.</p>
                <p class="indent">The pillar disperses gas or vapor, and it extinguishes candles, torches, and similar unprotected flames in the area. It causes protected flames, such as those of lanterns, to dance wildly and has a 75 percent chance to extinguish them.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>Each creature in a 10-foot wide and 120-foot long line in a direction you choose must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save a creature takes 10d8 thunder damage and is deafened for 10 minutes. On a successful save, it takes half as much damage and is deafened until the end of your next turn.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>

    <!-- Songspells -->
        <element name="Adohorn’s Foruitous Medley" type="Spell" source="The Minstrel Class" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_SONGSPELL_ADOHORNS_FORUITOUS_MEDLEY">
            <supports>Minstrel Songspell</supports>
            <description>
                <p>You can clear and refocus a creature’s mind. Make a Charisma (Performance) check. One creature of your choice within 30 feet of you gains a bonus to Intelligence, Wisdom, and Charisma based skill checks depending on your Charisma (Performance) result.</p>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Check Result</td><td>Effect</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1-24</td><td>+2 bonus on Intelligence, Wisdom, and Charisma based skill checks</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>24-29</td><td>+3 bonus on Intelligence, Wisdom, and Charisma based skill checks</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>30+</td><td>+4 bonus on Intelligence, Wisdom, and Charisma based skill checks</td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="keywords"></set>
                <set name="level">1</set>
                <set name="school">Songspell</set>
                <set name="time">1 action</set>
                <set name="range">30 feet</set>
                <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
                <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
                <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
                <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
                <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
        <element name="Ballad of the Blue Morpho" type="Spell" source="The Minstrel Class" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_SONGSPELL_BALLAD_OF_THE_BLUE_MORPHO">
            <supports>Minstrel Songspell</supports>
            <description>
                <p>You can cause a creature’s body to become more swift and agile. Make a Charisma (Performance) check. One creature of your choice within 30 feet of you gains a bonus to AC when targeted by ranged attacks depending on your Charisma (Performance) result.</p>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Check Result</td><td>Effect</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1-24</td><td>+2 AC vs ranged attacks</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>24-29</td><td>+3 AC vs ranged attacks</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>30+</td><td>+4 AC vs ranged attacks</td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="keywords"></set>
                <set name="level">1</set>
                <set name="school">Songspell</set>
                <set name="time">1 action</set>
                <set name="range">30 feet</set>
                <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
                <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
                <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
                <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
                <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
        <element name="Charin’s Ode to the Wind" type="Spell" source="The Minstrel Class" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_SONGSPELL_CHARINS_ODE_TO_THE_WIND">
            <supports>Minstrel Songspell</supports>
            <description>
                <p>You cause bolts and blasts to fly true. Make a Charisma (Performance) check. One creature of your choice within 30 feet of you gains a bonus on ranged attack rolls depending on your Charisma (Performance) result.</p>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Check Result</td><td>Effect</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1-24</td><td>+2 to ranged attack rolls</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>24-29</td><td>+3 to ranged attack rolls</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>30+</td><td>+4 to ranged attack rolls</td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="keywords"></set>
                <set name="level">1</set>
                <set name="school">Songspell</set>
                <set name="time">1 action</set>
                <set name="range">30 feet</set>
                <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
                <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
                <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
                <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
                <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
        <element name="Christopher Faith’s Steel Waltz" type="Spell" source="The Minstrel Class" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_SONGSPELL_CHRISTOPHER_FAITHS_STEEL_WALTZ">
            <supports>Minstrel Songspell</supports>
            <description>
                <p>You can cause a creature’s skin to harden. Make a Charisma (Performance) check. One creature of your choice within 30 feet of you gains a bonus to AC when targeted by melee attacks depending on your Charisma (Performance) result.</p>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Check Result</td><td>Effect</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1-24</td><td>+2 AC vs melee attacks</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>24-29</td><td>+3 AC vs melee attacks</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>30+</td><td>+4 AC vs melee attacks</td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="keywords"></set>
                <set name="level">1</set>
                <set name="school">Songspell</set>
                <set name="time">1 action</set>
                <set name="range">30 feet</set>
                <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
                <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
                <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
                <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
                <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
        <element name="Dirge of the Spider Queen" type="Spell" source="The Minstrel Class" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_SONGSPELL_DIRGE_OF_THE_SPIDER_QUEEN">
            <supports>Minstrel Songspell</supports>
            <description>
                <p>You can allow a creature to traverse vertical surfaces with ease. Make a Charisma (Performance) check. One creature of your choice within 30 feet of you gains a swim speed depending on your Charisma (Performance) result.</p>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Check Result</td><td>Effect</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1-24</td><td>30 feet climb speed</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>24-29</td><td>40 feet climb speed</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>30+</td><td>50 feet climb speed</td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="keywords"></set>
                <set name="level">1</set>
                <set name="school">Songspell</set>
                <set name="time">1 action</set>
                <set name="range">30 feet</set>
                <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
                <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
                <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
                <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
                <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
        <element name="Elazzin’s Baroque" type="Spell" source="The Minstrel Class" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_SONGSPELL_ELAZZINS_BAROQUE">
            <supports>Minstrel Songspell</supports>
            <description>
                <p>You add brevity to a creature’s gait. Make a Charisma (Performance) check. One creature of your choice within 30 feet of you gains a bonus to its speed depending on your Charisma (Performance) result.</p>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Check Result</td><td>Effect</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1-24</td><td>+10 feet movement speed</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>24-29</td><td>+20 feet movement speed</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>30+</td><td>+30 feet movement speed</td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="keywords"></set>
                <set name="level">1</set>
                <set name="school">Songspell</set>
                <set name="time">1 action</set>
                <set name="range">30 feet</set>
                <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
                <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
                <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
                <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
                <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
        <element name="Gilliam’s Recitation" type="Spell" source="The Minstrel Class" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_SONGSPELL_GILLIAMS_RECITATION">
            <supports>Minstrel Songspell</supports>
            <description>
                <p>You can steel a creature’s mind and soul. Make a Charisma (Performance) check. One creature of your choice within 30 feet of you gains a bonus to Intelligence, Wisdom, and Charisma saving throws depending on your Charisma (Performance) result.</p>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Check Result</td><td>Effect</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1-24</td><td>+2 bonus on Intelligence, Wisdom, and Charisma saving throws</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>24-29</td><td>+3 bonus on Intelligence, Wisdom, and Charisma saving throws</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>30+</td><td>+4 bonus on Intelligence, Wisdom, and Charisma saving throws</td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="keywords"></set>
                <set name="level">1</set>
                <set name="school">Songspell</set>
                <set name="time">1 action</set>
                <set name="range">30 feet</set>
                <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
                <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
                <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
                <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
                <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
        <element name="Grok’s War Chant" type="Spell" source="The Minstrel Class" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_SONGSPELL_GROKS_WAR_CHANT">
            <supports>Minstrel Songspell</supports>
            <description>
                <p>You stir a ferocity inside of your allies. Make a Charisma (Performance) check. One creature of your choice within 30 feet of you gains a bonus die on damage rolls depending on your Charisma (Performance) result.</p>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Check Result</td><td>Effect</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1-24</td><td>1d8 on damage rolls</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>24-29</td><td>1d10 on damage rolls</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>30+</td><td>1d12 on damage rolls</td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="keywords"></set>
                <set name="level">1</set>
                <set name="school">Songspell</set>
                <set name="time">1 action</set>
                <set name="range">30 feet</set>
                <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
                <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
                <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
                <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
                <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
        <element name="Hendrickson’s Chanson" type="Spell" source="The Minstrel Class" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_SONGSPELL_HENDRICKSONS_CHANSON">
            <supports>Minstrel Songspell</supports>
            <description>
                <p>You can call upon elemental energies to protect your allies. Make a Charisma (Performance) check and choose one type of damage: acid, cold, fire, lightning, necrotic, radiant, or thunder. One creature of your choice within 30 feet of you has the chosen type of damage reduced by a certain amount depending on your Charisma (Performance) result.</p>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Check Result</td><td>Effect</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1-24</td><td>Energy damage reduced by 1d6</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>24-29</td><td>Energy damage reduced by 1d8</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>30+</td><td>Energy damage reduced by 1d12</td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="keywords"></set>
                <set name="level">1</set>
                <set name="school">Songspell</set>
                <set name="time">1 action</set>
                <set name="range">30 feet</set>
                <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
                <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
                <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
                <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
                <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
        <element name="Maideth’s Merciful Melody" type="Spell" source="The Minstrel Class" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_SONGSPELL_MAIDETHS_MERCIFUL_MELODY">
            <supports>Minstrel Songspell</supports>
            <description>
                <p>You can mend wounds and revitalize your allies. Make a Charisma (Performance) check. One creature of your choice within 30 feet of you regains an amount of hit points depending on your Charisma (Performance) result. Additionally, that creature regains 1 hit point at the beginning of its next turn.</p>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Check Result</td><td>Effect</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1-24</td><td>1d8 hit points</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>24-29</td><td>1d10 hit points</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>30+</td><td>1d12 hit points</td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="keywords"></set>
                <set name="level">1</set>
                <set name="school">Songspell</set>
                <set name="time">1 action</set>
                <set name="range">30 feet</set>
                <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
                <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
                <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
                <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
                <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
        <element name="Rondeau’s Aquan Shanty" type="Spell" source="The Minstrel Class" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_SONGSPELL_RONDEAUS_AQUAN_SHANTY">
            <supports>Minstrel Songspell</supports>
            <description>
                <p>You can allow a creature to glide through water with ease. Make a Charisma (Performance) check. One creature of your choice within 30 feet of you gains a swim speed depending on your Charisma (Performance) result.</p>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Check Result</td><td>Effect</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1-24</td><td>30 feet swim speed</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>24-29</td><td>40 feet swim speed</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>30+</td><td>50 feet swim speed</td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="keywords"></set>
                <set name="level">1</set>
                <set name="school">Songspell</set>
                <set name="time">1 action</set>
                <set name="range">30 feet</set>
                <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
                <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
                <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
                <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
                <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
        <element name="Swiftfoot’s Tribute" type="Spell" source="The Minstrel Class" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_SONGSPELL_SWIFTFOOTS_TRIBUTE">
            <supports>Minstrel Songspell</supports>
            <description>
                <p>You can fill a creature’s body with vigor. Make a Charisma (Performance) check. One creature of your choice within 30 feet of you gains a bonus to Strength, Dexterity, and Constitution saving throws depending on your Charisma (Performance) result.</p>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Check Result</td><td>Effect</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1-24</td><td>+2 bonus on Strength, Dexterity, and Constitution saving throws</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>24-29</td><td>+3 bonus on Strength, Dexterity, and Constitution saving throws</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>30+</td><td>+4 bonus on Strength, Dexterity, and Constitution saving throws</td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="keywords"></set>
                <set name="level">1</set>
                <set name="school">Songspell</set>
                <set name="time">1 action</set>
                <set name="range">30 feet</set>
                <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
                <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
                <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
                <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
                <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
        <element name="The Aria of Byron MacRae" type="Spell" source="The Minstrel Class" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_SONGSPELL_THE_ARIA_OF_BYRON_MACRAE">
            <supports>Minstrel Songspell</supports>
            <description>
                <p>You can hone a creature’s physical finesse. Make a Charisma (Performance) check. One creature of your choice within 30 feet of you gains a bonus to Strength, Dexterity, and Constitution based skill checks depending on your Charisma (Performance) result.</p>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Check Result</td><td>Effect</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1-24</td><td>+2 bonus on Strength, Dexterity, and Constitution based skill checks</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>24-29</td><td>+3 bonus on Strength, Dexterity, and Constitution based skill checks</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>30+</td><td>+4 bonus on Strength, Dexterity, and Constitution based skill checks</td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="keywords"></set>
                <set name="level">1</set>
                <set name="school">Songspell</set>
                <set name="time">1 action</set>
                <set name="range">30 feet</set>
                <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
                <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
                <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
                <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
                <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
        <element name="The Ballet of Umbra Viator" type="Spell" source="The Minstrel Class" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_SONGSPELL_THE_BALLET_OF_UMBRA_VIATOR">
            <supports>Minstrel Songspell</supports>
            <description>
                <p>You can cause the wind beneath a creature to rise. Make a Charisma (Performance) check. One creature of your choice within 30 feet of you gains a flying speed depending on your Charisma (Performance) result.</p>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Check Result</td><td>Effect</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1-24</td><td>30 feet flying speed</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>24-29</td><td>40 feet flying speed</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>30+</td><td>50 feet flying speed</td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="keywords"></set>
                <set name="level">1</set>
                <set name="school">Songspell</set>
                <set name="time">1 action</set>
                <set name="range">30 feet</set>
                <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
                <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
                <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
                <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
                <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
        <element name="The Courageous Lion, Roland" type="Spell" source="The Minstrel Class" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_SONGSPELL_THE_COURAGEOUS_LION_ROLAND">
            <supports>Minstrel Songspell</supports>
            <description>
                <p>You spark a rigorous zeal in your allies and encourage them to wade into battle. Make a Charisma (Performance) check. One creature of your choice within 30 feet of you gains a bonus on melee attack rolls depending on your Charisma (Performance) result.</p>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Check Result</td><td>Effect</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1-24</td><td>+2 to melee attack rolls</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>24-29</td><td>+3 to melee attack rolls</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>30+</td><td>+4 to melee attack rolls</td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="keywords"></set>
                <set name="level">1</set>
                <set name="school">Songspell</set>
                <set name="time">1 action</set>
                <set name="range">30 feet</set>
                <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
                <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
                <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
                <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
                <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            </setters>
        </element>

    <!-- Special Weapons -->
        <element name="Chakram" type="Weapon" source="The Minstrel Class" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_WEAPON_CHAKRAM">
            <supports>ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_RANGED, ID_INTERNAL_DAMAGE_TYPE_SLASHING, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_THROWN, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_THROWN</supports>
            <description>
                <p></p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="category">Weapons</set>
                <set name="cost" currency="gp">30</set>
                <set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
                <set name="slot">onehand</set>
                <set name="range">20/60</set>
                <set name="damage" type="slashing">1d6</set>
                <set name="proficiency">ID_SHEM_TTC_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_CHAKRAM</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
            <element name="Weapon Proficiency (Chakram)" type="Proficiency" source="The Minstrel Class" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_CHAKRAM">
                <supports>Weapon, Martial, Ranged, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_RANGED, ID_INTERNAL_DAMAGE_TYPE_SLASHING, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_THROWN, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_SPECIAL, ID_SHEM_TTC_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_SPECIAL_CHAKRAM</supports>
            </element>

        <element name="War Fan" type="Weapon" source="The Minstrel Class" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_WEAPON_WAR_FAN">
            <supports>Weapon, Martial, Melee, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_MELEE,ID_INTERNAL_DAMAGE_TYPE_SLASHING, ID_INTERNAL_DAMAGE_TYPE_BLUDGEONING, ID_SHEM_TTC_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_DEFLECTING</supports>
            <description>
                <p></p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="category">Weapons</set>
                <set name="cost" currency="gp">10</set>
                <set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
                <set name="slot">onehand</set>
                <set name="damage" type="slashing">1d6</set>
                <set name="proficiency">ID_SHEM_TTC_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_WAR_FAN</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
            <element name="Deflecting" type="Weapon Property" source="The Minstrel Class" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_DEFLECTING">
                <description>
                    <p>When you make an attack roll with a chakram it automatically returns to your hand after the attack is resolved regardless if it hit or missed, unless the roll was a 1.</p>
                </description>
            </element>
            <element name="Weapon Proficiency (War Fan)" type="Proficiency" source="The Minstrel Class" id="ID_SHEM_TTC_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_WAR_FAN">
                <supports>Weapon, Martial, Melee, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_MELEE, ID_INTERNAL_DAMAGE_TYPE_SLASHING, ID_INTERNAL_DAMAGE_TYPE_BLUDGEONING, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_FINESSE, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_LIGHT, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_SPECIAL, ID_SHEM_TTC_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_SPECIAL_CHAKRAM</supports>
            </element>

</elements>