<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Demon Hunter</name>
        <update version="0.0.2">
            <file name="class-demon-hunter.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/classes/class-demon-hunter.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="The Demon Hunter" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_DODST_GMBINDER_SOURCE_THE_DEMON_HUNTER">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation">TDH</set>
            <set name="url">https://www.gmbinder.com/share/-MItlb8G9fFrwfkrGciD</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" abbreviation="DODST" url="https://www.gmbinder.com/profile/dodst">Dodst</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20210105</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Demon Hunter" type="Class" source="The Demon Hunter" id="ID_DODST_TDH_CLASS_DEMON_HUNTER">
        <description>
            <p>A lady holds a silent breath as she slides a bolt into her crossbow. Hidden behind debris she watches as a bone devil stalks the remains of a village it has destroyed. Knowing that the devil is unsuspecting, she bolts out of her hiding spot to lay waste to the fiend, as her companion emboldens her presence</p>
            <p class="indent">The creatures surround the man, hiding out of sight amidst the shadows. stalking him, preparing. They have been gathering for hours as he waits, calm, collected. They prepare their numbers for their imminent attacks, launching into sight hoping to catch him off guard. He smiles, for the prey have finally gathered for the predator.</p>
            <p class="indent">A haggard halfling wanders out of what was once a town. The buildings have collapsed walls, and burn marks, while the center of town is but a patch of scorched earth, the devils that had been there prior, but ash in the wind.</p>
            <p class="indent">Upon the fields of slaughter, a lone human transforms, bearing the form of an angel. He makes quick work of the gnolls that descend on his location, drawing his blade from their corpses and heading in the direction of the demon Yeenoghu, for it is time for them to settle their battle.</p>
            <h4>BOND OF THE FALLEN</h4>
            <p>Demons hunters are those who are lucky enough to cross paths with a fallen divinity, or other powerful divinity. Though not a god, an angel can still grant power, and before you lay one broken, dying, tainted by the demons it fought. Looking in its eyes, you can tell that it still refuses to give up. Alternatively, an angel or powerful demon hunter may share a part of their divine essence with you, allowing you to combat future threats, and help others, by forming a demi-angel within you. Its war has not ended, and it is ready to do anything to complete its task, and so it offers you a deal, allowing it to recuperate within your body. When you die, its body will reform and it can return to battle, in the meantime it will train you, altering your body to withstand the horrors of the demonic planes, and granting you power that few achieve in their lifetimes.</p>
            <h4>THE PINNACLE OF HUNTERS</h4>
            <p>Warriors of the mortal realms, demon hunters specialize in hunting the monsters that threaten the mortal planes, be them demons, devils, or the likes of the undead liches, and aberrant aberrations. They learn to track their targets as the apex predators of the realms, using an assortment of knowledge, skill and magic to find any hunt, wherever it may choose to hide. They move stealthily through the destruction of their foes, and strike when the enemy least expects it. Demon hunters focus their combat training on techniques that will slay fiends quickly, so that they may help those in need quickly and efficiently.</p>
            <p class="indent">Thanks to their familiarity with fiends, demon hunters acquire the ability to cast spells that utilize the divine powers granted to them by the angels, much as a cleric or paladin would. Their spells, like their combat abilities, emphasize speed, stealth, and the decimation of all that is deemed unholy and demonic. A demon hunter’s talents and abilities are honed with the grim purpose of fighting a never ending war against the most formidable of enemies.</p>
            <h4>CREATING A DEMON HUNTER</h4>
            <p>As you create your demon hunter character, consider what led you to the presence of an angel or other celestial/ godlike power, and what led you to accept its powers and become its host? Was your village caught in the battle between the angel and a demon? Was your sister stolen as a child by cultists for a dark ritual and now you seek the power to destroy what was summoned? Was it by happenstance that you came across the body of a dying angel, who had escaped from the outer realms only to lay there dying in the woods? Or perhaps you are a part of a special order that fights alongside angels, and acts as hosts in extreme situations, teaching you the secrets of fighting the abyss and hells while preparing you to save the life of a divine warrior.</p>
            <p class="indent">You might be a normal person who wound up in a situation that you can barely handle, and now must fight for your life.</p>
            <p class="indent">Why do you hate more than demons, going so far as to train to target another species beyond demons and devils? Did a monster kill someone you loved or was it employed by the likes of Orcus? Or do you deem them as dangerous as the demons you squander, actively attempting to protect people from multiple fronts? Is your adventuring career a means to an end, or a significant change? What made you join up with a band of adventurers? Do you find it challenging to socialize with those who haven’t faced horrors from the outer realms, or do you welcome the relief from solitude that they offer?</p>
            <h5>QUICK BUILD</h5>
            <p>You can make a demon hunter quickly by following these suggestions. First make Dexterity your highest ability score, followed by Intelligence. Second choose the acolyte background.</p>
            <h2>CLASS FEATURES</h2>
            <p>As an demon hunter, you gain the following class features.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">HIT POINTS</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Hit Dice:</strong> 1d8 per demon hunter level</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at 1st Level:</strong> 8 + your Constitution modifier</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at Higher Levels:</strong> 1d8 (or 5) + your Constitution modifier per demon hunter level after 1st</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">PROFICIENCIES</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled mb">
                <li><strong>Armor:</strong> Light armor, medium armor</li>
                <li><strong>Weapons:</strong> Simple weapons, hand crossbow, heavy crossbow, shortsword, rapier</li>
                <li><strong>Tools:</strong> Alchemist’s supplies, thieves’ tools</li>
            </ul>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Saving Throws:</strong> Dexterity, Intelligence</li>
                <li><strong>Skills:</strong> Choose three skills from Acrobatics, Athletics, Arcana, Deception, History, Insight, Investigation, Nature, Perception, Stealth, and Survival</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">EQUIPMENT</h5>
            <p>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>(a) a rapier or (b) a shortsword</li>
                <li>(a) a hand crossbow with 20 bolts or (b) a light crossbow with 20 bolts</li>
                <li>(a) a dungeoneer’s pack or (b) An explorer’s pack</li>
                <li>Studded leather armor, a dagger, and an arcane focus</li>
            </ul>
            <h5>STARTING EQUIPMENT</h5>
            <p>When you create your demon hunter, you receive equipment based on a combination of your class and background. You can however choose to instead start out with a number of gold pieces based on the following chart and spend the gold on items from the equipment lists in Chapter 5 of the Players Handbook.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">Starting Wealth</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Class</td><td>Ability Score Minimum</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>Demon Hunter</td><td>3d6 x 10 gp</td></tr>
            </table>
        <!-- class table here -->
            <h5 class="caption">THE DEMON HUNTER</h5>
            <table class="class-features">
                <thead>
                    <tr><td class="col-5">Level</td><td class="col-10">Proficiency Bonus</td><td class="col-60 left">Features</td><td class="col-10">Radiant Strikes</td><td class="col-10">Cantrips Known</td><td class="col-10">Spells Known</td><td class="col-10">Spell Slot</td><td class="col-10">Slot Level</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td> 1st</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Radiant Strikes, Targets of Enmity</td><td>1d6</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 2nd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Fighting Style, Hunter’s Path, Pact Magic</td><td>1d6</td><td>1</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>1st</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 3rd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Metamorphosis</td><td>1d6</td><td>1</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>1st</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 4th</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Ability Score Increase, Martial Versatility (Optional)</td><td>1d6</td><td>2</td><td>3</td><td>1</td><td>1st</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 5th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Multiattack</td><td>1d8</td><td>2</td><td>3</td><td>1</td><td>2nd</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 6th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Hunter’s Sense, Keen Insight</td><td>1d8</td><td>2</td><td>4</td><td>2</td><td>2nd</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 7th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Hunter’s Path Feature</td><td>1d8</td><td>2</td><td>4</td><td>2</td><td>2nd</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 8th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Ability Score Increase, Martial Versatility (Optional)</td><td>1d8</td><td>2</td><td>5</td><td>2</td><td>2nd</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 9th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Upgraded Metamorphosis</td><td>1d8</td><td>3</td><td>5</td><td>2</td><td>3rd</td></tr>
                <tr><td>10th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">─</td><td>1d8</td><td>3</td><td>6</td><td>2</td><td>3rd</td></tr>
                <tr><td>11th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Hunter’s Path Feature</td><td>1d10</td><td>3</td><td>6</td><td>3</td><td>3rd</td></tr>
                <tr><td>12th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Ability Score Increase, Martial Versatility (Optional)</td><td>1d10</td><td>3</td><td>7</td><td>3</td><td>3rd</td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Demonic Resistance</td><td>1d10</td><td>3</td><td>7</td><td>3</td><td>4th</td></tr>
                <tr><td>14th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Hunter’s Path Feature</td><td>1d10</td><td>3</td><td>8</td><td>3</td><td>4th</td></tr>
                <tr><td>15th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">─</td><td>1d10</td><td>4</td><td>8</td><td>3</td><td>4th</td></tr>
                <tr><td>16th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Ability Score Increase, Martial Versatility (Optional)</td><td>1d10</td><td>4</td><td>9</td><td>4</td><td>4th</td></tr>
                <tr><td>17th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">─</td><td>1d12</td><td>4</td><td>9</td><td>4</td><td>5th</td></tr>
                <tr><td>18th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Hunter’s Path Feature</td><td>1d12</td><td>4</td><td>10</td><td>4</td><td>5th</td></tr>
                <tr><td>19th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Ability Score Increase, Martial Versatility (Optional)</td><td>1d12</td><td>4</td><td>10</td><td>4</td><td>5th</td></tr>
                <tr><td>20th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">True Metamorphosis</td><td>1d12</td><td>4</td><td>11</td><td>4</td><td>5th</td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_DODST_TDH_CLASS_FEATURE_DEMON_HUNTER_RADIANT_STRIKES" />
            <div element="ID_DODST_TDH_CLASS_FEATURE_DEMON_HUNTER_TARGETS_OF_ENMITY" />
            <div element="ID_DODST_TDH_CLASS_FEATURE_DEMON_HUNTER_FIGHTING_STYLE" />
            <div element="ID_DODST_TDH_CLASS_FEATURE_DEMON_HUNTER_HUNTERS_PATH" />
            <div element="ID_DODST_TDH_CLASS_FEATURE_DEMON_HUNTER_PACT_MAGIC" />
            <div element="ID_DODST_TDH_CLASS_FEATURE_DEMON_HUNTER_METAMORPHOSIS" />
            <div element="ID_DODST_TDH_CLASS_FEATURE_DEMON_HUNTER_ABILITY_SCORE_INCREASE" />
            <div element="ID_DODST_TDH_CLASS_FEATURE_DEMON_HUNTER_MARTIAL_VERSATILITY" />
            <div element="ID_DODST_TDH_CLASS_FEATURE_DEMON_HUNTER_EXTRA_ATTACK" />
            <div element="ID_DODST_TDH_CLASS_FEATURE_DEMON_HUNTER_HUNTERS_SENSE" />
            <div element="ID_DODST_TDH_CLASS_FEATURE_DEMON_HUNTER_KEEN_INSIGHT" />
            <div element="ID_DODST_TDH_CLASS_FEATURE_DEMON_HUNTER_UPGRADED_METAMORPHOSIS" />
            <div element="ID_DODST_TDH_CLASS_FEATURE_DEMON_HUNTER_DEMONIC_RESISTANCE" />
            <div element="ID_DODST_TDH_CLASS_FEATURE_DEMON_HUNTER_TRUE_METAMORPHOSIS" />
            <h3>MULTICLASSING</h3>
            <p>Multiclassing can allow you to gain levels in multiple classes. The following information will help you with multiclassing into the demon hunter class.</p>
            <h5>PREREQUISITES</h5>
            <p>To qualify for a new class, you must meet the ability score prerequisites for both your current class, and the class you wish to multiclass into.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">Prerequisites</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Class</td><td>Ability Score Minimum</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>Demon Hunter</td><td>Dexterity 13 and Intelligence 13</td></tr>
            </table>
            <h5>PROFICIENCIES</h5>
            <p>When you gain a level in a class other than your first, you only gain some of that class’s starting proficiencies, as shown in the Multiclassing Proficiencies table.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">Multiclassing Proficiencies</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Class</td><td>Proficiencies Gained</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>Demon Hunter</td><td>Light armor, medium armor, simple weapons, hand crossbow, heavy crossbow, shortsword, rapierEpic Level Demon Hunter</td></tr>
            </table>
            <h2>EPIC LEVEL DEMON HUNTER</h2>
            <p>This section is meant to be an extension of the core class, and is designed to work with the Epic Levels document created by redditer by /u/Henry_smithy.</p>
            <p class="indent">Team Brievary holds no affiliation with /u/Henry_smithy. Use this content at your own discretion.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">EPIC LEVEL DEMON HUNTER</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Level</td><td>Proficiency Bonus</td><td>Features</td><td>Radiant Strikes</td><td>Cantrips Known</td><td>Spells Known</td><td>Spell Slot</td><td>Slot Level</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>21st</td><td>+7</td><td>Shifting Movement</td><td>1d12</td><td>4</td><td>11</td><td>5</td><td>5th</td></tr>
                <tr><td>22nd</td><td>+7</td><td>—</td><td>1d12</td><td>4</td><td>12</td><td>5</td><td>5th</td></tr>
                <tr><td>23rd</td><td>+7</td><td>Gift of the Damned</td><td>1d20</td><td>4</td><td>12</td><td>5</td><td>5th</td></tr>
                <tr><td>24th</td><td>+7</td><td>Ability Score Improvement</td><td>1d20</td><td>4</td><td>13</td><td>5</td><td>5th</td></tr>
                <tr><td>25th</td><td>+8</td><td>Divine Manifestation</td><td>1d20</td><td>4</td><td>13</td><td>5</td><td>5th</td></tr>
            </table>
            <h4>SHIFTING MOVEMENT</h4>
            <p>You understand the boundaries of the realms. You can spend 3 radiant points to cast dimension door as a bonus action.</p>
            <h4>GIFT OF THE DAMNED</h4>
            <p>You have seen as much bloodshed as the damned souls of the hells. Your symbiotic partner has also witness death beyond count, and together you have formed a method to prevent more from falling in your presence. You can spend 1 minute shifting a portion of the divine essence of the angel within you to cast resurrection on one target. Once you have used this feature, you must wait 28 days before you can cast it again, replenishing the divine essence sacrificed.</p>
            <p class="indent">There is a possibility that the resurrected soul will awaken as a demon hunter, and the essence can form it’s own conscience, becoming an angel one day.</p>
            <h4>DIVINE MANIFESTATION</h4>
            <p>Beginning at 25th level, your body undergoes a change rarely seen within demon hunters. You have long since surpassed the abilities of even the best of the demon hunters, and you are no longer a mere host to a angel, but have become a celestial yourself, the two souls merging into one new being. You are now considered a celestial for the purposes of spells and features, and a translucent form of your wings are always visible, though metamorphosis much be used to fully manifest them.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you have undergone this change, you also gain the following benefits.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Angelic Assistance.</i></b> You can expend two of your radiant points to heal another creature. The target regains 22 (4d8+4) hit points and is freed from any curse, disease, poison, blindness, or deafness.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Divine Resistance.</i></b> When you fail a saving throw against a spell of 5th level or lower, you can choose to succeed instead. Once you’ve used this feature, you must finish a short or long rest before you use it again.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="hd">d8</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_MEDIUM_ARMOR" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_CROSSBOW_HAND" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_CROSSBOW_HEAVY" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SHORTSWORD" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_RAPIER" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_ALCHEMISTS_SUPPLIES" requirements="!ID_DODST_TDH_CLASS_DEMON_HUNTER" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_THIEVES_TOOLS" requirements="!ID_DODST_TDH_CLASS_DEMON_HUNTER" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_DEXTERITY" requirements="!ID_DODST_TDH_CLASS_DEMON_HUNTER" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_INTELLIGENCE" requirements="!ID_DODST_TDH_CLASS_DEMON_HUNTER" />
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency, Demon Hunter" supports="Skill, Demon Hunter" number="3" requirements="!ID_DODST_TDH_CLASS_DEMON_HUNTER" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_DODST_TDH_CLASS_FEATURE_DEMON_HUNTER_RADIANT_STRIKES" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_DODST_TDH_CLASS_FEATURE_DEMON_HUNTER_TARGETS_OF_ENMITY" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_DODST_TDH_CLASS_FEATURE_DEMON_HUNTER_FIGHTING_STYLE" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_DODST_TDH_CLASS_FEATURE_DEMON_HUNTER_HUNTERS_PATH" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_DODST_TDH_CLASS_FEATURE_DEMON_HUNTER_PACT_MAGIC" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_DODST_TDH_CLASS_FEATURE_DEMON_HUNTER_METAMORPHOSIS" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_DODST_TDH_CLASS_FEATURE_DEMON_HUNTER_ABILITY_SCORE_INCREASE" level="4" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_DODST_TDH_CLASS_FEATURE_DEMON_HUNTER_MARTIAL_VERSATILITY" level="5" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_DODST_TDH_CLASS_FEATURE_DEMON_HUNTER_EXTRA_ATTACK" level="5" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_DODST_TDH_CLASS_FEATURE_DEMON_HUNTER_HUNTERS_SENSE" level="6" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_DODST_TDH_CLASS_FEATURE_DEMON_HUNTER_KEEN_INSIGHT" level="6" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_DODST_TDH_CLASS_FEATURE_DEMON_HUNTER_UPGRADED_METAMORPHOSIS" level="9" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_DODST_TDH_CLASS_FEATURE_DEMON_HUNTER_DEMONIC_RESISTANCE" level="13" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_DODST_TDH_CLASS_FEATURE_DEMON_HUNTER_TRUE_METAMORPHOSIS" level="20" />
        </rules>
        <multiclass id="ID_DODST_TDH_MULTICLASS_DEMON_HUNTER">
            <prerequisite>Dexterity 13 and Intelligence 13</prerequisite>
            <requirements>[dex:13],[int:13]</requirements>
            <setters>
                <set name="multiclass proficiencies">Light armor, medium armor, simple weapons, hand crossbow, heavy crossbow, shortsword, rapier</set>
            </setters>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS" />
            </rules>
        </multiclass>
    </element>
        <element name="Radiant Strikes" type="Class Feature" source="The Demon Hunter" id="ID_DODST_TDH_CLASS_FEATURE_DEMON_HUNTER_RADIANT_STRIKES">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 1st level, you know how to imbue divine energy into your strikes. Once per turn, you can use a radiant point to deal an extra 1d6 radiant damage to one creature you hit with an attack. The attack must use a finesse or a ranged weapon.</p>
                <p class="indent">Your number of radiant points is equal to your demon hunter level + your Dexterity modifier (minimum 1).</p>
                <p class="indent">When you spend a radiant point, it is unavailable until you finish a short or long rest, at the end of which all of your radiant points return.</p>
                <p class="indent">The amount of the extra damage increases as you gain levels in this class, as shown in the Radiant Strikes column of the Demon Hunter table.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="{{radiant-points}} radiant points/Short Rest">
                <description>Once per turn, you can expend a radiant point to deal an extra 1d{{radiant-strike:die-type}} radiant damage to one creature you hit with an attack with a finesse or a ranged weapon.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="radiant-strike:die-type" value="6" bonus="base" level="1" />
                <stat name="radiant-strike:die-type" value="8" bonus="base" level="5" />
                <stat name="radiant-strike:die-type" value="10" bonus="base" level="11" />
                <stat name="radiant-strike:die-type" value="12" bonus="base" level="17" />
                <stat name="radiant-points" value="level:demon hunter" />
                <stat name="radiant-points" value="dex-mod:min-one" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Targets of Enmity" type="Class Feature" source="The Demon Hunter" id="ID_DODST_TDH_CLASS_FEATURE_DEMON_HUNTER_TARGETS_OF_ENMITY">
            <description>
                <p>At 1st level, thanks to the aid of your symbiotic hunter’s bond, you have advantage on all checks to track or recall information on fiends and one more target of choice: aberrations, celestials, elementals, fey, monstrosities, or undead.</p>
                <p class="indent">At 6th level, you gain a +1 on all attack and damage rolls made against your Target of Enmity targets. This bonus becomes +2 at 10th level, and +3 at 14th level.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You have advantage on all checks to track or recall information on fiends and {{target-of-enmity}}.</description>
                <description level="6">You have a +{{target-of-enmity:bonus}} to attack and damage rolls against fiends and {{target-of-enmity}}. You have advantage on all checks to track or recall information on fiends and {{target-of-enmity}}.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Target of Enmity" supports="Demon Hunter Target of Enmity" />
                <stat name="target-of-enmity:bonus" value="1" level="6" />
                <stat name="target-of-enmity:bonus" value="1" level="10" />
                <stat name="target-of-enmity:bonus" value="1" level="14" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Aberrations" type="Class Feature" source="source" id="ID_DODST_TDH_CLASS_FEATURE_DEMON_HUNTER_TARGETS_OF_ENMITY_ABERRATIONS">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <supports>Demon Hunter Target of Enmity</supports>
                <description />
                <sheet display="false" />
                <rules>
                    <stat name="target-of-enmity" value="aberrations" inline="true" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Celestials" type="Class Feature" source="source" id="ID_DODST_TDH_CLASS_FEATURE_DEMON_HUNTER_TARGETS_OF_ENMITY_CELESTIALS">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <supports>Demon Hunter Target of Enmity</supports>
                <description />
                <sheet display="false" />
                <rules>
                    <stat name="target-of-enmity" value="celestials" inline="true" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Elementals" type="Class Feature" source="source" id="ID_DODST_TDH_CLASS_FEATURE_DEMON_HUNTER_TARGETS_OF_ENMITY_ELEMENTALS">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <supports>Demon Hunter Target of Enmity</supports>
                <description />
                <sheet display="false" />
                <rules>
                    <stat name="target-of-enmity" value="elementals" inline="true" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Fey" type="Class Feature" source="source" id="ID_DODST_TDH_CLASS_FEATURE_DEMON_HUNTER_TARGETS_OF_ENMITY_FEY">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <supports>Demon Hunter Target of Enmity</supports>
                <description />
                <sheet display="false" />
                <rules>
                    <stat name="target-of-enmity" value="fey" inline="true" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Monstrosities" type="Class Feature" source="source" id="ID_DODST_TDH_CLASS_FEATURE_DEMON_HUNTER_TARGETS_OF_ENMITY_MONSTROSITIES">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <supports>Demon Hunter Target of Enmity</supports>
                <description />
                <sheet display="false" />
                <rules>
                    <stat name="target-of-enmity" value="monstrosities" inline="true" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Undead" type="Class Feature" source="source" id="ID_DODST_TDH_CLASS_FEATURE_DEMON_HUNTER_TARGETS_OF_ENMITY_UNDEAD">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <supports>Demon Hunter Target of Enmity</supports>
                <description />
                <sheet display="false" />
                <rules>
                    <stat name="target-of-enmity" value="undead" inline="true" />
                </rules>
            </element>
        <element name="Fighting Style" type="Class Feature" source="The Demon Hunter" id="ID_DODST_TDH_CLASS_FEATURE_DEMON_HUNTER_FIGHTING_STYLE">
            <description>
                <p>At 2nd level, you adopt a style of fighting as your specialty. Choose one of the following options. You can’t take a Fighting Style option more than once, even if you later get to choose again.</p>
                <h5>ARCHERY</h5>
                <p>You gain a +2 bonus to Attack rolls you make with ranged weapons.</p>
                <h5>BLIND FIGHTING</h5>
                <p>You have blindsight with a range of 10 feet. Within that range, you can effectively see anything that isn’t behind total cover, even if you’re blinded or in darkness. Moreover, you can see an invisible creature within that range, unless the creature successfully hides from you.</p>
                <h5>CLOSE QUARTERS SHOOTER (UA)</h5>
                <p>When making a ranged attack while you are within 5 feet of a hostile creature, you do not have disadvantage on the attack roll. Your ranged attacks ignore half cover and three-quarters cover against targets within 30 feet of you. You have a +1 bonus to attack rolls on ranged attacks..</p>
                <h5>DEFENSE</h5>
                <p>While wearing armor, you gain a +1 bonus to AC.</p>
                <h5>TITAN FIGHTING</h5>
                <p>You gain a +2 bonus to melee weapon attack rolls you make against Large or larger creatures.</p>
                <h5>THROWN WEAPON FIGHTING</h5>
                <p>You can draw a weapon that has the thrown property as part of the attack you make with the weapon.</p>
                <p class="indent">In addition, when you hit with a ranged attack using a thrown weapon, you gain a +1 bonus to the damage roll.</p>
                <h5>TWO-WEAPON FIGHTING</h5>
                <p>When you engage in Two-Weapon Fighting, you can add your ability modifier to the damage of the second attack.</p>
                <h5>TUNNEL FIGHTER (UA)</h5>
                <p>As a bonus action, you can enter a defensive stance that lasts until the start of your next turn. While in your defensive stance, you can make opportunity attacks without using your reaction, and you can use your reaction to make a melee attack against a creature that moves more than 5 feet while within your reach..</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false" />
            <rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Fighting Style" supports="Fighting Style, Demon Hunter" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Hunter’s Path" type="Class Feature" source="The Demon Hunter" id="ID_DODST_TDH_CLASS_FEATURE_DEMON_HUNTER_HUNTERS_PATH">
            <description>
                <p>A demon hunter’s Path is the path a demon hunter takes to achieve their end goals. Angels can transform a mortal body in many ways, and can help them towards different forms of mutation. These paths are what differentiates one demon hunter from another, and shows how they prefer to go about dealing with their common enemies.</p>
                <p class="indent">When you reach the 2rd level, you can select a Hunter’s Path. This choice gives you a feature at 3rd, 7th, 11th, 15th and 18th level.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false" />
            <rules>
                <select type="Archetype" name="Demon Hunter’s Path" supports="Demon Hunter’s Path" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Pact Magic" type="Class Feature" source="The Demon Hunter" id="ID_DODST_TDH_CLASS_FEATURE_DEMON_HUNTER_PACT_MAGIC">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 2nd level you have accomplished a form of symbiosis with a dying angel. Thanks to the teachings of the angel you have learned to control the power within you, calling upon strong magic, granting you stronger spells, though limiting the amount of arcane power you can expel. See Spells Rules for the general rules of spellcasting and the Spells Listing for the demon hunter spell list.</p>
                <h5>CANTRIPS</h5>
                <p>You know one cantrip of your choice from the demon hunter spell list. You learn additional demon hunter cantrips of your choice at higher levels, as shown in the Cantrips Known column of the demon hunter table.</p>
                <h5>SPELL SLOTS</h5>
                <p>The demon hunter table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your demon hunter spells of 1st through 5th level. The table also shows what the level of those slots is; all of your spell slots are the same level. To cast one of your demon hunter spells of 1st level or higher, you must expend a spell slot. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a short or long rest.</p>
                <p class="indent">For example, when you are 9th level, you have two 3rd-level spell slots. To cast the 1st-level spell witch bolt, you must spend one of those slots, and you cast it as a 3rd-level spell.</p>
                <h5>SPELLS KNOWN OF 1ST LEVEL AND HIGHER</h5>
                <p>At 2nd level, you know two 1st-level spells of your choice from the demon hunter spell list.</p>
                <p class="indent">The Spells Known column of the demon hunter table shows when you learn more demon hunter spells of your choice of 1st level and higher. A spell you choose must be of a level no higher than what’s shown in the table’s Slot Level column for your level. When you reach 11th level, for example, you learn a new demon hunter spell, which can be 1st, 2nd, or 3rd level.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, when you gain a level in this class, you can choose one of the demon hunter spells you know and replace it with another spell from the demon hunter spell list, which also must be of a level for which you have spell slots.</p>
                <h5>SPELLCASTING ABILITY</h5>
                <p>Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for your demon hunter spells, so you use your Intelligence whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Intelligence modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a demon hunter spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b><i>Spell Save DC</i></b> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier</p>
                <p class="indent"><b><i>Spell attack modifier</i></b> = your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier</p>
                <h5>SPELLCASTING FOCUS</h5>
                <p>You can use an arcane focus (see the Adventuring Gear section) as a spellcasting focus for your demon hunter spells.</p>
            </description>
            <spellcasting name="Demon Hunter" ability="Intelligence" prepare="false">
                <list>Demon Hunter</list>
            </spellcasting>
            <sheet display="false" />
            <rules>
                <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS_SPELLCASTING_SLOTS_SOLO" requirements="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS"/>
                <stat name="demon hunter:spellcasting:slots:count" value="1" level="2"/>
                <stat name="demon hunter:spellcasting:slots:count" value="1" level="6"/>
                <stat name="demon hunter:spellcasting:slots:count" value="1" level="12"/>
                <stat name="demon hunter:spellcasting:slots:count" value="1" level="16"/>
                <stat name="demon hunter:spellcasting:slot" value="1" level="1" />
                <stat name="demon hunter:spellcasting:slot" value="1" level="5" />
                <stat name="demon hunter:spellcasting:slot" value="1" level="9" />
                <stat name="demon hunter:spellcasting:slot" value="1" level="13" />
                <stat name="demon hunter:spellcasting:slot" value="1" level="17" />
                <!-- negative count to remove slots -->
                <stat name="demon hunter:spellcasting:slots:1" value="demon hunter:spellcasting:slots:count" level="2" />
                <stat name="demon hunter:spellcasting:slots:1" value="-demon hunter:spellcasting:slots:count" level="5" />
                <stat name="demon hunter:spellcasting:slots:2" value="demon hunter:spellcasting:slots:count" level="5" />
                <stat name="demon hunter:spellcasting:slots:2" value="-demon hunter:spellcasting:slots:count" level="9" />
                <stat name="demon hunter:spellcasting:slots:3" value="demon hunter:spellcasting:slots:count" level="9" />
                <stat name="demon hunter:spellcasting:slots:3" value="-demon hunter:spellcasting:slots:count" level="13" />
                <stat name="demon hunter:spellcasting:slots:4" value="demon hunter:spellcasting:slots:count" level="13" />
                <stat name="demon hunter:spellcasting:slots:4" value="-demon hunter:spellcasting:slots:count" level="17" />
                <stat name="demon hunter:spellcasting:slots:5" value="demon hunter:spellcasting:slots:count" level="17" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Demon Hunter)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),0" level="2" spellcasting="Demon Hunter" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Demon Hunter)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),0" level="4" spellcasting="Demon Hunter" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Demon Hunter)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),0" level="9" spellcasting="Demon Hunter" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Demon Hunter)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),0" level="15" spellcasting="Demon Hunter" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Demon Hunter)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="2" number="2" spellcasting="Demon Hunter"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Demon Hunter)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="4" spellcasting="Demon Hunter"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Demon Hunter)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="6" spellcasting="Demon Hunter"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Demon Hunter)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="8" spellcasting="Demon Hunter"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Demon Hunter)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="10" spellcasting="Demon Hunter"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Demon Hunter)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="12" spellcasting="Demon Hunter"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Demon Hunter)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="14" spellcasting="Demon Hunter"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Demon Hunter)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="16" spellcasting="Demon Hunter"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Demon Hunter)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="18" spellcasting="Demon Hunter"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Demon Hunter)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="20" spellcasting="Demon Hunter"/>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Metamorphosis" type="Class Feature" source="The Demon Hunter" id="ID_DODST_TDH_CLASS_FEATURE_DEMON_HUNTER_METAMORPHOSIS">
            <description>
                <p>At 3nd level, your symbiotic relationship with your angel has started to transform your body even more. You can use your action to partially transform your appearance briefly. Dampened divine energy flows from your back like false wings, and you give off an aura of divine anger. Each creature of your choice that is within 20 ft. and is aware of you must succeed on Charisma saving throw against your spell save DC or become frightened for a number of rounds equal to your proficiency modifier (minimum 2). A creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.</p>
                <p class="indent">The transformation ends after a number of rounds equal to your proficiency modifier passes (minimum 2).</p>
                <p class="indent">After using this feature, you must finish a long rest before you can use it again.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You can transform your appearance briefly, and you give off an aura of divine anger. Each creature of your choice that is within {{metamorphosis:range}} ft. and is aware of you must succeed on Charisma saving throw (DC {{spellcasting:dc:int}}) or become frightened for {{proficiency}} rounds. The transformation ends after {{proficiency}} rounds.</description>
                <description level="9">You can transform your appearance briefly, and you give off an aura of divine anger. Each creature of your choice that is within {{metamorphosis:range}} ft. and is aware of you must succeed on Charisma saving throw (DC {{spellcasting:dc:int}}) or become frightened for {{proficiency}} rounds. Your wings shed bright light in a 10-foot radius and dim light for an additional 10 feet. When you land an attack against an opponent, you deal an additional 1d6 radiant damage. While under the transformation you are under the effects of a feather fall spell. The transformation ends after 1 minute.</description>
                <description level="20">You can transform your appearance briefly, and you give off an aura of divine anger. Each creature of your choice that is within {{metamorphosis:range}} ft. and is aware of you must succeed on Charisma saving throw (DC {{spellcasting:dc:int}}) or become frightened for {{proficiency}} rounds. Your wings shed bright light in a 10-foot radius and dim light for an additional 10 feet and grant you a flying speed of 30 feet. When you land an attack against an opponent, you deal an additional 1d6 radiant damage. While under the transformation you are under the effects of a feather fall spell. Attack rolls made against Targets of Enmity are made at advantage. Radiant damage against fiends is doubled. You gain true sight of 30 ft.The transformation ends after 1 minute.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="metamorphosis:range" value="20" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Ability Score Increase" type="Class Feature" source="The Demon Hunter" id="ID_DODST_TDH_CLASS_FEATURE_DEMON_HUNTER_ABILITY_SCORE_INCREASE">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false" />
            <rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Demon Hunter 4)" supports="Improvement Option,Demon Hunter,4" level="4" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Demon Hunter 8)" supports="Improvement Option,Demon Hunter,8" level="8" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Demon Hunter 12)" supports="Improvement Option,Demon Hunter,12" level="12" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Demon Hunter 16)" supports="Improvement Option,Demon Hunter,16" level="16" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Demon Hunter 19)" supports="Improvement Option,Demon Hunter,19" level="19" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Martial Versatility (Optional)" type="Class Feature" source="The Demon Hunter" id="ID_DODST_TDH_CLASS_FEATURE_DEMON_HUNTER_MARTIAL_VERSATILITY">
            <description>
                <p>Whenever you reach a level in this class that grants the Ability Score Improvement feature, you can replace a fighting style you know with another fighting style available to demon hunters. This replacement represents a shift of focus in your martial practice.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Extra Attack" type="Class Feature" source="The Demon Hunter" id="ID_DODST_TDH_CLASS_FEATURE_DEMON_HUNTER_EXTRA_ATTACK">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 5th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="extra attack:count" value="2" level="5" bonus="extra attack" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Hunter’s Sense" type="Class Feature" source="The Demon Hunter" id="ID_DODST_TDH_CLASS_FEATURE_DEMON_HUNTER_HUNTERS_SENSE">
            <description>
                <p>Upon reaching 6th level, your symbiotic relationship has altered your senses, causing the presence of strong evil to register on your senses like a noxious odor. You can sense the presence of any fiend or other Target of Enmity within 20 feet of you. You know the type of any being whose presence you sense, but not its identity or location. Within the same radius, you cannot be surprised by fiends and your Target of Enmity, and said creatures cannot gain advantage on attack rolls against you as a result of being hidden from you.</p>
                <p class="indent">When you reach 10th level, the range of this feature increases to 30 ft., 40 ft. at 14th level, and 50 ft. at 18th level.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can sense the presence of any fiends or {{target-of-enmity}} within {{hunters-sense:range}} feet of you. You know the type of any being whose presence you sense, but not its identity or location. Within the same radius, you cannot be surprised by fiends or {{target-of-enmity}}, and said creatures cannot gain advantage on attack rolls against you as a result of being hidden from you.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="hunters-sense:range" value="20" level="6" />
                <stat name="hunters-sense:range" value="10" level="10" />
                <stat name="hunters-sense:range" value="10" level="14" />
                <stat name="hunters-sense:range" value="10" level="18" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Keen Insight" type="Class Feature" source="The Demon Hunter" id="ID_DODST_TDH_CLASS_FEATURE_DEMON_HUNTER_KEEN_INSIGHT">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 6th level, your body continues to change and adapt to the form of your angelic counterpart, you start to pick up on the ways people talk around you. You gain advantage on all Wisdom (Insight) checks to tell if someone is telling a lie.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You have advantage on all Insight checks to tell if someone is telling a lie.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Upgraded Metamorphosis" type="Class Feature" source="The Demon Hunter" id="ID_DODST_TDH_CLASS_FEATURE_DEMON_HUNTER_UPGRADED_METAMORPHOSIS">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 9th level, your symbiotic relationship with your angel has transformed your body to a point where you can temporarily manifest its true form. When you use your Metamorphosis feature, divine energy flows from your back creating strange ethereal wings, and you now channel an aura of divine anger, granting Metamorphosis the following abilities:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Your wings shed bright light in a 10-foot radius and dim light for an additional 10 feet.</li>
                    <li>When you land an attack against an opponent, you deal an additional 1d6 radiant damage.</li>
                    <li>While under the transformation you are under the effects of a feather fall spell.</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">Your transformation now lasts for 1 minute, and after using this feature, you must finish a long rest before you can use it again.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false" />
        </element>
        <element name="Demonic Resistance" type="Class Feature" source="The Demon Hunter" id="ID_DODST_TDH_CLASS_FEATURE_DEMON_HUNTER_DEMONIC_RESISTANCE">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach the 13th level, your knowledge of your foes has extended to their arcane abilities. You gain advantage on all saving throws against spells cast against you by fiends and your Target of Enmity.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You have advantage on all saving throws against spells cast against you by fiends and {{target-of-enmity}}.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="True Metamorphosis" type="Class Feature" source="The Demon Hunter" id="ID_DODST_TDH_CLASS_FEATURE_DEMON_HUNTER_TRUE_METAMORPHOSIS">
            <description>
                <p>At 20th level, the angel infused in your body has finished transforming your body, enhancing your Metamorphosis feature, and altering your base physiology. All damage rolls made against fiends and your other target of enmity include additional radiant damage equal to your Intelligence modifier, and you can now telepathically communicate with creatures within 60 ft. of you, though this doesn’t overcome language barriers.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, when you activate Metamorphosis, you gain the following properties:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Your wings have fully manifested, you have a flying speed of 30 ft.</li>
                    <li>Attack rolls made against Targets of Enmity are made at advantage.</li>
                    <li>Radiant damage against fiends is doubled.</li>
                    <li>You gain true sight of 30 ft.</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">Your transformation now lasts for 10 minute, and after using this feature, you must finish a short or long rest before you can use it again.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>All damage rolls made against fiends and {{target-of-enmity}} include additional {{intelligence:modifier}} radiant damage, and you can now telepathically communicate with creatures within 60 ft. of you.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="true-metamorphosis:damage-type" inline="true" value="radiant" requirements="!ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_DEMON_HUNTER_PATH_OF_THE_DEMON_FUSED" />
                <stat name="radiant-strikes:damage-type" inline="true" value="radiant" requirements="!ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_DEMON_HUNTER_PATH_OF_THE_DEMON_FUSED" />
            </rules>
        </element>

    <element name="Path of the Annihilator" type="Archetype" source="The Demon Hunter" id="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_DEMON_HUNTER_PATH_OF_THE_ANNIHILATOR">
        <supports>Demon Hunter’s Path</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Those who choose the Path of the Annihilator don’t understand the meaning of mercy when it comes to fighting against the forces of evil. A lot of creatures are evil, fiends are only part of it, therefore everything will be used to accomplish the sacred task: the annihilation of every evil being.</p>
            <div element="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ANNIHILATOR_DETECT_EVIL" />
            <div element="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ANNIHILATOR_RELENTLESS_ASSAULT" />
            <div element="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ANNIHILATOR_ANGER_AGAINST_EVIL" />
            <div element="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ANNIHILATOR_RESISTANCE_AGAINST_EVIL" />
            <div element="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ANNIHILATOR_ANNIHILATOR_OF_EVIL" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ANNIHILATOR_DETECT_EVIL" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ANNIHILATOR_RELENTLESS_ASSAULT" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ANNIHILATOR_ANGER_AGAINST_EVIL" level="11" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ANNIHILATOR_RESISTANCE_AGAINST_EVIL" level="14" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ANNIHILATOR_ANNIHILATOR_OF_EVIL" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Detect Evil" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Demon Hunter" id="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ANNIHILATOR_DETECT_EVIL">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 2rd level, your metamorphosis shows the true nature of those around you. While in your metamorphosis, you can sense the alignment of any creature within 30 ft. of you.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>While in your metamorphosis, you can sense the alignment of any creature within 30 ft. of you.</description>
                <description level="18">You can sense the alignment of any creature within 60 ft. of you.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Relentless Assault" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Demon Hunter" id="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ANNIHILATOR_RELENTLESS_ASSAULT">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 7th level, when you’re hit by a melee attack, you can use your reaction to make a melee attack roll against that creature. If your assailant is a creature which has been marked as evil by your Detect Evil feature, you can also use your Radiant Strikes feature on the attack, without expending a radiant point.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Reaction">
                <description>When you’re hit by a melee attack, you can use your reaction to make a melee attack roll against that creature. If your assailant is a creature which has been marked as evil by your Detect Evil feature, you can also use your Radiant Strikes feature on the attack, without expending a radiant point.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Anger Against Evil" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Demon Hunter" id="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ANNIHILATOR_ANGER_AGAINST_EVIL">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 11th level, you use a bonus action to determine the alignment of a single creature within 30 ft. of you. If the creature’s alignment is evil, then you gain the effect of the spell <i>hunter’s mark</i> on the creature without a need for concentration. You can use this feature twice per long rest.</p>
                <p class="indent">At 15th level you can detect the alignment of 2 creatures with a single use of this feature, and can use the feature 3 times per long rest, and four times at 18th, while detecting up to three creatures alignments per use.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description usage="2/Long Rest">You can determine the alignment of a single creature within 30 ft. of you. If the creature’s alignment is evil, then you gain the effect of the spell hunter’s mark on the creature without a need for concentration.</description>
                <description level="15" usage="3/Long Rest">You can determine the alignment of two creatures within 30 ft. of you. If the creatures’ alignment is evil, then you gain the effect of the spell hunter’s mark on the creature without a need for concentration.</description>
                <description level="18" usage="4/Long Rest">You can determine the alignment of three creatures within 30 ft. of you. If the creatures’ alignment is evil, then you gain the effect of the spell hunter’s mark on the creature without a need for concentration.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HUNTERS_MARK" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Resistance Against Evil" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Demon Hunter" id="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ANNIHILATOR_RESISTANCE_AGAINST_EVIL">
            <description>
                <p>At 14th level, you have an unstoppable will against the spells of villains. You gain advantage to all saving throws against spells cast against you by a creature detected as evil by your Detect Evil feature.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You gain advantage to all saving throws against spells cast against you by a creature detected as evil by your Detect Evil feature.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Annihilator of Evil" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Demon Hunter" id="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ANNIHILATOR_ANNIHILATOR_OF_EVIL">
            <description>
                <p>Reaching 18th level, no one can hide their real nature from you. The Detect Evil feature is now active outside of Metamorphosis and its range has increased to 60 ft.</p>
                <p class="indent">Also when you use your Metamorphosis feature you choose to gain a temporary new target of enmity for the duration of your metamorphosis which can be of any type you want.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you use your Metamorphosis feature you choose to gain a temporary new target of enmity for the duration of your metamorphosis which can be of any type you want.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    <element name="Path of the Stalker" type="Archetype" source="The Demon Hunter" id="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_DEMON_HUNTER_PATH_OF_THE_STALKER">
        <supports>Demon Hunter’s Path</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You hone your skills to be quick and efficient. Being quick on your feet, and the first to react to any given situation, Demon hunters who embrace the Path of the Stalker are expert trackers, and have no qualms entering what some may call a sticky situation.</p>
            <div element="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STALKER_VAULT" />
            <div element="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STALKER_EVASION" />
            <div element="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STALKER_STALKERS_MOBILITY" />
            <div element="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STALKER_EFFICIENT_DEFLECTION" />
            <div element="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STALKER_RADIANT_ONSLAUGHT" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STALKER_VAULT" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STALKER_EVASION" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STALKER_STALKERS_MOBILITY" level="11" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STALKER_EFFICIENT_DEFLECTION" level="14" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STALKER_RADIANT_ONSLAUGHT" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Vault" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Demon Hunter" id="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STALKER_VAULT">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 2rd level, you can take the disengage action as a bonus action, and gain an additional 10 feet of movement when disengaging.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>y\You Disengage as a bonus action, and gain an additional 10 feet of movement when disengaging.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Evasion" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Demon Hunter" id="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STALKER_EVASION">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 7th level, you can nimbly dodge out of the way of certain area effects, such as an ancient red dragon’s fiery breath or an ice storm spell. When you are subjected to an effect that allows you to make a Dexterity saving throw to take only half damage, you instead take no damage if you succeed on the saving throw, and only half damage if you fail.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you are subjected to an effect that allows you to make a Dexterity saving throw to take only half damage, you instead take no damage if you succeed on the saving throw, and only half damage if you fail.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Stalker’s Mobility" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Demon Hunter" id="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STALKER_STALKERS_MOBILITY">
            <description>
                <p>At 11th level, your walking speed increases by 10 feet. If you have a climbing or swimming speed, this increase applies to that speed as well.</p>
                <p class="indent">This bonus increases by 10 feet when you reach the 17th level, and an additional 10 feet at the 19th level. This increase will affect your True Metamorphosis flying speed at level 20.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false" />
            <rules>
                <stat name="speed:misc" value="10" level="11" />
                <stat name="speed:misc" value="10" level="17" />
                <stat name="speed:misc" value="10" level="19" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Efficient Deflection" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Demon Hunter" id="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STALKER_EFFICIENT_DEFLECTION">
            <description>
                <p>At 14th level, your weapons training has improved to the point where you can use your opponent’s momentum to counteract their attacks.</p>
                <p class="indent">When a creature lands a successful melee attack roll against you while within 5 ft. of you, you can use your reaction to make a Dexterity saving throw against the attack roll, taking the normal damage on a fail, or taking no damage on a success, with the creature taking the damage instead.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you have used this feature you must complete a long rest before using it again.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest" action="Reaction">
                <description>When a creature lands a successful melee attack roll against you while within 5 ft. of you, you can use your reaction to make a Dexterity saving throw against the attack roll, taking the normal damage on a fail, or taking no damage on a success, with the creature taking the damage instead.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Radiant Onslaught" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Demon Hunter" id="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STALKER_RADIANT_ONSLAUGHT">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 18th level, You have fully weaponized the divine energy flowing within you. Whenever you use your Radiant Strikes feature you double the dice used.</p>
                <p class="indent">When you use the Radiant Strike Feature against a fiend or a Target of Enmity, you triple the dice used.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally when you use your True Metamorphosis feature, radiant damage against fiends is tripled.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Whenever you use your Radiant Strikes feature you double the dice used. When you use the Radiant Strike Feature against fiends or {{target-of-enmity}}, you triple the dice used. Additionally when you use your True Metamorphosis feature, radiant damage against fiends is tripled.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    <element name="Path of the Demon-Fused" type="Archetype" source="The Demon Hunter" id="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_DEMON_HUNTER_PATH_OF_THE_DEMON_FUSED">
        <supports>Demon Hunter’s Path</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You desire more power, tainting your new form with the blood and souls of demons. A more brutal form, demon hunters on the Path of the Demon-Fused tend to act on primal instinct, and will sooner turn themselves into a monster to achieve their goals, then worry about what consequences these actions may have.</p>
            <div element="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEMON_FUSED_DEMONIC_ALTERATION" />
            <div element="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEMON_FUSED_WAR_MAGIC" />
            <div element="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEMON_FUSED_EYES_OF_THE_FIEND" />
            <div element="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEMON_FUSED_DAWN_OF_THE_DEVIL" />
            <div element="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEMON_FUSED_DEMONIC_GIFT" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEMON_FUSED_DEMONIC_ALTERATION" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEMON_FUSED_WAR_MAGIC" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEMON_FUSED_EYES_OF_THE_FIEND" level="11" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEMON_FUSED_DAWN_OF_THE_DEVIL" level="14" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEMON_FUSED_DEMONIC_GIFT" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Demonic Alteration" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Demon Hunter" id="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEMON_FUSED_DEMONIC_ALTERATION">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 2nd level, your absorption of demonic energy has altered the course of your mutations. Your Radiant Strikes feature now deals necrotic damage, and you can cast the <i>darkness</i> spell once per long rest without expending a spell slot.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, after 2nd level, any form of metamorphosis is altered and takes on a more demonic form. When you reach 9th level your Upgraded metamorphosis ability is altered, and the following changes are made:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Bright light within 10 ft of you is dimmed, and dim light within 10 ft. is treated as darkness.</li>
                    <li>When you land an attack against an opponent, you deal an additional 1d6 of necrotic damage instead of radiant.</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">Additionally when you reach 20th level, the radiant damage of True Metamorphosis is also changed to necrotic.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can cast darkness once per long rest without expending a spell slot. Any form of metamorphosis is altered and takes on a more demonic form.</description>
                <description level="9">You can cast darkness once per long rest without expending a spell slot. Any form of metamorphosis is altered and takes on a more demonic form. Your Upgraded metamorphosis ability is altered, and the following changes are made: Bright light within 10 ft of you is dimmed, and dim light within 10 ft. is treated as darkness. When you land an attack against an opponent, you deal an additional 1d6 of necrotic damage instead of radiant.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="true-metamorphosis:damage-type" inline="true" value="necrotic" />
                <stat name="radiant-strikes:damage-type" inline="true" value="necrotic" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DARKNESS" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="War Magic" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Demon Hunter" id="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEMON_FUSED_WAR_MAGIC">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 7th level, when you use your action to cast a cantrip, you can make one weapon attack as a bonus action.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you use your action to cast a cantrip, you can make one weapon attack as a bonus action.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Eyes of the Fiend" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Demon Hunter" id="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEMON_FUSED_EYES_OF_THE_FIEND">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 11th level, you gain darkvision out to a range of 60 feet. If you already have darkvision from your race, its range increases by 30 feet. With this feature, you can see normally in darkness, both magical and nonmagical, and are capable of discerning color.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false" />
            <rules>
                <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_DARKVISION_OR_INCREASE_30" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Dawn of the Devil" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Demon Hunter" id="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEMON_FUSED_DAWN_OF_THE_DEVIL">
            <description>
                <p>At 14th level the demonic energies you have been absorbing have tainted your physical form. Strange colored markings and scars cover your body, amidst other changes. You gain a resistance to fire damage, and the range of your aura of divine anger from the metamorphosis feature is increased to 30 ft.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_FIRE" />
                <stat name="metamorphosis:range" value="10" level="14" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Demonic Gift" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Demon Hunter" id="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEMON_FUSED_DEMONIC_GIFT">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 18th level, when you hit a creature that is not a fiend with an attack, you can force a portion of the demonic energies in your body into theirs.</p>
                <p class="indent">The creature takes 10d10 necrotic damage and is paralyzed until the end of their turn.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>When you hit a creature that is not a fiend with an attack, the creature takes 10d10 necrotic damage and is paralyzed until the end of their turn.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    <element name="Path of the Deadeye" type="Archetype" source="The Demon Hunter" id="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_DEMON_HUNTER_PATH_OF_THE_DEADEYE">
        <supports>Demon Hunter’s Path</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You are less confrontational than others of your skill. Where most demon hunters will let their presence become aware to their enemies, performing close quarters skirmishes, you prefer to conduct your battles from farther back. Excellent snipers, and eagle-eyed scouts, demon hunters on the Path of the Deadeye are perilous foes who can defeat an entire war band so long as they are kept at range.</p>
            <div element="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEADEYE_DEADLY_PRECISION" />
            <div element="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEADEYE_RAPID_STRIKE" />
            <div element="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEADEYE_HEAVENS_SNIPER" />
            <div element="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEADEYE_SNAP_SHOT" />
            <div element="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEADEYE_DIVINE_SHOT" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEADEYE_DEADLY_PRECISION" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEADEYE_RAPID_STRIKE" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEADEYE_HEAVENS_SNIPER" level="11" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEADEYE_SNAP_SHOT" level="14" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEADEYE_DIVINE_SHOT" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Deadly Precision" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Demon Hunter" id="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEADEYE_DEADLY_PRECISION">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning when you choose this archetype at 2nd level, your aim becomes deadly. As a bonus action, you can take careful aim at a creature you can see that is within range of a ranged weapon you’re wielding. Until the end of this turn, your ranged attacks with that weapon against that target gain two benefits:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>The attacks gain advantage.</li>
                    <li>On each hit, the weapon deals additional damage to the target equal to 1 + half your demon hunter level.</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">You can use this feature three times. You regain all expended uses of it when you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="{{deadly-precision:uses}}/Short Rest">
                <description>You can take careful aim at a creature you can see that is within range of a ranged weapon you’re wielding. Until the end of this turn, your ranged attacks with that weapon against that target gain two benefits: The attacks gain advantage. On each hit, the weapon deals additional {{deadly-precision:damage}} damage to the target.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="deadly-precision:uses" value="3" level="2" />
                <stat name="deadly-precision:damage" value="1" />
                <stat name="deadly-precision:damage" value="level:demon hunter:half" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Rapid Strike" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Demon Hunter" id="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEADEYE_RAPID_STRIKE">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 7th level, you learn to trade accuracy for swift strikes. If you have advantage on a weapon attack against a target on your turn, you can forgo that advantage to immediately make an additional weapon attack against the same target as a bonus action.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>If you have advantage on a weapon attack against a target on your turn, you can forgo that advantage to immediately make an additional weapon attack against the same target as a bonus action.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Heaven’s Sniper" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Demon Hunter" id="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEADEYE_HEAVENS_SNIPER">
            <description>
                <p>At 11th level, your symbiotic partner has helped to improve your skills with ranged weapons. When you make a ranged weapon attack, attacking at long range doesn’t impose disadvantage on your ranged weapon attack rolls.</p>
                <p class="indent">Furthermore, your new mutation has come with additional benefits. You also gain proficiency in your choice of the Insight, Investigation, Perception, or Survival skill.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you make a ranged weapon attack, attacking at long range doesn’t impose disadvantage on your ranged weapon attack rolls.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency, Heaven’s Sniper" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INVESTIGATION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SURVIVAL" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Snap Shot" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Demon Hunter" id="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEADEYE_SNAP_SHOT">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 14th level, you are ever ready to spring into action. If you take the Attack action on your first turn of a combat, you can make one additional ranged weapon attack as part of that action.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>If you take the Attack action on your first turn of a combat, you can make one additional ranged weapon attack as part of that action.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Divine Shot" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Demon Hunter" id="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEADEYE_DIVINE_SHOT">
            <description>
                <p>At 18th level, you are capable of consolidated your divine energy into the form of an arrow or bolt. Whenever you use the Radiant Strikes feature on a ranged weapon attack you gain the following abilities:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>No arrow or bolt is consumed by the Attack.</li>
                    <li>The damage of the bolt is changed to radiant.</li>
                    <li>You gain a +2 bonus to the Attack and damage rolls of the base weapon.</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, you can release a divine arrow to strike down powerful demons and foes. you fire this weapon from any ranged weapon you carry, dealing 3d10 radiant damage on a normal strike, or 4d10 damage against fiends or a Target of Enmity. You must complete a long rest before you can fire off a divine bolt again.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Whenever you use the Radiant Strikes feature on a ranged weapon attack you gain the following abilities: No arrow or bolt is consumed by the Attack. The damage of the bolt is changed to radiant. You gain a +2 bonus to the Attack and damage rolls. Additionally, you can release a divine arrow to strike down powerful demons and foes. you fire this weapon from any ranged weapon you carry, dealing 3d10 radiant damage on a normal strike, or 4d10 damage against fiends or {{target-of-enmity}}. You must complete a long rest before you can fire off a divine bolt again.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    <element name="Path of the Archangel" type="Archetype" source="The Demon Hunter" id="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_DEMON_HUNTER_PATH_OF_THE_ARCHANGEL">
        <supports>Demon Hunter’s Path</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You hold one ultimate goal: Revive the angel. You subscribe to combat, less to destroy creatures of evil, but to reinforce your body so that when it is passed onto the divine, your angel will be prepared to fight future battles at a level far superior to most, and with little to no risk of returning to a symbiotic state. The most religious of the your trade, demon hunters of the Path of the Archangel believe their purpose is to be a servant, rather than a partner, and are granted better control over their divine essence to achieve this goal.</p>
            <div element="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCHANGEL_ESSENCE_EXPANSE" />
            <div element="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCHANGEL_FORM_OF_THE_ARCHANGEL" />
            <div element="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCHANGEL_VOLLEY" />
            <div element="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCHANGEL_DIVINE_AURA" />
            <div element="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCHANGEL_TEMPORARY_RETURN" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCHANGEL_ESSENCE_EXPANSE" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCHANGEL_FORM_OF_THE_ARCHANGEL" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCHANGEL_VOLLEY" level="11" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCHANGEL_DIVINE_AURA" level="14" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCHANGEL_TEMPORARY_RETURN" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Essence Expanse" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Demon Hunter" id="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCHANGEL_ESSENCE_EXPANSE">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 2nd level, your proficiency with your divine essence has altered the course of your mutations. You can now expend a radiant point as an action to heal an ally within 5 feet of you for a number of hit points equal to 1 Radiant Strike die + your Intelligence modifier, and you can cast the spell <i>aid</i> once per long rest without expending a spell slot.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, after 2nd level, any form of metamorphosis is altered and takes on a more divine form. When you reach 9th level your Upgraded metamorphosis ability is altered, and the following changes are made:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Your wings shed bright light in a 20-foot radius and dim light for an additional 20 feet.</li>
                    <li>When you land an attack against an opponent, you deal an additional 1d6 radiant damage.</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">Additionally when you reach 20th level, you can add your intelligence modifier to the radiant damage of the True Metamorphosis feature.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can now expend a radiant point as an action to heal an ally within 5 feet of you for a number of hit points equal to 1 Radiant Strike die + {{intelligence:modifier}}, and you can cast the spell aid once per long rest without expending a spell slot.</description>
                <description level="9">You can now expend a radiant point as an action to heal an ally within 5 feet of you for a number of hit points equal to 1 Radiant Strike die + {{intelligence:modifier}}, and you can cast the spell aid once per long rest without expending a spell slot. Your Upgraded metamorphosis ability is altered, and the following changes are made: Your wings shed bright light in a 20-foot radius and dim light for an additional 20 feet. When you land an attack against an opponent, you deal an additional 1d6 radiant damage.</description>
                <description level="20">You can now expend a radiant point as an action to heal an ally within 5 feet of you for a number of hit points equal to 1 Radiant Strike die + {{intelligence:modifier}}, and you can cast the spell aid once per long rest without expending a spell slot. Your Upgraded metamorphosis ability is altered, and the following changes are made: Your wings shed bright light in a 20-foot radius and dim light for an additional 20 feet. When you land an attack against an opponent, you deal an additional 1d6 radiant damage. You add {{intelligence:modifier}} to the radiant damage of your True Metamorphosis feature.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AID" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Form of the Archangel" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Demon Hunter" id="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCHANGEL_FORM_OF_THE_ARCHANGEL">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 7th level, you gain the ability to temporarily grow and take on the appearance of a celestial being. As a bonus action, you assume this archangel form, which lasts for 1 minute, or until you end it as a bonus action or are incapacitated.</p>
                <p class="indent">You undergo the following changes while in your archangel form:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Your size becomes Large, unless you were larger.</li>
                    <li>Any speed you have becomes 5 feet, unless the speed was lower.</li>
                    <li>Your reach increases by 5 feet.</li>
                    <li>You gain a number of temporary hit points at the start of each of your turns. The number equals half your demon hunter level. When the form ends, you lose any temporary hit points you have from it.</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">You can use this feature a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, and regain expended uses after completing a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="{{proficiency}}/Long Rest">
                <description>You assume this archangel form, which lasts for 1 minute, or until you end it as a bonus action or are incapacitated.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Volley" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Demon Hunter" id="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCHANGEL_VOLLEY">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 11th level, you can use your action to make a ranged attack against any number of creatures within 5 feet of a point you can see within your weapon’s range. You must have ammunition for each target, as normal, and you make a separate attack roll for each target.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>You can use your action to make a ranged attack against any number of creatures within 5 feet of a point you can see within your weapon’s range. You must have ammunition for each target, as normal, and you make a separate attack roll for each target.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Divine Aura" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Demon Hunter" id="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCHANGEL_DIVINE_AURA">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 14th level, your Form of the Archangel form emanates a magical aura that fortifies your injured allies. When any ally starts their turn within 30 feet of your archangel form, that ally regains a number of hit points equal to your wisdom modifier. This aura has no effect on a creature that has half or more of its hit points, and it has no effect on undead and constructs.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When any ally starts their turn within 30 feet of your archangel form, that ally regains {{wisdom:modifier}} hit points equal. This aura has no effect on a creature that has half or more of its hit points, and it has no effect on undead and constructs.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Temporary Return" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Demon Hunter" id="ID_DODST_TDH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCHANGEL_TEMPORARY_RETURN">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 18th level, Death can temporarily revive the angel within.</p>
                <p class="indent">When you have to make a death saving throw at the start of your turn, you can instead have your angel take over your body, and enter into your choice of Form of the Archangel or Metamorphosis. You regain hit points equal to half your hit point maximum, and then you stand up if you so choose. Each creature of your choice that is within 15 feet of you takes radiant damage equal to 2d6 + your Intelligence modifier, and is blinded until the end of the current turn.</p>
                <p class="indent">The use of this feature does not expend a use of your Form of the Archangel or Metamorphosis feature. Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>When you have to make a death saving throw at the start of your turn, you can instead have your angel take over your body, and enter into your choice of Form of the Archangel or Metamorphosis. You regain hit points equal to half your hit point maximum, and then you stand up if you so choose. Each creature of your choice that is within 15 feet of you takes 2d6 + {{intelligence:modifier}} radiant damage, and is blinded until the end of the current turn.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    <!-- Demon Hunter Skills -->
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ACROBATICS">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ATHLETICS">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ARCANA">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_DECEPTION">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_HISTORY">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INVESTIGATION">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_NATURE">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_STEALTH">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SURVIVAL">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>

    <!-- Demon Hunter Fighting Styles -->
        <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_ARCHERY">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_DEFENSE">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_TWOWEAPON_FIGHTING">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_WOTC_TCE_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTING_STYLE_BLIND_FIGHTING">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_WOTC_TCE_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTING_STYLE_THROWN_WEAPON_FIGHTING">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_WOTC_UA2015_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_CLOSE_QUARTERS_SHOOTER">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_WOTC_UA2015_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_TUNNEL_FIGHTER">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <element name="Titan Fighting" type="Class Feature" source="source" id="ID_DODST_TDH_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTING_STYLE_TITAN_FIGHTING">
            <supports>Fighting Style, Demon Hunter</supports>
            <description>
                <p>You gain a +2 bonus to melee weapon attack rolls you make against Large or larger creatures.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You gain a +2 bonus to melee weapon attack rolls you make against Large or larger creatures.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    <!-- Demon Hunter Spells -->
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_CREATE_BONFIRE">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DANCING_LIGHTS">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ELDRITCH_BLAST">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_SCAG_SPELL_GREEN_FLAME_BLADE">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LIGHT">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGE_HAND">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MENDING">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MESSAGE">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MINOR_ILLUSION">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PRESTIDIGITATION">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RAY_OF_FROST">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_CAUSE_FEAR">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CHARM_PERSON">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COLOR_SPRAY">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMPREHEND_LANGUAGES">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_MAGIC">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_POISON_AND_DISEASE">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISGUISE_SELF">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DIVINE_FAVOUR">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENTANGLE">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FAERIE_FIRE">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FEATHER_FALL">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HELLISH_REBUKE">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_IDENTIFY">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LONGSTRIDER">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PROTECTION_FROM_GOOD_AND_EVIL">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PURIFY_FOOD_AND_DRINK">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHIELD_OF_FAITH">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ALTER_SELF">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ARCANE_LOCK">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLINDNESS_DEAFNESS">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLUR">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_THOUGHTS">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENHANCE_ABILITY">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HEAT_METAL">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HOLD_PERSON">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INVISIBILITY">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LEVITATE">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LOCATE_OBJECT">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGIC_WEAPON">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MIRROR_IMAGE">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MISTY_STEP">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PHANTASMAL_FORCE">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SEE_INVISIBILITY">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SUGGESTION">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ZONE_OF_TRUTH">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLINK">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CLAIRVOYANCE">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COUNTERSPELL">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CRUSADERS_MANTLE">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DAYLIGHT">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISPEL_MAGIC">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ELEMENTAL_WEAPON">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FEAR">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GLYPH_OF_WARDING">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGIC_CIRCLE">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAJOR_IMAGE">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_MELFS_MINUTE_METEORS">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_NONDETECTION">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PROTECTION_FROM_ENERGY">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_REMOVE_CURSE">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SENDING">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SLEET_STORM">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TONGUES">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WIND_WALL">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ARCANE_EYE">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AURA_OF_LIFE">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BANISHMENT">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMPULSION">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONFUSION">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONTROL_WATER">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DEATH_WARD">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DIMENSION_DOOR">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DIVINATION">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FREEDOM_OF_MOVEMENT">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GREATER_INVISIBILITY">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HALLUCINATORY_TERRAIN">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ICE_STORM">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LOCATE_CREATURE">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_OTILUKES_RESILIENT_SPHERE">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WALL_OF_FIRE">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CIRCLE_OF_POWER">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONE_OF_COLD">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONTACT_OTHER_PLANE">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DESTRUCTIVE_WAVE">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DOMINATE_PERSON">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DREAM">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISPEL_GOOD_AND_EVIL">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GEAS">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HOLD_MONSTER">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_HOLY_WEAPON">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LEGEND_LORE">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MODIFY_MEMORY">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SCRYING">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SEEMING">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TELEKINESIS">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TELEPORTATION_CIRCLE">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WALL_OF_FORCE">
            <supports>Demon Hunter</supports>
        </append>

	<element name="Darkvision or Increase 30" type="Grants" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_DARKVISION_OR_INCREASE_30">
		<rules>
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_DARKVISION_INCREASE_30_DARKVISION" requirements="!ID_VISION_DARKVISION" />
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_DARKVISION_INCREASE_30_DARKVISION_INCREASE" requirements="ID_VISION_DARKVISION" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Darkvision" type="Grants" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_DARKVISION_INCREASE_30_DARKVISION">
		<rules>
			<grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_DARKVISION" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Darkvision Increase 30" type="Grants" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_DARKVISION_INCREASE_30_DARKVISION_INCREASE">
		<rules>
			<stat name="darkvision:increase" value="30" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_DARKVISION_INCREASE_30_DARKVISION" />
			<stat name="darkvision:range" value="darkvision:increase" bonus="increase" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_DARKVISION_INCREASE_30_DARKVISION" />
		</rules>
	</element>

</elements>