<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Variant Classes</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="class-variant-classes.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/classes/class-variant-classes.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Variant Classes" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_NCATS_VC_SOURCE_Variant Classes">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation">VC</set>
            <set name="url">https://homebrewery.naturalcrit.com/share/J0ATz7dHxUbg</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" abbreviation="NCATS" url="https://www.reddit.com/user/NCats_secretalt/">u/NCats_secretalt</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20220126</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Archivist" type="Class" source="source" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_Archivist">
        <description>
			<h4>DIVINE KNOWLEDGE</h4>
			<p>Since ancient times, studiers of magic have divided magic between the source of its power: the Divine and the Arcane. Traditionally, Arcane magic was defined by magic sourced by the universe itself, be it through a wizards study or a sorcerers bloodline. Divine magic however, is usually sourced by a greater power, be it the forces of nature or the gods that built reality.</p>
			<p class="indent">Divine magic is most often accessed by clerics and druids as agents of these entitys, however, just because it is usually sourced by these powers, does not mean one cannot access them through study themselves. With great study, one could come to an understanding of the nature of divine magic, to tap into it the same way a wizard would tap into the arcane.</p>
			<h4>CLOISTERED SCHOLARS</h4>
			<p>In terms of a church, Archivists serve an important role within any that they might find themselves serving. Whilest a paladin might serve as a soldier to a church, and a cleric serves as a priest and healer, an archivist often finds themselves in a less public role. They see themselves to attending the records and texts of a church, studying them to gain greater understanding of what the divine truelly is. While people may visit a cleric to hear their divine insight, people will visit an archivist to hear of the history and lore that surrounds the gods.</p>
			<p class="indent">Of course, just like a cleric or paladin, they are not bound to serving a church. Some archivists wander the world to gain knowledge, just the same way a wizard might.</p>
			<h4>UNBOUNDED</h4>
			<p>Unlike other divine magicians, an Archivist is not bound to a higher entity, as their power comes from an understanding of divine magic as a force within the universe, not from faith. A god can deny an archivist their power as much as they could a wizard from theirs.</p>
			<p class="indent">As such, it is not impossible to find archivists with strange studies and powers that may normally not be possible to find with a cleric. An evil archivist has just as much a chance to learn spells of the life domain as a good archivist, while an evil cleric will often be denied access from a good god into the life domain.</p>
			<h4>CREATING AN ARCHIVIST</h4>
			<p>When you create your achivist character, consider what drove them to become a studier of the divine. What made them interested in undestanding divinity as a science rather than as a faith? Does divine magic come to them naturally, or is controlling it a challenge? Where you taken under the wing of another archivist to begin your studies, or did your research come without the guidance of others?</p>
			<p class="indent">From there, consider what drew you forth from your study into a life of adventuring. Are you simply eager to better practice manipulating divine forces? Or maybe you were forced into it, by some sort of danger or disaster? Or perhaps you simply seek some sort of ancient source of divine knowledge?</p>
			<h5>QUICK BUILD</h5>
			<p>You can make an archivist quickly by following these suggestions. First, Intelligence should be your highest ability score, followed by Constitution or Dexterity. Second, choose the sage background. Third, choose the Light, Spare the Dying and Toll the Dead cantrips, along with the following 1st-level spells for your prayerbook: Cure Wounds, Detect Evil and Good, Detect Magic, Guiding Bolt, Healing Word, Inflict Wounds, Protection from Evil and Good and Shield of Faith.</p>
            <h2>CLASS FEATURES</h2>
            <p>As an archivist, you gain the following class features.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">HIT POINTS</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Hit Dice:</strong> 1d6 per archivist level</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at 1st Level:</strong> 6 + your Constitution modifier</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at Higher Levels:</strong> 1d6 (or 4) + your Constitution modifier per archivist level after 1st</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">PROFICIENCIES</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled mb">
                <li><strong>Armor:</strong> Light Armor</li>
                <li><strong>Weapons:</strong> Daggers, darts, slings, quarterstaffs, light crossbows</li>
                <li><strong>Tools:</strong> None</li>
            </ul>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Saving Throws:</strong> Intelligence, Wisdom</li>
                <li><strong>Skills:</strong> Choose two from Arcana, History, Insight, Investigation, Medicine, and Religion</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">EQUIPMENT</h5>
            <p>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>(a) a quarterstaff or (b) a dagger</li>
                <li>(a) a component pouch or (b) a holy focus or (c) an arcane focus</li>
                <li>(a) a scholar's pack or (b) an priest's's pack</li>
                <li>A prayerbook</li>
            </ul>
        <!-- class table here -->
            <h5 class="caption">THE ARCHIVIST</h5>
            <table class="class-features">
                <thead>
                    <tr><td class="col-5">Level</td><td class="col-10">Proficiency Bonus</td><td class="left">Features</td><td class="col-10">Cantrips Known</td><td>1st</td><td>2nd</td><td>3rd</td><td>4th</td><td>5th</td><td>6th</td><td>7th</td><td>8th</td><td>9th</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td> 1st</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Divine Recovery, Spellcasting</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 2nd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Scholar's Tradition</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 3rd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Cantrip Formulas, Domain Studies</td><td>3</td><td>4</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 4th</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 5th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">—</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 6th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Scholar's Tradition feature</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 7th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Divine Formulas</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>1</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 8th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement, Domain Studies</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 9th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">—</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>1</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>10th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Scholar's Tradition feature</td><td>5</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>11th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">—</td><td>5</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>12th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement, Domain Studies, Domain Expertise</td><td>5</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">—</td><td>5</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>14th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Scholar's Tradition feature</td><td>5</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>15th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">—</td><td>5</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>16th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement, Domain Studies</td><td>5</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>17th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">—</td><td>5</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>1</td></tr>
                <tr><td>18th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Divine Specialities</td><td>5</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>1</td></tr>
                <tr><td>19th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>5</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>1</td></tr>
                <tr><td>20th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Miracle</td><td>5</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>2</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>1</td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_ARCHIVIST_SPELLCASTING" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_ARCHIVIST_DIVINE_RECOVERY" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_ARCHIVIST_SCHOLARS_TRADITION" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_ARCHIVIST_DOMAIN_STUDIES" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_ARCHIVIST_CANTRIP_FORMULAS" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_ARCHIVIST_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_ARCHIVIST_DIVINE_FORMULAS" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_ARCHIVIST_DOMAIN_EXPERTISE" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_ARCHIVIST_DIVINE_SPECIALITIES" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_ARCHIVIST_MIRACLE" />
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="hd">d6</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_DAGGER" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_DART" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SLING" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_QUARTERSTAFF" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_CROSSBOW_LIGHT" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_INTELLIGENCE" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_WISDOM" />
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency, Archivist" supports="Skill, Archivist" number="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_ARCHIVIST_SPELLCASTING" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_ARCHIVIST_DIVINE_RECOVERY" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_ARCHIVIST_SCHOLARS_TRADITION" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_ARCHIVIST_DOMAIN_STUDIES" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_ARCHIVIST_CANTRIP_FORMULAS" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_ARCHIVIST_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" level="4" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_ARCHIVIST_DIVINE_FORMULAS" level="7" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_ARCHIVIST_DOMAIN_EXPERTISE" level="12" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_ARCHIVIST_DIVINE_SPECIALITIES" level="18" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_ARCHIVIST_MIRACLE" level="20" />
        </rules>
    </element>
		<element name="Spellcasting" type="Class Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_ARCHIVIST_SPELLCASTING">
			<description>
				<p>As a student of divine magic, you have a prayerbook noting ways to invoke divine power.</p>
				<h5>Spell List</h5>
				<p>An archivist is a student of divine magic, as such, the spells they can learn reflect this. The archivist spell list is identical to the cleric spell list of your games world.</p>
				<h5>Cantrips</h5>
				<p>At 1st level, you know three cantrips of your choice from the cleric spell list. You learn additional cleric cantrips of your choice at higher levels, as shown in the Cantrips Known column of the archivist table.</p>
				<p class="indent">These cleric cantrips count as archivist spells when you cast them.</p>
				<h5>Prayerbook</h5>
				<p>At 1st level, you have a prayerbook containing six 1st-level archivist spells of your choice.</p>
				<p class="indent">The spells your prayerbook holds reflect your understanding of divine magic as a force within the multiverse, a combination of your own research as well as knowledge you come across throughout your journey. Your prayerbook might contain spells from other individuals, such as knowledge found within an evil clerics temple, or another archivists notes within the depths of a churches archives.</p>
				<p class="indent">Copying a Spell into the Book. When you find a cleric or archivist spell of 1st level or higher, you can add it to your prayerbook as an archivist spellif it is of a level for which you have spell slots and if you can spare the time to decipher and copy it.</p>
				<p class="indent">Copying a spell into your prayerbook involves reproducing the basic form of the spell, then deciphering the unique system of notation used by the person who wrote it. You must practice the spell until you understand the sounds or gestures required, then transcribe it into your prayerbook using your own notation.</p>
				<p class="indent">For each level of the spell, the process takes 2 hours and costs 30 gp. The cost represents material components you expend as you experiment with the spell to master it, as well as the fine inks you need to record it. Once you have spent this time and money, you can prepare the spell just like your other spells.</p>
				<p class="indent">Replacing the Book. You can copy a spell from your own prayerbook into another book - for example, if you want to make a backup copy of your prayerbook. This is just like copying a new spell into your prayerbook, but faster and easier, since you understand your own notation and already know how to cast the spell. You need spend only 1 hour and 8 gp for each level of the copied spell.</p>
				<p class="indent">If you lose your prayerbook, you can use the same procedure to transcribe the spells that you have prepared into a new prayerbook. Filling out the remainder of your prayerbook requires you to find new spells to do so, as normal. For this reason, many archivists keep backup prayerbooks in a safe place.</p>
				<p class="indent">The Book's Appearance. Your prayerbook is unique to you, with its own manner of style of writing and noting the knowledge within, with various flourishes and additional notes. Some archivists keep simple, plain leather tomes to hold their spells, while others may carry elaborately decorated tomes, or sometimes a barely held together pile of notes and scrolls</p>
				<h5>Preparing and Casting Spells</h5>
				<p>The Archivist table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your spells of 1st level and higher. To cast one of these spells, you must expend a slot of the spell's level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.</p>
				<p class="indent">You prepare the list of archivist spells that are available for you to cast. To do so, choose a number of archivist spells from your prayerbook equal to your Intelligence modifier + your archivist level (minimum of one spell). The spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots.</p>
				<p class="indent">For example, if you're a 3rd-level archivist, you have four 1st-level and two 2nd-level spell slots. With an Intelligence of 16, your list of prepared spells can include six spells of 1st or 2nd level, in any combination, chosen from your spellbook. If you prepare the 1st-level spell Bless, you can cast it using a 1st-level or a 2nd-level slot. Casting the spell doesn't remove it from your list of prepared spells.</p>
				<p class="indent">You can change your list of prepared spells when you finish a long rest. Preparing a new list of archivist spells requires time spent studying your spellbook and memorizing the incantations and gestures you must make to cast the spell: at least 1 minute per spell level for each spell on your list.</p>
				<h5>Spellcasting Ability</h5>
				<p>Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for your archivist spells, since you learn your spells through dedicated study and memorization. You use your Intelligence whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Intelligence modifier when setting the saving throw DC for an archivist spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.</p>
				<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Spell save DC</strong> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier</p>
				<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Spell attack modifier</strong> = your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier</p>
				<h5>Ritual Casting</h5>
				<p>You can cast an archivist spell as a ritual if that spell has the ritual tag and you have the spell in your prayerbook. You don't need to have the spell prepared.</p>
				<h5>Spellcasting Focus</h5>
				<p>You can use an arcane focus or a holy symbol as a spellcasting focus for your archivist spells.</p>
				<h5>Learning Spells of 1st Level and Higher</h5>
				<p>Each time you gain an archivist level, you can add three archivist spells of your choice to your prayerbook. Each of these spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots, as shown on the Archivist table. On your adventures, you might find other spells that you can add to your Prayerbook.</p>
			</description>
			<spellcasting name="Archivist" ability="Intelligence" prepare="true">
				<list>Cleric</list>
			</spellcasting>
			<sheet>
				<description></description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
				<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_RITUAL_CASTING" />
				<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_INTERNAL_PROFICIENCY_SPELLFOCUS_GROUP_ARCANE_FOCUS" />
				<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS_SPELLCASTING_SLOTS_FULL" requirements="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS" />
				<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_INTERNAL_PROFICIENCY_SPELLFOCUS_GROUP_HOLY_SYMBOL" />

				<stat name="archivist:spellcasting:slots:1" value="2" level="1" />
				<stat name="archivist:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="2" />
				<stat name="archivist:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="3" />
				<stat name="archivist:spellcasting:slots:2" value="2" level="3" />
				<stat name="archivist:spellcasting:slots:2" value="1" level="4" />
				<stat name="archivist:spellcasting:slots:3" value="2" level="5" />
				<stat name="archivist:spellcasting:slots:3" value="1" level="6" />
				<stat name="archivist:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="7" />
				<stat name="archivist:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="8" />
				<stat name="archivist:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="9" />
				<stat name="archivist:spellcasting:slots:5" value="1" level="9" />
				<stat name="archivist:spellcasting:slots:5" value="1" level="10" />
				<stat name="archivist:spellcasting:slots:5" value="1" level="18" />
				<stat name="archivist:spellcasting:slots:6" value="1" level="11" />
				<stat name="archivist:spellcasting:slots:6" value="1" level="19" />
				<stat name="archivist:spellcasting:slots:7" value="1" level="13" />
				<stat name="archivist:spellcasting:slots:7" value="1" level="20" />
				<stat name="archivist:spellcasting:slots:8" value="1" level="15" />
				<stat name="archivist:spellcasting:slots:9" value="1" level="17" />

				<stat name="archivist:spellcasting:prepare" value="intelligence:modifier" />
				<stat name="archivist:spellcasting:prepare" value="level:archivist" />

				<select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Archivist)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), 0" level="1" number="3" spellcasting="Archivist" />
				<select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Archivist)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), 0" level="4" number="1" spellcasting="Archivist" />
				<select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Archivist)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), 0" level="10" number="1" spellcasting="Archivist" />

				<select type="Spell" name="Prayerbook (Archivist)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), 1" level="1" number="6" spellcasting="Archivist" />
				<select type="Spell" name="Prayerbook (Archivist)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="2" number="2" spellcasting="Archivist" />
				<select type="Spell" name="Prayerbook (Archivist)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="3" number="2" spellcasting="Archivist" />
				<select type="Spell" name="Prayerbook (Archivist)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="4" number="2" spellcasting="Archivist" />
				<select type="Spell" name="Prayerbook (Archivist)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="5" number="2" spellcasting="Archivist" />
				<select type="Spell" name="Prayerbook (Archivist)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="6" number="2" spellcasting="Archivist" />
				<select type="Spell" name="Prayerbook (Archivist)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="7" number="2" spellcasting="Archivist" />
				<select type="Spell" name="Prayerbook (Archivist)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="8" number="2" spellcasting="Archivist" />
				<select type="Spell" name="Prayerbook (Archivist)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="9" number="2" spellcasting="Archivist" />
				<select type="Spell" name="Prayerbook (Archivist)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="10" number="2" spellcasting="Archivist" />
				<select type="Spell" name="Prayerbook (Archivist)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="11" number="2" spellcasting="Archivist" />
				<select type="Spell" name="Prayerbook (Archivist)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="12" number="2" spellcasting="Archivist" />
				<select type="Spell" name="Prayerbook (Archivist)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="13" number="2" spellcasting="Archivist" />
				<select type="Spell" name="Prayerbook (Archivist)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="14" number="2" spellcasting="Archivist" />
				<select type="Spell" name="Prayerbook (Archivist)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="15" number="2" spellcasting="Archivist" />
				<select type="Spell" name="Prayerbook (Archivist)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="16" number="2" spellcasting="Archivist" />
				<select type="Spell" name="Prayerbook (Archivist)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="17" number="2" spellcasting="Archivist" />
				<select type="Spell" name="Prayerbook (Archivist)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="18" number="2" spellcasting="Archivist" />
				<select type="Spell" name="Prayerbook (Archivist)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="19" number="2" spellcasting="Archivist" />
				<select type="Spell" name="Prayerbook (Archivist)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="20" number="2" spellcasting="Archivist" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Divine Recovery" type="Class Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_ARCHIVIST_DIVINE_RECOVERY">
			<description>
				<p>You can take time to regain some of your magical energy by studying your prayerbook. Once per day when you finish a short rest, you can choose expended spell slots to recover. The spell slots can have a combined level that is equal to or less than half your archivist level (rounded up), and none of the slots can be 6th level or higher.</p>
				<p class="indent">For example, if you're a 4th-level archivist, you can recover up to two levels worth of spell slots. You can recover either a 2nd-level spell slot or two 1st-level spell slots.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
				<description>You can expend up to {{level:archivist:half:up}} combined spell slot levels.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Scholar's Tradition" type="Class Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_ARCHIVIST_SCHOLARS_TRADITION">
			<description>
				<p>When you reach second level, you gain a Scholar's Tradition, allowing you to better understand divine magic by borrowing wizardly knowledge. Choose an Arcane Tradition from the wizard class as your scholar's tradition. Your choice grants you features at 2nd level and again at 6th, 10th, and 14th level.</p>
				<p class="indent">When an Arcane Tradition feature refers to your spellbook, your wizard level, or a wizard spell, it instead refers to your prayerbook, your archivist level, or an archivist spell.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet display="false">
				<description></description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
				<select type="Archetype" name="Arcane Tradition" supports="Arcane Tradition" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Domain Studies" type="Class Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_ARCHIVIST_DOMAIN_STUDIES">
			<description>
				<p>At 3rd level, you expand your understanding of divine magic by focusing upon a divine domain, granting you additional magical knowledge. Choose a Divine Domain from the cleric class as your studied domain.</p>
				<p class="indent">You gain access to the Domain Spells of that divine domain, gaining these domain spells at the levels noted on the respective domain spells table. Once you gain a domain spell, you always have it prepared, and it doesn't count against the number of spells you can prepare each day.</p>
				<p class="indent">If you have a domain spell that doesn't appear on the archivist spell list, the spell is nonetheless an archivist spell for you.</p>
				<p class="indent">At higher levels you expand your understanding of Divine Domains. At 8th, 12th, 16th and 19th levels, you choose an additional Divine Domain to learn. These domains are inactive until you prepare them, not granting you additional spells. At the end of a long rest, you can change your currently prepared domain to different divine domain that you know, losing access to spells from your previous domain and instead gaining the spells from the new domain.</p>
				<p class="indent">Whenever you gain a new domain, you can choose to replace a domain you already have with a different one.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description>You can prepare one of your Divine Domains at the end of a long rest.</description>
				<description level="12">You can prepare two of your Divine Domains at the end of a long rest.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
				<select type="Class Feature" name="Divine Domain" supports="Archivist Divine Domain" level="3" allowReplace="true" />
				<select type="Class Feature" name="Divine Domain" supports="Archivist Divine Domain" level="8" allowReplace="true" />
				<select type="Class Feature" name="Divine Domain" supports="Archivist Divine Domain" level="12" allowReplace="true" />
				<select type="Class Feature" name="Divine Domain" supports="Archivist Divine Domain" level="16" allowReplace="true" />
				<select type="Class Feature" name="Divine Domain" supports="Archivist Divine Domain" level="19" allowReplace="true" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Cantrip Formulas" type="Class Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_ARCHIVIST_CANTRIP_FORMULAS">
			<description>
				<p>At 3rd level, you have scribed a set of divine formulas in your prayerbook that you can use to formulate a cantrip in your mind. Whenever you finish a long rest and consult those formulas in your prayerbook, you can replace one archivist cantrip you know with another cantrip from the archivist spell list.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description>Whenever you finish a long rest and consult those formulas in your prayerbook, you can replace one archivist cantrip you know with another cantrip from the archivist spell lis</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Ability Score Improvement" type="Class Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_ARCHIVIST_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT">
			<description>
				<p>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
				<p class="indent">If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet display="false" />
			<rules>
				<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Archivist 4)" supports="Improvement Option,Archivist,4" level="4" />
				<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Archivist 8)" supports="Improvement Option,Archivist,8" level="8" />
				<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Archivist 12)" supports="Improvement Option,Archivist,12" level="12" />
				<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Archivist 16)" supports="Improvement Option,Archivist,16" level="16" />
				<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Archivist 19)" supports="Improvement Option,Archivist,19" level="19" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Divine Formulas" type="Class Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_ARCHIVIST_DIVINE_FORMULAS">
			<description>
				<p>At 7th level, you learn how to dissassemble and reconstruct divine knowledge in order to alter your prayerbook. At the end of a long rest, you can replace one of the spells within your prayerbook with a different archivist spell of the same level, as you recycle the formulas and knowledge behind the spell into a different set of divine codes.</p>
				<p class="indent">Doing so is not a perfect transaction, with certain amounts of runes and notes being lost and wasted, as well as new divine notes needed to be created from scratch. For each level of the spell replaced, the process consumes 5gp of magical inks and componenets.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
				<description>At the end of a long rest, you can replace one of the spells within your prayerbook with a different archivist spell of the same level. For each level of the spell replaced, the process consumes 5gp of magical inks and componenets.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Domain Expertise" type="Class Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_ARCHIVIST_DOMAIN_EXPERTISE">
			<description>
				<p>At 12th level, you better your understanding of divine domains. You can prepare two sets of domain spells from your Domain Studies, rather than one, when you go to prepare your domain spells. You have both sets of spells prepared, and neither of their spells count against the total number of spells you can prepare.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet display="false" />
			<rules>
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Divine Specialities" type="Class Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_ARCHIVIST_DIVINE_SPECIALITIES">
			<description>
				<p>When you reach 18th level, your practice with your spells has given you the ability to cast certain spells of yours with little effort.</p>
				<p class="indent">Choose 3 spells up to 3rd level from either your prayerbook or from any of your divine domain spell lists.</p>
				<p class="indent">These spells are always prepared for you, they do not count against the number of spells you have prepared, and you can cast each of them once at their lowest level without expending a spell slot. When you do so, you can't do so again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
				<p class="indent">If you want to cast any of these spells at a higher level, you must expend a spell slot as normal.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description>Choose 3 spells up to 3rd level from either your prayerbook or from any of your divine domain spell lists. These spells are always prepared for you, they do not count against the number of spells you have prepared, and you can cast each of them once at their lowest level once per long rest without expending a spell slot.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Miracle" type="Class Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_ARCHIVIST_MIRACLE">
			<description>
				<p>At 20th level, you learn how to invoke a miracle, a divine event of great power usually only summoned forth rarely by clerics. However, by study and practice, you can master your knowledge of the divine to summon forth a miracle into existance.</p>
				<p class="indent">As an action, by speaking the holy words of the miracle you need, you replicate the effects of a cleric spell of 8th level or lower, or a spell from any class of 7th level or lower. You don’t need to meet any requirements in that spell, including costly components. The spell simply takes effect.</p>
				<p class="indent">Alternatively, you can invoke a miracle to perform an effect from one of the following:</p>
				<ul>
                    <li>You create one object of up to 25,000 gp in value that isn’t a magic item.</li>
                    <li>Create a magical item, or add the effects of a magical item to an existing item, to a maximum rarity of Very Rare</li>
                    <li>You allow up to twenty creatures that you can see to regain all hit points, and you end all effects on them described in the greater restoration spell.</li>
                    <li>Return a creature from the dead.</li>
                    <li>Transport creatures of your choice to another location that you know of, or transport another creature to you.</li>
                    <li>You grant up to ten creatures that you can see resistance to a damage type you choose.</li>
                    <li>You grant up to ten creatures you can see immunity to a single spell or other magical effect for 8 hours. For instance, you could make yourself and all your companions immune to a lich’s life drain attack.</li>
                    <li>Undo a single event that occurred within the last 8 hours, changing the result of a dice roll. Reality then shifts to account for this alternate future.</li>
				</ul>
				<p>Alternatively, you may achieve an effect not listed above of an equal or lesser value.</p>
				<p class="indent">Invoking a miracle to do anything other than replicate a spell drains you of your energy. After enduring that stress, each time you cast a spell until you finish a long rest, you take 1d10 necrotic damage per level of that spell. This damage can’t be reduced or prevented in any way. In addition, your Strength drops to 3, if it isn’t 3 or lower already, for 2d4 days. For each of those days that you spend resting and doing nothing more than light activity, your remaining recovery time decreases by 2 days.</p>
				<p class="indent">Once you invoke a miracle, you cannot do so again until you've completed a long rest. You are unable to invoke a miracle while suffering from the fatigue of creating a non-spell effect.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet action="Action">
				<description>You replicate the effects of a cleric spell of 8th level or lower, a spell from any class of 7th level or lower, or an effect from those listed. You don’t need to meet any requirements in that spell, including costly components.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
			</rules>
		</element>
	
	<!-- Archivist Skills -->
		<append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ARCANA">
			<supports>Archivist</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_HISTORY">
			<supports>Archivist</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT">
			<supports>Archivist</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INVESTIGATION">
			<supports>Archivist</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_MEDICINE">
			<supports>Archivist</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_RELIGION">
			<supports>Archivist</supports>
		</append>

</elements>