<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Shae Class</name>
        <author url="https://www.reddit.com/user/JMacGaems/">u/JMacGaems</author>
        <update version="0.0.2">
            <file name="class-shae.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/classes/class-shae.xml" />
            <!-- https://www.gmbinder.com/share/-L_lx2Uy4dqJxdAD_Wo7 -->
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Shae" type="Class" source="GM Binder" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_SHAE">
        <description>
            <p>A thin human, dressed in all black, drops down into a sand pit. In front of him stand a half-orc, greataxe in hand and muscles rippling. The half-orc thinks that he has it in the bag until he realizes that none of his hits have affected the human. With blinding speed the human finishes the half-orc, quickly grabbing the gold in the pot, and leaving.</p>
            <p class="indent">Alone in the tower of a crazed wizard, the elf climbs the steps to the highest chambers. There the wizard lies in wait. The wizard attempts to end the fight before it begins by unleashing his most powerful spell onto the elf. With a quick flick of her wrist, the elf dismantles his magic and sends the spell hurling back at the caster.</p>
            <p class="indent">The corrupt noble hides in his chamber. Outside his door, he can hear the sounds of his men being slaughtered. The sounds stop. He stands up and heads towards the door. A dagger clocked in shadow phases through the door plunging itself into his chest. He stumbles back and as he does a tiefling materializes in front of him holding the dagger.</p>
            <p class="indent">Shaes are masters of infiltration and one-on-one combat that draw power from the Shadowfell to fuel a special type of magic the call Secrets. Each shae brings a different approach to combat. Some shae enjoy being in the front lines, some enjoy a more arcane approach, and some prefer to never be seen in the first place.</p>
            <h4>COLD AND CALCULATING</h4>
            <p>The shae are seen by most to be heartless. This is probably due to the fact that during training shae are taught to suppress their emotions. Doing this keeps the shae cool under pressure and when faced with hard decisions they never rush. They analyze the situation and proceed with the optimal choice.</p>
            <h4>LOYALTY</h4>
            <p>Shae usual live most of their life working for others as contract killers. Rarely do they make friends. However, if you do make friends with a shae, you are friends for life and if someone tries to hurt you even the gods would be powerless to save them.</p>
            <h4>CREATING A SHAE</h4>
            <p></p>
            <h5>QUICK BUILD</h5>
            <p>You can make a Shae quickly by following these suggestions - First, Dexterity should be your highest ability score, followed by Charisma. Next, take either the Criminal or Urchin background.</p>
            <h2>CLASS FEATURES</h2>
            <p>As a shae, you gain the following class features.</p>
            <h5>HIT POINTS</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Hit Dice:</strong> 1d10 per class level</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at 1st Level:</strong> 10 + your Constitution modifier</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at Higher Levels:</strong> 1d10 (or 6) + your Constitution modifier per class level after 1st</li>
            </ul>
            <h5>PROFICIENCIES</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Armor:</strong> Light armor, medium armor</li>
                <li><strong>Weapons:</strong> Simple weapons, martial weapons</li>
                <li><strong>Tools:</strong> Thieves’ Tools</li>
            </ul>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Saving Throws:</strong> Dexterity, Charisma</li>
                <li><strong>Skills:</strong> Choose three from: Acrobatics, Deception, Investigation, Perception, Performance, Persuasion, Sleight of Hand, and Stealth</li>
            </ul>
            <h5>EQUIPMENT</h5>
            <p>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>(a) leather armor or (b) scale mail</li>
                <li>(a) a rapier or (b) a shortsword</li>
                <li>(a) a shortbow and quiver of 20 arrows or (b) a shortsword</li>
                <li>(a) a burglar’s pack, (b) a dungeoneer’s pack, or (c) an explorer’s pack</li>
                <li>two daggers, and thieves’ tools</li>
            </ul>
            <div element="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAE_SHAE_TRAINING" />
            <div element="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAE_SHADE_POINTS" />
            <div element="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAE_SHAE_SECRETS" />
            <div element="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAE_MEDITATION" />
            <div element="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAE_SHAE_CLANS" />
            <div element="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAE_ABILITY_SCORE_INCREASE" />
            <div element="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAE_EXTRA_ATTACK" />
            <div element="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAE_MIND_OF_STEEL" />
            <div element="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAE_EVASION" />
            <div element="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAE_SHADOW_INFUSION" />
            <div element="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAE_ADVANCED_SHAE_TRAINING" />
            <div element="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAE_DOUBLE_TAKE" />
            <div element="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAE_SHAE_AMBITION" />
            <div element="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAE_SHAE_MASTER" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <setters>
            <set name="hd">d10</set>
            <set name="short">A master of single combat that draws power from the Shadowfell.</set>
        </setters>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_MEDIUM_ARMOR" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_MARTIAL_WEAPONS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_THIEVES_TOOLS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_DEXTERITY" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CHARISMA" />
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency (Shae)" number="3" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ACROBATICS|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_DECEPTION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INVESTIGATION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERFORMANCE|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERSUASION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SLEIGHTOFHAND|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_STEALTH" />
            
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAE_SHAE_TRAINING" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAE_SHADE_POINTS" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAE_SHAE_SECRETS" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAE_MEDITATION" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAE_SHAE_CLANS" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAE_ABILITY_SCORE_INCREASE" level="4" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAE_EXTRA_ATTACK" level="5" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAE_MIND_OF_STEEL" level="6" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAE_EVASION" level="7" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAE_SHADOW_INFUSION" level="9" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAE_ADVANCED_SHAE_TRAINING" level="11" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAE_DOUBLE_TAKE" level="15" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAE_SHAE_AMBITION" level="17" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAE_SHAE_MASTER" level="20" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Shae Training" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAE_SHAE_TRAINING">
        <description>
            <p>At 1st level, your vigorous training with the shae has trained your body to go beyond the limitations of a normal person. You gain the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>Your base movement speed increases by 5 feet.</li>
                <li>You gain Darkvision, if your race did not already possess Darkvision, up to 30 ft.</li>
                <li>You gain proficiency stealth or deception. If your already proficient you double your bonus.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
            <rules>
                <stat name="speed:misc" value="5" />
                <select type="Grants" name="Skill Proficiency (Shae Training)" supports="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_OR_DOUBLE_DECEPTION|ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_OR_DOUBLE_STEALTH" />
                <grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_DARKVISION" />
            </rules>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Shade Points" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAE_SHADE_POINTS">
        <description>
            <p>At 2nd level, your connection to the Shadowfell allows you to harness energy called Shade Points. Your Shae level determines the number of points you have, as shown in the Shade Points column of the Shae table. You can spend these points to use various shae features. Expended shade points return after finishing a long rest, at the end of which you draw more energy back from the Shadowfell. Some of your shae features require your target to make a saving throw to resist the feature’s effects. The saving throw DC is calculated as follows:</p>
            <p class="indent">Secrets Save DC= 8 + Proficiency bonus + Charisma Modifier</p>
            <p class="indent">Secrets Attack modifier = your proficiency bonus + your Charisma Modifier</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You have {{shade-points}} Shade Points. Expended shade points return after finishing a long rest. Secrets Save DC = {{secrets:save-dc}}. Secrets Attack modifier = {{secrets:attack-modifier}}.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="shade-points" value="level" />
            <stat name="secrets:save-dc" value="8" />
            <stat name="secrets:save-dc" value="proficiency" />
            <stat name="secrets:save-dc" value="charisma:modifier" />
            <stat name="secrets:attack-modifier" value="proficiency" />
            <stat name="secrets:attack-modifier" value="charisma:modifier" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Shae Secrets" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAE_SHAE_SECRETS">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 2nd level, you learn 3 secret techniques that the shae have created to make them more formidable in combat. Each secret takes a bonus action, except for Sha (requires an action), and 1 shade point to cast, except for Sha (requires no points) and has a Somatic component. At 5th level, you can use an action to instead cast the enhanced version of the secrets. The round you cast an enhanced secret does not count toward the effects duration.</p>
            <p class="indent">Casting a secret takes a lot of energy. You can only cast one secret on your turn.</p>
            <h5>KAGE</h5>
            <p>You take the shadows around you and wrap them around a target within 30 feet of you. The target must make a Charisma saving throw against your Secrets DC. On a failed save, you gain advantage on your first attack each round against the target. This effect persists for a number of rounds equals your Charisma modifier (minimum of 1). Only one creature can be targeted by this effect at a time. Creatures have advantage versus kage’s saving throw if they have been affected by it within the last 24 hours.</p>
            <p><b>ENHANCED</b></p>
            <p>When you hit a target affected by kage for the first time that round with a melee weapon attack, you deal additional necrotic damage equal to 1d6 + half your level.</p>
            <h5>CHA</h5>
            <p>You attempt to mess with the mind of your foe making you a blur to them. Select a target within 30 feet of you. The target must make an Intelligence saving throw against your Secrets DC. On a failed save, the creature has disadvantage on attacks against you. This effect persists for a number of rounds equals your Charisma modifier (minimum of 1). Only one creature can be targeted by this effect at a time. Creatures have advantage versus cha’s saving throw if they have been affected by it within the last 24 hours.</p>
            <p><b>ENHANCED</b></p>
            <p>You gain resistance to weapon damage dealt by the target.</p>
            <h5>SHA</h5>
            <p>You can manipulate the shadows of a target within 15 feet of you causing it to curl around the creature and constrict their movement. Make a melee secrets attack roll. On a hit, the target takes 1d6 necrotic damage. The target must then make a Strength saving throw (you can decide which). On a failed save the creatures movement speed decreases to 0 until the start of you next turn.</p>
            <p class="indent">This damage increase at 5th level (2d6), 11th level (3d6), and 17th level (4d6).</p>
            <p><b>ENHANCED</b></p>
            <p>When you enhance sha, you can either choose between the original effect or it must make a Charisma saving throw. On a fail, until the start of your next turn, the creature subtracts a 1d4 on the next saving throw it makes.</p>
            <h5>LESSER SECRETS</h5>
            <p>In addition to the secrets already granted to you, you gain access to lesser secrets (detailed at the end of the class). These secrets enhance the body allowing you to do feats though of as impossible. They do not require any components to activate. You can choose 2 lesser secrets. You can switch out the secrets you know on a short rest. As you level up, you can prepare additional secrets as shown in the shae class table.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAE_SHAE_SECRETS_KAGE" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAE_SHAE_SECRETS_KAGE_ENHANCED" level="5" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAE_SHAE_SECRETS_CHA" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAE_SHAE_SECRETS_CHA_ENHANCED" level="5" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAE_SHAE_SECRETS_SHA" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAE_SHAE_SECRETS_SHA_ENHANCED" level="5" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAE_LESSER_SECRETS" level="2" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Kage" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAE_SHAE_SECRETS_KAGE">
            <description>
                <p>You take the shadows around you and wrap them around a target within 30 feet of you. The target must make a Charisma saving throw against your Secrets DC. On a failed save, you gain advantage on your first attack each round against the target. This effect persists for a number of rounds equals your Charisma modifier (minimum of 1). Only one creature can be targeted by this effect at a time. Creatures have advantage versus kage’s saving throw if they have been affected by it within the last 24 hours.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1 Shade Point" action="Bonus Action">
                <description>A target within 30 feet of you must make a Charisma saving throw (save DC {{secrets:save-dc}}. On a failed save, you gain advantage on the first attack each round against the target. This lasts for {{kage:duration}} rounds. Only one creature can be targeted by this effect at a time. Creatures have advantage versus kage’s saving throw if they have been affected by it within the last 24 hours.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="kage:duration" value="1" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="kage:duration" value="charisma:modifier" bonus="base" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Kage: Enhanced" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAE_SHAE_SECRETS_KAGE_ENHANCED">
            <description>
                <p>When you hit a target affected by kage for the first time that round with a melee weapon attack, you deal additional necrotic damage equal to 1d6 + half your level.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1 Shade Point" action="Action">
                <description>In addition to the regular effect, when you hit a target affected by kage for the first time that round with a melee weapon attack, you deal additional 1d6 + {{level:half}} necrotic damage.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Cha" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAE_SHAE_SECRETS_CHA">
            <description>
                <p>You attempt to mess with the mind of your foe making you a blur to them. Select a target within 30 feet of you. The target must make an Intelligence saving throw against your Secrets DC. On a failed save, the creature has disadvantage on attacks against you. This effect persists for a number of rounds equals your Charisma modifier (minimum of 1). Only one creature can be targeted by this effect at a time. Creatures have advantage versus cha’s saving throw if they have been affected by it within the last 24 hours.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1 Shade Point" action="Bonus Action">
                <description>A target within 30 feet of you must make an Intelligence saving throw (save DC {{secrets:save-dc}}. On a failed save, the creature has disadvantage on attacks against you. This lasts for {{cha:duration}} rounds. Only one creature can be targeted by this effect at a time. Creatures have advantage versus cha’s saving throw if they have been affected by it within the last 24 hours.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="cha:duration" value="1" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="cha:duration" value="charisma:modifier" bonus="base" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Cha: Enhanced" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAE_SHAE_SECRETS_CHA_ENHANCED">
            <description>
                <p>You gain resistance to weapon damage dealt by the target.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1 Shade Point" action="Action">
                <description>In addition to the regular effect, you also gain resistance to weapon damage dealt by the target.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Sha" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAE_SHAE_SECRETS_SHA">
            <description>
                <p>You can manipulate the shadows of a target within 15 feet of you causing it to curl around the creature and constrict their movement. Make a secrets attack roll. On a hit, the target takes 1d6 necrotic damage. The target must then make a Strength saving throw (you can decide which). On a failed save the creatures movement speed decreases to 0 until the start of you next turn.</p>
                <p class="indent">This damage increase at 5th level (2d6), 11th level (3d6), and 17th level (4d6).</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>Make a secrets attack roll against a creature within 15 feet of you. On a hit, the target takes {{sha:damage-dice}}d6 necrotic damage. The target must then make a Strength or Dexterity saving throw (you can decide which, save DC {{secrets:save-dc}}). On a failed save the creatures movement speed decreases to 0 until the start of you next turn.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="sha:damage-dice" value="1" level="2" />
                <stat name="sha:damage-dice" value="1" level="5" />
                <stat name="sha:damage-dice" value="1" level="11" />
                <stat name="sha:damage-dice" value="1" level="17" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Sha: Enhanced" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAE_SHAE_SECRETS_SHA_ENHANCED">
            <description>
                <p>When you enhance sha, you can either choose between the original effect or the creature must make a Charisma saving throw. On a fail, until the start of your next turn, the creature subtracts a 1d4 on the next saving throw it makes.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>You can either choose between the original effect or the creature must make a Charisma saving throw. On a fail, until the start of your next turn, the creature subtracts a 1d4 on the next saving throw it makes.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Lesser Secrets" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAE_LESSER_SECRETS">
            <description>
                <p>In addition to the secrets already granted to you, you gain access to lesser secrets (detailed at the end of the class). These secrets enhance the body allowing you to do feats though of as impossible. They do not require any components to activate. You can choose 2 lesser secrets. You can switch out the secrets you know on a short rest. As you level up, you can prepare additional secrets as shown in the shae class table.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can choose up to {{lesser-secrets:known}} lesser secrets. You can change prepared secrets each short rest.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="lesser-secrets:known" value="2" level="2" />
                <stat name="lesser-secrets:known" value="1" level="6" />
                <stat name="lesser-secrets:known" value="1" level="10" />
                <stat name="lesser-secrets:known" value="1" level="14" />
                <stat name="lesser-secrets:known" value="1" level="18" />
            </rules>
        </element>
    <element name="Meditation" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAE_MEDITATION">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at level 2, you have learned to recover most of your used shade points. During a short rest you can recover up to half of your maximum shade points (rounded down). For example, if you have a max of 6 shade points and you start your rest with 2 you will gain 1 back.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>During a short rest you can recover up to half of your maximum shade points (rounded down).</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Shae Clans" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAE_SHAE_CLANS">
        <description>
            <p>The three shae clans were once one in the same, however the founder decided to split up the disciplines to ensure that no one shae was more powerful than he. He taught each of his sons a discipline and set them out into to the world to develop it and make it their own.</p>
            <p class="indent">When you reach 3rd level, you gain additional training under a certain clan, all detailed at the end of the class description. Your clan grants you features at 3rd level and again at 8th, 13th, and 18th level.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Archetype" name="Shae Clan" supports="Shae Clan" level="3" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Ability Score Increase" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAE_ABILITY_SCORE_INCREASE">
        <description>
            <p>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two Ability Scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Shae 4)" supports="Improvement Option,Shae,4" level="4" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Shae 8)" supports="Improvement Option,Shae,8" level="8" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Shae 12)" supports="Improvement Option,Shae,12" level="12" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Shae 16)" supports="Improvement Option,Shae,16" level="16" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Shae 19)" supports="Improvement Option,Shae,19" level="19" />     
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Extra Attack" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAE_EXTRA_ATTACK">
        <description>
            <p>Beginning at 5th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the attack action on your turn.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="extra attack:count" value="2" level="5" bonus="extra attack" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Mind of Steel" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAE_MIND_OF_STEEL">
        <description>
            <p>At 6th level, when you are subjected to a Wisdom or Intelligence saving throw, you can add your Charisma modifier to the roll. You make this choice after you see the roll, but before the DM says the results. You can use this ability once per long rest.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can use this feature twice between long rests starting at 10th level and three times between long rests starting at 14th level.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="{{mind-of-steel:uses}}/Long Rest">
            <description>When you are subjected to a Wisdom or Intelligence saving throw, you can add your Charisma modifier to the roll. You make this choice after you see the roll, but before the DM says the results.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="mind-of-steel:uses" value="1" level="6" />
            <stat name="mind-of-steel:uses" value="1" level="10" />
            <stat name="mind-of-steel:uses" value="1" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Evasion" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAE_EVASION">
        <description>
            <p>Beginning at 7th level, you can partially shift your body into the Shadowfell to avoid certain area effects, such as a red dragon’s fiery breath or an Ice Storm spell. When you are subjected to an effect that allows you to make a Dexterity saving throw to take only half damage, you can use your reaction and 1 shade point to instead take no damage if you succeed on the saving throw, and only half damage if you fail.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you are subjected to an effect that allows you to make a Dexterity saving throw to take only half damage, you can use your reaction and 1 shade point to instead take no damage if you succeed on the saving throw, and only half damage if you fail.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Shadow Infusion" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAE_SHADOW_INFUSION">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 9th level, when you roll the maximum damage on at least one of you weapons damage die, add your Charisma modifier to the damage roll.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you roll the maximum damage on at least one of your weapons damage die, add your charisma modifier ({{charisma:modifier}}) to the damage roll.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Advanced Shae Training" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAE_ADVANCED_SHAE_TRAINING">
        <description>
            <p>At 11th level, all necrotic damage done from shae abilities ignore resistances and treats immunity as resistance against creatures marked by secrets. In addition, your movement speed increases by 5 feet and you gain resistance to necrotic damage.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>All necrotic damage done from shae abilities ignore resistances and treats immunity as resistance against creatures marked by secrets.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_NECROTIC" />
            <stat name="speed:misc" value="5" level="11" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Double Take" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAE_DOUBLE_TAKE">
        <description>
            <p>At level 15, once per turn, you can take an additional reaction by spending 1 shade points. You can only use one reaction per trigger.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Once per turn, you can take an additional reaction by spending 1 shade points. You can only use one reaction per trigger.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Shae Ambition" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAE_SHAE_AMBITION">
        <description>
            <p>At level 17, your expertise in battle gives you the edge on your enemies. When you roll initiative, you do so with advantage.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you roll initiative, you do so with advantage.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Shae Master" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAE_SHAE_MASTER">
        <description>
            <p>At 20th level, your shae training has finally completed and you have raised to the rank of master. You gain the following benefits</p>
            <ul>
                <li>All necrotic damage done from shae abilities ignores resistance and immunity to all targets.</li>
                <li>You gain Blindsight up to 15ft.</li>
                <li>Your Dexterity and Charisma increase by 2 points each to a max of 22.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>All necrotic damage done from shae abilities ignores resistance and immunity to all targets.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
			<grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_BLINDSIGHT" />
            <stat name="dexterity:max" value="2" />
            <stat name="charisma:max" value="2" />
            <stat name="dexterity" value="2" />
            <stat name="charisma" value="2" />
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Striker" type="Archetype" source="GM Binder" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_SHAE_STRIKER">
        <supports>Shae Clan</supports>
        <description>
            <div element="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STRIKER_HARD_TO_CRACK" />
            <div element="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STRIKER_TAINTED_BLOOD" />
            <div element="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STRIKER_FLEX" />
            <div element="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STRIKER_CRACK_IN_THE_ARMOR" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STRIKER_HARD_TO_CRACK" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STRIKER_TAINTED_BLOOD" level="8" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STRIKER_FLEX" level="13" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STRIKER_CRACK_IN_THE_ARMOR" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Hard to Crack" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STRIKER_HARD_TO_CRACK">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at level 3, your hit point maximum increase by 1 per shae level. In addition, when you land a melee attack you can spend 1 shade point to gain 1d10 + your Constitution modifier in temporary hit points. If you roll a 1 you can reroll it but you must take the new result. You can use this once per turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you land a melee attack you can spend 1 shade point to gain 1d10 + {{constitution:modifier}} in temporary hit points. If you roll a 1 you can reroll it but you must take the new result. You can use this once per turn.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="hp" value="level" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Tainted Blood" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STRIKER_TAINTED_BLOOD">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at level 8, you score a critical hit on a 19. Whenever you roll a critical on the dice for a melee attack, the target takes 1d6 necrotic damage at the start of it’s next turn. This damage increases to 2d6 at 18th level.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You score a critical hit on a 19. Whenever you roll a critical on the dice for a melee attack, the target takes {{tainted-blood:damage-dice}}d6 necrotic damage at the start of it’s next turn.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="tainted-blood:damage-dice" value="1" level="8" />
                <stat name="tainted-blood:damage-dice" value="1" level="18" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Flex" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STRIKER_FLEX">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at level 13, when an attacker that you can see hits you with an attack, you can use your reaction to reduce the damage. Choose any number of hit die up to your half your proficiency bonus (rounded down) to expend and expend a number of shade points equal to the amount of hit dice you chose. Roll the dice and subtract that number from the damage. If you roll any 1’s you can reroll them but you must take the new results.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Reaction">
                <description>When an attacker that you can see hits you with an attack, you can reduce the damage. Choose up to {{flex:hit-dice}} hit die to expend and expend {{flex:hit-dice}} shade points. Roll the dice and subtract that number from the damage. If you roll any 1’s you can reroll them but you must take the new results.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="flex:hit-dice" value="proficiency:half" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Crack in the Armor" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STRIKER_CRACK_IN_THE_ARMOR">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at level 18, as an	action, expending 3 shade points, you can make a special attack. The attack deals normal damage and the target becomes vulnerable to the next attack you make against it.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>You can expend 3 shade points to make a special attack that deals normal damage and the target becomes vulnerable to the next attack you make against it.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    <element name="Keeper" type="Archetype" source="GM Binder" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_SHAE_KEEPER">
        <supports>Shae Clan</supports>
        <description>
            <div element="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_KEEPER_SPELLCASTING" />
            <div element="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_KEEPER_WELL_RESEARCHED" />
            <div element="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_KEEPER_POWER_IN_SECRETS" />
            <div element="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_KEEPER_SPELL_BREAKER" />
            <div element="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_KEEPER_ARCANA_THIEF" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <spellcasting name="Shae" ability="Charisma" prepare="true">
            <list known="true">Shae</list>
        </spellcasting>
        <setters>
            <set name="spellcaster">true</set>
            <set name="spellcastingAbility">Charisma</set>
            <set name="spellcastingClass">Shae</set>
        </setters>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_KEEPER_SPELLCASTING" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_KEEPER_WELL_RESEARCHED" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_KEEPER_POWER_IN_SECRETS" level="8" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_KEEPER_SPELL_BREAKER" level="13" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_KEEPER_ARCANA_THIEF" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Limited Flexible Spell Casting" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_KEEPER_SPELLCASTING">
            <description>
                <h5>SPELLCASTING</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Class Level</td><td>Spell Level</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>3</td><td>1st</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>7</td><td>2nd</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>13</td><td>3rd</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>18</td><td>4th</td></tr>
                </table>
                <h5>Cantrips</h5>
                <p>At 3rd level, you know three cantrips of your choice from the shae spell list.</p>
                <h5>Preparing and Casting Spells</h5>
                <p>You can cast a spell using a number of shade points equal to the spells level. The table shows you the highest level of spell you can cast. You can prepare a number of spells equal to your proficiency bonus + 2. Once a day when you finish a short rest you can change one of your spells. When you finish a long rest you can change any number of your prepared spells.</p>
                <h5>Casting at Higher Levels</h5>
                <p>You can cast spells at higher levels by spending a number of shade points equal to the level you wish to cast the spell at.</p>
                <h5>Spellcasting Ability</h5>
                <p>Your spellcasting modifier is Charisma. If the spell requires the creature to make a saving throw the DC is equal to your Secrets DC.</p>
                <h5>Spellcasting Focus</h5>
                <p>You can use your weapon as a spellcasting focus for your Shae spells.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can cast a spell by spending a number of Shade Points equal to the level of the spell.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Shae)" number="3" supports="$(spellcasting:list), 0" spellcasting="Shae" known="true" />
                <stat name="shae:spellcasting:prepare" value="proficiency" />
                <stat name="shae:spellcasting:prepare" value="2" />
                <stat name="shae:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="3" />
                <stat name="shae:spellcasting:slots:1" value="-1" level="3" />
                <stat name="shae:spellcasting:slots:2" value="1" level="7" />
                <stat name="shae:spellcasting:slots:2" value="-1" level="7" />
                <stat name="shae:spellcasting:slots:3" value="1" level="13" />
                <stat name="shae:spellcasting:slots:3" value="-1" level="13" />
                <stat name="shae:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="18" />
                <stat name="shae:spellcasting:slots:4" value="-1" level="18" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Well Researched" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_KEEPER_WELL_RESEARCHED">
            <description>
                <p>At 3rd level, your research has sharpened your skills. You can add half your proficiency bonus, rounded down, to any Wisdom or Intelligence ability checks or saving throws you make that doesn’t already include your proficiency bonus.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, you can use your bonus action to recall spent shade points. You gain a number of shade points equal to your proficiency bonus. You cannot gain more shade points than your maximum using this feature. Once you use this ability you cannot use it again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description> You can use your bonus action to recall spent shade points. You gain a number of shade points equal to your proficiency bonus. You cannot gain more shade points than your maximum using this feature.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WELL_RESEARCHED_PASSIVE" level="3" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Well Researched" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WELL_RESEARCHED_PASSIVE">
                <description />
                <sheet>
                    <description>You can {{proficiency:half}} to any Wisdom or Intelligence ability checks or saving throws you make that doesn’t already include your proficiency bonus.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
        <element name="Power in Secrets" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_KEEPER_POWER_IN_SECRETS">
            <description>
                <p>At 8th level, when you cast an enhanced secret or spell you can use your bonus action to make a weapon attack. When you do so you deal additional necrotic damage equal to your Charisma modifier.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>When you cast an enhanced secret or spell you make a weapon attack. When you do so you deal {{charisma:modifier}} additional necrotic damage.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Spell Breaker" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_KEEPER_SPELL_BREAKER">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 13th level, when you use counterspell or dispel magic you add half your proficiency bonus (rounded down) to the ability check.</p>
                <p class="indent">In addition, when you successfully dispel or counter magic you gain 1 shade points.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you use counterspell or dispel magic you add {{proficiency:half}} to the ability check. In addition, when you successfully dispel or counter magic you gain 1 shade points.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Arcana Thief" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_KEEPER_ARCANA_THIEF">
            <description>
                <p>At level 18, your thirst for knowledge allows you to learn on the fly. When you see or counter a spell cast within 60 feet you can use your reaction (not needed if you used Counter Spell) to make an arcana check (this cannot be used on 8th and 9th level spells). The DC equals 10 + the spells level. If you succeed on the check you can spend a number of points equal to the spells level to add this spell to your shae spell list. You can gain a number of spells this way equal to your Charisma modifier. Spells you learn using this feature cannot deal direct damage to a target, such as <i>fireball</i>. However, if you were to learn the spell <i>simulacrum</i>, you are not dealing direct damage even if you are using the clone in combat.</p>
                <p class="indent">If you use this feature again you can switch out one of these spells. After seven days you lose access to the spell. If the spell that you copied is of 4th level or lower, the highest you can cast it as is 4th level. Spells of 5th, 6th, and 7th level can only be cast at their lowest level.</p>
                <p class="indent">Casting spells at high levels are taxing on the body. You can only cast spells of 6th and 7th level twice per long rest.</p>
                <p class="indent">In addition, if you can maintain an acquired spell in your spell list for a year it is permanently added to your spell list after which the spell no longer counts against the number of spell you can acquire using this feature.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you see or counter a spell cast within 60 feet you can use your reaction (not needed if you used Counter Spell) to make an arcana check (this cannot be used on 8th and 9th level spells). The DC equals 10 + the spells level. If you succeed on the check you can spend a number of points equal to the spells level to add this spell to your shae spell list. You can gain up to {{charisma:modifier}} spells this way.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    <element name="Jumper" type="Archetype" source="GM Binder" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_SHAE_JUMPER">
        <supports>Shae Clan</supports>
        <description>
            <div element="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_JUMPER_BLINKING_DAGGERS" />
            <div element="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_JUMPER_SHIFT" />
            <div element="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_JUMPER_ANCHOR_POINT" />
            <div element="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_JUMPER_PHASING_DAGGERS" />
            <div element="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_JUMPER_THIRSTING_DAGGERS" />
            <div element="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_JUMPER_CHAUFFER" />
            <div element="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_JUMPER_SPECTRAL_DAGGER" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_JUMPER_BLINKING_DAGGERS" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_JUMPER_SHIFT" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_JUMPER_ANCHOR_POINT" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_JUMPER_PHASING_DAGGERS" level="8" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_JUMPER_THIRSTING_DAGGERS" level="13" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_JUMPER_CHAUFFER" level="13" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_JUMPER_SPECTRAL_DAGGER" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Blinking Daggers" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_JUMPER_BLINKING_DAGGERS">
            <description>
                <p>You always know the shadow daggers secret. Using the same bonus action, you can spend addition Shade Points up to your proficiency bonus to create additional daggers. The daggers that you do not hold in your hands float around your forearm. The duration of this secret increases to 1 hour.</p>
                <p class="indent">When a creature or object you can see is hit by an attack using your shadow daggers, you can use your reaction to teleport to an unoccupied space of your choosing within 5 feet of the target. If there is no unoccupied space, then the ability is wasted.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>You always know the Shadow Daggers secret. When you use the Shadow Daggers secret, you can spend up to {{proficiency}} Shade Points to create an additional dagger per point spent. The duration of Shadow Daggers is 1 hour. When a creature or object you can see is hit by an attack using your shadow daggers, you can use your reaction to teleport to an unoccupied space of your choosing within 5 feet of the target. If there is no unoccupied space, then the ability is wasted.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAE_SHADOW_DAGGERS" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Shift" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_JUMPER_SHIFT">
            <description>
                <p>At 3rd level, you can teleport to any of your shadow daggers within 30 feet of you as a bonus action. You know the exact location of all your daggers. If you attempt to teleport to a dagger located on a space that is occupied, you instead go to the nearest unoccupied space of your choosing.</p>
                <p class="indent">The range of this ability increases to 60 feet at 13th level.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can teleport to any of your shadow daggers within {{shift:range}} feet of you as a bonus action. You know the exact location of all your daggers. If you attempt to teleport to a dagger located on a space that is occupied, you instead go to the nearest unoccupied space of your choosing.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="shift:range" value="30" level="3" />
                <stat name="shift:range" value="60" level="13" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Anchor Point" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_JUMPER_ANCHOR_POINT">
            <description>
                <p>At 8th level, as an action, you create an invisible sigil on a surface using 1 shade point. This sigil lasts until you take a short or long rest. While within 150 feet of the sigil you can use a bonus action and 2 shade point teleport back to it. Once you do so the sigil fades away.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>You create an invisible sigil on a surface using 1 shade point. This sigil lasts until you take a short or long rest. While within 150 feet of the sigil you can use a bonus action and 2 shade point teleport back to it. Once you do so the sigil fades away.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Phasing Daggers" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_JUMPER_PHASING_DAGGERS">
            <description>
                <p>At 8th level, barriers cannot keep your blade from plunging into your target. When you throw your shadow dagger, you can spend 2 shade points to make it intangible. The dagger can phase through up to 5 feet of material (not lead). If after 5 feet the dagger is still going through solid material it returns back to you. The dagger can only go through one object.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you throw your shadow dagger, you can spend 2 shade points to make it intangible. The dagger can phase through up to 5 feet of material (not lead). If after 5 feet the dagger is still going through solid material it returns back to you. The dagger can only go through one object.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Thirsting Daggers" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_JUMPER_THIRSTING_DAGGERS">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 13th level, each time you reduce a dangerous creature (DM’s discretion) to 0 hit points with a shadow dagger and kill them, you regain 1 spent shade point.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Each time you reduce a dangerous creature (DM’s discretion) to 0 hit points with a shadow dagger and kill them, you regain 1 spent shade point.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Chauffeur" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_JUMPER_CHAUFFER">
            <description>
                <p>At 13th level, when you use Shift you can bring one creature within 5 feet of you that is your size or smaller along with you.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you use Shift you can bring one creature within 5 feet of you that is your size or smaller along with you.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Spectral Dagger" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_JUMPER_SPECTRAL_DAGGER">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 18th level, your dagger bends to your will, twisting and turning and phasing through your enemies. As an action, and expending 3 shade points, choose up to 5 creatures you can see within the range of your dagger. Make a ranged attack against each creature. You can hit a target multiple times if there are at least 3 different targets. If all hits are successful you deal an extra 3d4 damage on each hit.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>You can expend 3 shade points, and make a ranged attach against up to 5 creatures you can see within the range of your dagger. You can hit a target multiple times if there are at least 3 different targets. If all hits are successful you deal an extra 3d4 damage on each hit.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    <!-- Shae Spells -->
      <!-- Cantrips -->
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGE_HAND">
            <supports>Shae</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MESSAGE">
            <supports>Shae</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_THAUMATURGY">
            <supports>Shae</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FRIENDS">
            <supports>Shae</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MINOR_ILLUSION">
            <supports>Shae</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GUIDANCE">
            <supports>Shae</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLADE_WARD">
            <supports>Shae</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DANCING_LIGHTS">
            <supports>Shae</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_MOLD_EARTH">
            <supports>Shae</supports>
        </append>

      <!-- 1st Level Spells -->
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CHARM_PERSON">
            <supports>Shae</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FEATHER_FALL">
            <supports>Shae</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SLEEP">
            <supports>Shae</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_IDENTIFY">
            <supports>Shae</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FOG_CLOUD">
            <supports>Shae</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ABSORB_ELEMENTS">
            <supports>Shae</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_MAGIC">
            <supports>Shae</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_SNARE">
            <supports>Shae</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMPREHEND_LANGUAGES">
            <supports>Shae</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BANE">
            <supports>Shae</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ALARM">
            <supports>Shae</supports>
        </append>

      <!-- 2nd Level Spells -->
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DARKNESS">
            <supports>Shae</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MISTY_STEP">
            <supports>Shae</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ALTER_SELF">
            <supports>Shae</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_KNOCK">
            <supports>Shae</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPIDER_CLIMB">
            <supports>Shae</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SEE_INVISIBILITY">
            <supports>Shae</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIND_TRAPS">
            <supports>Shae</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PASS_WITHOUT_TRACE">
            <supports>Shae</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LOCATE_OBJECT">
            <supports>Shae</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ARCANE_LOCK">
            <supports>Shae</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SILENCE">
            <supports>Shae</supports>
        </append>

      <!-- 3rd Level Spells -->
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_NONDETECTION">
            <supports>Shae</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COUNTERSPELL">
            <supports>Shae</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GLYPH_OF_WARDING">
            <supports>Shae</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HASTE">
            <supports>Shae</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISPEL_MAGIC">
            <supports>Shae</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SENDING">
            <supports>Shae</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FLY">
            <supports>Shae</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAJOR_IMAGE">
            <supports>Shae</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGIC_CIRCLE">
            <supports>Shae</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HYPNOTIC_PATTERN">
            <supports>Shae</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TONGUES">
            <supports>Shae</supports>
        </append>

      <!-- 4th Level Spells -->
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ARCANE_EYE">
            <supports>Shae</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DIMENSION_DOOR">
            <supports>Shae</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_SHADOW_OF_MOIL">
            <supports>Shae</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BANISHMENT">
            <supports>Shae</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONFUSION">
            <supports>Shae</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LEOMUNDS_SECRET_CHEST">
            <supports>Shae</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MORDENKAINENS_PRIVATE_SANCTUM">
            <supports>Shae</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_OTILUKES_RESILIENT_SPHERE">
            <supports>Shae</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LOCATE_CREATURE">
            <supports>Shae</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FREEDOM_OF_MOVEMENT">
            <supports>Shae</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GREATER_INVISIBILITY">
            <supports>Shae</supports>
        </append>

    <!-- Lesser Secrets -->
        <element name="Shadow Daggers" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_JMACGAEMS_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SHAE_SHADOW_DAGGERS">
            <description>
                <p>You can use your bonus action to create two daggers made of shadow that use your charisma modifier for your attack and damage rolls. These daggers have the same statistics of a normal dagger except they do force or necrotic damage (you choose when you make them and you can choose for each one to be different). When you throw a dagger it teleports back to your hand if you choose it to. These daggers last for 10 minutes before vanishing. At 3rd level, the daggers gain a +1 to attack and damage rolls. This increases to +2 at 10th level and +3 at 17th level. Also at 10th level, the daggers deal an additional die of damage. You can dismiss the daggers as a bonus action.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="Lesser Secret: 1 Shade Point">
                <description>You can create two daggers made of shadow that use your charisma modifier ({{charisma:modifier}}) for your attack and damage rolls. These daggers have the same statistics of a normal dagger except they do force or necrotic damage (you choose when you make them and you can choose for each one to be different). When you throw a dagger it teleports back to your hand if you choose it to. These daggers last for 10 minutes before vanishing.</description>
                <description level="3">You can create two daggers made of shadow that use your charisma modifier ({{charisma:modifier}}) for your attack and damage rolls. These daggers have the same statistics of a normal dagger except they do force or necrotic damage (you choose when you make them and you can choose for each one to be different). The daggers gain a +1 to attack and damage rolls. When you throw a dagger it teleports back to your hand if you choose it to. These daggers last for 10 minutes before vanishing.</description>
                <description level="10">You can create two daggers made of shadow that use your charisma modifier ({{charisma:modifier}}) for your attack and damage rolls. These daggers have the same statistics of a normal dagger except they do force or necrotic damage (you choose when you make them and you can choose for each one to be different). The daggers gain a +2 to attack and damage rolls and do an additional 1d4 damage. When you throw a dagger it teleports back to your hand if you choose it to. These daggers last for 10 minutes before vanishing.</description>
                <description level="17">You can create two daggers made of shadow that use your charisma modifier ({{charisma:modifier}}) for your attack and damage rolls. These daggers have the same statistics of a normal dagger except they do force or necrotic damage (you choose when you make them and you can choose for each one to be different). The daggers gain a +3 to attack and damage rolls and do an additional 1d4 damage. When you throw a dagger it teleports back to your hand if you choose it to. These daggers last for 10 minutes before vanishing.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
</elements>