<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Mesmer Class</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="class-mesmer.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/classes/class-mesmer.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="The Mesmer" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_AERONDRAKE_GMBINDER_SOURCE_THE_MESMER">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation">MESMER</set>
            <set name="url">https://www.gmbinder.com/share/-L3x8hIaH5iziHFqz9xb</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" abbreviation="AD" url="https://www.reddit.com/user/AeronDrake/">u/AeronDrake</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20201030</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Mesmer" type="Class" source="The Mesmer" id="ID_AD_MESMER_CLASS_MESMER">
        <description>
            <p>A human dressed in fancy clothes walks quietly through the battlefield looking directly to the orc shaman in front of him. The orc rises his arms and starts to shout an arcane spell. A small ball of fire appears in his hands, and with each word the ball grows larger and larger. When the fireball was ready to be released, the human points the orc while he quickly whispers some words, and just a second before the fireball is released, it disappears in the air, and the human starts to walk again towards the confused orc.</p>
            <p class="indent">The gnome examines a large room, filled with empty crates and dusty tables. After a few minutes, she closes her eyes and touches the ground to cast a spell. A few seconds pass, and in a blink of an eye, the whole room is transformed into a clean room, the crates are filled with weapons and in one of the tables appears a complete map of the city and some letters with orders for transporting illegal products. The gnome takes the map and the letters and exit to the street in direction to the local authorities headquarter.</p>
            <p class="indent">The elf walks to the mansion entrance. He didn’t know the guards, but that wasn’t a problem. When he reaches the gate, he finishes to whisper an incantation, and then both guards salute him and opens the door. The elf smiles and enter to the mansion.</p>
            <p class="indent">Whether an adventurer, an investigator or an infiltrator, a mesmer controls the energy to manipulate minds, create illusions and interrupt the flow of magic to stop a magical effect or spell.</p>
            <h4>ENERGY MANIPULATORS</h4>
            <p>For the common folk, a mesmer is an illusionist that came from a circus who can create illusions and play tricks in the mind of its audience for entertainment. Even though mesmers can do that kind of tricks, they are more powerful than just a local magician, and only a few knows or have seen the true power of mesmers. They use the energy surrounding every living entity and canalizes it to cast powerful spells, create illusions, and striking the mind. They are constantly storing energy and releasing it with each spell they cast, maintaining the balance between the living creatures around them, unless they decide to destroy the energy from a particular foe, causing devastating mind strikes, and in some cases, draining its energy.</p>
            <p class="indent">Similar to wizards, mesmers studies the energy of the living and manipulate the arcane essence of it to use it as they need. Every mesmer school specialize in teaching and discovering new ways to use the mesmer magic traditions: domination, dueling, illusion and inspiration.</p>
            <h4>COVERT AGENTS AND INVESTIGATORS</h4>
            <p>When an empire or guild can’t send a thief or an assassin to a place to collect information, they send a mesmer to gather what they need. Mesmers can enter and leave a place like nothing happened thanks to its illusions and trickery. Their ability to disguise themselves and to distract foes using mind tricks makes them the perfect infiltrators in stealthy tasks.</p>
            <p class="indent">In other cases, they work with local authorities to investigate unknown occurrences where magic is or may be involved, and for tracking down dangerous spellcasters due its ability to control the energy used in spells, interrupting their foes before they can cast a spell.</p>
            <h4>COMBAT ILLUSIONISTS</h4>
            <p>Mesmers are masters of illusion and control, subverting the enemy’s energy for their own use, and that of their allies. Combined with any other profession, their skills provide excellent support, turning enemies’ powers against them and changing the very fabric of reality to hinder foes and help allies. Mesmers have the ability to cast spells quickly, which can make all the difference in the heat of battle. Their powers of domination allow them to take control of enemy skills and energy. Their unique illusionary talents can slow or even halt enemy movement and skill casting, or cause imaginary illnesses that drain health and energy from foes while healing and energizing allies. While Mesmers are not known for brute strength, their abilities to confuse, distract, and drain the enemy’s resources more than compensates.</p>
            <h4>CREATING A MESMER</h4>
            <p>Creating a mesmer requires a backstory related to one mesmer traditions. As a starting character, you’ll choose a mesmer tradition that will guide how you use the energy, but the exact moment of discovery is up to you to decide. Perhaps you belong to a mesmer family Maybe you discovered that you can somewhat control that energy? Someone taught you the basics of the mesmer magic? You learned some illusion tricks for entering the local circus? Did you attend a mesmer school where you studied a mesmer tradition and practiced your incantations? Did you were an apprentice investigator for a small town?</p>
            <h5>QUICK BUILD</h5>
            <p>You can make a mesmer quickly by following these suggestions. First, Charisma should be your highest ability score, followed by Dexterity. Second, choose the entertainer or the Investigator background. Third, choose the Energy bolt and Minor illusion cantrips. (You can find the investigator background in the Sword Coast Adventurer’s Guide)</p>
            <h2>CLASS FEATURES</h2>
            <p>As a mesmer, you gain the following class features.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">HIT POINTS</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Hit Dice:</strong> 1d6 per mesmer level</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at 1st Level:</strong> 6 + your Constitution modifier</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at Higher Levels:</strong> 1d6 (or 4) + your Constitution modifier per mesmer level after 1st</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">PROFICIENCIES</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled mb">
                <li><strong>Armor:</strong> None</li>
                <li><strong>Weapons:</strong> Simple weapons, greatswords, rapiers and scimitars.</li>
                <li><strong>Tools:</strong> Disguise kit</li>
            </ul>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Saving Throws:</strong> Dexterity, Charisma</li>
                <li><strong>Skills:</strong> Choose two skills from Arcana, Deception, Insight, Perception, Performance, Persuasion, and Stealth</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">EQUIPMENT</h5>
            <p>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>(a) a shortbow and quiver of 20 arrows or (b) any simple weapon</li>
                <li>An arcane focus, a dagger and an entertainer’s pack</li>
            </ul>
        <!-- class table here -->
            <h5 class="caption">THE MESMER</h5>
            <table class="class-features">
                <thead>
                    <tr><td class="col-5">Level</td><td class="col-10">Proficiency Bonus</td><td class="col-60 left">Features</td><td class="col-10">Cantrips Known</td><td class="col-10">Energy Points</td><td class="col-10">Max Spell Level</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td> 1st</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Mesmer Casting, Mesmer Magic Tradition</td><td>2</td><td>4</td><td>1st</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 2nd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Fast Casting (2 uses)</td><td>2</td><td>6</td><td>1st</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 3rd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Charismatic, Energy Drain</td><td>2</td><td>12</td><td>2nd</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 4th</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>2</td><td>15</td><td>2nd</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 5th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">—</td><td>3</td><td>20</td><td>3rd</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 6th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Mesmer Magic Feature</td><td>3</td><td>27</td><td>3rd</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 7th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Mesmer Knowledge</td><td>3</td><td>32</td><td>4th</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 8th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>3</td><td>38</td><td>4th</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 9th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">—</td><td>4</td><td>44</td><td>5th</td></tr>
                <tr><td>10th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Mesmer Magic Feature</td><td>4</td><td>57</td><td>5th</td></tr>
                <tr><td>11th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Fast Casting (3 uses)</td><td>4</td><td>64</td><td>6th</td></tr>
                <tr><td>12th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>4</td><td>64</td><td>6th</td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">—</td><td>4</td><td>73</td><td>7th</td></tr>
                <tr><td>14th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Mesmer Magic Feature</td><td>4</td><td>73</td><td>7th</td></tr>
                <tr><td>15th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Veil of Illusions</td><td>5</td><td>83</td><td>8th</td></tr>
                <tr><td>16th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>5</td><td>83</td><td>8th</td></tr>
                <tr><td>17th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Fast Casting (4 uses)</td><td>5</td><td>94</td><td>9th</td></tr>
                <tr><td>18th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Web of Disruption</td><td>5</td><td>94</td><td>9th</td></tr>
                <tr><td>19th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>5</td><td>114</td><td>9th</td></tr>
                <tr><td>20th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Ether Feast</td><td>5</td><td>114</td><td>9th</td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_AD_MESMER_CLASS_FEATURE_MESMER_MESMER_CASTING" />
            <div element="ID_AD_MESMER_CLASS_FEATURE_MESMER_MESMER_MAGIC_TRADITION" />
            <div element="ID_AD_MESMER_CLASS_FEATURE_MESMER_FAST_CASTING" />
            <div element="ID_AD_MESMER_CLASS_FEATURE_MESMER_CHARISMATIC" />
            <div element="ID_AD_MESMER_CLASS_FEATURE_MESMER_ENERGY_DRAIN" />
            <div element="ID_AD_MESMER_CLASS_FEATURE_MESMER_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" />
            <div element="ID_AD_MESMER_CLASS_FEATURE_MESMER_MESMER_KNOWLEDGE" />
            <div element="ID_AD_MESMER_CLASS_FEATURE_MESMER_VEIL_OF_ILLUSIONS" />
            <div element="ID_AD_MESMER_CLASS_FEATURE_MESMER_WEB_OF_DISRUPTION" />
            <div element="ID_AD_MESMER_CLASS_FEATURE_MESMER_ETHER_FEAST" />
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="hd">d6</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_GREATSWORD" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_RAPIER" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SCIMITAR" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_DISGUISE_KIT" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_DEXTERITY" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CHARISMA" />
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency, Mesmer" supports="Skill, Mesmer" number="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AD_MESMER_CLASS_FEATURE_MESMER_MESMER_CASTING" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AD_MESMER_CLASS_FEATURE_MESMER_MESMER_MAGIC_TRADITION" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AD_MESMER_CLASS_FEATURE_MESMER_FAST_CASTING" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AD_MESMER_CLASS_FEATURE_MESMER_CHARISMATIC" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AD_MESMER_CLASS_FEATURE_MESMER_ENERGY_DRAIN" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AD_MESMER_CLASS_FEATURE_MESMER_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" level="4" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AD_MESMER_CLASS_FEATURE_MESMER_MESMER_KNOWLEDGE" level="7" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AD_MESMER_CLASS_FEATURE_MESMER_VEIL_OF_ILLUSIONS" level="15" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AD_MESMER_CLASS_FEATURE_MESMER_WEB_OF_DISRUPTION" level="18" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AD_MESMER_CLASS_FEATURE_MESMER_ETHER_FEAST" level="20" />
            <stat name="cha-mod:min-one" value="1" bonus="base"/>
            <stat name="cha-mod:min-one" value="charisma:modifier" bonus="base"/>
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Mesmer Casting" type="Class Feature" source="The Mesmer" id="ID_AD_MESMER_CLASS_FEATURE_MESMER_MESMER_CASTING">
            <description>
                <p>With the manipulation of the energy flowing in you and in the other creatures, you learned a way to use the magic based on that energy. See chapter 10 of the Player’s Handbook for the general rules of spellcasting. The mesmer spell list is at the end of this supplement.</p>
                <h5>ENERGY POINTS</h5>
                <p>The Mesmer table shows how many energy points you have to cast your spells of 1st level and higher. Each spell has a point cost based on its level. Instead of gaining a number of spell slots to cast your spells from the Mesmer Magic feature, you gain a pool of energy points instead. You expend a number of energy points to create a spell slot of a given level, and then use that slot to cast a spell. You can’t reduce your energy points total to less than 0, and you regain all spent energy points when you finish a long rest.</p>
                <p class="indent">Spells of 5th level and lower are the common spells a mesmer will cast. You can use energy points to create a maximum of three slots of each level of 5th or lower per long rest.</p>
                <p class="indent">Spells of 6th level and higher are particularly taxing to cast. You can use energy points to create one slot of each level of 6th or higher. You can’t create another slot of the same level until you finish a long rest.</p>
                <p class="indent">The number of energy points you have to spend is based on your level as a spellcaster, as shown in the Spell to Point Cost table. Your level also determines you maximum-level spell slot you can create. Even though you might have enough points to create a slot above this maximum, you can’t do so.</p>
                <h5>CANTRIPS</h5>
                <p>At 1st level, you know two cantrips of your choice from the mesmer spell list. You learn additional mesmer cantrips of your choice at higher levels, as shown in the Cantrips Known column of the Mesmer table.</p>
                <h5>PREPARING AND CASTING SPELLS</h5>
                <p>You prepare the list of mesmer spells that are available for you to cast, choosing from the mesmer spell list. When you do so, choose a number of mesmer spells equal to your Charisma modifier + your mesmer level (minimum of one spell). The spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots.</p>
                <p class="indent">For example, if you are a 3rd-level mesmer, you have four 1st-level and two 2nd-level spell slots. With a Charisma of 16, your list of prepared spells can include six spells of 1st or 2nd level, in any combination. If you prepare the 1st-level spell backfire, you can cast it using a 1st-level or 2nd-level slot. Casting the spell doesn’t remove it from your list of prepared spells.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can change your list of prepared spells when you finish a long rest. Preparing a new list of mesmer spells requires time spent in concentration on the energy: at least 1 minute per spell level for each spell on your list.</p>
                <h5 class="caption">SPELL TO POINT COST</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Spell Level</td><td>Point Cost</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1st</td><td>2</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>2nd</td><td>3</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td>5</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>4th</td><td>6</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td>7</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>6th</td><td>9</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>7th</td><td>10</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>8th</td><td>11</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td>13</td></tr>
                </table>
                <h5>SPELLCASTING ABILITY</h5>
                <p>Charisma is your spellcasting ability for your mesmer spells, since the power of your magic relies on your ability to use the energy within yourself and others living creatures. You use your Charisma whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition. you use your Charisma modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a mesmer spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.</p>
                <p style="text-align: center;"><b>Spell save DC</b> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier</p>
                <p style="text-align: center;"><b>Spell attack modifier</b> = your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier</p>
                <h5>RITUAL CASTING</h5>
                <p>You can cast a mesmer spell as a ritual if that spell has the ritual tag and you have the spell prepared</p>
                <h5>SPELLCASTING FOCUS</h5>
                <p>You can use an arcane focus (found in chapter 5 of the Player’s Handbook) as a spellcasting focus for your mesmer spells.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="{{mesmer:energy-points}} Energy Points/Long Rest">
                <description>You expend energy points to create spell slots up to {{mesmer:spell-level}}-level according to the Spell to Point Cost table. You can create up to 3 slots per spell level.</description>
                <description level="11">You expend energy points to create spell slots up to {{mesmer:spell-level}}-level according to the Spell to Point Cost table. You can create up to 3 slots per spell level up to 5th. You can create a single slot of 6th-level or higher.</description>
            </sheet>
            <spellcasting name="Mesmer" ability="Charisma" prepare="true">
                <list known="true">Mesmer</list>
            </spellcasting>
            <rules>
                <stat name="mesmer:energy-points" value="4" level="1" />
                <stat name="mesmer:energy-points" value="2" level="2" />
                <stat name="mesmer:energy-points" value="6" level="3" />
                <stat name="mesmer:energy-points" value="3" level="4" />
                <stat name="mesmer:energy-points" value="5" level="5" />
                <stat name="mesmer:energy-points" value="7" level="6" />
                <stat name="mesmer:energy-points" value="5" level="7" />
                <stat name="mesmer:energy-points" value="6" level="8" />
                <stat name="mesmer:energy-points" value="6" level="9" />
                <stat name="mesmer:energy-points" value="13" level="10" />
                <stat name="mesmer:energy-points" value="7" level="11" />
                <stat name="mesmer:energy-points" value="9" level="13" />
                <stat name="mesmer:energy-points" value="10" level="15" />
                <stat name="mesmer:energy-points" value="11" level="17" />
                <stat name="mesmer:energy-points" value="20" level="19" />
                <stat name="mesmer:spell-level" inline="true" value="1st" level="1" />
                <stat name="mesmer:spell-level" inline="true" value="2nd" level="3" />
                <stat name="mesmer:spell-level" inline="true" value="3rd" level="5" />
                <stat name="mesmer:spell-level" inline="true" value="4th" level="7" />
                <stat name="mesmer:spell-level" inline="true" value="5th" level="9" />
                <stat name="mesmer:spell-level" inline="true" value="6th" level="11" />
                <stat name="mesmer:spell-level" inline="true" value="7th" level="13" />
                <stat name="mesmer:spell-level" inline="true" value="8th" level="15" />
                <stat name="mesmer:spell-level" inline="true" value="9th" level="17" />
                <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_RITUAL_CASTING" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_INTERNAL_PROFICIENCY_SPELLFOCUS_GROUP_ARCANE_FOCUS" />
                <stat name="mesmer:spellcasting:slots:1" value="mesmer:spellcasting:slots:1" level="1" />
                <stat name="mesmer:spellcasting:slots:1" value="-mesmer:spellcasting:slots:1" level="3" />
                <stat name="mesmer:spellcasting:slots:2" value="mesmer:spellcasting:slots:1" level="3" />
                <stat name="mesmer:spellcasting:slots:2" value="-mesmer:spellcasting:slots:1" level="5" />
                <stat name="mesmer:spellcasting:slots:3" value="mesmer:spellcasting:slots:1" level="5" />
                <stat name="mesmer:spellcasting:slots:3" value="-mesmer:spellcasting:slots:1" level="7" />
                <stat name="mesmer:spellcasting:slots:4" value="mesmer:spellcasting:slots:1" level="7" />
                <stat name="mesmer:spellcasting:slots:4" value="-mesmer:spellcasting:slots:1" level="9" />
                <stat name="mesmer:spellcasting:slots:5" value="mesmer:spellcasting:slots:1" level="9" />
                <stat name="mesmer:spellcasting:slots:5" value="-mesmer:spellcasting:slots:1" level="11" />
                <stat name="mesmer:spellcasting:slots:6" value="mesmer:spellcasting:slots:1" level="11" />
                <stat name="mesmer:spellcasting:slots:6" value="-mesmer:spellcasting:slots:1" level="13" />
                <stat name="mesmer:spellcasting:slots:7" value="mesmer:spellcasting:slots:1" level="13" />
                <stat name="mesmer:spellcasting:slots:7" value="-mesmer:spellcasting:slots:1" level="15" />
                <stat name="mesmer:spellcasting:slots:8" value="mesmer:spellcasting:slots:1" level="15" />
                <stat name="mesmer:spellcasting:slots:8" value="-mesmer:spellcasting:slots:1" level="17" />
                <stat name="mesmer:spellcasting:slots:9" value="mesmer:spellcasting:slots:1" level="17" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Mesmer)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),0" spellcasting="Mesmer" number="2" level="1"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Mesmer)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),0" spellcasting="Mesmer" level="5"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Mesmer)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),0" spellcasting="Mesmer" level="9"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Mesmer)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),0" spellcasting="Mesmer" level="15"/>
                <stat name="memser:spellcasting:prepare" value="1" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="memser:spellcasting:prepare:calc" value="charisma:modifier" />
                <stat name="memser:spellcasting:prepare:calc" value="level:mesmer" />
                <stat name="memser:spellcasting:prepare" value="memser:spellcasting:prepare:calc" bonus="base" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Mesmer Magic Tradition" type="Class Feature" source="The Mesmer" id="ID_AD_MESMER_CLASS_FEATURE_MESMER_MESMER_MAGIC_TRADITION">
            <description>
                <p>The mesmers are masters of illusions and create confusion among their foes, taking the arcane energy in their surroundings, transforming and using it as they need.</p>
                <p class="indent">At first level, you choose a Mesmer Magic Tradition: Domination Magic, Dueling Magic, Illusion Magic or Inspiration Magic, which are detailed at the end of the class description. Your choice grants you features at 1st level and again at 6th, 10th, and 14th level.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Archetype" name="Mesmer Magic Tradition" supports="Mesmer Magic Tradition" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Fast Casting" type="Class Feature" source="The Mesmer" id="ID_AD_MESMER_CLASS_FEATURE_MESMER_FAST_CASTING">
            <description>
                <p>At 2nd level, you are trained to cast your spells faster than before to interrupt your foes and protect yourself. You have two additional reactions which can be used in the same round or in separated rounds (allowing you to use three reactions before your next turn or two reactions in two separated rounds). You can use these reactions only to use one of your mesmer spells or a mesmer feature. You regain any expended reactions when you finish a short or long rest.</p>
                <p class="indent">The number of extra reactions increases to three when you reach 11th level in this class and to four when you reach 17th level in this class.</p>
                <p class="indent">In addition, when you take the Ready action to cast a mesmer spell, you can keep the spell ready for a number of rounds equal to your Charisma modifier. You don’t need to use additional actions to keep the spell ready, and if you take the Ready action again while you have a readied action or spell, the previous one is lost.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="{{fast-casting:reactions}}/Short Rest">
                <description>You have {{fast-casting:reactions}} to use to cast mesmer spells or use a mesmer feature. In addition, when you take the Ready action to cast a mesmer spell, you can keep the spell ready for up to {{charisma:modifier}} rounds.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="fast-casting:reactions" value="2" level="2" />
                <stat name="fast-casting:reactions" value="1" level="11" />
                <stat name="fast-casting:reactions" value="1" level="17" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Charismatic" type="Class Feature" source="The Mesmer" id="ID_AD_MESMER_CLASS_FEATURE_MESMER_CHARISMATIC">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 3rd level, when you roll a 1 or 2 on a Charisma-based skill check which you are proficient, you can reroll the die and must use the new roll, even if the new roll is a 1 or a 2.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you roll a 1 or 2 on a Charisma-based skill check which you are proficient, you can reroll the die and must use the new roll, even if the new roll is a 1 or a 2.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Energy Drain" type="Class Feature" source="The Mesmer" id="ID_AD_MESMER_CLASS_FEATURE_MESMER_ENERGY_DRAIN">
            <description>
                <p>At 3rd level, you can use your innate mesmer magic to take your foes energy and recover yours. As an action, a creature you can see within 60 feet of you must make a Constitution saving throw (DC equals to your mesmer spell save DC). On a failed save, the target takes force damage equal to 1d6 + your Charisma modifier and you regain energy points equal half the damage dealt. You can’t regain more points than the energy points column in the mesmer table.</p>
                <p class="indent">The damage increases by 1d6 when you reach 10th level (2d6), and 14th level (3d6).</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you must finish a long rest before you can use it again.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>A creature you can see within 60 feet of you must make a Constitution saving throw (DC {{spellcasting:dc:cha}}). On a failed save, the target takes force damage equal to {{energy-drain:damage-dice}}d6 + {{charisma:modifier}} and you regain energy points equal half the damage dealt. You can’t regain more points than the energy points column in the mesmer table.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="energy-drain:damage-dice" value="1" level="3" />
                <stat name="energy-drain:damage-dice" value="1" level="10" />
                <stat name="energy-drain:damage-dice" value="1" level="14" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Ability Score Improvement" type="Class Feature" source="The Mesmer" id="ID_AD_MESMER_CLASS_FEATURE_MESMER_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Mesmer 4)" supports="Improvement Option,Mesmer,4" level="4" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Mesmer 8)" supports="Improvement Option,Mesmer,8" level="8" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Mesmer 12)" supports="Improvement Option,Mesmer,12" level="12" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Mesmer 16)" supports="Improvement Option,Mesmer,16" level="16" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Mesmer 19)" supports="Improvement Option,Mesmer,19" level="19" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Mesmer Knowledge" type="Class Feature" source="The Mesmer" id="ID_AD_MESMER_CLASS_FEATURE_MESMER_MESMER_KNOWLEDGE">
            <description>
                <p>At 7th level, you are considered a sage on energy knowledge thanks to years of studying in the mesmer academy. You have advantage on any skill check related to magic and arcane knowledge you make.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You have advantage on any skill check related to magic and arcane knowledge you make.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Veil of Illusions" type="Class Feature" source="The Mesmer" id="ID_AD_MESMER_CLASS_FEATURE_MESMER_VEIL_OF_ILLUSIONS">
            <description>
                <p>At 15th level, you create a magical veil around you, making harder to read your intentions. You are now proficient with the Charisma (Deception) and Charisma (Persuasion) skills. Additionally, as a bonus action you can spend 2 energy points to impose disadvantage on Wisdom (Insight) checks against you for 10 minutes.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="2 energy points">
                <description>You can impose disadvantage on Insight checks against you for 10 minutes.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_DECEPTION" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERSUASION" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Web of Disruption" type="Class Feature" source="The Mesmer" id="ID_AD_MESMER_CLASS_FEATURE_MESMER_WEB_OF_DISRUPTION">
            <description>
                <p>At 18th level, you can focus on a foe and cast a powerful hex to fully interrupt him for a short time.</p>
                <p class="indent">As an action, you target a creature and it must make a Charisma saving throw. On a failed save, it’s paralyzed for a number of rounds equal to your Charisma modifier.</p>
                <p class="indent">At the end of each of its turns, the target can make another Charisma saving throw. On a success, the web of disruption effect ends on the target. If the effect ends before the duration of the web, the target takes 6d6 of force damage.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can’t use this feature on two or more creatures at the same time or on a creature which has been under the effects of the Web of Disruption in the past 24 hours.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>You target a creature and it must make a Charisma saving throw. On a failed save, it’s paralyzed for {{charisma:modifier}} rounds. At the end of each of its turns, the target can make another Charisma saving throw. On a success, the web of disruption effect ends on the target. If the effect ends before the duration of the web, the target takes 6d6 of force damage.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Ether Feast" type="Class Feature" source="The Mesmer" id="ID_AD_MESMER_CLASS_FEATURE_MESMER_ETHER_FEAST">
            <description>
                <p>At 20th level, you can now create two 6th level spell slots and two 7th level spell slots per long rest instead of just once.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can now create two 6th level spell slots and two 7th level spell slots per long rest instead of just once.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>

    <!-- Mesmer Magic Traditions -->
    <element name="Domination Magic" type="Archetype" source="The Mesmer" id="ID_AD_MESMER_ARCHETYPE_MESMER_DOMINATION_MAGIC">
        <supports>Mesmer Magic Tradition</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The mesmers dedicated to the Domination Magic use skills and spells that disrupt their foes while dealing damage. These mesmers also are focused on punishing their foes for undertaking actions.</p>
            <p class="indent">Mesmers using Domination Magic focus on shutting down their enemies as much as they can.</p>
            <div element="ID_AD_MESMER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DOMINATION_VISIONS_OF_REGRET" />
            <div element="ID_AD_MESMER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DOMINATION_CRY_OF_FRUSTRATION" />
            <div element="ID_AD_MESMER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DOMINATION_POWER_LOCK" />
            <div element="ID_AD_MESMER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DOMINATION_OVERLOAD" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AD_MESMER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DOMINATION_VISIONS_OF_REGRET" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AD_MESMER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DOMINATION_CRY_OF_FRUSTRATION" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AD_MESMER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DOMINATION_POWER_LOCK" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AD_MESMER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DOMINATION_OVERLOAD" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Visions of Regret" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Mesmer" id="ID_AD_MESMER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DOMINATION_VISIONS_OF_REGRET">
            <description>
                <p>At 1st level, when a creature within 60 feet of you that you can see hits you with an attack, you can use a reaction to cause the creature to make a Charisma saving throw. The creature takes 2d8 force damage on a failed saving throw, and half as much damage to a successful one.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can use this feature twice before you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Reaction" usage="2/Long Rest">
                <description>When a creature within 60 feet of you that you can see hits you with an attack, you cause the creature to make a Charisma saving throw. The creature takes 2d8 force damage on a failed saving throw, and half as much damage to a successful one.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Cry of Frustration" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Mesmer" id="ID_AD_MESMER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DOMINATION_CRY_OF_FRUSTRATION">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 6th level, when a creature within 60 feet that you can see makes a saving throw, you can use a reaction and expend 3 energy points to give it disadvantage on its first saving throw. If the creature fails the save, it also takes force damage equal to 1d10 + your Charisma modifier.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier (a minimum of once) before you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Reaction" usage="{{cha-mod:min-one}}/Short Rest">
                <description>When a creature within 60 feet that you can see makes a saving throw, you can expend 3 energy points to give it disadvantage on its first saving throw. If the creature fails the save, it also takes 1d10 + {{charisma:modifier}} force damage.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Power Lock" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Mesmer" id="ID_AD_MESMER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DOMINATION_POWER_LOCK">
            <description>
                <p>At 10th level, as a reaction when a creature you can see within 60 feet of you makes an attack or uses a spell, it must make a Charisma saving throw. On a failed save, its attack fails and it can’t use the same attack or spell until the end of his next turn.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Reaction" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>When a creature you can see within 60 feet of you makes an attack or uses a spell, it must make a Charisma saving throw. On a failed save, its attack fails and it can’t use the same attack or spell until the end of his next turn.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Overload" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Mesmer" id="ID_AD_MESMER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DOMINATION_OVERLOAD">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 14th level, when you attack a single creature with a cantrip or spell, you can cause the attack to deal an extra 1d10 force damage to the target.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you attack a single creature with a cantrip or spell, you can cause the attack to deal an extra 1d10 force damage to the target.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>

    <element name="Dueling Magic" type="Archetype" source="The Mesmer" id="ID_AD_MESMER_ARCHETYPE_MESMER_DUELING_MAGIC">
        <supports>Mesmer Magic Tradition</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The mesmers dedicated to the Dueling Magic are magical fighters who uses powerful illusions of themselves to confuse and distract their foes while fighting in close combat.</p>
            <div element="ID_AD_MESMER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DUELING_ILLUSORY_DUELIST" />
            <div element="ID_AD_MESMER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DUELING_CONJURE_ILLUSIONS" />
            <div element="ID_AD_MESMER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DUELING_IMPROVED_ILLUSIONS" />
            <div element="ID_AD_MESMER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DUELING_PERFECT_ILLUSIONS" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AD_MESMER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DUELING_ILLUSORY_DUELIST" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AD_MESMER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DUELING_CONJURE_ILLUSIONS" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AD_MESMER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DUELING_IMPROVED_ILLUSIONS" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AD_MESMER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DUELING_PERFECT_ILLUSIONS" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Illusory Duelist" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Mesmer" id="ID_AD_MESMER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DUELING_ILLUSORY_DUELIST">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 1st level, you can use a weapon you’re proficient with as a spellcasting focus for your mesmer spells.</p>
                <p class="indent">Also at 1st level, while you are wearing no armor and not wielding a shield, your Armor Class equals 10 + your Dexterity modifier + your Charisma modifier.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Wou can use a weapon you’re proficient with as a spellcasting focus for your mesmer spells. Also at 1st level, while you are wearing no armor and not wielding a shield, your AC is {{ac:unarmored defense mesmer}}.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="ac:unarmored defense mesmer:base" value="10" />
                <stat name="ac:unarmored defense mesmer:dexterity" value="dexterity:modifier" />
                <stat name="ac:unarmored defense mesmer:charisma" value="charisma:modifier" />
                <stat name="ac:unarmored defense mesmer" value="ac:unarmored defense mesmer:base" />
                <stat name="ac:unarmored defense mesmer" value="ac:unarmored defense mesmer:dexterity" />
                <stat name="ac:unarmored defense mesmer" value="ac:unarmored defense mesmer:charisma" />
                <stat name="ac:calculation" value="ac:unarmored defense mesmer" bonus="calculation" equipped="[armor:none],[shield:none]" alt="Unarmored Defense (Mesmer)" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Conjure Illusions" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Mesmer" id="ID_AD_MESMER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DUELING_CONJURE_ILLUSIONS">
            <description>
                <p>At 1st level, as an action, you channel your energy to create an illusion of yourself. It appears in an unoccupied space that you can see within 30 feet of you. The conjured illusions have an AC of 10, 1 hit point, and a Strength of 2, they take their turn on your initiative and they can move up to 30 feet to a space you can see, but they must remain within 120 feet of you. A conjured illusion mimics your movement, including your attacks, but deals no damage.</p>
                <p class="indent">The illusions lasts for 10 minutes, until you lose your concentration (as if you were concentrating on a spell), or until its hit points drops to 0. You can use your action to dismiss the illusions.</p>
                <p class="indent">Each time a creature targets you with an attack or spell while you are within 5 feet of one of your conjured illusions, it must make an Intelligence saving throw against your spell save DC. On a failed save, it targets the illusion instead.</p>
                <p class="indent">The number of illusions you create increases to 2 when you reach 6th level, to 3 when you reach 10th level, and to 4 when you reach 14th level.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier (a minimum of once) before you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="{{cha-mod:min-one}}/Long Rest">
                <description>You create {{conjure-illusions:duplicates}} illusion of yourself. It appears in an unoccupied space that you can see within 30 feet of you. The conjured illusions have an AC of 10, 1 hit point, and a Strength of 2, they take their turn on your initiative and they can move up to 30 feet to a space you can see, but they must remain within 120 feet of you. A conjured illusion mimics your movement, including your attacks, but deals no damage.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="conjure-illusions:duplicates" value="1" level="1" />
                <stat name="conjure-illusions:duplicates" value="1" level="6" />
                <stat name="conjure-illusions:duplicates" value="1" level="10" />
                <stat name="conjure-illusions:duplicates" value="1" level="14" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Improved Illusions" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Mesmer" id="ID_AD_MESMER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DUELING_IMPROVED_ILLUSIONS">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, while you have at least one of your illusions of yourself, you can use the following options below.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Illusion Strike.</b> When you make a melee attack or cast a spell, you can spend 2 energy points to do it as though you were in the illusion’s space, but you must use your own senses. You can also use this option when you spend a reaction for making an attack of opportunity.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Mirror Image.</b> As a bonus action, you can spend 3 energy points and create a new illusion within 30 feet of you. The maximum number of illusions you can have is determined by the Conjure Illusions feature.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Phantasmal Swap.</b> As a reaction when you are hit by an attack or targeted by a spell, but before taking damage, you can spend 3 energy points to swap your position with one of your illusions within 10 feet of you. You can use this feature twice before you finish a short or long rest.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Shatter.</b> As a bonus action, you can choose one of your illusions and destroy it. All creatures within 5 feet of the illusion must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, it takes force damage equal to 1d10 + your Charisma modifier, or half as much on a successful one. You can expend up to 6 energy points to increase the damage by 1d10 for every 2 energy points.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>While you have at least one of your illusions of yourself, you can use the following options: Illusion Strike, Mirror Image, Phantasmal Swap, or Shatter.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Perfect Illusions" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Mesmer" id="ID_AD_MESMER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DUELING_PERFECT_ILLUSIONS">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 14th level, if you are within 5 feet from a conjured illusion of yourself, creatures have disadvantage on attack rolls and spell attacks against you or against that illusion.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>If you are within 5 feet from a conjured illusion of yourself, creatures have disadvantage on attack rolls and spell attacks against you or against that illusion.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>

    <element name="Illusion Magic" type="Archetype" source="The Mesmer" id="ID_AD_MESMER_ARCHETYPE_MESMER_ILLUSION_MAGIC">
        <supports>Mesmer Magic Tradition</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The mesmers who focus on the Illusion Magic focus on hinder enemies, reducing their efficiency and movement with hexes and deceiving their foes.</p>
            <p class="indent">The Illusion Magic also helps the mesmer with illusions that trick your foes for your own benefit or provides defenses and temporary features for the mesmer.</p>
            <div element="ID_AD_MESMER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ILLUSION_IMAGINED_BURDEN" />
            <div element="ID_AD_MESMER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ILLUSION_DISTORTION" />
            <div element="ID_AD_MESMER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ILLUSION_ILLUSIONARY_CONDITION" />
            <div element="ID_AD_MESMER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ILLUSION_PHANTOM_PAIN" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AD_MESMER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ILLUSION_IMAGINED_BURDEN" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AD_MESMER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ILLUSION_DISTORTION" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AD_MESMER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ILLUSION_ILLUSIONARY_CONDITION" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AD_MESMER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ILLUSION_PHANTOM_PAIN" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Imagined Burden" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Mesmer" id="ID_AD_MESMER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ILLUSION_IMAGINED_BURDEN">
            <description>
                <p>At 1st level, when a creature within 60 feet that you can see moves or takes an action, you can use a reaction to reduce its speed by half and the target can’t take reactions for a number of rounds equal to half of your Charisma modifier (rounded up).</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Reaction" usage="1/Short Rest">
                <description>when a creature within 60 feet that you can see moves or takes an action, you can reduce its speed by half and the target can’t take reactions for a number of rounds equal to half of your Charisma modifier (rounded up).</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Distortion" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Mesmer" id="ID_AD_MESMER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ILLUSION_DISTORTION">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, you can distort your physical form to avoid some damage. As a reaction when you take damage, you can halve that damage against you. You can use this feature twice before you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Reaction" usage="2/Long Rest">
                <description>When you take damage, you can halve that damage against you.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Illusionary Condition" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Mesmer" id="ID_AD_MESMER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ILLUSION_ILLUSIONARY_CONDITION">
            <description>
                <p>At 10th level, when you use a spell on a creature within 60 feet of you which you can see, it must make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, the target is blinded or deafened (your choice) and it can only use either a bonus action or an action on each of its turns for a number of rounds equal to half of your Charisma modifier (rounded up).</p>
                <p class="indent">You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier (a minimum of once) before you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="{{cha-mod:min-one}}/Long Rest">
                <description>When you use a spell on a creature within 60 feet of you which you can see, it must make a Wisdom saving throw (DC {{spellcasting:dc:cha}}). On a failed save, the target is blinded or deafened (your choice) and it can only use either a bonus action or an action on each of its turns for a number of rounds equal to half of your Charisma modifier (rounded up).</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Phantom Pain" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Mesmer" id="ID_AD_MESMER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ILLUSION_PHANTOM_PAIN">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 14th level, as a bonus action, a creature within 60 feet of you which you can see must make a Charisma saving throw. On a failed save, the target takes 1d6 force damage at the beginning of each of its turns and any healing effect it receives is reduced to half for 1 minute. At the end of each of its turns, the target can make another Charisma saving throw. On a success, the Phantom Pain effect ends on the target.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can’t use this feature in two or more creatures at the same time.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>A creature within 60 feet of you which you can see must make a Charisma saving throw. On a failed save, the target takes 1d6 force damage at the beginning of each of its turns and any healing effect it receives is reduced to half for 1 minute. At the end of each of its turns, the target can make another Charisma saving throw. On a success, the Phantom Pain effect ends on the target.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>

    <element name="Inspiration Magic" type="Archetype" source="The Mesmer" id="ID_AD_MESMER_ARCHETYPE_MESMER_INSPIRATION_MAGIC">
        <supports>Mesmer Magic Tradition</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Mesmers who use Inspiration Magic focus on a more defensive style, giving resistances, reducing damage and using arcane energies to heal and protect himself.</p>
            <p class="indent">The Inspiration Magic uses special mantras, which are a series of stances that provide protection and defenses to the mesmer.</p>
            <div element="ID_AD_MESMER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INSPIRATION_MANTRA_OF_PROTECTION" />
            <div element="ID_AD_MESMER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INSPIRATION_CHANNELING" />
            <div element="ID_AD_MESMER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INSPIRATION_MANTRA_OF_RESTORATION" />
            <div element="ID_AD_MESMER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INSPIRATION_MANTRA_OF_EXPEL" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AD_MESMER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INSPIRATION_MANTRA_OF_PROTECTION" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AD_MESMER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INSPIRATION_CHANNELING" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AD_MESMER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INSPIRATION_MANTRA_OF_RESTORATION" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AD_MESMER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INSPIRATION_MANTRA_OF_EXPEL" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Mantra of Protection" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Mesmer" id="ID_AD_MESMER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INSPIRATION_MANTRA_OF_PROTECTION">
            <description>
                <p>At 1st level, you gain proficiency with another saving throw of your choice. In addition, you learn the absorb elements spell, which you always have it prepared, and it doesn’t count against the number of spells you can prepare each day.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Proficiency" name="Saving Throw Proficiency" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_STRENGTH|ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CONSTITUTION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_INTELLIGENCE|ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_WISDOM" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ABSORB_ELEMENTS" spellcasting="Mesmer" prepared="true" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Channeling" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Mesmer" id="ID_AD_MESMER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INSPIRATION_CHANNELING">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, when you take an action to cast a spell, you can use your reaction and spend up to two mesmer Hit Die to recover 1d8 energy points per each Hit Dice spend.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until your finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Reaction" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>When you take an action to cast a spell, you can use your reaction and spend up to 2 mesmer Hit Die to recover 1d8 energy points per each Hit Dice spend.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Mantra of Restoration" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Mesmer" id="ID_AD_MESMER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INSPIRATION_MANTRA_OF_RESTORATION">
            <description>
                <p>At 10th level, you can recover a small amount of energy when using your spells. Whenever you use a 1st level or higher spell, you gain 1 energy point. You cannot have more energy points than shown on the table for your level, and every point left is lost.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Whenever you use a 1st level or higher spell, you gain 1 energy point. You cannot have more energy points than shown on the table for your level, and every point left is lost.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Mantra of Expel" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Mesmer" id="ID_AD_MESMER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INSPIRATION_MANTRA_OF_EXPEL">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 14th level, as a reaction, you can expend 3 energy points to gain advantage on a saving throw against a spell. In addition, if the spell deals damage, you take only half damage if you fail the check, and no damage on a success.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Reaction" usage="3 energy points">
                <description>You can gain advantage on a saving throw against a spell. In addition, if the spell deals damage, you take only half damage if you fail the check, and no damage on a success.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>

    <!-- Mesmer Skills -->
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ARCANA">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_DECEPTION">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERFORMANCE">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERSUASION">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_STEALTH">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>

    <!-- Mesmer Spell List -->
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FRIENDS">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LIGHT">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGE_HAND">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MINOR_ILLUSION">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PRESTIDIGITATION">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_SCAG_SPELL_SWORD_BURST">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_THAUMATURGY">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CHARM_PERSON">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COLOR_SPRAY">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_MAGIC">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISGUISE_SELF">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISSONANT_WHISPERS">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ILLUSORY_SCRIPT">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGE_ARMOR">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGIC_MISSILE">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SILENT_IMAGE">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SLEEP">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ALTER_SELF">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLINDNESS_DEAFNESS">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLUR">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CALM_EMOTIONS">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CROWN_OF_MADNESS">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HOLD_PERSON">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INVISIBILITY">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LESSER_RESTORATION">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGIC_MOUTH">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_MIND_SPIKE">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MIRROR_IMAGE">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_NYSTULS_MAGIC_AURA">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PHANTASMAL_FORCE">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_SHADOW_BLADE">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SILENCE">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SUGGESTION">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ZONE_OF_TRUTH">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_CATNAP">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COUNTERSPELL">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISPEL_MAGIC">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ENEMIES_ABOUND">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FEAR">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HASTE">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HYPNOTIC_PATTERN">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAJOR_IMAGE">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_NONDETECTION">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PHANTOM_STEED">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PROTECTION_FROM_ENERGY">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_REMOVE_CURSE">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SLOW">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_CHARM_MONSTER">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMPULSION">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONFUSION">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GREATER_INVISIBILITY">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HALLUCINATORY_TERRAIN">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_OTILUKES_RESILIENT_SPHERE">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PHANTASMAL_KILLER">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_POLYMORPH">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BIGBYS_HAND">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CREATION">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DOMINATE_PERSON">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DREAM">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GREATER_RESTORATION">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HOLD_MONSTER">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MISLEAD">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MODIFY_MEMORY">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SCRYING">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SEEMING">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_STEEL_WIND_STRIKE">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_SYNAPTIC_STATIC">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WALL_OF_FORCE">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISINTEGRATE">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GLOBE_OF_INVULNERABILITY">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GUARDS_AND_WARDS">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MASS_SUGGESTION">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_MENTAL_PRISON">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PROGRAMMED_ILLUSION">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ETHEREALNESS">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FORCECAGE">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MIRAGE_ARCANE">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MORDENKAINENS_SWORD">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_POWER_WORD_PAIN">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PROJECT_IMAGE">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SQUESTER">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SIMULACRUM">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANTIMAGIC_FIELD">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANTIPATHY_SYMPATHY">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DOMINATE_MONSTER">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FEEBLEMIND">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GLIBNESS">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ILLUSORY_DRAGON">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_MADDENING_DARKNESS">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MIND_BLANK">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_POWER_WORD_STUN">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_MASS_POLYMORPH">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_PSYCHIC_SCREAM">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHAPECHANGE">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TRUE_POLYMORPH">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WEIRD">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
        </append>

    <!-- New Mesmer Spells -->
        <element name="Backfire" type="Spell" source="The Mesmer" id="ID_AD_MESMER_SPELL_BACKFIRE">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
            <description>
                <p>The creature must make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, it has disadvantage on the attack roll. If the attack still hits, the attacker takes 2d8 force damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 1st.</p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="keywords"></set>
                <set name="level">1</set>
                <set name="school">enchantment</set>
                <set name="isRitual">false</set>
                <set name="time">1 reaction, which you take in response when you see a creature making an attack within 60 feet of you.</set>
                <set name="range">60 feet</set>
                <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
                <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
                <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
                <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
        <element name="Chaos Storm" type="Spell" source="The Mesmer" id="ID_AD_MESMER_SPELL_CHAOS_STORM">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
            <description>
                <p>You create an energy storm in a 20-foot-radius sphere on the ground centered on a point within range. The area is considered difficult terrain while the storm last. When a creature enters the area for the first time on a turn or starts its turn there, it must make a Wisdom saving throw, taking 3d8 force damage on a failed save, or half as much on a successful one.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can use a bonus action to move the storm 10 feet in any direction.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for every slot level above 4th.</p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="keywords"></set>
                <set name="level">4</set>
                <set name="school">evocation</set>
                <set name="isRitual">false</set>
                <set name="time">1 action</set>
                <set name="range">150 feet</set>
                <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
                <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
                <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
                <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
        <element name="Empathy" type="Spell" source="The Mesmer" id="ID_AD_MESMER_SPELL_EMPATHY">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
            <description>
                <p>A creature that you can see within range must make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, the target is affected by this spell. Until the spell ends, whenever the creature makes an attack roll, it takes 1d10 force damage.</p>
                <p class="indent">The creature can make a Wisdom saving throw at the end of each of its turns. On a successful save, the spell ends.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d10 for every slot level above 1st.</p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="keywords"></set>
                <set name="level">1</set>
                <set name="school">enchantment</set>
                <set name="isRitual">false</set>
                <set name="time">1 action</set>
                <set name="range">60 feet</set>
                <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
                <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
                <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
                <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
        <element name="Energy Bolt" type="Spell" source="The Mesmer" id="ID_AD_MESMER_SPELL_ENERGY_BOLT">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
            <description>
                <p>As an action, you create a small energy bolt to strike one creature or object that you can see within 120 feet of you. Make a ranged spell attack against the target. On a hit, the target takes 1d10 force damage.</p>
                <p class="indent">This spell’s damage increases by 1d10 when you reach 5th level (2d10), 11th level (3d10), and 17th level (4d10).</p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="keywords"></set>
                <set name="level">0</set>
                <set name="school">Evocation</set>
                <set name="isRitual">false</set>
                <set name="time">1 Action</set>
                <set name="range">120 feet</set>
                <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
                <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
                <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
                <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
        <element name="Power Leech" type="Spell" source="The Mesmer" id="ID_AD_MESMER_SPELL_POWER_LEECH">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
            <description>
                <p>Choose a creature that is casting a spell within range that you can see. The creature must make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, the creature takes 1d6 psychic damage and you regain a number of energy points equal to half the spell level used by the creature (rounded up). Use the Spell to Point Cost table to transform the spell level into points.</p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="keywords"></set>
                <set name="level">3</set>
                <set name="school">abjuration</set>
                <set name="isRitual">false</set>
                <set name="time">1 reaction, which you take when you see a creature within 60 feet of you casting a spell</set>
                <set name="range">60 feet</set>
                <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
                <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
                <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
                <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
                <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
        <element name="Spirit of Failure" type="Spell" source="The Mesmer" id="ID_AD_MESMER_SPELL_SPIRIT_OF_FAILURE">
            <supports>Mesmer</supports>
            <description>
                <p>You implant a spirit fully of thoughts with failures on your enemies to reduce their abilities in combat. Until the end of your next turn, that creature must roll a d100 when it makes an attack roll. If the result is 1 to 25, the attack misses and the spell ends.</p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="keywords"></set>
                <set name="level">2</set>
                <set name="school">enchantment</set>
                <set name="isRitual">false</set>
                <set name="time">1 action</set>
                <set name="range">30 feet</set>
                <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
                <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
                <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
                <set name="duration">1 round</set>
                <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            </setters>
        </element>

</elements>