<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>The Wildkeeper Class v2.1</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="class-wildkeeper.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/classes/class-wildkeeper.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="The Wildkeeper Class" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_SHILONIOUS_GMBINDER_SOURCE_The Wildkeeper Class">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation">TWBC</set>
            <set name="url">https://www.gmbinder.com/share/-MChWbwFU3skyiJf0-SN</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" abbreviation="SHI" url="https://www.gmbinder.com/profile/shilonious">Shilonious</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20210113</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Wildkeeper" type="Class" source="The Wildkeeper Class" id="ID_SHI_TWBC_CLASS_WILDKEEPER">
        <description>
            <p>Holding true to his instincts, a wood elf stands still in a silent grove, waiting as the hordes of undead surround him. At the very last second, a bright burst of light zips from a nearby tree to his shoulder. Bringing his palm up to caress the face of his companion, he is now confident in his victory.</p>
            <p class="indent">Watching from the darkness, a half-orc crawls through the mud as rain pours down overhead. He is a blade in the night, unseen and unheard. However, as he stealthily moves beside the underbrush towards his target, he is aware that he is not the only predator stalking his prey. A flash of purple mist disperses just as quick as it occurred, revealing a creature with the visage of a skeletal wolf, its jaws firmly clamped deep into the neck of the half-orc's target.</p>
            <p class="indent">Searching through the masses of bodies after a battle, a dwarven soldier cries out for his missing half. With the speed of a cracking whip, a small squirrel-like creature appears at his side, chirping in a sing-songy voice. He smiles down at the animal, as if welcoming an old friend.</p>
            <p class="indent">Be they a pair on a covert mission to assassinate a political figure, or a powerful general riding his spirit into battle, a wildkeeper and his spirit animal are representatives of the raw strength achieved by joining man and beast. They are not gods, nor are they of the fey or druids. On the contrary, they are simply a devastating reminder of the power two parties can obtain when they work together. When a wildkeeper is born, their spirit gives life to an animal companion. This animal companion is usually brought to the physical world for the first time through a ceremony, or some other ritual.</p>
            <h4>HARD-FOUGHT VICTORS</h4>
            <p>Hailing from the forests, wildkeepers focus on training their bonded animals. They practice fighting techniques known only to them, complimenting their combat abilities with that of their wildbond's. Wildkeepers focus their energy on strengthening their bonds to further unlock the capabilities of their spirit animal.</p>
            <p class="indent">However magical their spirit bond may seem, not every wildkeeper knows spells, as their spirits do not pull from the weave, but from the natural energies of the Material Plane. Due to this source, they are often observed meditating in nature, as a form of hardening one's inner power.</p>
            <h4>NEVER ALONE</h4>
            <p>Whether a baker, farmer, soldier, or mercenary, a wildkeeper will never be without his closest ally. Often times, their bond will grant them attention from those unknowing of wildkeeper traditions, be it negative or positive. Regardless, they are well respected for their tactical abilities on the battlefield, and their well spoken diplomacy off of it. That's not to say that wildkeepers are always friendly. Some wildkeepers draw their bond's power not from companionship, but from lust for power. As they feed their wildbond's ego, so too does their's grow as well. A wildkeeper's spirit animal will always reflect the true nature of their match.</p>
            <p class="indent">The unbreakable bond that wildkeepers possess conveniently makes them perfect for adventuring, since they have no fear of the loneliness most quests entail. When interacting with an only child, those without any pets, or those who have never taken a spouse, wildkeepers converse with an air of exasperation around them. They are still fairly fast to get over their internal struggle, though, as they know to judge a person's worth not by face, but by fortitude. Misguided single folk may be inept when it comes to the ways of friendship and trust, but they always have the chance to prove themselves.</p>
            <h4>CREATING A WILDKEEPER</h4>
            <p class="indent">As you create your wildkeeper character, consider the nature of the ritual that gave you your particular capabilities. Was your life bond forged under the glow of a full moon, during a ceremony conducted by an ancient shaman? Did you discover your wildbond by accident during a near-death experience? Or did you instead receive careful teachings as you were brought up by an elder wildkeeper, eager to show you their ways? You might even be just now discovering your bond, many years into your life.</p>
            <p class="indent">How do you treat your spirit animal? Are you relaxed and laid-back about any mistakes they may make? Or do you instead give harsh punishments in the form of beatings? Are you happy with the way your bond works? Or does the thought of your wildbond make you cringe and squirm? Is there any goal that you feel you were placed on this plane to achieve? Is your wildbond getting in the way of you succeeding? Are you best friends with your spirit twin, pushing everyone else away but them? Or do you instead try to spend as much time possible socializing with others, attempting to distance yourself from their alien ways?</p>
            <h5>OPTIONAL RULE: MULTICLASSING</h5>
            <p>If your group uses the optional rule for multiclassing in the Player's Handbook, here's what you need to know if you choose the wildkeeper as one of your classes.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b>Ability Score Minimum.</b> In order to multiclass, you must have at least a 13 in Dexterity and Wisdom to take a level in this class, or to take a level in another class if you are already a wildkeeper.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b>Proficiencies Gained.</b> If wildkeeper isn't your initial class, you gain proficiency in simple weapons, martial weapons, shields, light armor, and one skill from the wildkeeper list when you take your first level in this class.</p>
            <h5>QUICK BUILD</h5>
            <p>You can make a wildkeeper quickly by following these suggestions. First, make Dexterity your highest ability score, followed by Wisdom. Second, choose the outlander background.</p>
            <h2>CLASS FEATURES</h2>
            <p>As an wildkeeper, you gain the following class features.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">HIT POINTS</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Hit Dice:</strong> 1d8 per wildkeeper level</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at 1st Level:</strong> 8 + your Constitution modifier</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at Higher Levels:</strong> 1d8 (or 5) + your Constitution modifier per wildkeeper level after 1st</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">PROFICIENCIES</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled mb">
                <li><strong>Armor:</strong> Light armor, shields</li>
                <li><strong>Weapons:</strong> Simple weapons, martial weapons</li>
                <li><strong>Tools:</strong> None</li>
            </ul>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Saving Throws:</strong> Wisdom, Strength</li>
                <li><strong>Skills:</strong> Choose three from Animal Handling, Athletics, Performance, Nature, Perception, and Survival</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">EQUIPMENT</h5>
            <p>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>(a) a shortsword or (b) any simple weapon</li>
                <li>(a) a shield or (b) any martial weapon</li>
                <li>(a) a shortbow and a quiver of 20 arrows or (b) a hand crossbow and 10 bolts or (c) a net</li>
                <li>An explorer's pack, leather armor, and a hunting trap.</li>
            </ul>
        <!-- class table here -->
            <h5 class="caption">THE WILDKEEPER</h5>
            <table class="class-features">
                <thead>
                    <tr><td class="col-5">Level</td><td class="col-10">Proficiency Bonus</td><td class="col-60 left">Features</td><td class="col-10">Wildbond Attack</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td> 1st</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Wildbond, Spirit Path</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 2nd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Adaptive Body, Bond Sight</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 3rd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Sharpened Spirit</td><td>1d4</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 4th</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Ability Score Increase, Growth in Power</td><td>1d4</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 5th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Extra Attack</td><td>1d6</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 6th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Spirit Path Feature</td><td>1d6</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 7th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Spirit Strikes, Wild Knowledge</td><td>1d6</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 8th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Ability Score Increase</td><td>1d6</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 9th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Animal Heart, Wild Knowledge (2)</td><td>1d8</td></tr>
                <tr><td>10th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Spirit Path Feature</td><td>1d8</td></tr>
                <tr><td>11th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Extra Attack (2), Fang and Bone</td><td>1d8</td></tr>
                <tr><td>12th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Ability Score Increase</td><td>1d8</td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Natural Luck (one use)</td><td>1d10</td></tr>
                <tr><td>14th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Spirit Path Feature</td><td>1d10</td></tr>
                <tr><td>15th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Spirit Vitality</td><td>1d10</td></tr>
                <tr><td>16th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Ability Score Increase</td><td>1d10</td></tr>
                <tr><td>17th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Natural Luck (two uses)</td><td>1d12</td></tr>
                <tr><td>18th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Lifebonder</td><td>1d12</td></tr>
                <tr><td>19th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Ability Score Increase</td><td>1d12</td></tr>
                <tr><td>20th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Truebond</td><td>1d12</td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDKEEPER_WILDBOND" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDKEEPER_SPIRIT_PATH" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDKEEPER_ADAPTIVE_BODY" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDKEEPER_BOND_SIGHT" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDKEEPER_SHARPENED_SPIRIT" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDKEEPER_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDKEEPER_GROWTH_IN_POWER" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDKEEPER_EXTRA_ATTACK" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDKEEPER_SPIRIT_STRIKES" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDKEEPER_WILD_KNOWLEDGE" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDKEEPER_ANIMAL_HEART" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDKEEPER_FANG_AND_BONE" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDKEEPER_NATURAL_LUCK" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDKEEPER_SPIRIT_VITALITY" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDKEEPER_LIFEBONDER" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDKEEPER_TRUEBOND" />
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="hd">d8</set>
            <set name="short"></set>
        </setters>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_SHIELDS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_MARTIAL_WEAPONS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_WISDOM" requirements="!ID_SHI_TWBC_MULTICLASS_WILDKEEPER" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_STRENGTH" requirements="!ID_SHI_TWBC_MULTICLASS_WILDKEEPER" />
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency, Wildkeeper" supports="Skill, Wildkeeper" number="3" requirements="!ID_SHI_TWBC_MULTICLASS_WILDKEEPER" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDKEEPER_WILDBOND" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDKEEPER_SPIRIT_PATH" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDKEEPER_ADAPTIVE_BODY" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDKEEPER_BOND_SIGHT" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDKEEPER_SHARPENED_SPIRIT" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDKEEPER_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" level="4" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDKEEPER_GROWTH_IN_POWER" level="4" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDKEEPER_EXTRA_ATTACK" level="5" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDKEEPER_SPIRIT_STRIKES" level="7" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDKEEPER_WILD_KNOWLEDGE" level="7" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDKEEPER_ANIMAL_HEART" level="9" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDKEEPER_FANG_AND_BONE" level="11" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDKEEPER_NATURAL_LUCK" level="13" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDKEEPER_SPIRIT_VITALITY" level="17" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDKEEPER_LIFEBONDER" level="18" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDKEEPER_TRUEBOND" level="20" />
        </rules>
        <multiclass id="ID_SHI_TWBC_MULTICLASS_WILDKEEPER">
            <prerequisite>Dexterity 13, Wisdom 13</prerequisite>
            <requirements>[dex:13],[wis:13]</requirements>
            <setters>
                <set name="multiclass proficiencies">If wildkeeper isn’t your initial class, you gain proficiency in simple weapons, martial weapons, and one skill from the wildkeeper list when you take your first level in this class.</set>
            </setters>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS" />
                <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency, Wildkeeper" supports="Skill, Wildkeeper" />
            </rules>
        </multiclass>
    </element>
        <element name="Wildbond" type="Class Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDKEEPER_WILDBOND">
            <description>
                <p>Your spirit manifests itself as an animal that you are linked to, your wildbond. It is friendly to you and your companions, and it obeys your commands. See the wildbond's game statistics in the wildbond stat block. You determine the creature's appearance, such as how many legs it has; your choice has no effect on its game statistics.</p>
                <p class="indent">In combat, the wildbond shares your initiative count, but takes its turn immediately after yours. It can move, use its reaction, and use any bonus action it has on its own, but the only action it takes on its turn is the Dodge action, unless you take a bonus action on your turn to command it to take one of the actions in its stat block, such as the attack it gains later on, or the Dash, Disengage, Help, Hide, or Search action.</p>
                <p class="indent">If you or your wildbond drop to 0 hit points, it becomes part of your spirit once more, leaving behind no physical form. Alternatively, as an action, you can cause your wildbond to disappear into your spirit temporarily.</p>
                <p class="indent">While your wildbond is part of your spirit, you can use your bonus action on your turn to bring it back to your side. When you do so, you can choose to expend one or more Hit Die. For each Hit Die spent in this way, roll the die and add your Wisdom modifier to it. The wildbond regains a number of hit points equal to the total roll. It then reappears at the start of your next turn in an unoccupied space within 5 feet of you.</p>
                <p class="indent">When you spend Hit Die to restore hit points during a short rest, your wildbond regains hit points equal to half the total hit points you regained. It regains all of its hit points at the end of a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Spirit Path" type="Class Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDKEEPER_SPIRIT_PATH">
            <description>
                <p>Choose a path that you want your spirit to follow, causing it to strengthen in unique ways. Choose Spirit of the Elements, Spirit of the Giant, Spirit of War, or Spirit of the Dark, all detailed at the end of the class description. The spirit you choose grants you features at 3rd level and again at 6th, 10th, and 14th level.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Adaptive Body" type="Class Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDKEEPER_ADAPTIVE_BODY">
            <description>
                <p>At 2nd level, your spirit bond's strength sparks evolution. Choose from one of the following options:</p>
                <p class="indent">Gills. Your wildbond manifests gills. It can now breathe air and water. In addition, you both gain a swimming speed equal to your normal speed. You lose your swimming speed while wearing heavy armor.</p>
                <p class="indent">Wings. Your wildbond grows a pair of wings. It gains a flying speed equal to its normal speed. In addition, when you make a high jump, you can now leap 5 feet higher.</p>
                <p class="indent">Fleet Footed. Your wildbond's body has grown lighter. Your wildbond's can now take the Dash action as a bonus action. In addition, your movement speed increases by 5 feet.</p>
                <p class="indent">Nature Touched. Your bond evolves to now draw power from the innate magic of the world. You learn two cantrips of your choice from the druid spell list. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for them. Whenever you gain a level in this class, you can replace one of these cantrips with another cantrip from the druid spell list.</p>
                <p class="indent">In addition, when you cast a spell with a range other than self, you can choose to have the spell originate from your wildbond. Your wildbond must be within 100 feet of you, and it must use its reaction to deliver the spell when you cast it. If the spell requires an attack roll, you use your attack modifier for the roll.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Bond Sight" type="Class Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDKEEPER_BOND_SIGHT">
            <description>
                <p>At 2nd level, you can now use your wildbond's eyes as if they were your own. As an action, if your wildbond is within 100 feet of you, you can see through its eyes and hear what it hears until the start of your next turn, gaining the benefits of any Special Senses that the wildbond has. During this time, you are deaf and blind with regard to your own Senses.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Sharpened Spirit" type="Class Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDKEEPER_SHARPENED_SPIRIT">
            <description>
                <p>At 3rd level, your wildbond has evolved to assist you in battle. Choose the natural weapon your wildbond has grown, such as claws, horns, or hooves, and whether it deals bludgeoning, piercing, or slashing damage. Once you choose your wildbond's natural weapon, you cannot change it again.</p>
                <p class="indent">The damage die of your wildbond's natural weapon attacks changes as you gain wildkeeper levels, as shown in the Wildbond Attack column of the Wildkeeper table.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Ability Score Improvement" type="Class Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDKEEPER_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
				<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Wildkeeper 4)" supports="Improvement Option,Wildkeeper,4" level="4" />
				<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Wildkeeper 8)" supports="Improvement Option,Wildkeeper,8" level="8" />
				<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Wildkeeper 12)" supports="Improvement Option,Wildkeeper,12" level="12" />
				<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Wildkeeper 16)" supports="Improvement Option,Wildkeeper,16" level="16" />
				<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Wildkeeper 19)" supports="Improvement Option,Wildkeeper,19" level="19" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Growth in Power" type="Class Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDKEEPER_GROWTH_IN_POWER">
            <description>
                <p>At 4th level, your strength progresses, empowering your spirit. Your wildbond grows by one size, from Tiny to Small. If you took the Spirit of the Giant spirit path at 3rd level, it instead grows from Small to Medium.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Extra Attack" type="Class Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDKEEPER_EXTRA_ATTACK">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 5th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</p>
                <p class="indent">At 11th level, your wildbond can attack twice, instead of once, whenever it takes the Natural Weapon action on its turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Spirit Strikes" type="Class Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDKEEPER_SPIRIT_STRIKES">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 7th level, your wildbond's natural weapon attacks count as magical for the purpose of overcoming resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Wild Knowledge" type="Class Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDKEEPER_WILD_KNOWLEDGE">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 7th level and again at 9th level, you gain proficiency in one skill of your choice from the list of skills available to wildkeepers at 1st level.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Animal Heart" type="Class Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDKEEPER_ANIMAL_HEART">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 9th level, your wildbond has gained the ability to converse with animals. Your wildbond can crudely convey ideas to beasts with an Intelligence score lower than 9, and can discern any simple information they converse back. You learn any information it learns this way.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Fang and Bone" type="Class Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDKEEPER_FANG_AND_BONE">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 11th level, your bond's combat efficiency is phenomenal. Your wildbond can now add your Wisdom modifier to its damage rolls. In addition, if your wildbond attempts to hit a creature within 5 feet of you with a natural weapon attack, you can use your reaction to grant it advantage on its attack roll.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Natural Luck" type="Class Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDKEEPER_NATURAL_LUCK">
            <description>
                <p>At 13th level, you can reroll a saving throw that your wildbond fails. If you do so, you must use the new roll, and you can't use this feature again until you finish a long rest.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can use this feature twice between long rests starting at 17th level.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Spirit Vitality" type="Class Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDKEEPER_SPIRIT_VITALITY">
            <description>
                <p>At 15th level, your spirit is wiser, allowing you to stretch your Hit Die thin. Your wildbond regains the same amount of hit points you regain whenever you spend Hit Die as part of a short rest. In addition, when you roll a 1 on a Hit Die, you can reroll the die and must use the new roll.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Lifebonder" type="Class Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDKEEPER_LIFEBONDER">
            <description>
                <p>At level 18, you and your wildbond are now able to benefit from each other's vigor. When your wildbond is within 5 feet of you, you both gain a +1 bonus to your AC.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Truebond" type="Class Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_WILDKEEPER_TRUEBOND">
            <description>
                <p>At 20th level, you have fully bonded with your spirit animal. While your wildbond is part of your spirit, you can use your bonus action or action on your turn to summon it. When you spend Hit Die as part of summoning it, you gain hit points equal to half the total roll.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>

    <!-- Wildkeeper Spirit Bonds -->
    <element name="Spirit of the Elements" type="Archetype" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_WILDKEEPER_SPIRIT_OF_THE_ELEMENTS">
        <supports>Wildkeeper Spirit Path</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Your spirit walks the paths that dwell in the Elemental Planes. A Spirit of the Elements wildbond is one that has connected itself further than just the plane it is grounded on. Accessing these new powers, it strengthens itself through the aid of the innate magic that flows through the realms, allowing it to be more versatile in any situation that it finds itself in. These wildbonds tend to be happier spirited, their connection to the different planes giving them newfound peace and energy.</p>
            <div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_OF_THE_ELEMENTS_ELEMENTAL_STUDY" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_OF_THE_ELEMENTS_ELEMENTAL_ENHANCEMENT" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_OF_THE_ELEMENTS_PLANAR_RESISTANCE" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_OF_THE_ELEMENTS_ELEMENTAL_MASTERY" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_OF_THE_ELEMENTS_ELEMENTAL_STUDY" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_OF_THE_ELEMENTS_ELEMENTAL_ENHANCEMENT" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_OF_THE_ELEMENTS_PLANAR_RESISTANCE" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_OF_THE_ELEMENTS_ELEMENTAL_MASTERY" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Elemental Study" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_OF_THE_ELEMENTS_ELEMENTAL_STUDY">
            <description>
                <p>At 1st level, when you adopt this path, you choose an element and gain its feature. You can choose an additional cantrip to learn from this feature when you reach level 6, 10, and 14.</p>
                <p class="indent">Air. You learn the gust cantrip and the jump spell.</p>
                <p class="indent">Earth. You learn the mold earth cantrip and the earth tremor spell.</p>
                <p class="indent">Fire. You learn the control flames cantrip and the burning hands spell.</p>
                <p class="indent">Water. You learn the shape water cantrip and the ice knife spell.</p>
                <p class="indent">The spell you learn can be cast at 1st level twice with this trait, requiring no material components, and you regain the ability to cast it this way when you finish a short or long rest.</p>
                <h5>SPELLCASTING</h5>
                <p class="indent">You use your Wisdom whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Wisdom modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a spell from this path you cast and when making an attack roll with one.</p>
                <p style="text-align: center;"><b>Spell Save DC</b> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier</p>
                <p style="text-align: center;"><b>Spell attack modifier</b> = your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier</p>
                <p class="indent">If at later levels you use your bonus action to command your wildbond to attack on the same turn that you have casted a spell, or are maintaining concentration on a spell, that you have gained from this spirit path, your wildbond's attack deals 1d8 additional force damage. This damage increases to 2d8 at level 10.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Elemental Enhancement" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_OF_THE_ELEMENTS_ELEMENTAL_ENHANCEMENT">
            <description>
                <p>At level 6, you gain a magical benefit based on the element of your choice. You can choose the same element you selected at 1st level or a different one.</p>
                <p class="indent">Air. You learn the warding wind spell.</p>
                <p class="indent">Earth. You learn the maximilian's earthen grasp spell.</p>
                <p class="indent">Fire. You learn the scorching ray spell.</p>
                <p class="indent">Water. You learn the snilloc's snowball storm spell.</p>
                <p class="indent">The spell you learn can be cast at 2nd level twice with this trait, requiring no material components, and you regain the ability to cast it this way when you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Planar Resistance" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_OF_THE_ELEMENTS_PLANAR_RESISTANCE">
            <description>
                <p>At 10th level, your spirit has walked the Elemental Planes long enough to expose you to their harshest climates. You gain a unique defensive capability based on the element of your choice. You can choose the same element you selected previously or a different one.</p>
                <p class="indent">Air. You have advantage on Dexterity (Acrobatics) checks you make to break free of grapples. In addition, you can add your Dexterity modifier to your high jump distance, and half your Dexterity score to your long jump distance.</p>
                <p class="indent">Earth. You can move across difficult terrain made of earth or stone without expending extra movement.</p>
                <p class="indent">Fire. You gain resistance to fire damage.</p>
                <p class="indent">Water. You gain resistance to cold damage.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Elemental Mastery" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_OF_THE_ELEMENTS_ELEMENTAL_MASTERY">
            <description>
                <p>At level 14, you gain a powerful boon based on the element of your choice. You can choose the same element you selected previously or a different one.</p>
                <p class="indent">Air. You learn the fly spell.</p>
                <p class="indent">Earth. You learn the erupting earth spell.</p>
                <p class="indent">Fire. You learn the fireball spell.</p>
                <p class="indent">Water. You learn the tidal wave spell.</p>
                <p class="indent">The spell you learn can be cast at 3rd level twice with this trait, requiring no material components, and you regain the ability to cast it this way when you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>

    <element name="Spirit of the Giant" type="Archetype" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_WILDKEEPER_SPIRIT_OF_THE_GIANT">
        <supports>Wildkeeper Spirit Path</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Your spirit walks the path of the great beasts of yore. A Spirit of the Giant wildbond is one that truly shows the depth and connection of a wildbond and its partner. Always aiming to improve alongside each other, you grow in spirit as your wildbond grows in size and fortitude. Your pride and love for your wildbond knows no bounds. Most see this growth as a great accomplishment achieved by the wildkeeper, as they are often kind hearted and helpful.</p>
            <div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_OF_THE_GIANT_SPIRIT_GROWTH" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_OF_THE_GIANT_GENTLE_GIANT" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_OF_THE_GIANT_IMPROVED_SPIRIT_GROWTH" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_OF_THE_GIANT_GRANT_POWER" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_OF_THE_GIANT_SPIRIT_GROWTH" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_OF_THE_GIANT_GENTLE_GIANT" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_OF_THE_GIANT_IMPROVED_SPIRIT_GROWTH" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_OF_THE_GIANT_GRANT_POWER" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Spirit Growth" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_OF_THE_GIANT_SPIRIT_GROWTH">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at level 1, your spirit bond grows faster than any other spirit. Your wildbond gains the following benefits:</p>
                <p class="indent">Size Increase. Its size increases to Small.</p>
                <p class="indent">Bulky Build. Its hit point maximum increases by 2. Whenever you gain a level hereafter, its hit point maximum increases by an additional 2 hit points.</p>
                <p class="indent">Pack Mule. It has advantage on Strength (Athletics) checks it makes when pulling, lifting, or carrying.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Gentle Giant" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_OF_THE_GIANT_GENTLE_GIANT">
            <description>
                <p>At level 6, your wildbond keeps growing, and it has also grown a thick coat of fur. Your wildbond gains the following benefits:</p>
                <p class="indent">Size Increase. Its size increases to Large.</p>
                <p class="indent">Thicker Hide. Its AC increases by 2.</p>
                <p class="indent">Playful Nature. Its Charisma score increases by 4 and it now has advantage on any Charisma checks made when interacting with children.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Improved Spirit Growth" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_OF_THE_GIANT_IMPROVED_SPIRIT_GROWTH">
            <description>
                <p>At 10th level, your spirit bond has reached an extremely impressive size. Your wildbond gains the following benefits:</p>
                <p class="indent">Size Increase. Its size increases to Huge.</p>
                <p class="indent">Boundful. Its movement speed increases by 10 feet.</p>
                <p class="indent">Strengthened Strikes. Its natural weapon attacks now score a critical hit on a roll of 19 or 20.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Grant Power" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_OF_THE_GIANT_GRANT_POWER">
            <description>
                <p>At 14th level, as an action, you can cause your wildbond to grow in size and power for 1 minute. This effect ends early if your wildbond is reduced to 0 hit points or if you dismiss it as a bonus action on your turn. While the transformation is active, your wildbond gains the following benefits:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Its size increases to Gargantuan.</li>
                    <li>It gains temporary hit points equal to half its current hit points.</li>
                    <li>Its AC increases by 2, and it has advantage on Strength and Constitution saving throws.</li>
                    <li>Its natural weapon attack's reach increases to 10 feet.</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this ability, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>

    <element name="Spirit of War" type="Archetype" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_WILDKEEPER_SPIRIT_OF_WAR">
        <supports>Wildkeeper Spirit Path</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Your spirit now walks the path of beasts who have been weaponized for warfare. A Spirit of War wildbond is one of combat expertise. The fighting spirit within you constantly pushing you to train with your wildbond, your strength and teamwork are unmatched by those around you. It always remains alert, allowing you to perceive threats through its animal eyes and, in combat, seems to know your moves before you make them, striking at the optimal time to ensure a devastating flurry of attacks.</p>
            <div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_OF_WAR_WARBONDER" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_OF_WAR_QUICK_TO_STRIKE" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_OF_WAR_SECOND_GROWTH" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_OF_WAR_BOND_UNRELENTING" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_OF_WAR_SPIRIT_ROAR" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_OF_WAR_WARBONDER" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_OF_WAR_QUICK_TO_STRIKE" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_OF_WAR_SECOND_GROWTH" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_OF_WAR_BOND_UNRELENTING" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_OF_WAR_SPIRIT_ROAR" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Warbonder" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_OF_WAR_WARBONDER">
            <description>
                <p>At 1st level, your spirit bond has grown strong enough to allow you to coordinate attacks with your wildbond. Your wildbond can take the Help action as a bonus action on its turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Quick to Strike" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_OF_WAR_QUICK_TO_STRIKE">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, you have learned how to pounce like a predator. Immediately after initiative is rolled, you can use your reaction to quickly strike. You and your wildbond can move up to half your movement speeds, and then each make a melee weapon attack.</p>
                <p class="indent">In addition, you now have advantage on any initiative rolls made while within 30 feet of your wildbond.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Second Growth" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_OF_WAR_SECOND_GROWTH">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, your spirit has further grown. You can choose to have your wildbond increase in size from Small to Medium, or stay the same size as it previously was.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Bond Unrelenting" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_OF_WAR_BOND_UNRELENTING">
            <description>
                <p>At level 10, your connection with your wildbond feels untouchable. When your wildbond is reduced to 0 hit points, you can use your reaction to cause it to drop to 1 hit point instead. You can’t use this feature again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Spirit Roar" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_OF_WAR_SPIRIT_ROAR">
            <description>
                <p>At 14th level, your spirit bond has been tempered by your combat experience, letting you harness your wildbond's innate vocal power. As an action, each creature of your choice within 60 feet of you that can hear you must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw against a DC equal to 8 + your Proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier or become frightened of you for 1 minute. A creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success. If a creature's saving throw is successful or the effect ends for it, the creature is immune to this feature for the next 24 hours</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>

    <element name="Spirit of the Dark" type="Archetype" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_WILDKEEPER_SPIRIT_OF_THE_DARK">
        <supports>Wildkeeper Spirit Path</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Your spirit now walks the paths of the Plane of Shadow. A Spirit of the Dark wildbond is one that has tapped into dark spirit magic, giving it the power of the night. It’s body becomes darker and its eyes glow a faint purple, writhing from the necrotic energy within. Most see this alteration of your spirit bond as twisted and corrupt, some even condemning you for allowing it to happen. You see its potential and prowess in mastering the shadows.</p>
            <div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_OF_THE_DARK_NIGHTBONDER" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_OF_THE_DARK_ONE_WITH_DEATH" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_OF_THE_DARK_SECOND_GROWTH" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_OF_THE_DARK_SHADOW_CREATURE" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_OF_THE_DARK_LIFE_SAPPER" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_OF_THE_DARK_NIGHTBONDER" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_OF_THE_DARK_ONE_WITH_DEATH" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_OF_THE_DARK_SECOND_GROWTH" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_OF_THE_DARK_SHADOW_CREATURE" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_OF_THE_DARK_LIFE_SAPPER" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Nightbonder" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_OF_THE_DARK_NIGHTBONDER">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at level 1, your spirit bond draws power from the night. Your wildbond's darkvision extends to 120 feet. In addition, when you and your wildbond are within 30 feet of each other, you can each add your Wisdom modifier to any Dexterity (Stealth) checks you make.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="One with Death" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_OF_THE_DARK_ONE_WITH_DEATH">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, you tap into forbidden magic to strengthen your spirit. You and your wildbond gain resistance to necrotic damage. In addition, you now have advantage on death saving throws you make.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Second Growth" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_OF_THE_DARK_SECOND_GROWTH">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, your spirit has further grown. You can choose to have your wildbond increase in size from Small to Medium, or stay the same size as it previously was.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Shadow Creature" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_OF_THE_DARK_SHADOW_CREATURE">
            <description>
                <p>At level 10, when your wildbond is in dim light or darkness, the wildbond can use its bonus action to teleport up to 60 feet to an unoccupied space it can see that is also in dim light or darkness. If you are within 60 feet of your wildbond when it teleports, you can choose to swap places with your wildbond.</p>
                <p class="indent">If the wildbond makes an attack on the same turn it teleports in this way, the attack deals an additional 1d8 necrotic damage.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Life Sapper" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SPIRIT_OF_THE_DARK_LIFE_SAPPER">
            <description>
                <p>At 14th level, you have fully bonded with the spirit of the dark. You and your wildbond gain immunity to necrotic damage. Additionally, when you or your wildbond have advantage on an attack, you can choose to forgo that advantage. If the attack hits, it deals an additional 2d8 necrotic damage and you or your wildbond (your choice) regain hit points equal to the necrotic damage dealt. You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier (a minimum of once). You regain any expended uses when you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>

    <!-- Wildkeeper Skills -->
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ANIMALHANDLING">
            <supports>Wildkeeper</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ATHLETICS">
            <supports>Wildkeeper</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERFORMANCE">
            <supports>Wildkeeper</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_NATURE">
            <supports>Wildkeeper</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION">
            <supports>Wildkeeper</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SURVIVAL">
            <supports>Wildkeeper</supports>
        </append>

    <!-- Wildbond Companion -->
        <element name="Wildbond" type="Companion" source="The Wildkeeper Class" id="ID_SHI_TWBC_COMPANION_WILDBOND">
            <supports>Wildbond</supports>
            <description>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="size">Tiny</set>
                <set name="type">beast</set>
                <set name="alignment">neutral</set>
                <set name="ac">12+ proficiency bonus</set>
                <set name="hp">2 + your Wisdom modifier + five times your wildkeeper level (the wildbond has a number of Hit Dice [d8s] equal to your wildkeeper level)</set>
                <set name="speed">30 ft.</set>
                <set name="strength">12</set>
                <set name="dexterity">14</set>
                <set name="constitution">14</set>
                <set name="intelligence">4</set>
                <set name="wisdom">10</set>
                <set name="charisma">8</set>
                <set name="saves">Dex +2 plus PB, Wis +2 plus PB</set>
                <set name="skills">Acrobatics +2 plus PB, Perception +0 plus PB x 2, Stealth +2 plus PB</set>
                <set name="conditionImmunities">charmed, exhaustion</set>
                <set name="senses">darkvision 60 ft., passive Perception 10 + (PB x 2)</set>
                <set name="languages">understands the languages you speak</set>
                <set name="challenge">0</set>
                <set name="traits">ID_SHI_TWBC_COMPANION_WILDBOND_TRAIT_AGILE</set>
                <set name="actions">ID_SHI_TWBC_COMPANION_WILDBOND_ACTION_NATURAL_WEAPON</set>
                <set name="reactions">ID_SHI_TWBC_COMPANION_WILDBOND_REACTION_QUICK_STEPS</set>
            </setters>
            <rules>
                <stat name="companion:proficiency" value="proficiency" />
                <stat name="companion:ac" value="12" />
                <stat name="companion:ac" value="companion:proficiency" />
                <stat name="companion:hp:max" value="2" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="companion:hp:max" value="wisdom:modifier" />
                <stat name="companion:hp:max" value="level:wildkeeper" />
                <stat name="companion:hp:max" value="level:wildkeeper" />
                <stat name="companion:hp:max" value="level:wildkeeper" />
                <stat name="companion:hp:max" value="level:wildkeeper" />
                <stat name="companion:hp:max" value="level:wildkeeper" />
                <stat name="companion:speed" value="30" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="companion:perception:proficiency" value="companion:proficiency" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="companion:perception:proficiency" value="companion:proficiency" bonus="double" />
                <stat name="companion:stealth:proficiency" value="companion:proficiency" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="companion:acrobatics:proficiency" value="companion:proficiency" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="companion:dexterity:save:proficiency" value="companion:proficiency" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="companion:wisdom:save:proficiency" value="companion:proficiency" bonus="base" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Agile" type="Companion Trait" source="The Wildkeeper Class" id="ID_SHI_TWBC_COMPANION_WILDBOND_TRAIT_AGILE">
            <description>
                <p>The wildbond doesn't provoke opportunity attacks when it moves out of an enemy's reach.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Natural Weapon" type="Companion Action" source="The Wildkeeper Class" id="ID_SHI_TWBC_COMPANION_WILDBOND_ACTION_NATURAL_WEAPON">
            <description>
                <p>Melee Weapon Attack: your to hit modifier to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 1d4 + PB chosen damage.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Quick Steps" type="Companion Reaction" source="The Wildkeeper Class" id="ID_SHI_TWBC_COMPANION_WILDBOND_REACTION_QUICK_STEPS">
            <description>
                <p>The wildbond imposes disadvantage on the attack roll of one creature it can see that is within 5 feet of it, provided the attack roll is targeting it.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

</elements>