<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Sigilant Class</name>
        <author url="https://www.reddit.com/u/Rsquared">u/Rsquared</author>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="class-sigilant.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/classes/class-sigilant.xml" />
        </update>
        <!-- version 2: https://www.gmbinder.com/share/-Lf0BAsRBGEPXcyycTXN -->
    </info>
    
    <element name="Sigilant" type="Class" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_CLASS_SIGILANT">
        <description>
            <p>A graceful elf steps inside the swing of an orc’s greataxe. Her hand contorts in complex figures, and a glowing brand appears on her enemy. With a precise stab, she strikes through it, and carelessly pivots away as a conflagration consumes her opponent.</p>
            <p class="indent">An assassin slips through the shadows, using wit and magic in equal amounts to remain unseen. His blade glows ice-white a moment before he lunges for his target, cold as death before the corpse reaches the ground.</p>
            <p class="indent">A plate-clad warrior roars a challenge, his armor sparking, the air stinking of ozone. He swings recklessly through a massed pack of hobgoblins, fearlessly relying on protective layers of steel and magic while he focuses on carving a path of blood and lightning.</p>
            <h4>MASTERS OF RUNES</h4>
            <p>Spellsword. Duskblade. Magus. Common terms, used for many styles of mystic warrior. The Sigilant is different. Where other warriors cast their spells and swing their swords separately, the Sigilant’s rune-empowered strikes unleash punishing elemental effects.</p>
            <p class="indent">Derived from the rune magics of the Giants and Dwarves, or perhaps the rune scribes of ancient times, the sigil is a vicious brand laid upon an enemy, ready to explode in a shower of elemental energy when struck with a weapon. Study of the bellicose applications for magicks leaves little room for other mystic endeavors, though a Sigilant often learns a few spells for life outside of battle.</p>
            <h4>THE ARMA ARCANA</h4>
            <p>Sigilants call their art the Arma Arcana; their skill is in binding elemental forces to the physical plane in intricate and delicate webs of magic. These techniques require expert memorization and wit to form and mold the sigil. As a Sigilant improves in skill, they can bind more sigils at once, with devastating results when unleashed with a weapon strike or in a torrent of evocation magic.</p>
            <p class="indent">Sigilants rarely form schools or academies, commonly training in a master-student format. A prospective student may petition a master Sigilant for education in exchange for menial service, ending at the master’s discretion.</p>
            <h2>CLASS FEATURES</h2>
            <p>As a Sigilant, you gain the following class features.</p>
            <h5>HIT POINTS</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Hit Dice:</strong> 1d8 per Sigilant level</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at 1st Level:</strong> 8 + your Constitution modifier</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at Higher Levels:</strong> 1d8 (or 5) + your Constitution modifier per class level after 1st</li>
            </ul>
            <h5>PROFICIENCIES</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Armor:</strong> Light armor, medium armor</li>
                <li><strong>Weapons:</strong> Simple weapons, martial weapons</li>
                <li><strong>Tools:</strong> None</li>
            </ul>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Saving Throws:</strong> Constitution, Intelligence</li>
                <li><strong>Skills:</strong> Choose two from Athletics, Acrobatics, Arcana, History, Insight, Investigation, and Persuasion</li>
            </ul>
            <h5>EQUIPMENT</h5>
            <p>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background (or 5d4 x 10 gp):</p>
            <ul>
                <li>(a) a martial weapon or (b) two simple weapons</li>
                <li>(a) a chain shirt or (b) leather armor</li>
                <li>(a) five javelins or (b) a longbow and 20 arrows</li>
                <li>(a) a scholar’s pack or (b) a dungeoneer’s pack</li>
            </ul>
			<h5 class="caption">THE class</h5>
            <table class="class-features">
                <thead>
                    <tr><th class="col-5">Level</th><th>Proficiency Bonus</th><th class="left">Features</th><th>Runes</th><th>1st</th><th>2nd</th><th>3rd</th><th>4th</th><th>5th</th></tr>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                    <tr><td>1st</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Runecrafting, Bladecasting, Student of Writ</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>2nd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Edge and Aegis, Evocant Sigil, Spellcasting</td><td>2</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Ordo Arcana</td><td>2</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>4th</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Ability Score Increase</td><td>2</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Extra Attack</td><td>2</td><td>4</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>6th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Abjurant Sigil, Limited Ritual Magic</td><td>2</td><td>4</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>7th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Order Feature</td><td>3</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>8th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Ability Score Increase</td><td>3</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">—</td><td>3</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>10th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Conjurant Circle</td><td>3</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>11th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Elemental Escalation</td><td>3</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>12th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Ability Score Increase</td><td>3</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>13th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">—</td><td>3</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>1</td><td>—</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>14th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Mixed Magical Arts</td><td>3</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>1</td><td>—</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>15th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Order Feature</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>16th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Ability Score Increase</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>17th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">—</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>1</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>18th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Divinant Mastery</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>1</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>19th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Ability Score Increase</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>20th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Martial Maelstrom</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td></tr>
                </tbody>
            </table>

            <div element="ID_RSQUARD_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SIGILANT_RUNECRAFTING" />
            <div element="ID_RSQUARD_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SIGILANT_BLADECASTING" />
            <div element="ID_RSQUARD_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SIGILANT_STUDENT_OF_WRIT" />
            <div element="ID_RSQUARD_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SIGILANT_EDGE_AND_AEGIS" />
            <div element="ID_RSQUARD_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SIGILANT_EVOCANT_SIGIL" />
            <div element="ID_RSQUARD_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SIGILANT_SPELLCASTING" />
            <div element="ID_RSQUARD_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SIGILANT_ORDO_ARCANA" />
            <div element="ID_RSQUARD_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SIGILANT_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" />
            <div element="ID_RSQUARD_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SIGILANT_EXTRA_ATTACK" />
            <div element="ID_RSQUARD_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SIGILANT_ABJURANT_SIGIL" />
            <div element="ID_RSQUARD_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SIGILANT_LIMITED_RITUAL_MAGIC" />
            <div element="ID_RSQUARD_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SIGILANT_CONJURANT_CIRCLE" />
            <div element="ID_RSQUARD_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SIGILANT_ELEMENTAL_ESCALATION" />
            <div element="ID_RSQUARD_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SIGILANT_MIXED_MAGICAL_ARTS" />
            <div element="ID_RSQUARD_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SIGILANT_DIVINANT_MASTERY" />
            <div element="ID_RSQUARD_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SIGILANT_MARTIAL_MAELSTROM" />

            <h1>Sigilant Orders</h1>
            <p>As there are schools of magic, there are schools of swordsmanship. Sigilants combine the techniques of both, leading to many different ways to practice the Arma Arcana. Each Order of Sigilant has unique techniques, closely guarded secrets that are only taught to initiates of that Order.</p>
            <p class="indent">The major Orders of Sigilant detailed below are the Shadowdancer, the Warblade, and the Arcanamach. The Factotum are generalists, learning many different disciplines, while the Shadowdancers are Sigilants who focus on stealth and evasive techniques. The Warblades are found deep in the thick of battle, and the Arcanamach are mystic assassins trained in slaying other mages.</p>
            <p class="indent">The master-student format that most Sigilants learn under means that Order techniques are taught last, after a student has indicated proficiency in the basic skills of Spellstrike and Sigil. Further refinement of Order techniques is the ongoing responsibility of the student, a commitment to a lifetime of careful study and martial practice.</p>
            <h4>Order Spells</h4>
            <p>You gain access to these spells at the levels specified in the Order description. Once you gain access to a Order spell, you always have it prepared. Order spells don’t count against the number of spells you prepare. If you gain a Order spell that doesn’t appear on the Sigilant spell list, the spell is nonetheless an Sigilant spell for you.</p>
            <h4>Order Spellstrikes</h4>
            <p>Order Spellstrikes are specialized techniques, even more powerful than the elemental Spellstrikes. Each Sigilant Order has a signature Spellstrike, a jealously guarded secret, which you learn when inducted into your Order at 3rd level.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can use an Order Spellstrike when you meet the conditions for it. After using your Order Spellstrike, you must finish a short or long rest to do so again.</p>
            <p class="indent">When an Order Spellstrike effect requires a saving throw, use your Sigilant spell save DC.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <setters>
            <set name="hd">d8</set>
            <set name="short">An warrior that enhances their weapons with runes and elemental magic.</set>
        </setters>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_MEDIUM_ARMOR" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_MARTIAL_WEAPONS" />
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency (Sigilant)" number="2" requirements="!ID_RSQAURED_GM_BINDER_MULTICLASS_SIGILANT" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ATHLETICS|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ACROBATICS|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ARCANA|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_HISTORY|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INVESTIGATION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERSUASION" />

            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_RSQUARD_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SIGILANT_RUNECRAFTING" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_RSQUARD_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SIGILANT_BLADECASTING" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_RSQUARD_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SIGILANT_STUDENT_OF_WRIT" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_RSQUARD_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SIGILANT_EDGE_AND_AEGIS" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_RSQUARD_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SIGILANT_EVOCANT_SIGIL" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_RSQUARD_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SIGILANT_SPELLCASTING" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_RSQUARD_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SIGILANT_ORDO_ARCANA" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_RSQUARD_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SIGILANT_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" level="4" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_RSQUARD_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SIGILANT_EXTRA_ATTACK" level="5" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_RSQUARD_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SIGILANT_ABJURANT_SIGIL" level="6" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_RSQUARD_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SIGILANT_LIMITED_RITUAL_MAGIC" level="6" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_RSQUARD_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SIGILANT_CONJURANT_CIRCLE" level="10" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_RSQUARD_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SIGILANT_ELEMENTAL_ESCALATION" level="11" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_RSQUARD_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SIGILANT_MIXED_MAGICAL_ARTS" level="14" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_RSQUARD_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SIGILANT_DIVINANT_MASTERY" level="18" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_RSQUARD_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SIGILANT_MARTIAL_MAELSTROM" level="20" />
        </rules>
        <multiclass id="ID_RSQAURED_GM_BINDER_MULTICLASS_SIGILANT">
            <prerequisite>Strength or Dexterity 13, Intelligence 13</prerequisite>
            <requirements>([str:13]||[dex:13]),[int:13]</requirements>
            <setters>
                <set name="multiclass proficiencies"></set>
            </setters>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS" />
            </rules>
        </multiclass>
    </element>
        <element name="Runecrafting" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RSQUARD_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SIGILANT_RUNECRAFTING">
            <description>
                <p>You’ve learned how to create glyphs of arcane power to affect the world around you. At first level, your uses for this skill are limited to your supply of runes given in the Sigilant Table above. Any expended runes are restored at the end of a short or long rest.</p>
                <p class="indent">As a bonus action, you can expend one or more runes and/or one spell slot to create sigils. You create one sigil per rune, and multiple sigils based to the level of the spell slot, as given in the below table. Sigils that are created but not placed are lost.</p>
                <h5>Sigils per Spell Slot Level</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Spell Slot Level</td><td>Sigils Created</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1</td><td>2</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>2</td><td>3</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3</td><td>5</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>4</td><td>6</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5</td><td>8</td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="{{runecrafting:rune-count}} Runes/Short Rest" action="Bonus Action">
                <description>As a bonus action, you can expend one or more runes and/or one spell slot to create sigils. You create one sigil per rune, and multiple sigils based to the level of the spell slot, as given in the feature table. Sigils that are created but not placed are lost.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="runecrafting:rune-count" value="2" level="1" />
                <stat name="runecrafting:rune-count" value="1" level="7" />
                <stat name="runecrafting:rune-count" value="1" level="15" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Bladecasting" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RSQUARD_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SIGILANT_BLADECASTING">
            <description>
                <p>When you use Runecrafting, you can place one or more sigils on a weapon you are wielding, infusing it with magical effects. When you do, choose a Bladecasting type from the following elements: fire, lightning, cold or acid. You can change the Bladecasting’s damage type or add additional sigils to it when you use Runecrafting again.</p>
                <p class="indent">The Bladecasting ends when it has zero sigils, when you dismiss it or stop wielding the weapon, or when you finish a short or long rest; excess sigils are lost. You can have only one active Bladecasting at a time.</p>
                <p class="indent">Whenever you cast a spell containing the word "Smite" while wielding a Bladecasting weapon, the spell damage is dealt in the Bladecasting’s type.</p>
                <div class="sidebar">
                    <h4>Using your Bonus Action</h4>
                    <p>When you create sigils with Runecrafting, you can distribute them among creatures (Evocant Sigil), on your weapon (Bladecasting), or also use your action to summon a mephit (Conjurant Circle), in any combination, once you have those features.</p>
                </div>
                <h5>Spellstrike</h5>
                <p>Once per turn when you hit a creature with your Bladecasting weapon, you can expend a sigil from Bladecasting to inflict the relevant transmutation effect, dealing damage as part of your weapon attack:</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong>Acid: Corrosion.</strong> The target must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or its AC is reduced by 1 as armor or natural armor is weakened. A creature cannot have its AC reduced by more than 1, and it regains lost AC when it receives cumulative magical healing equal to your class level, or by using an action to adjust worn armor.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong>Cold: Shatter.</strong> A shower of razor-sharp ice blasts from your weapon. Each creature in a 15 foot cone emanating from you through the target takes 1d8 cold damage. Sigil-marked creatures in the cone must make a Dexterity saving throw; on a failure, the sigil bursts (see below).</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong>Fire: Ignition.</strong> The target takes 2d4 fire damage and must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or begin to burn for one round. Unless it is doused or spends its action to extinguish the flames, it takes 5 fire damage at the end of its next turn, and any sigil on the creature bursts.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong>Lightning: Shock.</strong> The target takes 2d4 lightning damage, and must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or make its next attack roll with disadvantage. This effect ends at the end of its next turn.</p>
                <p>When a Spellstrike requires a saving throw, use your Sigilant spell save DC. A creature that is immune to a damage type is immune to that Spellstrike effect.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you create sigils with Runecrafting, you can place them all on your weapon. You select a type of damage (acid, cold, fire, or lightning) the sigils will cause expended. Once per turn, when you hit a creature with your weapon, you can expend a sigil to inflict the relevant effect. Whenever you cast a smite spell while wielding a Bladecasting weapon, the spell damage is dealt in the Bladecasting’s type.</description>
                <description level="2">When you create sigils with Runecrafting, you can place them all on your weapon or distribute them among creature (for use with Evocant Sigil). You select a type of damage (acid, cold, fire, or lightning) the sigils will cause expended. Once per turn, when you hit a creature with your weapon, you can expend a sigil to inflict the relevant effect. Whenever you cast a smite spell while wielding a Bladecasting weapon, the spell damage is dealt in the Bladecasting’s type.</description>
                <description level="10">When you create sigils with Runecrafting, you can place them all on your weapon, distribute them among creatures (Evocant Sigil) or summon mephits (Conjurant Circle). You select a type of damage (acid, cold, fire, or lightning) the sigils will cause expended. Once per turn, when you hit a creature with your weapon, you can expend a sigil to inflict the relevant effect. Whenever you cast a smite spell while wielding a Bladecasting weapon, the spell damage is dealt in the Bladecasting’s type.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Student of Writ" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RSQUARD_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SIGILANT_STUDENT_OF_WRIT">
            <description>
                <p>You have studied glyphs and runes extensively, delving into the systems of binding power and meaning to marks in paper, stone and metal.</p>
                <p class="indent">You have advantage on ability checks to determine the purpose, meaning, or effect of glyphs, runes, warning signs, magical circles, or other written or inscribed art, and on saving throws against magical traps triggered by inscriptions (such as the explosion of a <em>glyph of warding</em>).</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You have advantage on ability checks to determine the purpose, meaning, or effect of glyphs, runes, warning signs, magical circles, or other written or inscribed art, and on saving throws against magical traps triggered by inscriptions (such as the explosion of a glyph of warding).</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Edge and Aegis" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RSQUARD_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SIGILANT_EDGE_AND_AEGIS">
            <description>
                <p>At 2nd level, you supplement your fighting style with magical enhancements taught in the Arma Arcana.</p>
                <p class="indent">The first time in a turn that you hit a creature with your Bladecasting weapon, you deal additional damage equal to your Intelligence modifier in the Bladecasting’s damage type.</p>
                <p class="indent">When you have a free hand and are not wielding a shield or a weapon with the heavy property, you add half your Intelligence modifier, rounded down, to your AC.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>The first time in a turn that you hit a creature with your Bladecasting weapon, you deal {{intelligence:modifier}} additional damage in the Bladecasting’s damage type. When you have a free hand and are not wielding a shield or a weapon with the heavy property, you add half your Intelligence modifier, rounded down, to your AC.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Evocant Sigil" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RSQUARD_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SIGILANT_EVOCANT_SIGIL">
            <description>
                <p>At 2nd level, you have learned to temporarily seal vicious magical energies into other creatures via your sigils. Choose an elemental damage type for your sigils - acid, cold, fire, or lightning - which you can change at the end of a long rest. Your Bladecastings need not be the same damage type as your sigils.</p>
                <p class="indent">When you use Runecrafting, you can place a sigil on one or more creatures within 30 feet. The range of your sigils increases to 45 feet at level 9, and 60 feet at level 17.</p>
                <p class="indent">Only one sigil can mark a creature at one time, and you can only utilize your own sigil-marks for the purpose of spells that affect a sigil.</p>
                <p class="indent">Your sigils can be visible, or invisible except to you or a detect magic spell. A sigil appears on the target’s skin, clothing, or armor as a faintly-glowing glyph of your design.</p>
                <p class="indent">When an attacker hits a sigil-marked creature and can see the sigil, it can choose to target and burst the sigil. The sigil’s energies are released in a flare of elemental magic, inflicting 2d4 damage of the sigil’s damage type as part of the weapon or spell attack. If a sigil-marked target fails a saving throw that results in it taking damage, the sigil bursts and deals 2d4 damage.</p>
                <p class="indent">Sigils dissipate and are removed if not burst in one minute, or on the death of the sigil-marked creature. You can remove a sigil at will. In any case, a removed sigil deals no damage.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Choose an elemental damage type for your sigils - acid, cold, fire, or lightning - which you can change at the end of a long rest. Your Bladecastings need not be the same damage type as your sigils. When you use Runecrafting, you can place a sigil on one or more creatures within {{evocant-sigil:range}} feet. When an attacker hits a sigil-marked creature and can see the sigil, it can choose to target and burst the sigil. The sigil’s energies are released in a flare of elemental magic, inflicting 2d4 damage of the sigil’s damage type. If a sigil-marked target fails a saving throw that results in it taking damage, the sigil bursts and deals 2d4 damage.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="evocant-sigil:range" value="30" level="2" />
                <stat name="evocant-sigil:range" value="15" level="9" />
                <stat name="evocant-sigil:range" value="15" level="17" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Spellcasting" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RSQUARD_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SIGILANT_SPELLCASTING">
            <description>
                <p>At 2nd level, you gain a spellbook containing spells that show the first glimmerings of your true power.</p>
                <h5>Spell Slots</h5>
                <p>The Sigilant table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your Sigilant spells of 1st level and higher. To cast one of your spells, you must expend a slot of the spell’s level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.</p>
                <h5>Your Spellbook</h5>
                <p>You have a spellbook containing three 1st-level Sigilant spells of your choice. Your spellbook is the repository of the Sigilant spells you know, except cantrips, if any, which are fixed in your mind.</p>
                <h5>Preparing and Casting Spells</h5>
                <p>The Sigilant table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your spells of 1st level and higher. To cast one of these spells, you must expend a slot of the spell’s level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.</p>
                <p class="indent">You prepare the list of Sigilant spells available for you to cast. To do so, choose a number of Sigilant spells from your spellbook equal to your Intelligence modifier + half your Sigilant level (minimum of one spell). The spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can change your list of prepared spells when you finish a long rest. Preparing a new list of Sigilant spells requires time spent studying your spellbook and memorizing the incantations and gestures you must make to cast the spell: at least 1 minute per spell level for each spell on your list.</p>
                <h5>Spellcasting Ability</h5>
                <p>Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for your Sigilant spells, since their power derives from your study and dedication. You use your Intelligence whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Intelligence modifier when setting the saving throw DC or when making an attack roll for a Sigilant spell.</p>
                <center>
                    <p><strong>Spell save DC</strong> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier</p>
                    <p><strong>Spell attack modifier</strong> = your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier</p>
                </center>
                <h5>Spellcasting Focus</h5>
                <p>You can use a simple or martial weapon as a spellcasting focus for your Sigilant spells.</p>
                <h5>Learning Spells of 1st Level and Higher</h5>
                <p>Each time you gain a Sigilant level, you can add one Sigilant spell of your choice to your spellbook for free. Each of these spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots, as shown on the Sigilant table. On your adventures, you might find other spells that you can add to your spellbook (see “Your Spellbook”, <em>Player’s Handbook</em> pg.114).</p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="spellcaster">true</set>
                <set name="spellcastingAbility">Intelligence</set>
            </setters>
            <spellcasting name="Sigilant" ability="Intelligence" prepare="true">
                <list>Sigilant</list>
            </spellcasting>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
    			<stat name="sigilant:spellcasting:slots:1" value="2" level="2" />
    			<stat name="sigilant:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="3" />
    			<stat name="sigilant:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="5" />
    			<stat name="sigilant:spellcasting:slots:2" value="2" level="5" />
    			<stat name="sigilant:spellcasting:slots:2" value="1" level="7" />
    			<stat name="sigilant:spellcasting:slots:3" value="2" level="9" />
    			<stat name="sigilant:spellcasting:slots:3" value="1" level="11" />
    			<stat name="sigilant:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="13" />
    			<stat name="sigilant:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="15" />
    			<stat name="sigilant:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="17" />
    			<stat name="sigilant:spellcasting:slots:5" value="1" level="17" />
    			<stat name="sigilant:spellcasting:slots:5" value="1" level="19" />

                <stat name="sigilant:spellcasting:prepare" value="intelligence:modifier" />
                <stat name="sigilant:spellcasting:prepare" value="level:sigilant:half" />

                <select type="Spell" name="Spellbook (Sigilant)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="2" number="3" spellcasting="Sigilant" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellbook (Sigilant)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="3" number="1" spellcasting="Sigilant" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellbook (Sigilant)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="4" number="1" spellcasting="Sigilant" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellbook (Sigilant)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="5" number="1" spellcasting="Sigilant" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellbook (Sigilant)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="6" number="1" spellcasting="Sigilant" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellbook (Sigilant)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="7" number="1" spellcasting="Sigilant" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellbook (Sigilant)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="8" number="1" spellcasting="Sigilant" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellbook (Sigilant)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="9" number="1" spellcasting="Sigilant" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellbook (Sigilant)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="10" number="1" spellcasting="Sigilant" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellbook (Sigilant)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="11" number="1" spellcasting="Sigilant" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellbook (Sigilant)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="12" number="1" spellcasting="Sigilant" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellbook (Sigilant)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="13" number="1" spellcasting="Sigilant" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellbook (Sigilant)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="14" number="1" spellcasting="Sigilant" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellbook (Sigilant)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="15" number="1" spellcasting="Sigilant" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellbook (Sigilant)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="16" number="1" spellcasting="Sigilant" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellbook (Sigilant)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="17" number="1" spellcasting="Sigilant" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellbook (Sigilant)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="18" number="1" spellcasting="Sigilant" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellbook (Sigilant)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="19" number="1" spellcasting="Sigilant" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellbook (Sigilant)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="20" number="1" spellcasting="Sigilant" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Ordo Arcana" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RSQUARD_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SIGILANT_ORDO_ARCANA">
            <description>
                <p>Upon reaching 3rd level you are inducted into your Sigilant Order, beginning to delve the greater secrets of the Arma Arcana. Choose either Arcanamach, Factotum, Shadowdancer, or Warblade as your Order.</p>
                <p class="indent">You gain your Order’s unique Spellstrike option at 3rd level, and additional Order abilities at 7th and 15th level.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Archetype" name="Ordo Arcana (Sigilant Order)" supports="Sigilant Order" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Ability Score Improvement" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RSQUARD_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SIGILANT_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT">
            <compendium display="false" />
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Sigilant 4)" supports="Improvement Option,Sigilant,4" level="4" />
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Sigilant 8)" supports="Improvement Option,Sigilant,8" level="8" />
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Sigilant 12)" supports="Improvement Option,Sigilant,12" level="12" />
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Sigilant 16)" supports="Improvement Option,Sigilant,16" level="16" />
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Sigilant 19)" supports="Improvement Option,Sigilant,19" level="19" />
		</rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Extra Attack" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RSQUARD_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SIGILANT_EXTRA_ATTACK">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 5th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
        		<stat name="extra attack:count" value="2" level="5" bonus="extra attack" />      
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Abjurant Sigil" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RSQUARD_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SIGILANT_ABJURANT_SIGIL">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 6th level, you have learned to quickly deploy a protective version of your sigil. When you or a creature within 10 feet of you takes damage, you can use a reaction to expend a spell slot, forming a momentary ward that reduces the damage by your Intelligence modifier, plus 1d6 per level of the spell slot. If any of the damage and your sigil are the same type, add 1d6 to the damage reduction.</p>
                <p class="indent">At 18th level, the range of this ability increases to 30 feet.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Reaction">
                <description>When you or a creature within {{abjurant-sigil:range}} feet of you takes damage, you can expend a spell slot, forming a momentary ward that reduces the damage by your Intelligence modifier, plus 1d6 per level of the spell slot. If any of the damage and your sigil are the same type, add 1d6 to the damage reduction.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="abjurant-sigil:range" value="10" level="6" />
                <stat name="abjurant-sigil:range" value="20" level="18" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Limited Ritual Magic" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RSQUARD_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SIGILANT_LIMITED_RITUAL_MAGIC">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, you’ve learned to cast some wizard spells, though not as readily or effectively as a wizard does. You can inscribe wizard spells in your spellbook as if they were Sigilant spells, though you can only prepare spells from the Sigilant list. However, you can cast a wizard spell as a ritual if that spell has the ritual tag and you have the spell in your spellbook.</p>
                <p class="indent">Choose two wizard spells with the ritual tag and add them to your spellbook. These spells must be of a level you can cast.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can inscribe wizard spells in your spellbook as if they were Sigilant spells, though you can only prepare spells from the Sigilant list. However, you can cast a wizard spell as a ritual if that spell has the ritual tag and you have the spell in your spellbook.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Spell" name="Ritual Wizard Spell" supports="Wizard,Ritual,2" number="2" level="6" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Conjurant Circle" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RSQUARD_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SIGILANT_CONJURANT_CIRCLE">
            <description>
                <p>At 10th level, you learn to use runic gates to summon minor denizens of the elemental planes for use as spies, distractions or combatants. When you use Runecrafting, you can also use your action to place paired sigils on the ground that summon one mephit for every two sigils you place, appearing in an unoccupied space you can see within 60 feet. Summoning and controlling mephits requires your concentration.</p>
                <p class="indent">A mephit understands and obeys your verbal commands to the best of its ability, acting on your turn. If you don’t issue any commands, it defends itself from hostile creatures, but otherwise takes no actions. A summoned mephit is unable to summon additional mephits. After one hour, or if you lose concentration, your summoned mephits return to their home plane.</p>
                <p class="indent">The mephits you summon are determined by your sigil:</p>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Fire</td><td>Cold</td><td>Lightning</td><td>Acid</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>Magma</td><td>Ice</td><td>Smoke</td><td>Mud</td></tr>
                </table>
                <p class="indent">You can control a number of mephits at one time up to your Intelligence modifier (minimum one).</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you use Runecrafting, you can also use your action to place paired sigils on the ground that summon one mephit for every two sigils you place, appearing in an unoccupied space you can see within 60 feet. Summoning and controlling mephits requires your concentration. You can control up to {{conjurant-circle:mephits}} mephits at one time.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="conjurant-circle:mephits" value="1" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="conjurant-circle:mephits" value="intelligence:modifier" bonus="base" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Elemental Escalation" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RSQUARD_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SIGILANT_ELEMENTAL_ESCALATION">
            <description>
                <p>Upon reaching 11th level, your Runecrafting abilities grow in power. Your sigil bursts deal additional damage equal to your Intelligence modifier.</p>
                <p class="indent">Your Bladecasting weapon attacks always deal bonus elemental damage, rather than once per turn. Additionally:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Your Corrosion Spellstrike deals 2d4 acid damage.</li>
                    <li>Your Shatter Spellstrike affects a 30 foot cone.</li>
                    <li>Your Ignition Spellstrike adds your Intelligence modifier to the initial fire damage.</li>
                    <li>The target of your Shock Spellstrike is unable to take reactions until the end of its next turn.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You sigil bursts deal an additional {{intelligence:modifier}} damage. Your Bladecasting weapon attacks always deal bonus elemental damage, rather than once per turn. Each damage type also has additional effects.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Mixed Magical Arts" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RSQUARD_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SIGILANT_MIXED_MAGICAL_ARTS">
            <description>
                <p>At 14th level, if you have no active sigils, you can change the damage type of your sigils when you use your Evocant or Abjurant Sigil, or when summoning mephits with Conjurant Circle.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>If you have no active sigils, you can change the damage type of your sigils when you use your Evocant or Abjurant Sigil, or when summoning mephits with Conjurant Circle.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Divinant Mastery" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RSQUARD_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SIGILANT_DIVINANT_MASTERY">
            <description>
                <p>At 18th level, you are a master of the Arma Arcana and can draw upon reserves of power when your magical senses detect danger. If you roll for initiative with no 1st level spell slots available, you regain two 1st level spell slots.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you have used this ability, you are unable to use it again until you have finished a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
                <description>If you roll for initiative with no 1st level spell slots available, you regain two 1st level spell slots.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Martial Maelstrom" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RSQUARD_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SIGILANT_MARTIAL_MAELSTROM">
            <description>
                <p>At 20th level, as an action you can unleash unlimited elemental energy. For one minute, a sirocco of elemental wrath affects the area around you to a distance of 30 feet, generating cacophonous noise and heavily obscuring the area and an additional 30 foot radius. You can see and hear normally through the storm.</p>
                <p class="indent">Whenever an enemy creature starts its turn in the maelstrom, the creature takes 2 damage from each of the following types: fire, cold, lightning, acid, thunder (10 damage total). This damage causes sigils to resonate and burst at the end of the creature’s turn.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you have used this ability, you are unable to use it again until you have finished a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You can unleash unlimited elemental energy. For one minute, a sirocco of elemental wrath affects the area around you to a distance of 30 feet, generating cacophonous noise and heavily obscuring the area and an additional 30 foot radius. You can see and hear normally through the storm. Whenever an enemy creature starts its turn in the maelstrom, the creature takes 2 damage from each of the following types: fire, cold, lightning, acid, thunder (10 damage total). This damage causes sigils to resonate and burst at the end of the creature’s turn.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    <!-- subclasses -->
        <element name="Arcanamach" type="Archetype" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_SIGILANT_ARCANAMACH">
            <supports>Sigilant Order</supports>
            <description>
                <p>The Arcanamach are Sigilants who focus on a specific style of magecraft, derived from a book known as the Grimoire Arcanamacha. The Grimoire teaches secrets of stealth, alertness, mental endurance, and combat-casting. Arcanamach are infamous mage-slayers, capable of countering other spellcasters with their complex interplay of sword and spell. Mercenary Aracanamach are valued highly as both assassins and guardians.</p>
                <p class="indent">Notably, they tend to avoid evocation and conjuration magics, preferring to use their spells to strengthen themselves and weaken their enemies.</p>
                <div element="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCANAMACH_DISPELLING_STRIKE" />
                <div element="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCANAMACH_BONUS_CANTRIPS" />
                <div element="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCANAMACH_ARCANAMACH_SPELLS" />
                <div element="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCANAMACH_EXTENDED_SPELLSTRENGTH" />
                <div element="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCANAMACH_TENACIOUS_SPELLS" />
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCANAMACH_DISPELLING_STRIKE" level="3" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCANAMACH_BONUS_CANTRIPS" level="3" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCANAMACH_ARCANAMACH_SPELLS" level="3" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCANAMACH_EXTENDED_SPELLSTRENGTH" level="7" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCANAMACH_TENACIOUS_SPELLS" level="15" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Dispelling Strike" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCANAMACH_DISPELLING_STRIKE">
                <description>
                    <p>When you hit a creature with a melee attack, you can use a bonus action to cast <em>dispel magic</em> on it without consuming a spell slot.</p>
                    <p class="indent">You can use a Spellstrike when you meet the conditions for it. After using your Spellstrike, you must finish a short or long rest to do so again.</p>
                    <p class="indent">When a Spellstrike effect requires a saving throw, use your Sigilant spell save DC.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
                    <description>When you hit a creature with a melee attack, you can use a bonus action to cast dispel magic on it without consuming a spell slot.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Bonus Cantrips" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCANAMACH_BONUS_CANTRIPS">
                <description>
                    <p>You learn stalking blade*, plus one wizard cantrip of your choice, which you cast as a Sigilant spell.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_SPELL_STALKING_BLADE" spellcasting="Sigilant" />
                    <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Arcanamach)" supports="Wizard,0" spellcasting="Sigilant" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Extended Spellstrength" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCANAMACH_EXTENDED_SPELLSTRENGTH">
                <description>
                    <p>Starting at 7th level, your mental focus is such that you can cast certain spells that would normally require your concentration without concentration. A qualifying spell must be of 1st or 2nd level, have a single target, and be from the Illusion, Transmutation, or Enchantment School.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Once you have cast a spell in this way, you cannot do so again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
                    <description>You can cast 1st or 2nd level concentration spells from the Illusion, Transmutation or Enchantment schools on a single target without concentration.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Tenacious Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCANAMACH_TENACIOUS_SPELLS">
                <description>
                    <p>Beginning at 15th level, your spells are particularly difficult to thwart. Attempts to dispel or counter your spells are never automatically successful, and the spellcasting checks to dispel or counter your spells are made at disadvantage.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>Attempts to dispel or counter your spells are never automatically successful, and the spellcasting checks to dispel or counter your spells are made at disadvantage.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Arcanamach Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCANAMACH_ARCANAMACH_SPELLS">
                <description>
                    <p>You gain access to these spells at the levels specified in the Order description. Once you gain access to a Order spell, you always have it prepared. Order spells don’t count against the number of spells you prepare. If you gain a Order spell that doesn’t appear on the Sigilant spell list, the spell is nonetheless an Sigilant spell for you.</p>
                    <table>
                        <thead>
                            <tr><td>Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                        </thead>
                        <tr><td>3</td><td><i>heroism</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>5</td><td><i>enlarge/reduce</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>9</td><td><i>counterspell</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>13</td><td><i>polymorph</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>17</td><td><i>far step</i></td></tr>
                    </table>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HEROISM" level="3" spellcasting="Sigilant" prepared="true" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENLARGE_REDUCE" level="5" spellcasting="Sigilant" prepared="true" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COUNTERSPELL" level="9" spellcasting="Sigilant" prepared="true" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_POLYMORPH" level="13" spellcasting="Sigilant" prepared="true" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_FAR_STEP" level="17" spellcasting="Sigilant" prepared="true" />
                </rules>
            </element>

        <element name="Factotum" type="Archetype" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_SIGILANT_FACTOTUM">
            <supports>Sigilant Order</supports>
            <description>
                <p>The Factotum are dabblers, professional explorers who plunder a wide variety of fields. They advocate reading through tomes of arcane magic to gain an understanding of spells, offering prayers to a variety of deities to earn their blessings, and observing warrior stances and exercises to understand the art of fighting.</p>
                <p class="indent">But while a Factotum learns many paths, it masters none of them. The other Orders consider the Factotum unserious, but this could not be further from the truth; Factotum simply treat all learning as equally precious.</p>
                <div element="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FACTOTUM_CUNNING_STRIKE" />
                <div element="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FACTOTUM_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" />
                <div element="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FACTOTUM_FACTOTUM_SPELLS" />
                <div element="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FACTOTUM_FLASH_OF_BRILLIANCE" />
                <div element="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FACTOTUM_OPPORTUNISTIC_PIETY" />
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FACTOTUM_CUNNING_STRIKE" level="3" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FACTOTUM_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" level="3" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FACTOTUM_FACTOTUM_SPELLS" level="3" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FACTOTUM_FLASH_OF_BRILLIANCE" level="7" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FACTOTUM_OPPORTUNISTIC_PIETY" level="15" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Cunning Strike" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FACTOTUM_CUNNING_STRIKE">
                <description>
                    <p>When you hit a creature with a melee attack, you can emulate a sneak attack as if you were a rogue of equal level, dealing an additional 1d6 damage for every two levels you have in this class.</p>
                    <p class="indent">When using this ability, you must meet the usual requirements for sneak attack.</p>
                    <p class="indent">You can use a Spellstrike when you meet the conditions for it. After using your Spellstrike, you must finish a short or long rest to do so again.</p>
                    <p class="indent">When an Order Spellstrike effect requires a saving throw, use your Sigilant spell save DC.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>When you hit a creature with a melee attack, you can emulate a sneak attack as if you were a rogue of equal level, dealing an additional {{cunning-strike:damage-dice}}d6 damage. You must meet the usual requirements for sneak attack.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="cunning-strike:damage-dice" value="level:sigilant:half" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Bonus Proficiencies" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FACTOTUM_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES">
                <description>
                    <p>You gain proficiency in a skill, a language, and a toolkit of your choice.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency (Factotum Sigilant)" level="3" supports="Skill" />
                    <select type="Language" name="Language Proficiency (Factotum Sigilant)" level="3" />
                    <select type="Proficiency" name="Tool Proficiency (Factotum Sigilant)" level="3" supports="Tool,!Musical Instrument" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Flash of Brilliance" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FACTOTUM_FLASH_OF_BRILLIANCE">
                <description>
                    <p>Beginning at 7th level, you can briefly imitate even a master. You focus on a task, adding your intelligence modifier to all of your ability checks for one minute.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Once you have used this ability, you are unable to do so again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
                    <description>You focus on a task, adding your Intelligence modifier to all of your ability checks for one minute.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Opportunistic Piety" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FACTOTUM_OPPORTUNISTIC_PIETY">
                <description>
                    <p>Factotum are legendary for the number of holy symbols, lucky trinkets, and blessed items they keep handy. The study of the divine empowers certain sigil techniques.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Starting at 15th level, you can also place sigils on yourself, or allies you can see in range, when you use Runecrafting. These sigils burst at the end of your turn, healing each target for 2d4 hit points.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Runecrafting">
                    <description>You can place sigils on yourself or allies you can see in range. These sigils burst at the end of your turn, healing each target for 2d4 hit points.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Factotum Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FACTOTUM_FACTOTUM_SPELLS">
                <description>
                    <p>You gain access to these spells at the levels specified in the Order description. Once you gain access to a Order spell, you always have it prepared. Order spells don’t count against the number of spells you prepare. If you gain a Order spell that doesn’t appear on the Sigilant spell list, the spell is nonetheless an Sigilant spell for you.</p>
                    <table>
                        <thead>
                            <tr><td>Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                        </thead>
                        <tr><td>3</td><td><i>healing word</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>5</td><td><i>suggestion</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>9</td><td><i>speak with dead</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>13</td><td><i>control water</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>17</td><td><i>legend lore</i></td></tr>
                    </table>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HEALING_WORD" level="3" spellcrafting="Sigilant" prepared="true" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SUGGESTION" level="5" spellcrafting="Sigilant" prepared="true" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_DEAD" level="9" spellcrafting="Sigilant" prepared="true" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONTROL_WATER" level="13" spellcrafting="Sigilant" prepared="true" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LEGEND_LORE" level="17" spellcrafting="Sigilant" prepared="true" />
                </rules>
            </element>


        <element name="Shadowdancer" type="Archetype" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_SIGILANT_SHADOWDANCER">
            <supports>Sigilant Order</supports>
            <description>
                <p>Shadowdancers are Sigilants with a bent towards shadow magic, a rare discipline connected to the Plane of Shadow. Legend holds that the first Shadowdancers were illusionist mages who studied with the secretive Shadar-kai.</p>
                <p class="indent">Despite the dark connotations, both heroic rogues and notorious assassins are known to dance the shadows.</p>
                <div element="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOWDANCER_SHADOWSTRIKE" />
                <div element="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOWDANCER_BONUS_CANTRIPS" />
                <div element="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOWDANCER_SHADOWDANCER_SPELLS" />
                <div element="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOWDANCER_UMBRAL_EVASION" />
                <div element="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOWDANCER_WREATH_OF_SHADOWS" />
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOWDANCER_SHADOWSTRIKE" level="3" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOWDANCER_BONUS_CANTRIPS" level="3" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOWDANCER_SHADOWDANCER_SPELLS" level="3" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOWDANCER_UMBRAL_EVASION" level="7" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOWDANCER_WREATH_OF_SHADOWS" level="15" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Shadowstrike" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOWDANCER_SHADOWSTRIKE">
                <description>
                    <p>You can use a bonus action to teleport up to 60 feet through the Plane of Shadow, to an unoccupied space within 5 feet of a creature. You must begin and end this teleport in dim light or darkness.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Dusky motes clinging to your form grant your melee attacks advantage until you attack or are attacked by a different creature, or you move into bright light.</p>
                    <p class="indent">You can use a Spellstrike when you meet the conditions for it. After using your Spellstrike, you must finish a short or long rest to do so again.</p>
                    <p class="indent">When an Order Spellstrike effect requires a saving throw, use your Sigilant spell save DC.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                    <description>You can teleport up to 60 feet through the Plane of Shadow, to an unoccupied space within 5 feet of a creature. You must begin and end this teleport in dim light or darkness. Dusky motes clinging to your form grant your melee attacks advantage until you attack or are attacked by a different creature, or you move into bright light.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Bonus Cantrips" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOWDANCER_BONUS_CANTRIPS">
                <description>
                    <p>You learn minor illusion, plus one wizard cantrip of your choice, which you cast as a Sigilant spell.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MINOR_ILLUSION" spellcasting="Sigilant" level="3" />
                    <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Shadowdancer)" supports="Wizard,0" spellcasting="Sigilant" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Umbral Evasion" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOWDANCER_UMBRAL_EVASION">
                <description>
                    <p>At 7th level, when you are subjected to an effect that allows you to make a Dexterity saving throw to take only half damage, you can use a reaction to evade that effect. You blink momentarily into the Plane of Shadow and take no damage if you succeed on the saving throw, and half damage if you fail.</p>
                    <p class="indent">You can use this ability a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum once), and regain all uses at the end of a long rest.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet action="Reaction" usage="{{umbral-evasion:uses}}/Long Rest">
                    <description>When you are subjected to an effect that allows you to make a Dexterity saving throw to take only half damage, you can evade that effect. You take no damage if you succeed on the saving throw, and half damage if you fail.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="umbral-evasion:uses" value="1" bonus="base" />
                    <stat name="umbral-evasion:uses" value="intelligence:modifier" bonus="base" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Wreath of Shadows" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOWDANCER_WREATH_OF_SHADOWS">
                <description>
                    <p>Beginning at 15th level, you can use an action to become invisible for one minute to all creatures that are currently sigil-marked. If a sigil bursts or dissipates, you become visible to that creature until you activate this feature again.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet action="Action">
                    <description>You become invisible for one minute to all creatures that are currently sigil-marked. If a sigil bursts or dissipates, you become visible to that creature until you activate this feature again.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Shadowdancer Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOWDANCER_SHADOWDANCER_SPELLS">
                <description>
                    <p>You gain access to these spells at the levels specified in the Order description. Once you gain access to a Order spell, you always have it prepared. Order spells don’t count against the number of spells you prepare. If you gain a Order spell that doesn’t appear on the Sigilant spell list, the spell is nonetheless an Sigilant spell for you.</p>
                    <table>
                        <thead>
                            <tr><td>Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                        </thead>
                        <tr><td>3</td><td><i>disguise self</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>5</td><td><i>shadow blade (or blur)</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>9</td><td><i>gaseous form</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>13</td><td><i>shadow conjuration*</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>17</td><td><i>steel wind strike (or seeming)</i></td></tr>
                    </table>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISGUISE_SELF" level="3" spellcrafting="Sigilant" prepared="true" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_SHADOW_BLADE" level="5" spellcrafting="Sigilant" prepared="true" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GASEOUS_FORM" level="9" spellcrafting="Sigilant" prepared="true" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_SPELL_SHADOW_CONJURATION" level="13" spellcrafting="Sigilant" prepared="true" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_STEEL_WIND_STRIKE" level="17" spellcrafting="Sigilant" prepared="true" />
                </rules>
            </element>


        <element name="Warblade" type="Archetype" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_SIGILANT_WARBLADE">
            <supports>Sigilant Order</supports>
            <description>
                <p>Sigilants who prefer power over finesse often choose the path of the Warblade, using heavy plate to ward off blows while smashing their foes with might and magic. A few prefer light armor, using their agility to draw foes close and strike precisely with lighter blades. Warblades are by far the most common Order of Sigilant, drawn to conflict. A single Warblade mercenary can turn the tide of a battle, a force multiplier to his allied side.</p>
                <p class="indent">Many Warblades remain stoically neutral and proudly avoid "distractions" such as good or evil, but some who rise in power shift toward tyranny and cruelty.</p>
                <div element="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARBLADE_RESONANCE_STRIKE" />
                <div element="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARBLADE_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" />
                <div element="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARBLADE_WARBLADE_SPELLS" />
                <div element="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARBLADE_NECRANT_SIGIL" />
                <div element="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARBLADE_MYSTIC_BULWARK" />
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARBLADE_RESONANCE_STRIKE" level="3" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARBLADE_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" level="3" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARBLADE_WARBLADE_SPELLS" level="3" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARBLADE_NECRANT_SIGIL" level="7" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARBLADE_MYSTIC_BULWARK" level="15" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Resonance Strike" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARBLADE_RESONANCE_STRIKE">
                <description>
                    <p>When you hit a creature with a melee attack, you can use a bonus action to cause nearby sigils to resonate with power.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Remove the sigil from every Sigil-marked creature within 30 feet, and each takes damage equal to 2d10 plus your Sigilant level in your sigil's damage type, or half as much on a successful Constitution saving throw.</p>
                    <p class="indent">You can use a Spellstrike when you meet the conditions for it. After using your Spellstrike, you must finish a short or long rest to do so again.</p>
                    <p class="indent">When an Order Spellstrike effect requires a saving throw, use your Sigilant spell save DC.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                    <description>When you hit a creature with a melee attack, you can nearby sigils to resonate with power. Remove the sigil from every Sigil-marked creature within 30 feet, and each takes damage equal to 2d10 plus your Sigilant level in your sigil's damage type, or half as much on a successful Constitution saving throw (save DC {{spellcasting:dc}}).</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Bonus Proficiencies" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARBLADE_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES">
                <description>
                    <p>You gain proficiency with heavy armor and shields.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_HEAVY_ARMOR" />
                    <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_SHIELDS" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Necrant Sigil" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARBLADE_NECRANT_SIGIL">
                <description>
                    <p>At 7th level, you learn to bind sigils to your own life, draining some of the energy from them to yourself.</p>
                    <p class="indent">When you burst a sigil with a melee weapon attack or use your Abjurant Sigil, you regain one hit point for each die of sigil damage or reduction.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>When you burst a sigil with a melee weapon attack or use your Abjurant Sigil, you regain one hit point for each die of sigil damage or reduction.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Mystic Bulwark" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARBLADE_MYSTIC_BULWARK">
                <description>
                    <p>Starting at 15th level, your arcane defense is impenetrable. When you start a Bladecasting, you can expend an additional sigil to apply ablative protective magics.</p>
                    <p class="indent">You gain temporary hit points equal to half your Sigilant level, which are lost when the Bladecasting ends.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>When you start a Bladecasting, you can expend an additional sigil to apply ablative protective magics. You gain {{level:sigilant:half}} temporary hit points, which are lost when Bladecasting ends.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Warblade Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WARBLADE_WARBLADE_SPELLS">
                <description>
                    <p>You gain access to these spells at the levels specified in the Order description. Once you gain access to a Order spell, you always have it prepared. Order spells don’t count against the number of spells you prepare. If you gain a Order spell that doesn’t appear on the Sigilant spell list, the spell is nonetheless an Sigilant spell for you.</p>
                    <table>
                        <thead>
                            <tr><td>Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                        </thead>
                        <tr><td>3</td><td><i>armor of agathys</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>5</td><td><i>ars explosis*</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>9</td><td><i>lightning bolt</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>13</td><td><i>wall of fire</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>17</td><td><i>maelstrom</i></td></tr>
                    </table>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ARMOR_OF_AGATHYS" level="3" spellcrafting="Sigilant" prepared="true" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_SPELL_ARS_EXPLOSIS" level="5" spellcrafting="Sigilant" prepared="true" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LIGHTNING_BOLT" level="9" spellcrafting="Sigilant" prepared="true" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WALL_OF_FIRE" level="13" spellcrafting="Sigilant" prepared="true" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_MAELSTROM" level="17" spellcrafting="Sigilant" prepared="true" />
                </rules>
            </element>


    <!-- Sigilant Specific Spells -->
        <element name="Anchoring Smite" type="Spell" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_SPELL_ANCHORING_SMITE">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
            <description>
                <p>The next time you hit a creature with a weapon attack before this spell ends, your weapon crackles with force, and the attack deals an extra 4d10 force damage to the target. Additionally, the target must make a Charisma save or be affected by an invisible dimensional anchor that completely blocks extradimensional travel, including all forms of teleportation. This anchor lasts for one minute before dissipating, and does not require your concentration.</p>
                <p class="indent">A dimensional anchor does not interfere with the movement of creatures already in ethereal or astral form when the spell is cast, nor does it block extradimensional perception or attack forms. Also, the dimensional anchor does not prevent summoned creatures from disappearing at the end of a summoning spell, though it can block the return of the corporeal form of a demon or other creature that returns to its home plane upon death.</p>
                <p class="indent">If the target is native to a different plane of existence than the one you’re on, the target is unable to willingly return to its home plane. Banishment spells and effects are blocked by the anchor.</p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="keywords"></set>
                <set name="level">4</set>
                <set name="school">Abjuration</set>
                <set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
                <set name="range">Self</set>
                <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
                <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
                <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
                <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
                <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
                <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
        <element name="Ars Abitis" type="Spell" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_SPELL_ARS_ABITIS">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
            <description>
                <p>All sigil-marked enemies within range must make a Strength saving throw or be pushed away from you 10 feet.</p>
                <p class="indent">At higher levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the push effect increases by 5 feet for each slot above 1st.</p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="keywords"></set>
                <set name="level">1</set>
                <set name="school">Abjuration</set>
                <set name="time">1 action</set>
                <set name="range">30 feet</set>
                <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
                <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
                <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
                <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
                <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
                <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
        <element name="Ars Explosis" type="Spell" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_SPELL_ARS_EXPLOSIS">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
            <description>
                <p>Remove a sigil from an enemy within 30 feet. Each creature within 10’ of the target must make a Dexterity saving throw. It takes 3d8 damage in the type of the sigil on a failure, or half damage on a success.</p>
                <p class="indent">At higher levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, you can choose an additional target for each slot above 2nd. A creature takes damage from this spell only once per casting.</p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="keywords"></set>
                <set name="level">2</set>
                <set name="school">Evocation</set>
                <set name="time">1 action</set>
                <set name="range">60 feet</set>
                <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
                <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
                <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
                <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
                <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
                <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
        <element name="Ars Infuris" type="Spell" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_SPELL_ARS_INFURIS">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
            <description>
                <p>A sigil-marked creature within range must succeed on a Charisma saving throw, or every creature adjacent to that creature can use their reaction to make a melee weapon attack against it.</p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="keywords"></set>
                <set name="level">2</set>
                <set name="school">Enchantment</set>
                <set name="time">1 action</set>
                <set name="range">30 feet</set>
                <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
                <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
                <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
                <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
                <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
                <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
        <element name="Ars Iteritas" type="Spell" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_SPELL_ARS_ITERATIS">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
            <description>
                <p>Place a sigil on creatures of your choice within range.</p>
                <p class="indent">At higher levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th or 5th level, the spell range increases by 15 feet for each slot above 3rd.</p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="keywords"></set>
                <set name="level">3</set>
                <set name="school">Evocation</set>
                <set name="time">1 action</set>
                <set name="range">30 feet</set>
                <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
                <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
                <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
                <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
                <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
        <element name="Ars Rejuvis" type="Spell" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_SPELL_ARS_REJUVIS">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
            <description>
                <p>Your enemies’ life force restores your allies’ health. Until the end of your next turn, when an ally makes a successful melee weapon attack against a sigil-marked enemy within range, they regain hit points equal to your spellcasting modifier (minimum 1). This does not burst the sigil.</p>
                <p class="indent">At higher levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the spell heals 1d6 additional damage for each slot above 2nd.</p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="keywords"></set>
                <set name="level">2</set>
                <set name="school">Necromancy</set>
                <set name="time">1 action</set>
                <set name="range">30 feet</set>
                <set name="duration">Until the end of your next turn</set>
                <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
                <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
                <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
                <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
                <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
        <element name="Ars Ultima" type="Spell" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_SPELL_ARS_ULTIMA">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
            <description>
                <p>Remove all sigils on all enemies within 30 feet. Each of those enemies must make a Charisma save or suffer 8d10 damage of your sigil’s damage type on a failed save, half as much on a successful save.</p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="keywords"></set>
                <set name="level">5</set>
                <set name="school">Evocation</set>
                <set name="time">1 action</set>
                <set name="range">30 feet</set>
                <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
                <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
                <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
                <set name="materialComponent">a weapon</set>
                <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
                <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
        <element name="Elemental Edge" type="Spell" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_SPELL_ELEMENTAL_EDGE">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
            <description>
                <p>You touch a nonmagical weapon and choose one of the following damage types: acid, cold, fire, lightning, or thunder. For the duration, the weapon has a +1d4 bonus to damage rolls and deals all of its damage in the chosen damage type.</p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="keywords"></set>
                <set name="level">1</set>
                <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
                <set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
                <set name="range">Touch</set>
                <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
                <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
                <set name="materialComponent">a non-magical weapon</set>
                <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
                <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
        <element name="Shadow Conjuration" type="Spell" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_SPELL_SHADOW_CONJURATION">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
            <description>
                <p>You summon a deadly shadow to serve you in combat. This shadow has the statistics of a shadow demon (MM pg.64), but is bound to serve you. It appears in an empty space of your choice within 30 feet and disappears when it drops to 0 hit points or you lose concentration. The spell fails if the area is brightly lit.</p>
                <p class="indent">Roll initiative for the shadow. When you summon it, and on each of your turns, you can issue a verbal command for its next turn without using any action. If you issue no command, it attacks any creature in reach that has attacked it.</p>
                <p class="indent">The shadow loses 4 hit points if it enters or begins its turn in an area of dim light, or 10 in an area of bright light. It can lose no more than 10 hit points per round in this manner.</p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="keywords"></set>
                <set name="level">4</set>
                <set name="school">Conjuration</set>
                <set name="time">1 action</set>
                <set name="range">see text</set>
                <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 10 minutes</set>
                <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
                <set name="materialComponent">an unlit candle</set>
                <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
                <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
        <element name="Stalking Blade" type="Spell" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RSQUARED_GM_BINDER_SPELL_STALKING_BLADE">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
            <description>
                <p>As part of the action used to cast this spell, you must make a melee attack with a weapon against a hostile creature within that weapon’s reach. Otherwise, the spell fails. On a hit, the target suffers the attack’s normal effects, and you place an invisible, magical tag upon that creature that lasts for one minute. If the creature teleports from a place you can see while the tag is active, you can use your reaction to siphon off some of the energy, teleporting yourself simultaneously to an unoccupied space within 5 feet of the target’s new location as the target takes 2d6 force damage from magical feedback.</p>
                <p class="indent">The spell’s damage increases when you reach higher levels. At 5th level, the melee attack deals an extra 1d8 force damage to the target, and the damage the target takes for teleporting increases to 3d6. Both damage rolls increase by an additional die at 11th level and 17th level.</p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="keywords"></set>
                <set name="level">0</set>
                <set name="school">Divination</set>
                <set name="time">1 action</set>
                <set name="range">Self</set>
                <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
                <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
                <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
                <set name="materialComponent">a weapon you’re proficient with</set>
                <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
                <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            </setters>
        </element>

    <!-- add spells to Sigilant list -->
      <!-- 1st level -->
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ABSORB_ELEMENTS">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ALARM">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BANE">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_CAUSE_FEAR">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMMAND">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMPREHEND_LANGUAGES">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_MAGIC">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FEATHER_FALL">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FOG_CLOUD">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ILLUSORY_SCRIPT">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LONGSTRIDER">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SEARING_SMITE">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHIELD">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SILENT_IMAGE">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_THUNDERWAVE">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_THUNDEROUS_SMITE">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ZEPHYR_STRIKE">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>

      <!-- 2nd level -->
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ALTER_SELF">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLINDNESS_DEAFNESS">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLUR">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BRANDING_SMITE">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DARKNESS">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENHANCE_ABILITY">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HOLD_PERSON">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INVISIBILITY">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LOCATE_OBJECT">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MIRROR_IMAGE">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGIC_WEAPON">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MISTY_STEP">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SEE_INVISIBILITY">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SILENCE">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPIDER_CLIMB">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>

      <!-- 3rd level -->
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BESTOW_CURSE">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLINDING_SMITE">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLINK">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISPEL_MAGIC">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ELEMENTAL_WEAPON">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FLY">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GLYPH_OF_WARDING">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HASTE">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGIC_CIRCLE">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_NONDETECTION">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PHANTOM_STEED">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_REMOVE_CURSE">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SENDING">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SLOW">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_VAMPIRIC_TOUCH">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>

      <!-- 4th level -->
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ARCANE_EYE">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BANISHMENT">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMPULSION">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONFUSION">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DIMENSION_DOOR">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ELEMENTAL_BANE">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FREEDOM_OF_MOVEMENT">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GREATER_INVISIBILITY">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HALLUCINATORY_TERRAIN">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LOCATE_CREATURE">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_STAGGERING_SMITE">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>

      <!-- 5th level -->
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BANISHING_SMITE">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CIRCLE_OF_POWER">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONJURE_ELEMENTAL">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DOMINATE_PERSON">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HOLD_MONSTER">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MODIFY_MEMORY">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PASSWALL">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TELEKINESIS">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WALL_OF_FORCE">
            <supports>Sigilant</supports>
        </append>


</elements>