<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Feral Ranger 2021 update</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="class-feral-ranger.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/classes/class-feral-ranger.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="The Feral Ranger" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_LEUKU_GMBINDER_SOURCE_The Feral Ranger">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation">TFR</set>
            <set name="url">https://www.gmbinder.com/share/-LLZ9c0h7nVx6eaPvHJO</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" abbreviation="LEUKU" url="https://www.gmbinder.com/profile/leuku">Leuku</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20210215</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Feral Ranger" type="Class" source="The Feral Ranger" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FERAL_RANGER">
        <description>
			<p class="flavor">A warrior who uses martial prowess and nature magic to combat threats on the edges of civilization.</p>			
			<p>Rough and wild looking, a human stalks alone through the shadows of trees, hunting the orcs he knows are planning a raid on a nearby farm. Clutching a shortsword in each hand, he becomes a whirlwind of steel, cutting down one enemy after another.</p>
			<p class="indent">After tumbling away from a cone of freezing air, an elf finds her feet and draws back her bow to loose an arrow at the white dragon. Shrugging off the wave of fear that emanates from the dragon like the cold of its breath, she sends one arrow after another to find the gaps between the dragon’s thick scales.</p>
			<p class="indent">Holding his hand high, a half-elf whistles to the hawk that circles high above him, calling the bird back to his side. Whispering instructions in Elvish, he points to the owlbear he’s been tracking and sends the hawk to distract the creature while he readies his bow.</p>
			<p class="indent">Far from the bustle of cities and towns, past the hedges that shelter the most distant farms from the terrors of the wild, amid the dense-packed trees of trackless forests and across wide and empty plains, rangers keep their unending watch.</p>
			<h4>DEADLY HUNTERS</h4>
			<p>Warriors of the wilderness, rangers specialize in hunting the monsters that threaten the edges of civilization—humanoid raiders, rampaging beasts and monstrosities, terrible giants, and deadly dragons. They learn to track their quarry as a predator does, moving stealthily through the wilds and hiding themselves in brush and rubble. Rangers focus their combat training on techniques that are particularly useful against their specific favored foes.</p>
			<p class="indent">Thanks to their familiarity with the wilds, rangers acquire the ability to cast spells that harness nature’s power, much as a druid does. Their spells, like their combat abilities, emphasize speed, stealth, and the hunt. A ranger’s talents and abilities are honed with deadly focus on the grim task of protecting the borderlands.</p>
			<h4>INDEPENDENT ADVENTURERS</h4>
			<p>Though a ranger might make a living as a hunter, a guide, or a tracker, a ranger’s true calling is to defend the outskirts of civilization from the ravages of monsters and humanoid hordes that press in from the wild. In some places, rangers gather in secretive orders or join forces with druidic circles. Many rangers, though, are independent almost to a fault, knowing that, when a dragon or a band of orcs attacks, a ranger might be the first—and possibly the last—line of defense.</p>
			<p class="indent">This fierce independence makes rangers well suited to adventuring, since they are accustomed to life far from the comforts of a dry bed and a hot bath. Faced with city-bred adventurers who grouse and whine about the hardships of the wild, rangers respond with some mixture of amusement, frustration, and compassion. But they quickly learn that other adventurers who can carry their own weight in a fight against civilization’s foes are worth any extra burden. Coddled city folk might not know how to feed themselves or find fresh water in the wild, but they make up for it in other ways.</p>
			<h4>CREATING A RANGER</h4>
			<p>As you create your ranger character, consider the nature of the training that gave you your particular capabilities. Did you train with a single mentor, wandering the wilds together until you mastered the ranger’s ways? Did you leave your apprenticeship, or was your mentor slain— perhaps by the same kind of monster that became your favored enemy? Or perhaps you learned your skills as part of a band of rangers affiliated with a druidic circle, trained in mystic paths as well as wilderness lore. You might be self-taught, a recluse who learned combat skills, tracking, and even a magical connection to nature through the necessity of surviving in the wilds.</p>
			<p class="indent">What’s the source of your particular hatred of a certain kind of enemy? Did a monster kill someone you loved or destroy your home village? Or did you see too much of the destruction these monsters cause and commit yourself to reining in their depredations? Is your adventuring career a continuation of your work in protecting the borderlands, or a significant change? What made you join up with a band of adventurers? Do you find it challenging to teach new allies the ways of the wild, or do you welcome the relief from solitude that they offer?</p>
            <h5>QUICK BUILD</h5>
            <p>You can make a feral ranger quickly by following these suggestions. First, make Dexterity your highest ability score, followed by Wisdom. Second, choose the outlander background.</p>
            <h2>CLASS FEATURES</h2>
            <p>As a feral ranger, you gain the following class features.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">HIT POINTS</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Hit Dice:</strong> 1d10 per feral ranger level</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at 1st Level:</strong> 10 + your Constitution modifier</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at Higher Levels:</strong> 1d10 (or 6) + your Constitution modifier per feral ranger level after 1st</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">PROFICIENCIES</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled mb">
                <li><strong>Armor:</strong> Light armor, Medium armor, shields</li>
                <li><strong>Weapons:</strong> Simple weapons, martial weapons</li>
                <li><strong>Tools:</strong> Herbalism Kit</li>
            </ul>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Saving Throws:</strong> Strength, Dexterity</li>
                <li><strong>Skills:</strong> Choose three from Animal Handling, Acrobatics, Athletics, Insight, Investigation, Medicine, Nature, Perception, Survival and Stealth</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">EQUIPMENT</h5>
            <p>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>(a) scale mail or (b) leather armor</li>
                <li>(a) two short swords or (b) two simple melee weapons</li>
                <li>(a) a dungeoneer’s pack or (b) an explorer’s pack</li>
                <li>a longbow, a quiver of 20 arrows, and an herbalism kit</li>
            </ul>
            <h5>STARTING EQUIPMENT</h5>
            <p>When you create a feral ranger, you can start with 4d4 x 10 gp instead of receiving the equipment from your class and background.</p>
        <!-- class table here -->
            <h5 class="caption">THE FERAL RANGER</h5>
            <table class="class-features">
                <thead>
                    <tr><td class="col-5">Level</td><td class="col-10">Proficiency Bonus</td><td class="left">Features</td><td class="col-10">Hunter’s Quarry</td><td>1st</td><td>2nd</td><td>3rd</td><td>4th</td><td>5th</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td> 1st</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Hunter’s Quarry, Adept Explorer</td><td>1</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 2nd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Fighting Style, Spellcasting, Ferocity</td><td>1</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 3rd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Ranger Fable</td><td>2</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 4th</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>2</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 5th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Hunter’s Focus, Extra Attack</td><td>2</td><td>4</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 6th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Adept Explorer, Keen Senses</td><td>3</td><td>4</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 7th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Ranger Fable Feature</td><td>3</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 8th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>3</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 9th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">—</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>10th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Adept Explorer, Primal Resilience</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>11th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Savagery, Ranger Fable Feature</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>12th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">─</td><td>5</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>1</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>14th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Beastly Fortitude</td><td>5</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>1</td><td>─</td></tr>
                <tr><td>15th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Ranger Fable Feature</td><td>5</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>─</td></tr>
                <tr><td>16th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>5</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>─</td></tr>
                <tr><td>17th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">─</td><td>6</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>1</td></tr>
                <tr><td>18th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Bewildering Assault</td><td>6</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>1</td></tr>
                <tr><td>19th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>6</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td></tr>
                <tr><td>20th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Apex Predator</td><td>6</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_HUNTERS_QUARRY" />
            <div element="ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_ADEPT_EXPLORER" />
            <div element="ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_FIGHTING_STYLE" />
            <div element="ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_SPELLCASTING" />
            <div element="ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_FEROCITY" />
            <div element="ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_RANGER_FABLE" />
            <div element="ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" />
            <div element="ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_HUNTERS_FOCUS" />
            <div element="ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_EXTRA_ATTACK" />
            <div element="ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_KEEN_SENSES" />
            <div element="ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_PRIMAL_RESILIENCE" />
            <div element="ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_SAVAGERY" />
            <div element="ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_BEASTLY_FORTITUDE" />
            <div element="ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_BEWILDERING_ASSAULT" />
            <div element="ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_APEX_PREDATOR" />
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="hd">d10</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_MEDIUM_ARMOR" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_SHIELDS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_MARTIAL_WEAPONS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_HERBALISM_KIT" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_STRENGTH" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_DEXTERITY" />
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency, Ranger" supports="Skill, Feral Ranger" number="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_HUNTERS_QUARRY" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_ADEPT_EXPLORER" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_FIGHTING_STYLE" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_SPELLCASTING" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_FEROCITY" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_RANGER_FABLE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" level="4" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_HUNTERS_FOCUS" level="5" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_EXTRA_ATTACK" level="5" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_KEEN_SENSES" level="6" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_PRIMAL_RESILIENCE" level="10" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_SAVAGERY" level="11" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_BEASTLY_FORTITUDE" level="14" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_BEWILDERING_ASSAULT" level="18" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_APEX_PREDATOR" level="20" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Hunter’s Quarry" type="Class Feature" source="The Feral Ranger" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_HUNTERS_QUARRY">
            <description>
                <p>Life on the periphery has given you a sense for the wild danger that lurks in others. Seeing how a creature reacts to an attack, or even a strong whiff of their scent, is enough to teach you of the strength a creature possesses.</p>
                <p class="indent">A 1st level, when you make a weapon attack against a creature, or you take the Search action against a creature within 30 feet of you, the DM tells you if the creature is your equal, superior, or inferior in regards to 1 of the following characteristics:</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Stronger.</b> Maximum Hit Points</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Tougher.</b> Armor Class</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Faster.</b> Largest Movement Speed</p>
                <p class="indent">When you learn all 3 of these characteristics about the creature, you can add its creature type to your Hunter’s Quarry list. Alternatively, you can add a creature’s type to your Hunter’s Quarry list by examining it over the course of 1 hour if it has died within the last 24 hours. If the creature’s type is humanoid, you must choose its race of humanoid (such as gnoll or orc).</p>
                <p class="indent">You can have one creature type on your Hunter’s Quarry list. This increases by 1 at 3rd (2), 6th (3), 9th (4), 13th (5), and 17th level (6). When you add a creature type to your list in excess of this number, you must replace a creature type of your choice on your list with it.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you make a weapon attack against a creature, or you take the Search action against a creature within 30 feet of you, the DM tells you if the creature is your equal, superior, or inferior in regards to 1 of the following characteristics: Stronger, Tougher, or Faster. When you learn all 3 of these characteristics about the creature, you can add its creature type to your Hunter’s Quarry list. Alternatively, you can add a creature’s type to your Hunter’s Quarry list by examining it over the course of 1 hour if it has died within the last 24 hours. You can have up to {{hunters-quarry:max}} creatures on your list.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="hunters-quarry:max" value="1" level="1" />
                <stat name="hunters-quarry:max" value="1" level="3" />
                <stat name="hunters-quarry:max" value="1" level="6" />
                <stat name="hunters-quarry:max" value="1" level="9" />
                <stat name="hunters-quarry:max" value="1" level="13" />
                <stat name="hunters-quarry:max" value="1" level="17" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Adept Explorer" type="Class Feature" source="The Feral Ranger" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_ADEPT_EXPLORER">
            <description>
                <p>You are an unsurpassed explorer and survivor. At 1st level, choose one of the following benefits. At 6th and 10th level, you can choose the same or different benefit. When you choose the same benefit, you gain an improved version of that benefit.</p>
                <h5>CANNY</h5>
                <p>Choose one skill you are proficient in. You can add double your proficiency bonus to ability checks using it. In addition, thanks to your extensive wandering, you are able to speak, read, and write one language of your choice.</p>
                <p class="indent">Each time you choose this benefit again, you can apply this benefit to another skill you are proficient in and another language.</p>
                <h5>ROVING</h5>
                <p>Your walking speed increases by 5, and you gain a climbing speed and a swimming speed equal to your walking speed.</p>
                <p class="indent">Each time you choose this benefit again, your walking speed increases by another 5 feet.</p>
                <h5>TIRELESS</h5>
                <p>Whenever you finish a long rest, you regain 1 additional hit die. You can have no more than 1 + your maximum number of hit dice in this way.</p>
                <p class="indent">Each time you choose this benefit again, the number of hit dice regained increases by 1.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false" />
            <rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Adept Explorer Feature" supports="Feral Ranger Adept Explorer" level="1" /> 
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Adept Explorer Feature" supports="Feral Ranger Adept Explorer" level="6" /> 
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Adept Explorer Feature" supports="Feral Ranger Adept Explorer" level="10" /> 
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Canny" type="Class Feature" source="The Feral Ranger" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_ADEPT_EXPLORER_CANNY1">
                <supports>Feral Ranger Adept Explorer</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>Choose one skill you are proficient in. You can add double your proficiency bonus to ability checks using it. In addition, thanks to your extensive wandering, you are able to speak, read, and write one language of your choice.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Each time you choose this benefit again, you can apply this benefit to another skill you are proficient in and another language.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false" />
                <rules>
                    <select type="Class Feature" name="Skill Proficiency, Canny" supports="Skill,Expertise" />
                    <select type="Language" name="Language, Canny" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Canny" type="Class Feature" source="The Feral Ranger" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_ADEPT_EXPLORER_CANNY2">
                <supports>Feral Ranger Adept Explorer</supports>
                <requirements>ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_ADEPT_EXPLORER_CANNY1</requirements>
                <description>
                    <p>Choose one skill you are proficient in. You can add double your proficiency bonus to ability checks using it. In addition, thanks to your extensive wandering, you are able to speak, read, and write one language of your choice.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Each time you choose this benefit again, you can apply this benefit to another skill you are proficient in and another language.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false" />
                <rules>
                    <select type="Class Feature" name="Skill Proficiency, Canny" supports="Skill,Expertise" />
                    <select type="Language" name="Language, Canny" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Canny" type="Class Feature" source="The Feral Ranger" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_ADEPT_EXPLORER_CANNY3">
                <supports>Feral Ranger Adept Explorer</supports>
                <requirements>ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_ADEPT_EXPLORER_CANNY2</requirements>
                <description>
                    <p>Choose one skill you are proficient in. You can add double your proficiency bonus to ability checks using it. In addition, thanks to your extensive wandering, you are able to speak, read, and write one language of your choice.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false" />
                <rules>
                    <select type="Class Feature" name="Skill Proficiency, Canny" supports="Skill,Expertise" />
                    <select type="Language" name="Language, Canny" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Roving" type="Class Feature" source="The Feral Ranger" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_ADEPT_EXPLORER_ROVING1">
                <supports>Feral Ranger Adept Explorer</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>Your walking speed increases by 5, and you gain a climbing speed and a swimming speed equal to your walking speed.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Each time you choose this benefit again, your walking speed increases by another 5 feet.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false" />
                <rules>
                    <stat name="innate speed:misc" value="5" />
                    <stat name="speed:climb" value="speed" bonus="base" />
                    <stat name="speed:swim" value="speed" bonus="base" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Roving" type="Class Feature" source="The Feral Ranger" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_ADEPT_EXPLORER_ROVING2">
                <supports>Feral Ranger Adept Explorer</supports>
                <requirements>ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_ADEPT_EXPLORER_ROVING1</requirements>
                <description>
                    <p>Your walking speed increases by 5, and you gain a climbing speed and a swimming speed equal to your walking speed.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Each time you choose this benefit again, your walking speed increases by another 5 feet.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false" />
                <rules>
                    <stat name="innate speed:misc" value="5" />
                    <stat name="speed:climb" value="speed" bonus="base" />
                    <stat name="speed:swim" value="speed" bonus="base" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Roving" type="Class Feature" source="The Feral Ranger" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_ADEPT_EXPLORER_ROVING3">
                <supports>Feral Ranger Adept Explorer</supports>
                <requirements>ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_ADEPT_EXPLORER_ROVING2</requirements>
                <description>
                    <p>Your walking speed increases by 5, and you gain a climbing speed and a swimming speed equal to your walking speed.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false" />
                <rules>
                    <stat name="innate speed:misc" value="5" />
                    <stat name="speed:climb" value="speed" bonus="base" />
                    <stat name="speed:swim" value="speed" bonus="base" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Tireless" type="Class Feature" source="The Feral Ranger" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_ADEPT_EXPLORER_TIRELESS1">
                <supports>Feral Ranger Adept Explorer</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>Whenever you finish a long rest, you regain 1 additional hit die. You can have no more than 1 + your maximum number of hit dice in this way.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Each time you choose this benefit again, the number of hit dice regained increases by 1.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>Whenever you finish a long rest, you regain {{tireless:hit-dice}} additional hit die. You can have no more than 1 + your maximum number of hit dice in this way.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="tireless:hit-dice" value="1" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Tireless" type="Class Feature" source="The Feral Ranger" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_ADEPT_EXPLORER_TIRELESS2">
                <supports>Feral Ranger Adept Explorer</supports>
                <requirements>ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_ADEPT_EXPLORER_TIRELESS1</requirements>
                <description>
                    <p>Whenever you finish a long rest, you regain 1 additional hit die. You can have no more than 1 + your maximum number of hit dice in this way.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Each time you choose this benefit again, the number of hit dice regained increases by 1.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false" />
                <rules>
                    <stat name="tireless:hit-dice" value="1" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Tireless" type="Class Feature" source="The Feral Ranger" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_ADEPT_EXPLORER_TIRELESS3">
                <supports>Feral Ranger Adept Explorer</supports>
                <requirements>ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_ADEPT_EXPLORER_TIRELESS2</requirements>
                <description>
                    <p>Whenever you finish a long rest, you regain 1 additional hit die. You can have no more than 1 + your maximum number of hit dice in this way.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false" />
                <rules>
                    <stat name="tireless:hit-dice" value="1" />
                </rules>
            </element>
        <element name="Fighting Style" type="Class Feature" source="The Feral Ranger" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_FIGHTING_STYLE">
            <description>
                <p>At 2nd level, you adopt a particular style of fighting as your specialty. Choose one of the following options. You can’t take a Fighting Style option more than once, even if you later get to choose again.</p>
                <h5>ARCHERY</h5>
                <p>You gain a +2 bonus to attack rolls you make with ranged weapons.</p>
                <h5>DEFENSE</h5>
                <p>While you are wearing armor, you gain a	+1 bonus to AC.</p>
                <h5>DUELING</h5>
                <p>When you are wielding a melee weapon in one hand and no other Weapons, you gain a +2 bonus to Damage Rolls with that weapon.</p>
                <h5>TWO WEAPON FIGHTING</h5>
                <p>When you engage in two-weapon fighting, you can add your ability modifier to the damage of the second Attack.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Fighting Style" supports="Fighting Style, Feral Ranger" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Spellcasting" type="Class Feature" source="The Feral Ranger" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_SPELLCASTING">
            <description>
                <p>By the time you reach 2nd level, you have learned to use the magical essence of Nature to cast Spells, as a druid does.</p>
                <h5>PREPARING AND CASTING SPELLS</h5>
                <p>The feral ranger table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your spells of 1st level and higher. To cast one of these spells, you must expend a slot of the spell’s level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.</p>
                <p class="indent">You prepare the list of feral ranger spells that are available for you to cast, choosing from the feral ranger spell list. When you do so, choose a number of feral ranger spells equal to your Wisdom modifier + half your feral ranger level, rounded down (minimum of one spell). The spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots.</p>
                <p class="indent">For example, if you are a 5th-level feral ranger, you have four 1st-level and two 2nd-level spell slots. With a Wisdom of 14, your list of prepared spells can include four spells of 1st or 2nd level, in any combination. If you prepare the 1st-level spell <i>animal friendship</i>, you can cast it using a 1st-level or a 2nd-level slot. Casting the spell doesn’t remove it from your list of prepared spells.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can change your list of prepared spells when you finish a long rest. Preparing a new list of feral ranger spells requires time spent embracing the wild within: at least 1 minute per spell Level for each spell on your list.</p>
                <h5>SPELLCASTING ABILITY</h5>
                <p>Wisdom is your Spellcasting ability for your feral ranger spells, since your magic draws on your attunement to nature. You use your Wisdom whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Wisdom modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a feral ranger spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.</p>
                <p style="text-align: center;"><b>Spell save DC</b> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier</p>
                <p style="text-align: center;"><b>Spell attack modifier</b> = your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false" />
            <spellcasting name="Feral Ranger" ability="Wisdom" prepare="true">
                <list known="true">Ranger</list>
            </spellcasting>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS_SPELLCASTING_SLOTS_HALF" requirements="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS"/>
                <stat name="feral ranger:spellcasting:slots:1" value="2" level="2" />
                <stat name="feral ranger:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="3" />
                <stat name="feral ranger:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="5" />
                <stat name="feral ranger:spellcasting:slots:2" value="2" level="5" />
                <stat name="feral ranger:spellcasting:slots:2" value="1" level="7" />
                <stat name="feral ranger:spellcasting:slots:3" value="2" level="9" />
                <stat name="feral ranger:spellcasting:slots:3" value="1" level="11" />
                <stat name="feral ranger:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="13" />
                <stat name="feral ranger:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="15" />
                <stat name="feral ranger:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="17" />
                <stat name="feral ranger:spellcasting:slots:5" value="1" level="17" />
                <stat name="feral ranger:spellcasting:slots:5" value="1" level="19" />
                <stat name="feral ranger:spellcasting:prepare" value="wisdom:modifier" />
                <stat name="feral ranger:spellcasting:prepare" value="level:feral ranger:half" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Ferocity" type="Class Feature" source="The Feral Ranger" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_FEROCITY">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 2nd level, once on each of your turns when you take the Attack Action, you can expend a feral ranger spell slot to make an additional weapon attack. If you expend a feral ranger spell slot of at least 3rd level, you make two additional weapon attacks instead. If you expend a spell slot of at least 5th level, three weapon attacks.</p>
                <p class="indent">In addition, you can use this feature to make a single weapon attack without expending a feral ranger spell slot a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier. You regain expended uses at the end of a long rest.</p>
                <p class="indent">If the target is one of your hunter’s quarries, you have advantage on these attacks.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="{{wisdom:modifier}}/Long Rest">
                <description>Once on each of your turns when you take the Attack Action, you can use this feature to make a single weapon attack without expending a feral ranger spell slot. You can expend a feral ranger spell slot to make an additional weapon attack. If the target is one of your hunter’s quarries, you have advantage on these attacks.</description>
                <description level="9">Once on each of your turns when you take the Attack Action, you can use this feature to make a single weapon attack without expending a feral ranger spell slot. You can expend a feral ranger spell slot to make an additional weapon attack. If you expend a spell slot of at least 5th level, three weapon attacks. If the target is one of your hunter’s quarries, you have advantage on these attacks.</description>
                <description level="17">Once on each of your turns when you take the Attack Action, you can use this feature to make a single weapon attack without expending a feral ranger spell slot. You can expend a feral ranger spell slot to make an additional weapon attack. If you expend a spell slot of at least 5th level, three weapon attacks. If you expend a spell slot of at least 5th level, three weapon attacks. If the target is one of your hunter’s quarries, you have advantage on these attacks.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Ranger Fable" type="Class Feature" source="The Feral Ranger" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_RANGER_FABLE">
            <description>
                <p>Ranger traditions are passed down through tales of legends old. Their origins have long passed from feeble memory, so only fables of their great and terrible deeds remain. Yet story is often inspiration enough for a young adventurer to enter deep into the woods and emerge a Ranger.</p>
                <p class="indent">At 3rd level, choose either the Hunted, Nightmare, or Horizon Walker Fable. Your choice grants features at 3rd level, and again at 7th, 11th, and 15th level.</p>
                <h5>FABLE SPELLS</h5>
                <p>Each fable has a list of spells - its fable spells - that you gain at the feral ranger levels noted in the fable description. Once you gain a fable spell, you always have it prepared, and it doesn’t count against the number of Spells you can prepare each day.</p>
                <p class="indent">If you have a fable spell that doesn’t appear on the feral ranger spell list, the spell is nonetheless a feral ranger spell for you.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false" />
            <rules>
                <select type="Archetype" name="Ranger Fable" supports="Feral Ranger Fable" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Ability Score Improvement" type="Class Feature" source="The Feral Ranger" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two Ability Scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false" />
            <rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Feral Ranger 4)" supports="Improvement Option,Feral Ranger,4" level="4" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Feral Ranger 8)" supports="Improvement Option,Feral Ranger,8" level="8" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Feral Ranger 12)" supports="Improvement Option,Feral Ranger,12" level="12" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Feral Ranger 16)" supports="Improvement Option,Feral Ranger,16" level="16" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Feral Ranger 19)" supports="Improvement Option,Feral Ranger,19" level="19" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Hunter’s Focus" type="Class Feature" source="The Feral Ranger" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_HUNTERS_FOCUS">
            <description>
                <p>At 5th level, you can as an action add to your Hunter’s Quarry list a type of creature you can see within 60 feet of you. This addition lasts for 1 minute and does not count against the number of creature types you can have on your list. When you do so, you can as a bonus action make a single weapon attack against that creature.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can use this feature a number of times equal to 1 + your Wisdom modifier (minimum 1). You regain all expended uses after a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="{{hunters-focus:uses}}/Long Rest">
                <description>You add to your Hunter’s Quarry list a type of creature you can see within 60 feet of you. This addition lasts for 1 minute and does not count against the number of creature types you can have on your list. When you do so, you can as a bonus action make a single weapon attack against that creature.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="hunters-focus:uses" value="1" />
                <stat name="hunters-focus:uses" value="wisdom:modifier" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Extra Attack" type="Class Feature" source="The Feral Ranger" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_EXTRA_ATTACK">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 5th level, you can Attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can Attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="extra attack:count" value="2" level="5" bonus="extra attack" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Keen Senses" type="Class Feature" source="The Feral Ranger" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_KEEN_SENSES">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, you can as a bonus action concentrate to heighten your senses. For as long as you maintain concentration, you have advantage on Wisdom checks that rely on hearing, smell, sight, touch, and taste.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>You concentrate to heighten your senses. For as long as you maintain concentration, you have advantage on Wisdom checks that rely on hearing, smell, sight, touch, and taste.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Primal Resilience" type="Class Feature" source="The Feral Ranger" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_PRIMAL_RESILIENCE">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 10th level, you recover stamina at an accelerated rate. Whenever you expend a hit die to regain hit points, you can add your Wisdom modifier to the hit points gained.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Whenever you expend a hit die to regain hit points, you add {{wisdom:modifier}} to the hit points gained.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Savagery" type="Class Feature" source="The Feral Ranger" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_SAVAGERY">
            <description>
                <p>By 11th level, your fierceness with weapons knows no equal. Once on each of your turns, when you make three or more weapon attacks against the same target, you can make one more weapon attack against the same target.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Once on each of your turns, when you make three or more weapon attacks against the same target, you can make one more weapon attack against the same target.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Beastly Fortitude" type="Class Feature" source="The Feral Ranger" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_BEASTLY_FORTITUDE">
            <description>
                <p>At 14th level, you can add your Wisdom modifier to Strength, Dexterity, and Constitution saving throws.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="strength:save:misc" value="wisdom:modifier" bonus="beastly fortitude" />
                <stat name="dexterity:save:misc" value="wisdom:modifier" bonus="beastly fortitude" />
                <stat name="constitution:save:misc" value="wisdom:modifier" bonus="beastly fortitude" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Bewildering Assault" type="Class Feature" source="The Feral Ranger" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_BEWILDERING_ASSAULT">
            <description>
                <p>At 18th level, your opening strikes bewilder your prey, stripping them of their initiative. On your first turn in combat, when you hit a creature that has yet to take a turn in combat with a weapon attack, it must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw against your spell save DC or become surprised until the end of their first turn. A creature immune to the surprised condition is immune to this ability.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>On your first turn in combat, when you hit a creature that has yet to take a turn in combat with a weapon attack, it must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw (DC {{spellcasting:dc:wis}}) or become surprised until the end of their first turn.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Apex Predator" type="Class Feature" source="The Feral Ranger" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_CLASS_FEATURE_FERAL_RANGER_APEX_PREDATOR">
            <description>
                <p>By 20th level, you become a hunter of unparalleled dominance and your prey tremble in your presence. Your Hunter’s Quarries have disadvantage on attacks against you and on saving throws against your spells and abilities.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Your Hunter’s Quarries have disadvantage on attacks against you and on saving throws against your spells and abilities.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>

    <element name="Hunter Fable" type="Archetype" source="The Feral Ranger" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FERAL_RANGER_HUNTER_FABLE">
        <supports>Feral Ranger Fable</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Some rangers seek to master weapons to better protect civilization from the terrors of the wilderness. Members of the Hunter Fable learn specialized fighting techniques for use against the most dire threats, from rampaging ogres and hordes of orcs to towering giants and terrifying dragons.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">Hunter Fable Spells</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Ranger level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>hunter’s mark</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>find traps</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>9th</td><td><em>speak with plants</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td><em>locate creature</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>17th</td><td><em>hold monster</em></td></tr>
            </table>
            <h5 class="caption">Hunter Fable Quirks</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d6</td><td>Quirks</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>To you, the hunt is a sacred practice with rites, rituals, and obligations. You have disdain for those who would defile it with petty self-pleasures</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>You use antlers in all of your decorating</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>You feel that especially strong and cunning prey deserve to be chased again another day</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>When the wind blows, you cannot help but comment on how it howls</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>You hunt to conserve animalkind and educate people about them</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>You live by the adage "Some may never live, but the crazy never die"</td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTER_FABLE_HUNTERS_PREY" />
            <div element="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTER_FABLE_DEFENSIVE_TACTICS" />
            <div element="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTER_FABLE_WEAPON_TEMPEST" />
            <div element="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTER_FABLE_SUPERIOR_HUNTERS_DEFENSE" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HUNTERS_MARK" spellcasting="Feral Ranger" prepared="true" level="3" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIND_TRAPS" spellcasting="Feral Ranger" prepared="true" level="5" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_PLANTS" spellcasting="Feral Ranger" prepared="true" level="9" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LOCATE_CREATURE" spellcasting="Feral Ranger" prepared="true" level="13" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HOLD_MONSTER" spellcasting="Feral Ranger" prepared="true" level="17" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTER_FABLE_HUNTERS_PREY" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTER_FABLE_DEFENSIVE_TACTICS" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTER_FABLE_WEAPON_TEMPEST" level="11" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTER_FABLE_SUPERIOR_HUNTERS_DEFENSE" level="15" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Hunter’s Prey" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Feral Ranger" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTER_FABLE_HUNTERS_PREY">
            <description>
                <p>At 3rd level, you gain one of the following features of your choice.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Colossus Slayer.</b> Your tenacity can wear down the most potent foes. When you hit a creature with a weapon attack, the creature takes an extra 1d8 damage if it’s below its hit point maximum. You can deal this extra damage only once per turn.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Giant Killer.</b> When a Large or larger creature within 5 feet of you hits or misses you with an attack, you can use your reaction to attack that creature immediately after its attack, provided that you can see the creature.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Horde Breaker.</b> Once on each of your turns when you make a weapon attack, you can make another attack with the same weapon against a different creature that is within 5 feet of the original target and within range of your weapon.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false" />
            <rules>
                <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Hunter’s Prey" supports="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTER_FABLE_HUNTERS_PREY_COLOSSUS_SLAYER|ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTER_FABLE_HUNTERS_PREY_GIANT_KILLER|ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTER_FABLE_HUNTERS_PREY_HORDE_BREAKER" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Colossus Slayer" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Feral Ranger" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTER_FABLE_HUNTERS_PREY_COLOSSUS_SLAYER">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>Your tenacity can wear down the most potent foes. When you hit a creature with a weapon attack, the creature takes an extra 1d8 damage if it’s below its hit point maximum. You can deal this extra damage only once per turn.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="1/Turn">
                    <description>When you hit a creature with a weapon attack, the creature takes an extra 1d8 damage if it’s below its hit point maximum.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Giant Killer" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Feral Ranger" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTER_FABLE_HUNTERS_PREY_GIANT_KILLER">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>When a Large or larger creature within 5 feet of you hits or misses you with an attack, you can use your reaction to attack that creature immediately after its attack, provided that you can see the creature.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet action="Reaction">
                    <description>When a Large or larger creature within 5 feet of you hits or misses you with an attack, you can use your reaction to attack that creature immediately after its attack, provided that you can see the creature.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Horde Breaker" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Feral Ranger" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTER_FABLE_HUNTERS_PREY_HORDE_BREAKER">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>Once on each of your turns when you make a weapon attack, you can make another attack with the same weapon against a different creature that is within 5 feet of the original target and within range of your weapon.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="1/Turn">
                    <description>When you make a weapon attack, you can make another attack with the same weapon against a different creature that is within 5 feet of the original target and within range of your weapon.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
        <element name="Defensive Tactics" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Feral Ranger" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTER_FABLE_DEFENSIVE_TACTICS">
            <description>
                <p>At 7th level, you gain one of the following features of your choice.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Escape the Horde.</b> Opportunity attacks against you are made with disadvantage.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Multiattack Defense.</b> When a creature hits you with an attack, you gain a +4 bonus to AC against all subsequent attacks made by that creature for the rest of the turn.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Steel Will.</b> You have advantage on saving throws against being frightened.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false" />
            <rules>
                <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Defensive Tactics" supports="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTER_FABLE_DEFENSIVE_TACTICS_ESCAPE_THE_HORDE|ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTER_FABLE_DEFENSIVE_TACTICS_MULTIATTACK_DEFENSE|ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTER_FABLE_DEFENSIVE_TACTICS_STEEL_WILL" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Escape the Horde" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Feral Ranger" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTER_FABLE_DEFENSIVE_TACTICS_ESCAPE_THE_HORDE">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>Opportunity attacks against you are made with disadvantage.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>Opportunity attacks against you are made with disadvantage.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Multiattack Defense" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Feral Ranger" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTER_FABLE_DEFENSIVE_TACTICS_MULTIATTACK_DEFENSE">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>When a creature hits you with an attack, you gain a +4 bonus to AC against all subsequent attacks made by that creature for the rest of the turn.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>When a creature hits you with an attack, you gain a +4 bonus to AC against all subsequent attacks made by that creature for the rest of the turn.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Steel Will" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Feral Ranger" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTER_FABLE_DEFENSIVE_TACTICS_STEEL_WILL">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>You have advantage on saving throws against being frightened.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>You have advantage on saving throws against being frightened.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
        <element name="Weapon Tempest" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Feral Ranger" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTER_FABLE_WEAPON_TEMPEST">
            <description>
                <p>At 11th level, you gain one of the following features of your choice.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Volley.</b> You can use your action to make a ranged attack against any number of creatures within 10 feet of a point you can see within your weapon’s range. You must have ammunition for each target, as normal, and you make a separate attack roll for each target.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Unerring Blade.</b> Once on each of your turns, when you miss with a melee weapon attack, you can make a single melee weapon attack against the same target.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false" />
            <rules>
                <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Weapon Tempest" supports="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTER_FABLE_WEAPON_TEMPEST_VOLLEY|ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTER_FABLE_WEAPON_TEMPEST_UNERRING_BLADE" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Volley" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Feral Ranger" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTER_FABLE_WEAPON_TEMPEST_VOLLEY">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>You can use your action to make a ranged attack against any number of creatures within 10 feet of a point you can see within your weapon’s range. You must have ammunition for each target, as normal, and you make a separate attack roll for each target.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet action="Action">
                    <description>You make a ranged attack against any number of creatures within 10 feet of a point you can see within your weapon’s range. You must have ammunition for each target, as normal, and you make a separate attack roll for each target.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Unerring Blade" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Feral Ranger" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTER_FABLE_WEAPON_TEMPEST_UNERRING_BLADE">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>Once on each of your turns, when you miss with a melee weapon attack, you can make a single melee weapon attack against the same target.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="1/Turn">
                    <description>When you miss with a melee weapon attack, you can make a single melee weapon attack against the same target.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
        <element name="Superior Hunter’s Defense" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Feral Ranger" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTER_FABLE_SUPERIOR_HUNTERS_DEFENSE">
            <description>
                <p>At 15th level, you gain one of the following features of your choice.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Evasion.</b> When you are subjected to an effect, such as a red dragon’s fiery breath or a lightning bolt spell, that allows you to make a Dexterity saving throw to take only half damage, you instead take no damage if you succeed on a saving throw, and only half damage if you fail.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Stand Against the Tide.</b> When a hostile creature misses you with a melee attack, you can use your reaction to force that creature to repeat the same attack against another creature (other than itself) of your choice.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Uncanny Dodge.</b> When an attacker that you can see hits you with an attack, you can use your reaction to halve the attack’s damage against you.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false" />
            <rules>
                <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Superior Hunter’s Defense" supports="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTER_FABLE_SUPERIOR_HUNTERS_DEFENSE_EVASION|ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTER_FABLE_SUPERIOR_HUNTERS_DEFENSE_STAND_AGAINST_THE_TIDE|ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTER_FABLE_SUPERIOR_HUNTERS_DEFENSE_UNCANNY_DODGE" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Evasion" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Feral Ranger" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTER_FABLE_SUPERIOR_HUNTERS_DEFENSE_EVASION">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>When you are subjected to an effect, such as a red dragon’s fiery breath or a lightning bolt spell, that allows you to make a Dexterity saving throw to take only half damage, you instead take no damage if you succeed on a saving throw, and only half damage if you fail.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>When you are subjected to an effect that allows you to make a Dexterity saving throw to take only half damage, you instead take no damage if you succeed on a saving throw, and only half damage if you fail.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Stand Against the Tide" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Feral Ranger" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTER_FABLE_SUPERIOR_HUNTERS_DEFENSE_STAND_AGAINST_THE_TIDE">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>When a hostile creature misses you with a melee attack, you can use your reaction to force that creature to repeat the same attack against another creature (other than itself) of your choice.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet action="Reaction">
                    <description>When a hostile creature misses you with a melee attack, you can use your reaction to force that creature to repeat the same attack against another creature (other than itself) of your choice.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Uncanny Dodge" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Feral Ranger" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTER_FABLE_SUPERIOR_HUNTERS_DEFENSE_UNCANNY_DODGE">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>When an attacker that you can see hits you with an attack, you can use your reaction to halve the attack’s damage against you.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet action="Reaction">
                    <description>When an attacker that you can see hits you with an attack, you can halve the attack’s damage against you.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>

    <element name="Nightmare Fable" type="Archetype" source="The Feral Ranger" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FERAL_RANGER_NIGHTMARE_FABLE">
        <supports>Feral Ranger Fable</supports>
        <description>
            <p>When something goes bump in the night, you are there. When a shadow casts a sinister reach, you are there. When something is hiding under the bed, you are there. Rangers of the Nightmare Fable stalk the forgotten woods, where terrors dwell and fade from the memories of the wakeful. But when the blood moon rises and man has tortured sleep for want of retribution, these nightmares breach the veil of the subconscious mind to bring deliverence to the conscious world.</p>
            <p class="indent">It is the duty of these rangers to return these creatures back into the folds of the seeming dreamscape, but whether they are more than just foe to the horrors of the mind is left in question, for when you stare into the abyss, the abyss stares back into you.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">Nightmare Fable Spells</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Ranger level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>dissonant whispers</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>darkness</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>9th</td><td><em>fear</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td><em>phantasmal killer</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>17th</td><td><em>dream</em></td></tr>
            </table>
            <h5 class="caption">Nightmare Fable Quirks</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d6</td><td>Quirks</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>When meeting people for the first time, you cannot help but cryptically warn them of imminent danger</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>You have a habit of creeping up as close as you can to others without them noticing before speaking</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>When apprehending monsters, you have a habit of tugging at their faces to see if they’re wearing a mask</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>You can only sleep through the night if you’re having nightmares</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>You are prone to speak of things past and things to come in a voice that is not your own, though whether there is any truth to it is up to question</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>When preparing food, examining a weapon, or bathed in blood, you cannot help but laugh maniacally</td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NIGHTMARE_FABLE_POLTERGEIST_PHENOMENA" />
            <div element="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NIGHTMARE_FABLE_TORMENTING_STRIKE" />
            <div element="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NIGHTMARE_FABLE_STALKER" />
            <div element="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NIGHTMARE_FABLE_DREAD_SLAYER" />
            <div element="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NIGHTMARE_FABLE_INSPIRE_FEAR" />
            <div element="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NIGHTMARE_FABLE_FIND_NIGHTMARE" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISSONANT_WHISPERS" spellcasting="Feral Ranger" prepared="true" level="3" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DARKNESS" spellcasting="Feral Ranger" prepared="true" level="5" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FEAR" spellcasting="Feral Ranger" prepared="true" level="9" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PHANTASMAL_KILLER" spellcasting="Feral Ranger" prepared="true" level="13" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DREAM" spellcasting="Feral Ranger" prepared="true" level="17" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NIGHTMARE_FABLE_POLTERGEIST_PHENOMENA" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NIGHTMARE_FABLE_TORMENTING_STRIKE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NIGHTMARE_FABLE_STALKER" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NIGHTMARE_FABLE_DREAD_SLAYER" level="11" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NIGHTMARE_FABLE_INSPIRE_FEAR" level="11" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NIGHTMARE_FABLE_FIND_NIGHTMARE" level="15" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Poltergeist Phenomena" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Feral Ranger" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NIGHTMARE_FABLE_POLTERGEIST_PHENOMENA">
            <description>
                <p>When you choose this fable at 3rd level, you learn the thaumaturgy cantrip and gain proficiency in Intimidation. If you are already proficient, choose a different skill from the Feral Ranger skill list.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false" />
            <rules>
                <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency" supports="Skill, Feral Ranger" default="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INTIMIDATION" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_THAUMATURGY" spellcasting="Feral Ranger" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Tormenting Strike" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Feral Ranger" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NIGHTMARE_FABLE_TORMENTING_STRIKE">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 3rd level, when you attack a creature with a weapon attack from your Ferocity feature, the creature must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw against your spell save DC or else become frightened of you for 1 minute. A creature can repeat this saving throw at the end of each of their turns, ending it on a success.</p>
                <p class="indent">Creatures who succeed on their saving throw are immune to this effect for 1 minute.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you attack a creature with a weapon attack from your Ferocity feature, the creature must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw (DC {{spellcasting:dc:wis}}) or else become frightened of you for 1 minute. A creature can repeat this saving throw at the end of each of their turns, ending it on a success.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Stalker" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Feral Ranger" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NIGHTMARE_FABLE_STALKER">
            <description>
                <p>At 7th level, if at the end of your turn no creature can see you, you can choose to turn invisible. The invisibility lasts until you take damage, make an attack, or cast a spell. You can do this a number of times equal to 1 + your Wisdom modifier (minimum 1). You regain expended uses at the end of a long rest.</p>
                <p class="indent">If the only creatures that can see you are frightened, you can use this feature at the end of your turn and you do not expend a use of it.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="{{stalker:uses}}/Long Rest">
                <description>If at the end of your turn no creature can see you, you can choose to turn invisible. If the only creatures that can see you are frightened, you can use this feature at the end of your turn and you do not expend a use of it.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="stalker:uses" value="1" />
                <stat name="stalker:uses" value="wisdom:modifier" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Dread Slayer" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Feral Ranger" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NIGHTMARE_FABLE_DREAD_SLAYER">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 11th level, frightened creatures whose CR are equal to or less than half your feral ranger level (rounded down) have disadvantage on saving throws against your spells and abilities. In addition, creatures immune to the frightened condition instead have advantage on saving throws against your spells and abilities that would inflict the frightened condition.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Frightened creatures whose CR are equal to or less than {{level:feral ranger:half}} have disadvantage on saving throws against your spells and abilities. In addition, creatures immune to the frightened condition instead have advantage on saving throws against your spells and abilities that would inflict the frightened condition.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Inspire Fear" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Feral Ranger" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NIGHTMARE_FABLE_INSPIRE_FEAR">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 11th level, your very touch can spread despair. As an action, you can touch an adjacent creature. The creature must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw against your spell save DC or else take 3d8 psychic damage and become frightened of you until the end of your next turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>You can touch an adjacent creature. The creature must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw (DC {{spellcasting:dc:wis}}) or else take 3d8 psychic damage and become frightened of you until the end of your next turn.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Find Nightmare" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Feral Ranger" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NIGHTMARE_FABLE_FIND_NIGHTMARE">
            <description>
                <p>At 15th level, phantasma becomes your companion, allowing you to enter and exit the interstice between the waking and dreaming realms at-will. You can conduct an hour long ritual lit only by the flames of a secluded campfire around which you tell frightening tales to summon a Nightmare.</p>
                <p class="indent">It acts on your turn and follows your mental commands (no action required by you), but will not attack except in defense of itself. If you are reduced to 0 hit points, it will retreat into the ethereal plane until you command it to return. If reduced to 0 hit points, it does not die but instead returns to the forgotten woods from whence it came, and can be summoned by conducting the ritual once more.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can conduct an hour long ritual lit only by the flames of a secluded campfire around which you tell frightening tales to summon a Nightmare. It acts on your turn and follows your mental commands (no action required by you), but will not attack except in defense of itself.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>

    <element name="Horizon Walker Fable" type="Archetype" source="The Feral Ranger" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FERAL_RANGER_HORIZON_WALKER_FABLE">
        <supports>Feral Ranger Fable</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Distant tales tell of a rampart of rangers that guard the world against threats originating from other planes or those that seek to ravage the mortal realm with otherworldly magic. They seek out planar portals and keep watch over them, venturing to the Inner Planes and the Outer Planes as needed to pursue their foes. These rangers are also friends to any forces in the multiverse - especially benevolent dragons, fey, and elementals - that work to preserve life and the order of the planes.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">Horizon Walker Fable Spells</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Ranger level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>protection from evil and good</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>misty step</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>9th</td><td><em>haste</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td><em>banishment</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>17th</td><td><em>teleportation circle</em></td></tr>
            </table>
            <h5 class="caption">Horizon Walker Fable Quirks</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d6</td><td>Quirks</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>You always carry a book with you, as there is no better weapon in the world than books</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>You are committed to telling your origin story one last time, though that last time never seems to come</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>As one who seeks despite ones origins, you hold no prejudice in associating with outcasts</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>Having witnessed the Wild Hunt, you are beset by visions of other realms</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>You carry a coin with you that inexplicably always comes up heads</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>You believe everyone deserves a place to call home</td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HORIZON_WALKER_FABLE_PORTAL_MAGIC" />
            <div element="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HORIZON_WALKER_FABLE_PLANAR_WARRIOR" />
            <div element="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HORIZON_WALKER_FABLE_ETHEREAL_STEP" />
            <div element="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HORIZON_WALKER_FABLE_DISTANT_STRIKE" />
            <div element="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HORIZON_WALKER_FABLE_SPECTRAL_DEFENSE" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PROTECTION_FROM_EVIL_AND_GOOD" spellcasting="Feral Ranger" prepared="true" level="3" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MISTY_STEP" spellcasting="Feral Ranger" prepared="true" level="5" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HASTE" spellcasting="Feral Ranger" prepared="true" level="9" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BANISHMENT" spellcasting="Feral Ranger" prepared="true" level="13" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TELEPORTATION_CIRCLE" spellcasting="Feral Ranger" prepared="true" level="17" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HORIZON_WALKER_FABLE_PORTAL_MAGIC" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HORIZON_WALKER_FABLE_PLANAR_WARRIOR" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HORIZON_WALKER_FABLE_ETHEREAL_STEP" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HORIZON_WALKER_FABLE_DISTANT_STRIKE" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HORIZON_WALKER_FABLE_SPECTRAL_DEFENSE" level="1" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Portal Magic" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Feral Ranger" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HORIZON_WALKER_FABLE_PORTAL_MAGIC">
            <description>
                <p>At 3rd level, you learn basic conjuration and gain the ability to magically sense the presence of a planar portal. You learn the mage hand cantrip, and as an Action, you detect the distance and direction to the closest planar portal within 1 mile of you.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Short Rest">
                <description>You detect the distance and direction to the closest planar portal within 1 mile of you.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGE_HAND" spellcasting="Feral Ranger" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Planar Warrior" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Feral Ranger" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HORIZON_WALKER_FABLE_PLANAR_WARRIOR">
            <description>
                <p>At 3rd level, you learn to draw on the energy of the multiverse to augment your attacks.</p>
                <p class="indent">When you use your Ferocity feature, until the end of your turn the damage from all of your weapon attacks including the triggering attack become force damage, and creatures hit by these attacks take an extra 1d8 force damage from the attack. A creature can take this extra damage only once on each of your turns.</p>
                <p class="indent">At 11th level, a creature can take this extra damage twice on each of your turns.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you use your Ferocity feature, until the end of your turn the damage from all of your weapon attacks including the triggering attack become force damage, and creatures hit by these attacks take an extra 1d8 force damage from the attack. A creature can take this extra damage only once on each of your turns.</description>
                <description level="11">When you use your Ferocity feature, until the end of your turn the damage from all of your weapon attacks including the triggering attack become force damage, and creatures hit by these attacks take an extra 1d8 force damage from the attack. A creature can take this extra damage twice on each of your turns.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Ethereal Step" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Feral Ranger" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HORIZON_WALKER_FABLE_ETHEREAL_STEP">
            <description>
                <p>At 7th level, you learn to step through the Ethereal Plane. As a Bonus Action, you can cast the <i>etherealness</i> spell with this feature, without expending a spell slot, but the spell ends at the end of the current turn.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="1/Short Rest">
                <description>You can cast the etherealness spell with this feature, without expending a spell slot, but the spell ends at the end of the current turn.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ETHEREALNESS" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Distant Strike" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Feral Ranger" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HORIZON_WALKER_FABLE_DISTANT_STRIKE">
            <description>
                <p>At 11th level, you gain the ability to pass between the planes in the blink of an eye. When you take the Attack Action, you can teleport up to 10 feet before every attack you make in the same turn to an unoccupied space you can see.</p>
                <p class="indent">If you attack at least two different creatures, you can make one additional attack with it against a third creature.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you take the Attack Action, you can teleport up to 10 feet before every attack you make in the same turn to an unoccupied space you can see. If you attack at least two different creatures, you can make one additional attack with it against a third creature.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Spectral Defense" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Feral Ranger" id="ID_LEUKU_TFR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HORIZON_WALKER_FABLE_SPECTRAL_DEFENSE">
            <description>
                <p>At 15th level, your ability to move between the planes enables you to slip through the boundaries to lessen the harm done to you during battle. When you take damage from an attack, you can use your reaction to give yourself resistance to all of that attack’s damage on this turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Reaction">
                <description>When you take damage from an attack, you give yourself resistance to all of that attack’s damage on this turn.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>


    <!-- Feral Ranger Skills -->
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ANIMALHANDLING">
            <supports>Feral Ranger</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ACROBATICS">
            <supports>Feral Ranger</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ATHLETICS">
            <supports>Feral Ranger</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT">
            <supports>Feral Ranger</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INVESTIGATION">
            <supports>Feral Ranger</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_MEDICINE">
            <supports>Feral Ranger</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_NATURE">
            <supports>Feral Ranger</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION">
            <supports>Feral Ranger</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SURVIVAL">
            <supports>Feral Ranger</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_STEALTH">
            <supports>Feral Ranger</supports>
        </append>

    <!-- Feral Ranger Fighting Styles -->
        <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_ARCHERY">
            <supports>Feral Ranger</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_DEFENSE">
            <supports>Feral Ranger</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_DUELING">
            <supports>Feral Ranger</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_TWOWEAPON_FIGHTING">
            <supports>Feral Ranger</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_WOTC_TCE_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTING_STYLE_DRUIDIC_WARRIOR">
            <supports>Feral Ranger</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_WOTC_TCE_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTING_STYLE_THROWN_WEAPON_FIGHTING">
            <supports>Feral Ranger</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_WOTC_TCE_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTING_STYLE_BLIND_FIGHTING">
            <supports>Feral Ranger</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_FUBR_TWC_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_FLEXIBILITY">
            <supports>Feral Ranger</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_WOTC_UA2015_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_CLOSE_QUARTERS_SHOOTER">
            <supports>Feral Ranger</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_WOTC_UA2015_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_TUNNEL_FIGHTER">
            <supports>Feral Ranger</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_LL_LLMA_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_MARINER">
            <supports>Feral Ranger</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_LL_LLMA_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_VERSATILE_FIGHTING">
            <supports>Feral Ranger</supports>
        </append>

</elements>