<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>The Castellan Class</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="class-castellan.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/classes/class-castellan.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
	<element name="The Castellan" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_SOURCE_THE_CASTELLAN">
		<description>
			<p>The Castellan is playtest content developed by Genuine, of Genuine Fantasy Press.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="abbreviation"></set>
			<set name="url">https://drive.google.com/file/d/1Grx3qzyOtmeh7QlGtzHN7RZ8fcW73Qnp/view</set>
			<set name="image"></set>
			<set name="author" abbreviation="GFP" url="https://www.genfantasypress.com/">Genuine Fantasy Press</set>
			<set name="third-party">true</set>
			<set name="release">20200120</set>
			<set name="information">This class does not support multiclassing.</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

    <element name="Castellan" type="Class" source="The Castellan" id="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_CLASS_CASTELLAN">
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">The chessboard battlefield is a riot of motion and sound; the clash of blades and shattering of shields punctuating the chorus of shouts and screams in the autumn twilight. Amidst the chaos, an armored dragonborn captain directs her blademaster to hold the line while she rushes to the side of her fallen court wizard. Helping the gnome to his feet, she yells encouragement in his ear as his eyes refocus, pointing towards the commander of the onrushing horde.</p>
            <p class="indent flavor">That commander, the last prince of a rogue elven state, lets out a bloodchilling howl, sending the wolves his druid had called forth to rush in behind his soldiers, the beasts leaping with unnatural strength to tear into the second line of the invaders. He calls a warning to a ranger about to be skewered, and the power behind his words allows the warrior to dodge aside at the last instant and retreat to safety.</p>
            <p class="indent flavor">An old dwarf sits invisibly atop a rocky outcropping near the battle, smoking a pipe and smiling as all the pieces fall into their proper places on the board. He nods to the darkness below, and his team begins to flicker across the rocky terrain, moving like shadows thanks to his subtle arcanery. The clash of steel seems to pause a heartbeat later as both sides realize that their leaders are calling for a halt, each held at knifepoint by a wickedly grinning agent of the Empire.</p>
            <p class="indent">These are castellans: leaders, guides, tacticians and advisors who enable others to accomplish impossible feats. A castellan’s companions are their castle, and they are responsible for ensuring the safety and success of those who place such faith in them.</p>
            <h4>ADVISORS AND LEADERS</h4>
            <p>A castellan can come in many forms, and while all are trained in the arts of battle, warfare is not their sole pursuit, and it is often an afterthought for many. Instead, a castellan focuses themselves on those that they are responsible for, seeing to their grievances and working to assure success for those in their charge. The problems that they work to resolve, and those that they ally with, are key to understanding the role of a castellan in a group and in the world. The cestallanic arts are more commonly practiced among those of learned backgrounds, though this discrepancy is merely based upon opportunity, rather than intrinsic merit. Anyone with sufficient training, skill, and that certain spark of greatness can become a castellan, for the ability to understand and guide others can be found among all races and peoples.</p>
            <h4>TACTICAL SUPREMACY</h4>
            <p>Among adventurers, castellans are best known for their ability to plan, support, and enable their allies to fight with greater skill and focus. Their strategies prior to battle are often subtle, but when the time for conflict arises, their plans flow smoothly into motion. The strength of their conviction lends speed and ferocity to their allies, their clever maneuverings keep their companions safe, and their watchful eyes can detect even the most subtle of weaknesses. A lone warrior is something to be wary of, but one aided by a castellan fights with the strength of ten.</p>
            <h4>DIVERSE ORIGINS</h4>
            <p>As castellans can be present in almost any culture, it is not uncommon for them to develop special skills and talents based upon where they come from and what values they hold. When working with others, a castellan is both a guide and a follower, adapting their hard-earned abilities to suit the needs of the group. Castellans often rise to posistions of leadership, where their abilities can best be of use to those who follow them, but not all take such a direct role. Castellans are masters of people, more than anything, and providing the proper words of advice or the calming gestures needed to diffuse a difficult situation are as natural to them as breathing. As such, they make fantastic advisors and aides, supporters and champions of collective causes. In more warlike cultures, they are often generals or captains, able to rally their soldiers to glory with nothing more than a single word. Among scholars and creatives, they provide a voice for those who struggle to speak, or an ear for those with much to say.</p>
            <h4>GRAND PLANS</h4>
            <p>The influence of a castellan can arise in many ways, some more subtle than others. A castellan’s presence upon the battlefield could take the form of yelled orders or shouted encouragement, but need not be so obvious. Many establish schemes and cunning methods of training, such that their allies perform better during combat by their own merit alone, while others may empower their companions with momentary surges of strength through murmured chants of magical origin. For a rare few, subtle machinations that can scarcely be understood cause the world to shift in their favor, seeming to warp fate at their will. Regardless of the source, a castellan’s presence is the core of their abilities, for they guide as naturally as a bird flies or a fish swims.</p>
            <h4>CREATING A CASTELLAN</h4>
            <p>When creating a castellan, consider you style of assistance first and foremost. Are you an advisor, allowing others to take the spotlight, or a grand leader with bold ambitions?</p>
            <p class="indent">Are you careful and cunning, creating deadly schemes and clever plots, or are you brash and aggressive, leading your allies to victory with brilliant improvization alone? How did you develop your skills, and what influence has your party had on your personal development? Consider all of these questions when creating a castellan.</p>
            <h5>QUICK BUILD</h5>
            <p>You can make a castellan quickly by following these suggestions. First, make Charisma your highest ability score, followed by Constitution. Then, choose a background suitable to allow you to develop strong leadership skills.</p>
            <h2>CLASS FEATURES</h2>
            <p>As an castellan, you gain the following class features.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">HIT POINTS</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Hit Dice:</strong> 1d10 per castellan level</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at 1st Level:</strong> 10 + your Constitution modifier</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at Higher Levels:</strong> 1d10 (or 6) + your Constitution modifier per castellan level after 1st</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">PROFICIENCIES</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled mb">
                <li><strong>Armor:</strong> Light, medium, heavy, and shields</li>
                <li><strong>Weapons:</strong> Simple weapons</li>
                <li><strong>Tools:</strong> Constitution, Intelligence</li>
            </ul>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Saving Throws:</strong> One gaming set of your choosing</li>
                <li><strong>Skills:</strong> Choose three skills from Arcana, Athletics, History, Insight, Intimidation, Nature, Persuasion, Stealth, Survival</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">EQUIPMENT</h5>
            <p>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>(a) chain mail or (b) studded leather armor</li>
                <li>a melee simple weapon and a shield</li>
                <li>a light crossbow and a case of 20 bolts</li>
                <li>a dungeoneer’s pack</li>
                <li>a gaming set of your choosing</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">THE CASTELLAN</h5>
            <table class="class-features">
                <thead>
                    <tr><td class="col-5">Level</td><td class="col-10">Proficiency Bonus</td><td class="col-60 left">Features</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td> 1st</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Castellan’s Presence, Confidence</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 2nd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Aptitude, Restorative Triage</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 3rd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Castellanic Archetype</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 4th</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 5th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Castellan’s Presence (2)</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 6th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Castellanic Archetype Feature</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 7th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Quick Study</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 8th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 9th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Strive Beyond</td></tr>
                <tr><td>10th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Castellanic Archetype Feature</td></tr>
                <tr><td>11th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Castellan’s Presence (3)</td></tr>
                <tr><td>12th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Masterful Instruction</td></tr>
                <tr><td>14th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Strive Beyond (2)</td></tr>
                <tr><td>15th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Castellanic Archetype Feature</td></tr>
                <tr><td>16th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td></tr>
                <tr><td>17th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Castellan’s Presence (4)</td></tr>
                <tr><td>18th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">United As One</td></tr>
                <tr><td>19th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td></tr>
                <tr><td>20th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Self Rule</td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_CLASS_FEATURE_CASTELLAN_CASTELLANS_PRESENCE" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_CLASS_FEATURE_CASTELLAN_CONFIDENCE" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_CLASS_FEATURE_CASTELLAN_APTITUDE" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_CLASS_FEATURE_CASTELLAN_RESTORATIVE_TRIAGE" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_CLASS_FEATURE_CASTELLAN_CASTELLANIC_ARCHETYPE" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_CLASS_FEATURE_CASTELLAN_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_CLASS_FEATURE_CASTELLAN_QUICK_STUDY" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_CLASS_FEATURE_CASTELLAN_STRIVE_BEYOND" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_CLASS_FEATURE_CASTELLAN_MASTERFUL_INSTRUCTION" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_CLASS_FEATURE_CASTELLAN_UNITED_AS_ONE" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_CLASS_FEATURE_CASTELLAN_SELF_RULE" />
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="hd">d10</set>
            <set name="short">A minorly-magical supportive class that works to enable others to succeed.</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_MEDIUM_ARMOR" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_HEAVY_ARMOR" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_SHIELDS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CONSTITUTION" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_INTELLIGENCE" />
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency, Castellan" number="3" supports="Skill,Castellan" />
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Gaming Set, Castellan" supports="Gaming Set" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_CLASS_FEATURE_CASTELLAN_CASTELLANS_PRESENCE" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_CLASS_FEATURE_CASTELLAN_CONFIDENCE" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_CLASS_FEATURE_CASTELLAN_APTITUDE" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_CLASS_FEATURE_CASTELLAN_RESTORATIVE_TRIAGE" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_CLASS_FEATURE_CASTELLAN_CASTELLANIC_ARCHETYPE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_CLASS_FEATURE_CASTELLAN_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" level="4" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_CLASS_FEATURE_CASTELLAN_QUICK_STUDY" level="7" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_CLASS_FEATURE_CASTELLAN_STRIVE_BEYOND" level="9" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_CLASS_FEATURE_CASTELLAN_MASTERFUL_INSTRUCTION" level="13" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_CLASS_FEATURE_CASTELLAN_UNITED_AS_ONE" level="18" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_CLASS_FEATURE_CASTELLAN_SELF_RULE" level="20" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Castellan’s Presence" type="Class Feature" source="The Castellan" id="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_CLASS_FEATURE_CASTELLAN_CASTELLANS_PRESENCE">
            <description>
                <p>At 1st level, your tactical expertise and encouraging demeanor allow you to bring out the best in others during combat. You can use your action during your turn to enter a state of strategic awareness until the start of your next turn. When you do this, you gain a single intervention, which you can use at any time during another creature’s turn to empower or afflict the creature in one of the following ways:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li><strong>Assault:</strong> The creature whose turn it is can immediately move up to half its speed and make a single weapon attack without using an action.</li>
                    <li><strong>Maneuver:</strong> The creature whose turn it is can immediately move up to its speed, and it gains the benefits of the Disengage action during this turn.</li>
                    <li><strong>Defend:</strong> The creature whose turn it is gains a single feint point, which lasts until the end of its next turn. During any turn, it can expend one feint point to cause an attack made against it to be made with disadvantage, or to gain advantage on a Dexterity saving throw.</li>
                    <li><strong>Expose:</strong> You reveal a weakness of the creature whose turn it is, causing the next attack targeting it to be made with advantage. The next time the creature takes damage before the start of its next turn, it takes extra damage of the same type equal to 1d12 + your Intelligence modifier.</li>
                </ul>
                <p>Using an intervention does not require an action by you or the creature, but a friendly target must be able to take actions in order to gain any benefits, and the target must be within 120 feet of you. Interventions you don’t use are lost at the start of your next turn. You can produce the same effect, or different effects, multiple times during the same turn provided you have the number of interventions required.</p>
                <p class="indent">Starting at 5th level, you gain two interventions when you use this feature. You gain three interventions starting at 11th level, and four interventions starting at 17th level.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>You can use your action during your turn to enter a state of strategic awareness until the start of your next turn. When you do this, you gain a single intervention, which you can use at any time during another creature’s turn to empower or afflict the creature in one of the following ways: Assault, Maneuver, Defend, or Expose. Using an intervention does not require an action by you or the creature, but a friendly target must be able to take actions in order to gain any benefits, and the target must be within 120 feet of you. Interventions you don’t use are lost at the start of your next turn.</description>
                <description level="5">You can use your action during your turn to enter a state of strategic awareness until the start of your next turn. When you do this, you gain two interventions, which you can use at any time during another creature’s turn to empower or afflict the creature in one of the following ways: Assault, Maneuver, Defend, or Expose. Using an intervention does not require an action by you or the creature, but a friendly target must be able to take actions in order to gain any benefits, and the target must be within 120 feet of you. Interventions you don’t use are lost at the start of your next turn.</description>
                <description level="11">You can use your action during your turn to enter a state of strategic awareness until the start of your next turn. When you do this, you gain three interventions, which you can use at any time during another creature’s turn to empower or afflict the creature in one of the following ways: Assault, Maneuver, Defend, or Expose. Using an intervention does not require an action by you or the creature, but a friendly target must be able to take actions in order to gain any benefits, and the target must be within 120 feet of you. Interventions you don’t use are lost at the start of your next turn.</description>
                <description level="17">You can use your action during your turn to enter a state of strategic awareness until the start of your next turn. When you do this, you gain four interventions, which you can use at any time during another creature’s turn to empower or afflict the creature in one of the following ways: Assault, Maneuver, Defend, or Expose. Using an intervention does not require an action by you or the creature, but a friendly target must be able to take actions in order to gain any benefits, and the target must be within 120 feet of you. Interventions you don’t use are lost at the start of your next turn.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Confidence" type="Class Feature" source="The Castellan" id="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_CLASS_FEATURE_CASTELLAN_CONFIDENCE">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 1st level, you can always make yourself heard. Creatures of your choosing that are within 120 feet of you can hear your speech, regardless of obstacles, volume, or other impediments. You still can’t speak audibly while affected by the <em>silence</em> spell or similar effects. Additionally, you can use your Intelligence modifier in place of your Dexterity modifier when rolling for initiative.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Creatures of your choosing that are within 120 feet of you can hear your speech, regardless of obstacles, volume, or other impediments. You still can’t speak audibly while affected by the silence spell or similar effects. Additionally, you can use your Intelligence modifier in place of your Dexterity modifier when rolling for initiative.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="initiative" value="intelligence:modifier" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="initiative" value="dexterity:modifier" bonus="base" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Aptitude" type="Class Feature" source="The Castellan" id="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_CLASS_FEATURE_CASTELLAN_APTITUDE">
            <description>
                <p>At 2nd level, you learn to bait and manipulate others, imbuing your words and gestures with power. When you use your Castellan’s Presence feature during your turn, you can use your bonus action to call a creature within 60 feet of you. If the target is unwilling, it must make a Wisdom saving throw with a DC equal to 8 + your Intelligence modifier + your profiency bonus. If the target fails or is willing, it uses its reaction to move up to its speed directly closer to you via the shortest and safest possible route. If it ends this movement within your reach, you can use your reaction to make a single melee weapon attack targeting it. If you hit, your attack deals no damage, but the creature’s next attack is made with disadvantage and deals half as much damage. A creature that can’t be charmed is immune to this feature.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>When you use your Castellan’s Presence feature during your turn, you can use your bonus action to call a creature within 60 feet of you. If the target is unwilling, it must make a Wisdom saving throw (save DC {{castellan:save-dc}}). If the target fails or is willing, it uses its reaction to move up to its speed directly closer to you via the shortest and safest possible route. If it ends this movement within your reach, you can use your reaction to make a single melee weapon attack targeting it. If you hit, your attack deals no damage, but the creature’s next attack is made with disadvantage and deals half as much damage. A creature that can’t be charmed is immune to this feature.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="castellan:save-dc" value="8" />
                <stat name="castellan:save-dc" value="proficiency" />
                <stat name="castellan:save-dc" value="intelligence:modifier" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Restorative Triage" type="Class Feature" source="The Castellan" id="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_CLASS_FEATURE_CASTELLAN_RESTORATIVE_TRIAGE">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 2nd level, you learn to rapidly heal your allies. When a creature ends its turn within your reach, you can use your reaction to aid it, causing it to regain hit points equal to twice your castellan level.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can do this a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum once) and you regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Reaction" usage="{{restorative-triage:uses}}/Long Rest">
                <description>When a creature ends its turn within your reach, you can aid it, causing it to regain {{restoration-triage:heal-hp}} hit points.</description>
                <description level="20" usage="{{restorative-triage:uses}}/Short Rest">When a creature ends its turn within your reach, you can aid it, causing it to regain {{restoration-triage:heal-hp}} hit points.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="restoration-triage:heal-hp" value="level:castellan" />
                <stat name="restoration-triage:heal-hp" value="level:castellan" />
                <stat name="restorative-triage:uses" value="1" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="restorative-triage:uses" value="intelligence:modifier" bonus="base" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Castellanic Archetype" type="Class Feature" source="The Castellan" id="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_CLASS_FEATURE_CASTELLAN_CASTELLANIC_ARCHETYPE">
            <description>
                <p>At 3rd level, you begin to specialize your talents and skills. Choose one of the following archetypes from those available. Your archetype grants you features at 3rd level, and again at 6th, 10th, and 15th level.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Archetype" name="Castellanic Archetype" supports="Castellanic Archetype" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Ability Score Improvement" type="Class Feature" source="The Castellan" id="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_CLASS_FEATURE_CASTELLAN_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Castellan 4)" supports="Improvement Option,Castellan,4" level="4" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Castellan 8)" supports="Improvement Option,Castellan,8" level="8" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Castellan 12)" supports="Improvement Option,Castellan,12" level="12" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Castellan 16)" supports="Improvement Option,Castellan,16" level="16" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Castellan 19)" supports="Improvement Option,Castellan,19" level="19" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Quick Study" type="Class Feature" source="The Castellan" id="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_CLASS_FEATURE_CASTELLAN_QUICK_STUDY">
            <description>
                <p>At 7th level, your ability to benefit from the skills and knowledge of others increases greatly. During a long rest, you can communicate with up to three creatures of your choosing, learning particular techniques and tricks you can use to your advantage. Choose a number of skills or languages that the chosen creatures are proficient in that you lack proficiency in equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum 1). You gain proficiency in those skills or languages until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>During a long rest, you can communicate with up to three creatures of your choosing, learning particular techniques and tricks you can use to your advantage. Choose up to {{quick-study:skills}} skills or languages that the chosen creatures are proficient in that you lack proficiency in. You gain proficiency in those skills or languages until you finish a long rest.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="quick-study:skills" value="1" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="quick-study:skills" value="intelligence:modifier" bonus="base" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Strive Beyond" type="Class Feature" source="The Castellan" id="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_CLASS_FEATURE_CASTELLAN_STRIVE_BEYOND">
            <description>
                <p>At 9th level, the faith your companions have in you is returned in full. As an action, you can provide incredible determination to a willing creature that can hear you. That creature can choose to immediately end any number of ongoing conditions or spells that are affecting it. It can only remove one level of exhaustion, however.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
                <p class="indent">Starting at 14th level, you can use this feature twice, and you recover all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="{{strive-beyond:uses}}/Long Rest">
                <description>You can provide incredible determination to a willing creature that can hear you. That creature can choose to immediately end any number of ongoing conditions or spells that are affecting it. It can only remove one level of exhaustion, however.</description>
                <description level="20" usage="{{strive-beyond:uses}}/Short Rest">You can provide incredible determination to a willing creature that can hear you. That creature can choose to immediately end any number of ongoing conditions or spells that are affecting it. It can only remove one level of exhaustion, however.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="strive-beyond:uses" value="1" level="9" />
                <stat name="strive-beyond:uses" value="1" level="14" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Masterful Instruction" type="Class Feature" source="The Castellan" id="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_CLASS_FEATURE_CASTELLAN_MASTERFUL_INSTRUCTION">
            <description>
                <p>At 13th level, your unique style of learning and teaching allows you to give back. When you use your Quick Study feature, each creature you learn from can choose up to two skills or languages you have proficiency in or are gaining proficiency in using Quick Study. The creature becomes proficient in those skills or languages until it finishes a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you use your Quick Study feature, each creature you learn from can choose up to two skills or languages you have proficiency in or are gaining proficiency in using Quick Study. The creature becomes proficient in those skills or languages until it finishes a long rest.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="United As One" type="Class Feature" source="The Castellan" id="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_CLASS_FEATURE_CASTELLAN_UNITED_AS_ONE">
            <description>
                <p>At 18th level, the bonds that bind you to your allies are strong and unbreakable. When a friendly creature you can see would be reduced to 0 hit points, you can use your reaction to bolster them, causing them to be reduced to 1 hit point instead. When you do, you can immediately use one of your interventions as though it was that creature’s turn.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t do so again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Reaction" usage="1/Short Rest">
                <description>When a friendly creature you can see would be reduced to 0 hit points, you can bolster them, causing them to be reduced to 1 hit point instead. When you do, you can immediately use one of your interventions as though it was that creature’s turn.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Self Rule" type="Class Feature" source="The Castellan" id="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_CLASS_FEATURE_CASTELLAN_SELF_RULE">
            <description>
                <p>At 20th level, your brilliance is absolute, and those that follow your words shall not falter before the task is complete. You regain all expended uses of all of your castellan features whenever you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

        <element name="Noble Representative" type="Archetype" source="The Castellan" id="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_ARCHETYPE_CASTELLAN_NOBLE_REPRESENTATIVE">
            <supports>Castellanic Archetype</supports>
            <description>
                <p>As a castellan, you associate with a wide variety of folk in your adventures, but you find yourself most at home among the finer things in life. Great warriors and wizards are often included in the peerage of the realm, but you and yours are a cut above the rest. You are a representative, both of your own noble demeanor and of those you associate with, questing with bold purpose and purity of intent. Castellans like you are blessed with the power to create meaningful change, and the responsibility to use that influence wisely. Join with those who change the face of the world, and engage in the noblest profession.</p>
                <div element="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NOBLE_REPRESENTATIVE_GLORIOUS_KNIGHTS" />
                <div element="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NOBLE_REPRESENTATIVE_STALWART_VIGIL" />
                <div element="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NOBLE_REPRESENTATIVE_STAND_FAST" />
                <div element="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NOBLE_REPRESENTATIVE_HONORED_HOUSE" />
                <div element="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NOBLE_REPRESENTATIVE_CASTLE_OF_HEROES" />
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NOBLE_REPRESENTATIVE_GLORIOUS_KNIGHTS" level="3" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NOBLE_REPRESENTATIVE_STALWART_VIGIL" level="3" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NOBLE_REPRESENTATIVE_STAND_FAST" level="6" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NOBLE_REPRESENTATIVE_HONORED_HOUSE" level="10" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NOBLE_REPRESENTATIVE_CASTLE_OF_HEROES" level="15" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Glorious Knights" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Castellan" id="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NOBLE_REPRESENTATIVE_GLORIOUS_KNIGHTS">
                <description>
                    <p>When you choose this archetype at 3rd level, your command of tactics and warcraft grows greater. Your Castellan’s Presence improves in the following ways:</p>
                    <ul>
                        <li><strong>Assault:</strong> The creature can roll 1d4 and add the result to the attack or damage roll (its choice) after the roll is made and result declared, possibly changing the outcome.</li>
                        <li><strong>Maneuver:</strong> If the creature would end this movement within 10 feet of you, it gains temporary hit points equal to your Intelligence modifier that last until it rolls initiative.</li>
                        <li><strong>Defend:</strong> If a creature is within 5 feet of you at any time while it has a feint point, you gain the benefits of the Dodge action until the start of your next turn, or until it is no longer within 5 feet of you.</li>
                        <li><strong>Expose:</strong> If the creature is hit by a weapon attack, it must make a Strength saving throw (DC = 8 + your Intelligence modifier + your proficiency bonus). If it fails, it is knocked prone. The creature need only make a single saving throw, even if it has been Exposed multiple times.</li>
                    </ul>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>Your Castellan’s Presence improves in the following ways. Assault: The creature can roll 1d4 and add the result to attack or damage roll. Maneuver: If the creature would end its movement within 10 feet of you, it receives {{intelligence:modifier}} temporary hit points until it rolls initiative. Defend: If a creature is within 5 feet at any time while it has a feint point, you gain the benefits of the Dodge action. Expose: If the creature is hit by a weapon attack, it must make a Strength saving throw (save DC {{castellan:save-dc}}) or be knocked prone.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Stalwart Vigil" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Castellan" id="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NOBLE_REPRESENTATIVE_STALWART_VIGIL">
                <description>
                    <p>Also at 3rd level, you can use your Intelligence modifier in place of your Wisdom modifier when making ability checks, and you gain proficiency with martial weapons.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>You can use your Intelligence modifier in place of your Wisdom modifier when making ability checks.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_MARTIAL_WEAPONS" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Stand Fast" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Castellan" id="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NOBLE_REPRESENTATIVE_STAND_FAST">
                <description>
                    <p>At 6th level, you learn to protect your allies with greater resolve. When you use your Aptitude feature to move a hostile creature towards you, opportunity attacks made against it as a result of its movement are made with advantage.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>When you use your Aptitude feature to move a hostile creature towards you, opportunity attacks made against it as a result of its movement are made with advantage.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Honored House" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Castellan" id="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NOBLE_REPRESENTATIVE_HONORED_HOUSE">
                <description>
                    <p>At 10th level, your expansive studies have revealed a method by which you can create a fitting abode for yourself and your companions. You can cast <em>Mordenkainen’s magnificent mansion</em> without expending a spell slot. Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for this spell.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
                    <div class="reference">
                        <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_MORDENKAINENS_MAGNIFICENT_MANSION" />
                    </div>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                    <description>You can cast Mordenkainen’s magnificent mansion without expending a spell slot. Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for this spell.</description>
                    <description level="20" usage="1/Short Rest">You can cast Mordenkainen’s magnificent mansion without expending a spell slot. Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for this spell.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MORDENKAINENS_MAGNIFICENT_MANSION" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Castle of Heroes" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Castellan" id="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NOBLE_REPRESENTATIVE_CASTLE_OF_HEROES">
                <description>
                    <p>At 15th level, your arcane talents and devotion to the art of war combine to reveal the true potential of your skills. When you use your Restorative Triage feature, the target also gains temporary hit points equal to twice your castellan level.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Additionally, you gain the following option for your Castellan’s Presence feature.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><strong>Fortress:</strong> You immediately conjure a stylized opaque wall of magical energy in an unoccupied space on a surface you can see within 30 feet of you. The wall can be up to 5 feet thick, 10 feet long, and 10 feet high. It has AC 10 and hit points equal to your castellan level. The wall vanishes at the end of your next turn, or when destroyed.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>When you use your Restorative Triage feature, the target also gains {{restoration-triage:heal-hp}} temporary hit points. Additionally, you gain the following option for your Castellan’s Presence feature. Fortress: You immediately conjure a stylized opaque wall of magical energy in an unoccupied space on a surface you can see within 30 feet of you. The wall can be up to 5 feet thick, 10 feet long, and 10 feet high. It has AC 10 and {{level:castellan}} hit points. The wall vanishes at the end of your next turn, or when destroyed.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>

        
        <element name="Wild Speaker" type="Archetype" source="The Castellan" id="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_ARCHETYPE_CASTELLAN_WILD_SPEAKER">
            <supports>Castellanic Archetype</supports>
            <description>
                <p>You are more at home in places far from civilization, and your forays there merely serve to emphasize the stark differences between city and wilderness. Your friends are the beasts of the sea, sky, and field, and the people that travel with you are often of the same opinion. You are a speaker for the wild things and primevial places, a keeper of old promises and ancient oaths. As a castellan, you are gifted with a voice that cannot be denied, and so you must use that strength to speak for those who are rarely understood. Rise to the occasion, and reveal to true might of the wild.</p>
                <div element="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WILD_SPEAKER_PRIMAL_CHAMPIONS" />
                <div element="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WILD_SPEAKER_BEAST_TONGUE" />
                <div element="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WILD_SPEAKER_FERAL_PURSUIT" />
                <div element="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WILD_SPEAKER_ANCIENT_SPEECH" />
                <div element="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WILD_SPEAKER_PRIMAL_HEART" />
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WILD_SPEAKER_PRIMAL_CHAMPIONS" level="3" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WILD_SPEAKER_BEAST_TONGUE" level="3" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WILD_SPEAKER_FERAL_PURSUIT" level="6" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WILD_SPEAKER_ANCIENT_SPEECH" level="10" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WILD_SPEAKER_PRIMAL_HEART" level="15" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Primal Champions" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Castellan" id="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WILD_SPEAKER_PRIMAL_CHAMPIONS">
                <description>
                    <p>When you choose this archetype at 3rd level, your words harken to the ancient truths of the wilderness. Your Castellan’s Presence improves in the following ways:</p>
                    <ul>
                        <li><strong>Assault:</strong> The attack deals an extra 1d6 damage, and the creature’s jump height and distance become equal to its speed during the current turn.</li>
                        <li><strong>Maneuver:</strong> The creature gains a climbing speed equal to its walking speed, and it ignores difficult terrain.</li>
                        <li><strong>Defend:</strong> If an attack misses the creature when it uses a feint point, it can immediately move up to its speed without provoking opprotunity attacks.</li>
                        <li><strong>Expose:</strong> If the creature takes damage, strong winds push it up to 15 feet in a horizontal direction of your choosing.</li>
                    </ul>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>Your Castellan’s Presence improves in the following ways. Assault: The attack deals an extra 1d6 damage, and the creature’s jump height and distance become equal to its speed during the current turn. Maneuver: The creature gains a climbing speed equal to its walking speed, and it ignores difficult terrain. Defend: If an attack misses the creature when it uses a feint point, it can immediately move up to its speed without provoking opprotunity attacks. Expose: If the creature takes damage, strong winds push it up to 15 feet in a horizontal direction of your choosing.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Beast Tongue" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Castellan" id="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WILD_SPEAKER_BEAST_TONGUE">
                <description>
                    <p>Also at 3rd level, you can cast <em>speak with animals</em> at will without using a spell slot. Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for this spell.</p>
                    <div class="reference">
                        <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_ANIMALS" />
                    </div>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>You can cast speak with animals at will without using a spell slot. Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for this spell.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_ANIMALS" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Feral Pursuit" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Castellan" id="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WILD_SPEAKER_FERAL_PURSUIT">
                <description>
                    <p>At 6th level, your howling cries call for your companions to hunt. When you use your Aptitude feature to move a hostile creature, friendly creatures of your choosing can use their reactions to move up to their speed towards that hostile creature at any time during its movement.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>When you use your Aptitude feature to move a hostile creature, friendly creatures of your choosing can use their reactions to move up to their speed towards that hostile creature at any time during its movement.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Ancient Speech" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Castellan" id="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WILD_SPEAKER_ANCIENT_SPEECH">
                <description>
                    <p>At 10th level, you learn to speak to the world itself, changing and shaping it to your will. You can perform a 10-minute ritual to call to the earth around you in a 300-foot radius sphere centered on you. Within this area, you can freely manipulate natural terrain over the duration, which gradually and harmlessly changes to suit your desired configuration. You can create earthen structures, cause existing plants to grow or recede, create pits or caverns, or otherwise manipulate the terrain in a manner of your choosing.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                    <description>You can perform a 10-minute ritual to call to the earth around you in a 300-foot radius sphere centered on you. Within this area, you can freely manipulate natural terrain over the duration, which gradually and harmlessly changes to suit your desired configuration. You can create earthen structures, cause existing plants to grow or recede, create pits or caverns, or otherwise manipulate the terrain in a manner of your choosing.</description>
                    <description level="20" usage="1/Short Rest">You can perform a 10-minute ritual to call to the earth around you in a 300-foot radius sphere centered on you. Within this area, you can freely manipulate natural terrain over the duration, which gradually and harmlessly changes to suit your desired configuration. You can create earthen structures, cause existing plants to grow or recede, create pits or caverns, or otherwise manipulate the terrain in a manner of your choosing.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Primal Heart" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Castellan" id="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WILD_SPEAKER_PRIMAL_HEART">
                <description>
                    <p>At 15th level, your intrinsic connection to the raw, natural world allows you unlock the power that lies dormant within all things, including yourself. When you use your Castellan’s Presence feature, you can now use any of the options during your turn, granting those benefits to yourself instead. Additionally, you gain the following option for your Castellan’s Presence feature.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><strong>Blood Frenzy:</strong> The creature whose turn it is becomes filled with primeval power and swiftness. During its turn, its melee attacks can target a second creature of its choosing within its reach. Make a single attack roll for both targets.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>When you use your Castellan’s Presence feature, you can now use any of the options during your turn, granting those benefits to yourself instead. Additionally, you gain the following option for your Castellan’s Presence feature. Blood Frenzy: The creature whose turn it is becomes filled with primeval power and swiftness. During its turn, its melee attacks can target a second creature of its choosing within its reach. Make a single attack roll for both targets.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>

        
        <element name="Shadowed Conspirator" type="Archetype" source="The Castellan" id="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_ARCHETYPE_CASTELLAN_SHADOWED_CONSPIRATOR">
            <supports>Castellanic Archetype</supports>
            <description>
                <p>There are many disreputable organizations that lurk in the shadows of the world, doing the things that others would deem underhanded, unwholesome, and unwelcome. You operate outside the traditional rules and structures, using methods and tools that are shunned and banned, and you surround yourself with equally unscrupulous individuals from all walks of life. Castellans like you are those that whisper in the dark and pull the strings of the lives around them, severing those strings only when a puppet has outlived their usefulness. Walk in the night without fear, for those that dwell within it shall answer your forbidden call.</p>
                <div element="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOWED_CONSPIRATOR_DARK_OPERATIVES" />
                <div element="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOWED_CONSPIRATOR_CUNNING_MISDIRECTION" />
                <div element="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOWED_CONSPIRATOR_WICKED_WHISPERS" />
                <div element="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOWED_CONSPIRATOR_WEB_OF_SECRETS" />
                <div element="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOWED_CONSPIRATOR_PAWNS_AND_KINGS" />
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOWED_CONSPIRATOR_DARK_OPERATIVES" level="3" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOWED_CONSPIRATOR_CUNNING_MISDIRECTION" level="3" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOWED_CONSPIRATOR_WICKED_WHISPERS" level="6" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOWED_CONSPIRATOR_WEB_OF_SECRETS" level="10" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOWED_CONSPIRATOR_PAWNS_AND_KINGS" level="15" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Dark Operatives" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Castellan" id="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOWED_CONSPIRATOR_DARK_OPERATIVES">
                <description>
                    <p>When you choose this archetype at 3rd level, your schemes and plans weave wicked webs. Your Castellan’s Presence improves in the following ways:</p>
                    <ul>
                        <li><strong>Assault:</strong> The creature can teleport up to half its speed to a location it can see instead of moving. The creature can choose to cast a cantrip instead of making a weapon attack, provided it hasn’t cast a cantrip this turn. If it was hidden, it remains hidden until after it attacks, and the attack deals an extra 1d10 damage on a hit.</li>
                        <li><strong>Maneuver:</strong> The creature can choose to Hide without using its action at any point during its current turn.</li>
                        <li><strong>Defend:</strong> If the creature uses a feint point in response to being attacked, the attacker has disadvantage on attack rolls targeting other creatures until the start of this creature’s next turn.</li>
                        <li><strong>Expose:</strong> If the creature takes damage, its movement speed is halved until the start of its next turn.</li>
                    </ul>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>Your Castellan’s Presence improves in the following ways. Assault:  The creature can teleport up to half its speed to a location it can see instead of moving. The creature can choose to cast a cantrip instead of making a weapon attack, provided it hasn’t cast a cantrip this turn. If it was hidden, it remains hidden until after it attacks, and the attack deals an extra 1d10 damage on a hit. Maneuver: The creature can choose to Hide without using its action at any point during its current turn. Defend: If the creature uses a feint point in response to being attacked, the attacker has disadvantage on attack rolls targeting other creatures until the start of this creature’s next turn. Expose: If the creature takes damage, its movement speed is halved until the start of its next turn.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Cunning Misdirection" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Castellan" id="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOWED_CONSPIRATOR_CUNNING_MISDIRECTION">
                <description>
                    <p>Also at 3rd level, while you are hidden, you are invisible to creatures that are more than 30 feet away from you.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>While you are hidden, you are invisible to creatures that are more than 30 feet away from you.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Wicked Whispers" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Castellan" id="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOWED_CONSPIRATOR_WICKED_WHISPERS">
                <description>
                    <p>At 6th level, you learn cripple your foes with confusion and doubt. When you use your Aptitude feature to move a creature, you can cause the creature to fall prone at any point during its movement, ending the movement.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>When you use your Aptitude feature to move a creature, you can cause the creature to fall prone at any point during its movement, ending the movement.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Web of Secrets" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Castellan" id="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOWED_CONSPIRATOR_WEB_OF_SECRETS">
                <description>
                    <p>At 10th level, your studies have unlocked the secrets of certain subtle mental magics. You can cast <em>sending</em> at will without using a spell slot. Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for this spell.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Additionally, you can communicate telepathically with creatures with whom you share a language that are within 120 feet of you. While you are communicating with a friendly creature, it can use your Intelligence modifier and profiencies in place of its Charisma modifier for ability checks and rolls made against creatures other than you, and it can add your proficiency bonus to Charisma checks it makes if it does not add its own.</p>
                    <div class="reference">
                        <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_SENDING" />
                    </div>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>You can cast sending at will without using a spell slot. Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for this spell. Additionally, you can communicate telepathically with creatures with whom you share a language that are within 120 feet of you. While you are communicating with a friendly creature, it can use your Intelligence modifier and profiencies in place of its Charisma modifier for ability checks and rolls made against creatures other than you, and it can add your proficiency bonus to Charisma checks it makes if it does not add its own.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SENDING" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Pawns and Kings" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Castellan" id="ID_GFP_CASTELLAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOWED_CONSPIRATOR_PAWNS_AND_KINGS">
                <description>
                    <p>At 15th level, your master plan is set in motion. You can use your Quick Study and Masterful Instruction features with any number of other creatures.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Additionally, you gain the following option for your Castellan’s Presence feature.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><strong>Deadly Coincidence:</strong> The next time this turn the creature whose turn it is misses with an attack, you can choose another creature (other than the attacker) that you can see that is within the attack’s reach or range. Reroll the attack against the new target.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>You can use your Quick Study and Masterful Instruction features with any number of other creatures. Additionally, you gain the following option for your Castellan’s Presence feature. Deadly Coincidence: The next time this turn the creature whose turn it is misses with an attack, you can choose another creature (other than the attacker) that you can see that is within the attack’s reach or range. Reroll the attack against the new target.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>

    <!-- Castellan skills -->
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ARCANA">
        <supports>Castellan</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ATHLETICS">
        <supports>Castellan</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_HISTORY">
        <supports>Castellan</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT">
        <supports>Castellan</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INTIMIDATION">
        <supports>Castellan</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_NATURE">
        <supports>Castellan</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERSUASION">
        <supports>Castellan</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_STEALTH">
        <supports>Castellan</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SURVIVAL">
        <supports>Castellan</supports>
    </append>
</elements>