<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Dancer</name>
        <author url="https://www.dmsguild.com/product/205334/The-Dancer-5e-Class">Johnny Tek</author>
        <update version="0.1.4">
            <file name="class-dancer.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/classes/class-dancer.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Dancer" type="Class" source="DMs Guild" id="ID_DMGUILD_CLASS_DANCER">
        <supports />
        <requirements />
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">First a click. Then a soft tap. Then descending ribbons of prismatic luminescence begin to surround the form of a half-elf maiden as she gives in to the rhythm of her soul. The glowing ribbons are conjured by the half-elf ’s intricate movements as she moves arms, legs, hips, and torso to the music of magical rapture. Clashing sounds of battle that filled the air just seconds ago fall to silence; in the moment there is not but a faint hum and the half-elf ’s steps as everyone in the room stares helplessly at the patterns of light brought about by the hypnotic spell.</p>
            <p class="flavor">The lanky tiefling stamps his feet down and brings his sword to bear. As the nearby ogre lunges downwards and sideways with its club, the tiefling jumps and twirls with evasive athleticism. Speaking a few arcane syllables, the tiefling’s movements speed up, and his blade swings become an elegant storm of lethal movements. The ogre will soon be riddled with bloody gashes as its opponent launches into a reaper’s dance.</p>
            <p class="flavor">The tabaxi looks on as her dwarf friend faces a daunting challenge. The much larger lizardman is large even for his kind, and the weight superiority over the dwarf is showing in the exchange of blows. The dwarf is barely standing his ground and will soon lose his footing. The tabaxi lets out a soft purr as she begins to twirl her arms in a smooth wavy motion. The tabaxi then points her hand towards the lizardman and imagines invisible tendrils of magical force interfering with his movements - pushing, pulling, prodding. The lizardman suddenly swings his greatsword much wider than intended, leaving his neck open for the dwarf ’s hefty axe.</p>
            <p class="indent">Dancers breathe and glide through an ocean of magic that they are trained to perceive from the very beginning of their studies. They combine this perception with the direction of their physical being to apply their aesthetic nuances and create beautiful arcana.</p>
            <h4>ART OF THE FLOW</h4>
            <p>Magic courses through all things in existence, and it is possible to read its flow as well as redirect it at will. This is the primary foundation of the dancer’s art. The arcane energies of the universe are like a well of paint, and the dancer’s body is the brush used to craft the paintings. Every single step, gesture, turn, and twist in a dancer’s repertoire adds to an enduring legacy of their magical tradition.</p>
            <p class="indent">Just as a Weave of underlying rules and principles (determined by the deity of magic) governs the shaping of magic, there is a Flow of eldritch force that fuels the very existence of magic. The Flow is like a turbulent crossing of rivers that has no set directions until it is tapped into by guiding forces.</p>
            <p class="indent">Unlike wizards, sorcerers, warlocks, and the like who tap into the Flow by forceful grip, the dancers read and smoothly redirect the Flow with gentle nudges. As such, though their magical prowess may pale in comparison to the mighty archmages, their perception of magic itself is virtually unrivaled in depth among practitioners of spell casting. Legends tell of dancers who had progressed so far in their perception of magic that they could sense and dodge the paths of harmful spells sent from miles away.</p>
            <h4>PROUD TRADITION</h4>
            <p>Out of the many performers called "dancers" in the world, very few actually practice the incorporation of magic into their choreographies. The artists that do practice magical dance techniques are often termed "Dancer dancers" or "spell dancers" to differentiate them from the rest. The rarity of their like has made the magic-using dancers the subject of many stories and songs to amuse and delight the masses.</p>
            <p class="indent">Contributing to the rarity is the fact that the dancers’ magical techniques are closely guarded secrets that are only shared with trusted friends, loved ones, and disciples. The art of magical dance is one that was originally created for spiritual purposes, to know oneself more deeply and become closer to the ancestors or the gods, so most dancers will be cautious not to teach those who would abuse the magic of dance for corrupt reasons. There is pride and camaraderie among the dancers as the preservers of a great legacy of magic and performance art.</p>
            <h4>CREATING A DANCER</h4>
            <p>The most revered of dancers have all striven to master their own hearts through their craft and opened their senses to the Flow as much as possible unto their dying breaths. By becoming one with the Flow, a dancer can awaken to the hidden truths of one’s own feelings and desires. The art of dance is about opening the doors of emotion and channeling the soul into movement and mastering a relationship with the Flow is a way of facilitating such release.</p>
            <p class="indent">Experience in the world is important to the growth and development of a dancer’s personal choreography and style. The dancer’s individualistic, explorative nature is suited to the life of a traveler or adventurer, so they can be found in roaming caravans, performance troupes, or adventuring parties. With every memory of their journeys giving further shape to their dance, most dancers will continue to visit new places and meet new peoples until their bodies are too frail to travel, or until they retire from their craft to either teach or raise families of their own. Typical overarching motivations for an adventuring dancer are to seek out other dancers to exchange ideas, to visit exotic locations for inspiration, or to build reputations as performers in their favored regions.</p>
            <h5>QUICK BUILD</h5>
            <p>You can make a dancer quickly by following these suggestions. First, make Dexterity your highest ability score, followed by Wisdom. Second, choose the entertainer background.</p>
            <h4>MULTICLASSING</h4>
            <p>To qualify for advancing in multiclass levels of dancer, you must have a Dexterity score of 13 or higher and a Wisdom score of 13 or higher (*Player’s Handbook*, chapter 6)</p>
            <h5>MULTICLASSING PROFICIENCIES</h5>
            <p>When you gain a level of dancer, you become proficient with simple weapons and martial weapons.</p>
            <h5>MULTICLASS SPELLCASTER</h5>
            <p>Each level of dancer is treated as 1/2 level of multiclass spellcaster for the purpose of determining available spell slots (*Player’s Handbook*, chapter 6).</p>
            <h2>CLASS FEATURES</h2>
            <p>As an class, you gain the following class features.</p>
            <h5>HIT POINTS</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Hit Dice:</strong> 1d8 per dancer level</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at 1st Level:</strong> 8 + your Constitution modifier</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at Higher Levels:</strong> 1d8 (or 5) + your Constitution modifier per dancer level after 1st</li>
            </ul>
            <h5>PROFICIENCIES</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Armor:</strong> None</li>
                <li><strong>Weapons:</strong> Simple weapons, martial weapons</li>
                <li><strong>Tools:</strong> None</li>
            </ul>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Saving Throws:</strong> Dexterity, Wisdom</li>
                <li><strong>Skills:</strong> Choose three from Acrobatics, Arcana, Athletics, Endurance, History, Insight, Perception, Performance, Religion, Sleight of Hand, and Stealth.</li>
            </ul>
            <h5>EQUIPMENT</h5>
            <p>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>(a) A light crossbow and 20 bolts, or (b) any martial weapon</li>
                <li>(a) An entertainer’s pack, or (b) an explorer’s pack</li>
                <li>Any martial melee weapon, two daggers, and an arcane focus</li>
            </ul>
            <h5>STARTING GOLD</h5>
            <p>A dancer starts with 4d4 x 10 gp.</p>

            <div element="ID_DMGUILD_CLASS_FEATURE_DANCER_FLOW_TRANCE" />
            <div element="ID_DMGUILD_CLASS_FEATURE_DANCER_UNARMORED_DEFENSE" />
            <div element="ID_DMGUILD_CLASS_FEATURE_DANCER_BEWITCHING_DANCE" />
            <div element="ID_DMGUILD_CLASS_FEATURE_DANCER_SPELLCASTING" />
            <div element="ID_DMGUILD_CLASS_FEATURE_DANCER_DANCERS_FLOW" />
            <div element="ID_DMGUILD_CLASS_FEATURE_DANCER_ELDRITCH_RHYTHM" />
            <div element="ID_DMGUILD_CLASS_FEATURE_DANCER_EXTRA_ATTACK" />
            <div element="ID_DMGUILD_CLASS_FEATURE_DANCER_EVASION" />
            <div element="ID_DMGUILD_CLASS_FEATURE_DANCER_FLOW_SENSE" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description>A warrior that casts spells and moves across the battlefield with supernatural agility. </description>
        </sheet>
        <setters>
          <set name="short">A warrior that casts spells and moves across the battlefield with supernatural agility. </set>
          <set name="hd">d8</set>
          <set name="spellcaster">true</set>
          <set name="spellcastingAbility">Wisdom</set>
        </setters>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" requirements="!ID_DMGUILD_MULTICLASS_DANCER" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_MARTIAL_WEAPONS" requirements="!ID_DMGUILD_MULTICLASS_DANCER" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_WISDOM" requirements="!ID_DMGUILD_MULTICLASS_DANCER" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_DEXTERITY" requirements="!ID_DMGUILD_MULTICLASS_DANCER" />
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency (Dancer)" supports="Skill,Dancer" number="3" requirements="!ID_DMGUILD_MULTICLASS_DANCER" />

            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_DMGUILD_CLASS_FEATURE_DANCER_FLOW_TRANCE" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_DMGUILD_CLASS_FEATURE_DANCER_UNARMORED_DEFENSE" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_DMGUILD_CLASS_FEATURE_DANCER_BEWITCHING_DANCE" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_DMGUILD_CLASS_FEATURE_DANCER_SPELLCASTING" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_DMGUILD_CLASS_FEATURE_DANCER_DANCERS_FLOW" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_DMGUILD_CLASS_FEATURE_DANCER_ELDRITCH_RHYTHM" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_DANCER_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT_DANCER" level="4" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_DMGUILD_CLASS_FEATURE_DANCER_EXTRA_ATTACK" level="5" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_DMGUILD_CLASS_FEATURE_DANCER_EVASION" level="7" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_DMGUILD_CLASS_FEATURE_DANCER_FLOW_SENSE" level="10" />
        </rules>
        <multiclass id="ID_DMGUILD_MULTICLASS_DANCER">
            <prerequisite>Dexterity 13 and Wisdom 13</prerequisite>
            <requirements>([dex:13],[wis:13])</requirements>
            <setters>
                <set name="multiclass proficiencies">Simple weapons, martial weapons</set>
            </setters>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_MARTIAL_WEAPONS" />
            </rules>
        </multiclass>
    </element>

    <element name="Flow Trance" type="Class Feature" source="DMs Guild" id="ID_DMGUILD_CLASS_FEATURE_DANCER_FLOW_TRANCE">
        <description>
            <p>When you dance, you are able to attune yourself to the Flow of magic and move to the intuitive directions of its currents. You add your Wisdom modifier (minimum +1) to Charisma (Performance) checks made when you dance.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You add your Wisdom modifier (minimum +1) to Charisma (Performance) checks made when you dance.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="Unarmored Defense" type="Class Feature" source="DMs Guild" id="ID_DMGUILD_CLASS_FEATURE_DANCER_UNARMORED_DEFENSE">
        <description>
            <p>While you are not wearing any armor, your Armor Class equals 10 + your Dexterity modifier + your Wisdom modifier.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>While you are not wearing any armor, your Armor Class {{ac:unarmored defense dancer}}.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
          <stat name="ac:unarmored defense dancer:base" value="10" />
          <stat name="ac:unarmored defense dancer:dexterity" value="dexterity:modifier" />
          <stat name="ac:unarmored defense dancer:constitution" value="wisdom:modifier" />

          <stat name="ac:unarmored defense dancer" value="ac:unarmored defense dancer:base" />
          <stat name="ac:unarmored defense dancer" value="ac:unarmored defense dancer:dexterity" />
          <stat name="ac:unarmored defense dancer" value="ac:unarmored defense dancer:constitution" />

          <stat name="ac:calculation" value="ac:unarmored defense dancer" bonus="calculation" equipped="[armor:none]" alt="Unarmored Defense (Dancer)" />
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Bewitching Dance" type="Class Feature" source="DMs Guild" id="ID_DMGUILD_CLASS_FEATURE_DANCER_BEWITCHING_DANCE">
        <description>
            <p>You can alter the flow of magic (and the reality that it is connected to) in your surroundings to hinder or distract others. To do so, you use a reaction when one creature (within 60 feet of you that you can see) makes an attack, ability check, or saving throw.</p>
            <p class="indent">After the result is determined, you can roll a die (d6 at 1st level) and subtract your roll from the target creature’s result.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier (a minimum of once). You regain any expended uses when you finish a long rest.</p>
            <p class="indent">Your bewitching Dance die changes when you reach certain levels in this class. The die becomes a d8 at 5th level, a d10 at 10th level, and a d12 at 15th level.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can’t use this feature while grappled, prone, or restrained.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="{{bewitching-dance:count}}/Long Rest" action="Reaction">
            <description>You use your reaction when one creature that you can see within 60 feet of you makes an attack, ability check, or saving throw to hinder or distract others. You can roll a d{{bewitching-dance:dice}} and subtract your roll from the target creature’s result. You can’t do this while grappled, prone, or restrained.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        <stat name="bewitching-dance:count" value="1" bonus="bewitching dance"/>
        <stat name="bewitching-dance:count" value="wisdom:modifier" bonus="bewitching dance"/>
        
        <stat name="bewitching-dance:dice" value="6" bonus="bewitching dance" />
        <stat name="bewitching-dance:dice" value="8" bonus="bewitching dance" level="5" />
        <stat name="bewitching-dance:dice" value="10" bonus="bewitching dance" level="10" />
        <stat name="bewitching-dance:dice" value="12" bonus="bewitching dance" level="15" />
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Spellcasting" type="Class Feature" source="DMs Guild" id="ID_DMGUILD_CLASS_FEATURE_DANCER_SPELLCASTING">
        <description>
            <p>By 2nd level, you’ve learned to cast magic spells by moving in synchronization with the flow of magic around you and influencing its direction with your personal rhythm. See chapter 10 of the *Player’s Handbook* for general rules of spellcasting.</p>
            <p class="indent">For a list of spells the dancer can learn, see Dancer Spell List on page 10 of the Dancer class.</p>
            <h5>SPELL SLOTS</h5>
            <p>The Dancer table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your spells of 1st level or higher. To cast one of these spells, you must expend a slot of the spell’s level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.</p>
            <p class="indent">For example, if you know the 1st-level spell cure wounds and have a 1st-level and a 2nd-level spell slot available, you can cast cure wounds using either slot.</p>
            <h5>SPELLS KNOWN OF 1ST LEVEL AND HIGHER</h5>
            <p>You know two 1st-level spells of your choice from the dancer spell list.</p>
            <p class="indent">The Spells Known column of the Dancer table shows when you learn more dancer spells of your choice. Each of these spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots, as shown on the table. For instance, when you reach 5th level in this class, you can learn one new spell of 1st or 2nd level.</p>
            <p class="indent">Additionally, when you gain a level in this class, you can choose one of the dancer spells you know and replace it with another spell from the dancer spell list, which also must be of a level for which you have spell slots.</p>
            <h5>SPELLCASTING ABILITY</h5>
            <p>Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for your dancer spells. You use your Wisdom whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. in addition, you use your Wisdom modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a dancer spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.</p>
            <p><b>Spell Save DC</b> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier</p>
            <p><b>Spell Attack Modifier</b> = your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier</p>
            <h5>SPELLCASTING FOCUS</h5>
            <p>You can use an arcane focus as a spellcasting focus for your dancer spells.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description>You have learned to manipulate the weave of magic with your dancing.</description>
        </sheet>
        <spellcasting name="Dancer" ability="Wisdom" prepare="false">
            <list>Dancer</list>
        </spellcasting>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS_SPELLCASTING_SLOTS_HALF" requirements="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS"/>
            
            <stat name="dancer:spellcasting:slots:1" value="2" level="2" />
            <stat name="dancer:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="3" />
            <stat name="dancer:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="5" />
            <stat name="dancer:spellcasting:slots:2" value="2" level="5" />
            <stat name="dancer:spellcasting:slots:2" value="1" level="7" />
            <stat name="dancer:spellcasting:slots:3" value="2" level="9" />
            <stat name="dancer:spellcasting:slots:3" value="1" level="11" />
            <stat name="dancer:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="13" />
            <stat name="dancer:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="15" />
            <stat name="dancer:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="17" />
            <stat name="dancer:spellcasting:slots:5" value="1" level="17" />
            <stat name="dancer:spellcasting:slots:5" value="1" level="19" />
            
            <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Dancer)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="2" number="2" spellcasting="Dancer"/>
            <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Dancer)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="3" spellcasting="Dancer"/>
            <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Dancer)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="5" spellcasting="Dancer"/>
            <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Dancer)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="7" spellcasting="Dancer"/>
            <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Dancer)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="9" spellcasting="Dancer"/>
            <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Dancer)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="11" spellcasting="Dancer"/>
            <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Dancer)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="13" spellcasting="Dancer"/>
            <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Dancer)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="15" spellcasting="Dancer"/>
            <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Dancer)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="17" spellcasting="Dancer"/>
            <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Dancer)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="19" spellcasting="Dancer"/>
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Dancer’s Flow" type="Class Feature" source="DMs Guild" id="ID_DMGUILD_CLASS_FEATURE_DANCER_DANCERS_FLOW">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 2nd level, you’ve learned to sense the flow of magic that permeates all things in existence, and you are able to draw energy from it to enhance your agility.</p>
            <p class="indent">You gain 2 flow points, which can be expended to augment your movements. You gain an additional flow point when you gain a level as a dancer.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once during your turn, you can expend 1 flow point to move a distance equal to half your speed; this movement does not count towards your expended movement for the turn and does not provoke attacks of opportunity.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can expend 1 flow point to gain advantage on a Strength (Athletics) check, Dexterity (Acrobatics) check, or Charisma (Performance) check (made to dance).</p>
            <p class="indent">You regain all expended flow points at the end of a short rest or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You have {{flow-points}} flow points. You can spend 1 flow point to move and additional distance equal to half your movement speed or gain advantage on a Strength (Athletics), Dexterity (Acrobatics) or Charisma (Performance) check.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="flow-points" value="level:dancer" />
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Eldritch Rhythm" type="Class Feature" source="DMs Guild" id="ID_DMGUILD_CLASS_FEATURE_DANCER_ELDRITCH_RHYTHM">
        <description>
            <p>When you reach 3rd level, you begin exploring a style of magical dance that either suits your individual aesthetic or is passed on to you from a teacher. You choose an Eldritch Rhythm from which to gain features for your dancer class advancement.</p>
            <p class="indent">Your choice grants you features at 3rd level and again at 6th, 11th, 14th, and 20th level.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet />
        <rules>
            <select type="Archetype" name="Eldritch Rhythm" supports="Eldritch Rhythm" />
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Ability Score Improvement" type="Class Feature" source="DMs Guild" id="ID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_DANCER_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT_DANCER">
        <description>
            <p>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Dancer 4)" supports="Improvement Option,Dancer,4" level="4" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Dancer 8)" supports="Improvement Option,Dancer,8" level="8" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Dancer 12)" supports="Improvement Option,Dancer,12" level="12" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Dancer 16)" supports="Improvement Option,Dancer,16" level="16" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Dancer 19)" supports="Improvement Option,Dancer,19" level="19" />
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Extra Attack" type="Class Feature" source="DMs Guild" id="ID_DMGUILD_CLASS_FEATURE_DANCER_EXTRA_ATTACK">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 5th level, when you use the Attack action, you can make a second attack as part of the action. You can choose the same or different target for the second attack.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description level="5">You can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="extra attack:count" value="2" level="5" bonus="extra attack" />
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Evasion" type="Class Feature" source="DMs Guild" id="ID_DMGUILD_CLASS_FEATURE_DANCER_EVASION">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 7th level, your enhanced senses help you to perceive incoming danger and dodge the brunt of area effects, such as a red dragon’s fire breath or a lightning bolt spell. When you are subjected to an effect that allows you to make a Dexterity saving throw to take only half damage, you instead take no damage if you succeed on the saving throw, and only half damage if you fail.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you are subjected to an effect that allows you to make a Dexterity saving throw to take only half damage, you instead take no damage if you succeed on the saving throw, and only half damage if you fail.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="Flow Sense" type="Class Feature" source="DMs Guild" id="ID_DMGUILD_CLASS_FEATURE_DANCER_FLOW_SENSE">
        <description>
            <p>At 10th level, your attuned senses can pick up on the slightest hint of hostile magic coming your way. Whenever a spell attack is made against you, or you must make a saving throw against a spell’s effect, you can expend 1 flow point as a reaction to grant disadvantage to the spell attack or gain advantage on your saving throw.</p>
            <p class="indent">At 18th level, you can also move up to half your speed when you use your Flow Sense feature; if this would remove you as an eligible target of a spell attack, then the spell attack automatically misses; if this would remove you from a spell’s area of effect, then the spell still activates but you are unaffected by it. This movement does not provoke opportunity attacks.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Reaction">
            <description level="10">Whenever a spell attack is made against you, or you must make a saving throw against a spell’s effect, you can expend 1 flow point as a reaction to grant disadvantage to the spell attack or gain advantage on your saving throw.</description>
            <description level="18">Whenever a spell attack is made against you, or you must make a saving throw against a spell’s effect, you can expend 1 flow point as a reaction to grant disadvantage to the spell attack or gain advantage on your saving throw. You can also move up to half your speed when you use your Flow Sense feature; if this would remove you as an eligible target of a spell attack, then the spell attack automatically misses; if this would remove you from a spell’s area of effect, then the spell still activates but you are unaffected by it. This movement does not provoke opportunity attacks.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="Rhythm of the Battle Dancer" type="Archetype" source="DMs Guild" id="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_RHYTHM_OF_THE_BATTLE_DANCER">
        <supports>Eldritch Rhythm</supports>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">To become one with both the Flow and the blade is to expand the horizon of possibility. The extension of self through the weapons we wield grants us great flexibility to explore the paths of our souls.</p>
            <p class="indent">The art of battle dancing is born from a veneration of war gods and the heroic sacrifices of warriors who died in battle. Battle dancers place a strong focus on martial training to complement their dancing style. A wielded weapon is considered as a part of the battle dancer’s body, with the battle dancer’s choreography incorporating this principle fiercely.</p>
            <p class="indent">Battle dancers have a strong reputation as bodyguards or assassins, using their dance as a way to hide their lethal skills behind the disguise of performance art. Hostile foes who underestimate the martial prowess of a battle dancer do not usually live long enough to continue their folly.</p>
            <div element="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTBD_FIGHTING_STYLE" />
            <div element="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTBD_WHIRLING_FLURRY" />
            <div element="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTBD_DEFENSIVE_DANCE" />
            <div element="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTBD_BEWITCHED_OPPORTUNITY" />
            <div element="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTBD_EXTRA_ATTACK" />
            <div element="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTBD_DEATH_DANCER" />
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTBD_FIGHTING_STYLE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTBD_WHIRLING_FLURRY" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTBD_DEFENSIVE_DANCE" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTBD_BEWITCHED_OPPORTUNITY" level="11" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTBD_EXTRA_ATTACK" level="14" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTBD_DEATH_DANCER" level="20" />
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Fighting Style" type="Archetype Feature" source="DMs Guild" id="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTBD_FIGHTING_STYLE">
        <description>
            <p>At 3rd level, you adopt a particular style of fighting as your specialty. Choose one of the following options. You can’t take a Fighting Style option more than once, even if you later get to choose again.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b>Dueling.</b> When you are wielding a melee weapon in one hand and no other weapons, you gain a +2 bonus to damage rolls with that weapon.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b>Great Weapon Fighting.</b> When you roll a 1 or 2 on a damage die for an attack you make with a melee weapon that you are wielding with two hands, you can reroll the die and must use the new roll, even if the new roll is a 1 or a 2. The weapon must have the two-handed or versatile property for you to gain this benefit.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b>Two-Weapon Fighting.</b> When you engage in two-weapon fighting, you can add your ability modifier to the damage of the second attack.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Fighting Style" supports="Fighting Style,Dancer" />
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Whirling Flurry" type="Archetype Feature" source="DMs Guild" id="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTBD_WHIRLING_FLURRY">
        <description>
            <p>At 3rd level, you can channel the Flow to guide your weapon swings with increased ferocity. When you use the Attack action, you can use a bonus action to make a melee weapon attack. If you are wielding two weapons, you can instead use this feature to make one attack each with both of your weapons on an opportunity attack.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier (a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="{{whirling-flurry:count}}">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="whirling-flurry:count" value="1" bonus="whirling flurry"/>
            <stat name="whirling-flurry:count" value="wisdom:modifier" bonus="whirling flurry"/>
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Defensive Dance" type="Archetype Feature" source="DMs Guild" id="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTBD_DEFENSIVE_DANCE">
        <description>
            <p>At 6th level, your connection to the Flow can guide you out of harm’s way at the last moment. You can expend 2 flow points as a reaction to gain a +4 bonus to AC against an attack made against you after the attack roll is made.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Reaction">
            <description>You can expend 2 flow points as a reaction to gain a +4 bonus to AC against an attack made against you after the attack roll is made.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="Bewitched Opportunity" type="Archetype Feature" source="DMs Guild" id="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTBD_BEWITCHED_OPPORTUNITY">
        <description>
            <p>At 11th level, when a creature affected by your bewitching Dance feature misses on an attack roll, you can use a reaction to move up to 5 feet and make a melee weapon attack against the affected creature if it is within range.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Reaction">
            <description>When a creature affected by your bewitching Dance feature misses on an attack roll, you can use a reaction to move up to 5 feet and make a melee weapon attack against the affected creature if it is within range.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="Extra Attack" type="Archetype Feature" source="DMs Guild" id="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTBD_EXTRA_ATTACK">
        <description>
            <p>At 14th level, when you use the Attack action, you can make a third attack as part of the action. You can choose the same or different target for the second attack.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="Death Dancer" type="Archetype Feature" source="DMs Guild" id="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTBD_DEATH_DANCER">
        <description>
            <p>At 20th level, you have mastered the final step of the battle dance, building up to a powerful final killing blow at the end of a sequence. If you score a normal hit against a creature with the attack granted by the Whirling Flurry feature, it is turned into a critical hit.</p>
            <p class="indent">In addition, you gain an additional two uses of Whirling Fury.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>A normal hit against a creature with the attack granted by Whirling Flurry is turned into a critical hit.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="whirling-flurry:count" bonus="whirling flurry" />
            <stat name="whirling-flurry:count" bonus="whirling flurry" />
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Rhythm of the Primal Song" type="Archetype" source="DMs Guild" id="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_RHYTHM_OF_THE_PRIMAL_SONG">
        <supports>Eldritch Rhythm</supports>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">The seasons come and go with each verse of nature’s song. The cycle of life continues with each turn of the Flow, and the children of nature thrive in its motion.</p>
            <p class="indent">There are legends of a primal song sung by the deities and spirits of nature in the earliest age of creation. It is said that pieces of the song were scattered throughout the Flow of magic, giving birth to new life wherever these remnants travel along the currents. The dancers who attune themselves to these remnants are known as primal seekers, and their dance is filled with nature’s magic.</p>
            <p class="indent">Primal seekers are often on journeys to visit natural locations of beauty, such as waterfalls, mountain summits, or crystal-filled caverns. They may sometimes be encountered as guides in the wilderness, or as ritual performers in the employ of rural villages and fey patrons. These dancers draw their inspiration from nature and acquire a magical affinity with the primal spirits in some ways similar to that of druids.</p>
            <div element="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTPS_NATURES_GIFT" />
            <div element="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTPS_RITE_OF_SPRING" />
            <div element="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTPS_RITE_OF_SUMMER" />
            <div element="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTPS_RITE_OF_AUTUMN" />
            <div element="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTPS_RITE_OF_WINTER" />
            <div element="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTPS_MASTER_OF_SEASONS" />
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTPS_NATURES_GIFT" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTPS_RITE_OF_SPRING" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTPS_RITE_OF_SUMMER" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTPS_RITE_OF_AUTUMN" level="11" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTPS_RITE_OF_WINTER" level="14" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTPS_MASTER_OF_SEASONS" level="20" />
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Nature’s Gift" type="Archetype Feature" source="DMs Guild" id="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTPS_NATURES_GIFT">
        <description>
            <p>At 3rd level, you learn the <i>druidcraft</i> cantrip and one druid cantrip of your choice. If you already know <i>druidcraft</i>, then you learn one druid cantrip of your choice instead of <i>druidcraft</i>. In addition, when you learn a new dancer spell, you can select the spell from the druid’s class spell list, and you can now use a druidic focus as a spellcasting focus for your dancer spells.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <spellcasting name="Dancer" extend="true">
            <extend>Druid</extend>
        </spellcasting>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DRUIDCRAFT" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Nature’s Gift)" supports="0,Druid" />
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Rite of Spring" type="Archetype Feature" source="DMs Guild" id="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTPS_RITE_OF_SPRING">
        <description>
            <p>At 3rd level, you learn the Rite of Spring, which celebrates new births and the hope brought about by new beginnings.</p>
            <p class="indent">You learn to cast <i>entangle</i> as a dancer spell; if you already know <i>entangle</i> then you learn one 1st level spell of your choice from the druid spell list as a dancer spell.</p>
            <p class="indent">In addition, when you use the Dancer’s Flow feature to move half your speed, you ignore difficult terrain for the movement.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you use Dancer’s Flow to move half your speed, you ignore difficult terrain for the movement.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENTANGLE" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Rite of Spring)" supports="1,Druid" />
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Rite of Summer" type="Archetype Feature" source="DMs Guild" id="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTPS_RITE_OF_SUMMER">
        <description>
            <p>At 6th level, you learn the Rite of Summer, which celebrates the vibrance of youth and the abundance of nature’s fruits.</p>
            <p class="indent">You learn to cast <i>cure wounds</i> and <i>goodberry</i> as dancer spells; if you already know either spell then you instead learn one 1st level spell of your choice (or two if you already know both spells) from the druid spell list as a dancer spell.</p>
            <p class="indent">In addition, when you cast a spell whose effect includes the regaining of hit points, you can expend 1 flow point to maximize the hit points regained.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can expend one flow point to maximize the hit points regained when you cast any spell that includes the regaining of hit points.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CURE_WOUNDS" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GOODBERRY" />
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Rite of Autumn" type="Archetype Feature" source="DMs Guild" id="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTPS_RITE_OF_AUTUMN">
        <description>
            <p>At 11th level, you learn the Rite of Autumn, which celebrates the lessons of age and the colors of change.</p>
            <p class="indent">When you take acid, cold, fire, lightning, or thunder damage, you can expend 2 flow points as a reaction to halve the damage and gain resistance to the damage’s type for 1 minute. If you use this feature again for a different damage type, you replace the resistance that you gained previously and refresh the duration to 1 minute.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Reaction">
            <description>When you take acid, cold, fire, lightning, or thunder damage, you can expend 2 flow points to halve the damage and gain resistance to that damange type for 1 minute. If you use this feature again, you replace the resistance previously gained.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="Rite of Winter" type="Archetype Feature" source="DMs Guild" id="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTPS_RITE_OF_WINTER">
        <description>
            <p>At 14th level, you learn the Rite of Winter, which celebrates the completion of life’s course and anticipation of the next generation’s birth.</p>
            <p class="indent">When your hit points reach 0, you automatically expend all of your remaining flow points and regain hit points equal to 1d6 per flow point.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When your hit points reach 0, you automatically expend all of your remaining flow points and regain hit points equal to 1d6 per flow point.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="Master of Seasons" type="Archetype Feature" source="DMs Guild" id="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTPS_MASTER_OF_SEASONS">
        <description>
            <p>At 20th level, you have completed your mastery of nature’s cycle, and gathered a remnant of the Primal Song into your very core as a dancer.</p>
            <p class="indent">You gain immunity to the charmed, deafened, frightened, paralyzed, and stunned conditions.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You have immunity to the charmed, deafened, frightened, paralyzed, and stunned conditions.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="Rhythm of the Seven Veils" type="Archetype" source="DMs Guild" id="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_RHYTHM_OF_THE_SEVEN_VEILS">
        <supports>Eldritch Rhythm</supports>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">There are seven virtues by which one can earn blessing. There are seven sins by which one can be damned. And then we have the seven beauties of magic, by which one can achieve perfection.</p>
            <p class="indent">The initiates of the seven veils dance tradition craft colorfully layered wards of magic over their own bodies, combining practical magic with a visual aesthetic. In a sense the seven veils dancers are as much painters as they are dancers, with every ward creation representing an individual’s personal artistry.</p>
            <p class="indent">Dancers of the seven veils rhythm are commonly known as seven veils initiates and are highly in demand among kings and nobles as entertainment for their parties. The visually pleasing nature of the seven veils technique is well suited for performance. These dancers pursue their mastery of aesthetic through the experimental blending of colors in their personal wards, or veils as they are commonly referred.</p>
            <div element="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTSV_VEILED_WARD" />
            <div element="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTSV_SUDDEN_VEILING" />
            <div element="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTSV_TRINITY_BLEND" />
            <div element="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTSV_COLOR_SHIFT" />
            <div element="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTSV_SUPREMACY_OF_SEVEN_VEILS" />
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTSV_VEILED_WARD" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTSV_SUDDEN_VEILING" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTSV_TRINITY_BLEND" level="11" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTSV_COLOR_SHIFT" level="14" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTSV_SUPREMACY_OF_SEVEN_VEILS" level="20" />
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Veiled Ward" type="Archetype Feature" source="DMs Guild" id="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTSV_VEILED_WARD">
        <description>
            <p>At 3rd level, you gain the ability to produce a ward that protects your body from harm or enhances your magic in some way. The ward appears as a collection of thin, translucent veils of various hues and patterns, with each subrange of color indicating a specific type of magical effect and produces dim light out to 10 feet.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can expend 1 flow point as a bonus action to craft a ward that surrounds and protects your body until it is dismissed, destroyed, or 1 hour has passed. You can dismiss your ward at any time without using an action. Crafting a new ward replaces the current one.</p>
            <p class="indent">When your ward is crafted, you gain a +2 bonus to AC and temporary hit points equal to 10 + your dancer level + your Wisdom modifier. When you no longer have temporary hit points, the ward is dismissed. When the ward is dismissed, you lose all of your temporary hit points.</p>
            <p class="indent">Choose one of the following colors when you craft the ward; each color has associated effects that are applied while the ward is active. You can add another color to your ward as a bonus action, up to a maximum of two.</p>
            <div element="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTSV_VEILED_WARD_RED" />
            <div element="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTSV_VEILED_WARD_ORANGE" />
            <div element="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTSV_VEILED_WARD_YELLOW" />
            <div element="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTSV_VEILED_WARD_GREEN" />
            <div element="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTSV_VEILED_WARD_BLUE" />
            <div element="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTSV_VEILED_WARD_INDIGO" />
            <div element="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTSV_VEILED_WARD_VIOLET" />
        </description>
        <sheet action="Bonus Action">
            <description>You gain {{veiled-ward:hp}} temporary hit points. You can expend 1 flow point to craft a ward that surrounds and protects your body until it is dismissed, destroyed, or 1 hour has passed. You can dismiss your ward at any time without using an action. Crafting a new ward replaces the current one. Choose one of the following colors when you craft the ward; each color has associated effects that are applied while the ward is active. You can add another color to your ward as a bonus action, up to a maximum of two.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="veiled-ward:hp" value="10" />
            <stat name="veiled-ward:hp" value="level:dancer" />
            <stat name="veiled-ward:hp" value="wisdom:modifier" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTSV_VEILED_WARD_RED" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTSV_VEILED_WARD_ORANGE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTSV_VEILED_WARD_YELLOW" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTSV_VEILED_WARD_GREEN" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTSV_VEILED_WARD_BLUE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTSV_VEILED_WARD_INDIGO" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTSV_VEILED_WARD_VIOLET" level="3" />
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Red" type="Archetype Feature" source="DMs Guild" id="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTSV_VEILED_WARD_RED">
        <description>
            <p>You have resistance to fire damage. If a creature hits you with a melee attack or attempts to grapple you, it takes 1d6 fire damage. A creature grappling you takes the damage again at the start of its turns.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="Orange" type="Archetype Feature" source="DMs Guild" id="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTSV_VEILED_WARD_ORANGE">
        <description>
            <p>You have resistance to acid damage. If a creature hits you with a melee attack or attempts to grapple you, it takes 1d6 acid damage. A creature grappling you takes the damage again at the start of its turns.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="Yellow" type="Archetype Feature" source="DMs Guild" id="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTSV_VEILED_WARD_YELLOW">
        <description>
            <p>You have resistance to lightning damage. If a creature hits you with a melee attack or attempts to grapple you, it takes 1d6 lightning damage. A creature grappling you takes the damage again at the start of its turns.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="Green" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTSV_VEILED_WARD_GREEN">
        <description>
            <p>You have resistance to poison damage. If a creature hits you with a melee attack or attempts to grapple you, it takes 1d6 poison damage. A creature grappling you takes the damage again at the start of its turns.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="Blue" type="Archetype Feature" source="DMs Guild" id="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTSV_VEILED_WARD_BLUE">
        <description>
            <p>You have resistance to cold damage. If a creature hits you with a melee attack or attempts to grapple you, it takes 1d6 cold damage. A creature grappling you takes the damage again at the start of its turns.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="Indigo" type="Archetype Feature" source="DMs Guild" id="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTSV_VEILED_WARD_INDIGO">
        <description>
            <p>You have advantage on saving throws against effects that would apply the restrained or petrified conditions. When you hit a creature with a melee attack, it must make a Constitution saving throw; on a failed save the creature is slowed until the end of its next turn.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="Violet" type="Archetype Feature" source="DMs Guild" id="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTSV_VEILED_WARD_VIOLET">
        <description>
            <p>You have advantage on saving throws against effects that would apply the blinded condition. You deal an extra 1d6 points of radiant damage on your melee weapon attacks against celestials, elementals, fey, fiends, and undead. The extra damage increases by another 2d6 against aberrations.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="Sudden Veiling" type="Archetype Feature" source="DMs Guild" id="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTSV_SUDDEN_VEILING">
        <description>
            <p>At 6th level, you can expend 1 flow point as a reaction to craft a Veiled Ward.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Reaction">
            <description>You can expend 1 flow point as a reaction to craft a Veiled Ward.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="Trinity Blend" type="Archetype Feature" source="DMs Guild" id="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTSV_TRINITY_BLEND">
        <description>
            <p>At 11th level, the maximum number of colors for your Veiled Ward is increased to three.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>The maximum number of colors for your Veiled Ward is increased to three.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="Color Shift" type="Archetype Feature" source="DMs Guild" id="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTSV_COLOR_SHIFT">
        <description>
            <p>At 14th level, you can change one of the colors of your current Veiled Ward as a bonus action on your turn.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Bonus Action">
            <description>You can change one of the colors of your current Veiled Ward as a bonus action on your turn.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="Supremacy of Seven Veils" type="Archetype Feature" source="DMs Guild" id="ID_DM_GUILD_ARCHETYPE_ROTSV_SUPREMACY_OF_SEVEN_VEILS">
        <description>
            <p>At 20th level, your Veiled Ward’s granted damage resistances are instead immunities. Indigo makes you immune to the restrained and petrified conditions. Violet makes you immune to the blinded condition.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Your Veiled Ward’s granted damage resistances are instead immunities</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

  <!-- Dancer Skills-->
  <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ACROBATICS">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ARCANA">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ATHLETICS">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ENDURANCE">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_HISTORY">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERFORMANCE">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_RELIGION">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SLIGHTOFHAND">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_STEALTH">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>

    <!-- Dancer Fighting Styles -->
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_DUELING">
        <supports>Dancer</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_GREAT_WEAPON_FIGHTING">
        <supports>Dancer</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_TWOWEAPON_FIGHTING">
        <supports>Dancer</supports>
    </append>

  <!-- Dancer Spell List -->
  <!-- Dancer 1st Level Spells -->
  <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ABSORB_ELEMENTS">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BANE">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLESS">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CAUSE_FEAR">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CHARM_PERSON">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COLOR_SPRAY">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMPREHEND_LANGUAGES">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CURE_WOUNDS">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_EVIL_AND_GOOD">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_MAGIC">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_POISON_AND_DISEASE">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISGUISE_SELF">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_EARTH_TREMOR">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_EXPEDITIOUS_RETREAT">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FAERIE_FIRE">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FALSE_LIFE">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FEATHER_FALL">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HEROISM">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HEX">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_IDENTIFY">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INFLICT_WOUNDS">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_JUMP">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LONGSTRIDER">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PROTECTION_FROM_EVIL_AND_GOOD">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SILENT_IMAGE">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SLEEP">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TASHAS_HIDEOUS_LAUGHTER">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ZEPHYR_STRIKE">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>

    <!-- Dancer 2nd Level Spells -->
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AID">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ALTER_SELF">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLINDNESS_DEAFNESS">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLUR">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CALM_EMOTIONS">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CROWN_OF_MADNESS">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DARKNESS">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DARKVISION">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_THOUGHTS">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_EARTHBIND">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENHANCE_ABILITY">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENLARGE_REDUCE">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENTHRALL">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GUST_OF_WIND">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INVISIBILITY">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LEVITATE">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGIC_WEAPON">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MIRROR_IMAGE">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MISTY_STEP">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PASS_WITHOUT_TRACE">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PHANTASMAL_FORCE">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_PYROTECHNICS">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ROPE_TRICK">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SEE_INVISIBILITY">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_SHADOW_BLADE">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SUGGESTION">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_WARDING_WIND">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ZONE_OF_TRUTH">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>

    <!-- Dancer 3rd Level Spells -->
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AURA_OF_VITALITY">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLINK">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_CATNAP">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COUNTERSPELL">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DAYLIGHT">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISPEL_MAGIC">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ELEMENTAL_WEAPON">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ENEMIES_ABOUND">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FEAR">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FLY">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GASEOUS_FORM">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HASTE">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HYPNOTIC_PATTERN">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_LIFE_TRANSFERENCE">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAJOR_IMAGE">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_NONDETECTION">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PROTECTION_FROM_ENERGY">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SLOW">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_THUNDER_STEP">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TONGUES">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WATER_WALK">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WIND_WALL">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>

    <!-- Dancer 4th Level Spells -->
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AURA_OF_LIFE">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AURA_OF_PURITY">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CHARM_MONSTER">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMPULSION">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONFUSION">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONTROL_WATER">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DIMENSION_DOOR">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ELEMENTAL_BANE">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIRE_SHIELD">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FREEDOM_OF_MOVEMENT">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GREATER_INVISIBILITY">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HALLUCINATORY_TERRAIN">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_OTILUKES_RESILIENT_SPHERE">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PHANTASMAL_KILLER">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>

    <!-- Dancer 5th Level Spells -->
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANIMATE_OBJECTS">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANTILIFE_SHELL">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BIGBYS_HAND">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_CONTROL_WINDS">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISPEL_EVIL_AND_GOOD">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DOMINATE_PERSON">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_FAR_STEP">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MASS_CURE_WOUNDS">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MISLEAD">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SEEMING">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_STEEL_WIND_STRIKE">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TELEKINESIS">
    <supports>Dancer</supports>
  </append>


</elements>