<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>The Seeker Class v4.3</name>
        <update version="0.0.7">
            <file name="class-seeker.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/classes/class-seeker.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="The Seeker Class" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_FRISKYRISQUE_HOMEBREWERY_SOURCE_The Seeker Class">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p>A flexible, intelligence-based magical expert for Dungeons & Dragons 5th Edition. Through deep study of signs from the divine, they are guided to a goal. Blessed with magic empowerment, they have the skills to accomplish any task. The Seeker uses a combination of fast and slow magic to be the ultimate utility caster.</p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation">TSC</set>
			<!-- version 3.4.1 https://homebrewery.naturalcrit.com/share/BZGWSstiDSZu -->
			<!-- version 3.4 https://homebrewery.naturalcrit.com/share/BZGWSstiDSZu -->
            <!-- version 3.3 <set name="url">https://homebrewery.naturalcrit.com/share/mjqKSW5Gsc8t</set>-->
            <!-- version 4.0.3 <set name="url">https://homebrewery.naturalcrit.com/share/AEJJNTA6VlxJ</set>-->
            <set name="url">https://homebrewery.naturalcrit.com/share/uj1LKwBAAllu</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" abbreviation="FR" url="https://www.reddit.com/u/FriskyRisque">u/FriskyRisque</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20210201</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Seeker" type="Class" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_CLASS_SEEKER">
        <description>
			<p>Under the cover of darkness, her picks dance through the lock in the blink of an eye with fingers deft from a prior enchantment. 'Only your light can snuff out the dark' were the words that brought her here, guided by her dreams. Recognizing and avoiding the pressure plate immediately behind the door was easier than she thought, infiltrating the Skyway in Sharn was the hard part, but she did her best work in the shadows. Sorcery bars the last door between the woman and her prey; a quick word and a gesture and the heretic's barrier spell is ravaged. The burnt bones and stars had shown her his home. The words that guided her blade ringed clearly in her head as she crept towards the heretic's sleeping form. Her knife pulsed with energy, poised high above the false prophet, the spell of silence would handle her next problem...</p>
			<p class="indent">A dream stirs the elf to waken, “a storm is coming and our quarry’s tracks will be lost” they announce as the hint of clouds begin to form in the east. The group grumbles as they begin to break camp, but know better than to question the visions of their elf companion.</p>
			<p class="indent">Having built a barricade, the bloodied warrior catches their breath while the harried priest tends to the unconscious mage, the fourth adventurer, as battered as he is, pulls out his teapot. “Is this really the time for that?” the warrior says, a slight tremble to their voice. Lighting a fire, the seeker doesn’t look up as he continues to rummage in his bag, “if you prefer to get out of this in one piece, then just keep them at bay, this brew will fix everything.” The tea leaves glow with a brilliant green light as the water comes to a boil. A smirk comes across the seeker’s face “I just wish we could see the look on their faces...”</p>
			<h4>DIVINE GUIDANCE</h4>
			<p>To be a Seeker is to be on a mission given out by a higher being. Maybe an angel appears in visions or the seeker is able to hear the whispers of a Prince of Hell, seekers follow a divine path. Although a seeker’s mission varies, most commonly they are looking for someone, a person of importance to their deity such as a prophet, muse, or even an avatar of another god. Unlike a paladin or cleric who may follow the tenets of a god and lead others in that religion, a seeker is given guidance by their deity. Through study of subtle signs and interpretation of omens and symbols that most would miss, a seeker’s path is laid before them. The tasks that seekers are given may be devoid of how to complete them, thus a seeker must be adept at gathering intelligence. Seekers care not where their information comes from, whether guidance gifted by the divine, the knowledge still held by the dead, or simply by charming those that would otherwise hoard secrets; by any means will they uncover the path laid before them.</p>
			<h4>FIND A PATH OR MAKE ONE</h4>
			<p>A seeker moves through the world with ease, adept at traveling quickly over the roughest of terrain. As such, a seeker needs to be adept at infiltrating the toughest to reach places around Eberron; they spring locks, recognize traps, and can work with the tools around them to get past the clockwork mechanisms common to this world. Not nearly to the level of an artificer’s mastery over all things mechanical and crafted, but similar to their other skills, seekers use magic to make up for their lack in certain areas.</p>
			<h4>MIND OVER MATTER</h4>
			<p>The skills a seeker possesses are minor compared to what they have trained for. A seeker uses their body as a vessel for empowering magics, allowing their spells to change how their own form functions. Because of this training, they more often rely not on talent, but instead on the use of magic to make up what is lacking. Continuing this line of thinking, seekers often rely on others to get through difficult situations, a wise seeker is aware that they cannot handle every situation thrown their way. Seekers should be able to work well with their fellow companions to accomplish the goals set before them by their patron, as such a seeker’s spells lean towards improving their gifts and the group rather than blatantly destructive magics. </p>
			<h4>CREATING A SEEKER</h4>
			<p>When creating a Seeker, consider what kind of deity you follow and quest for. What kind of training did you go through to become a seeker? How does your patron or god communicate with you and how do you read their omens? Will you aid your allies in combat with supportive magics or empower your own abilities to take down your foes? Be sure to work with the DM about your background.</p>
			<h5>QUICK BUILD</h5>
			<p>You can make a Seeker quickly by following these suggestions. First, make either Dexterity or Intelligence your highest ability score, followed by Constitution. Second, choose the Outlander background.</p>
            <h2>CLASS FEATURES</h2>
            <p>As a seeker, you gain the following class features.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">HIT POINTS</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Hit Dice:</strong> 1d8 per seeker level</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at 1st Level:</strong> 8 + your Constitution modifier</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at Higher Levels:</strong> 1d8 (or 5) + your Constitution modifier per seeker level after 1st</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">PROFICIENCIES</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled mb">
                <li><strong>Armor:</strong> Light armor, shields</li>
                <li><strong>Weapons:</strong> Simple Weapons, hand crossbows, longbows, longswords, rapiers, shortswords</li>
                <li><strong>Tools:</strong> Thieve's tools, one type of artisan's tools of your choice</li>
            </ul>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Saving Throws:</strong> Constitution, Intelligence</li>
                <li><strong>Skills:</strong> Choose two from Acrobatics, Arcana, Deception, History, Investigation, Medicine, Religion, Perception, Persuasion, Sleight of Hand, Stealth, Survival</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">EQUIPMENT</h5>
            <p>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>a rapier, shortsword, or longsword</li>
                <li>shortbow, shortsword, a dagger, or a shield</li>
                <li>leather armor</li>
                <li>Thieves’ or tinkerers’ tools and a dungeoneer’s pack</li>
                <li>One fortune telling device such as tarot cards, a crystal ball, various teas, etc.</li>
            </ul>
        <!-- class table here -->
            <h5 class="caption">THE SEEKER</h5>
            <table class="class-features">
                <thead>
                    <tr><td class="col-5">Level</td><td class="col-5">Proficiency Bonus</td><td class="left">Features</td><td class="col-10">Rites</td><td class="col-10">Cantrips Known</td><td>1st</td><td>2nd</td><td>3rd</td><td>4th</td><td>5th</td><td>6th</td><td>7th</td><td>8th</td><td>9th</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td> 1st</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Spellcasting and Rites, Mavenhood, Tea Leaves</td><td>1</td><td>2</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 2nd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Premonition, Sixth Sense</td><td>2</td><td>2</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 3rd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Magical Adaptation, Maven Feature</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>4</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 4th</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 5th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">—</td><td>5</td><td>3</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 6th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Destined Strike</td><td>6</td><td>3</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 7th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Ill Omen</td><td>7</td><td>3</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>1</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 8th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>8</td><td>3</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 9th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">—</td><td>9</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>1</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>10th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Holdfast, Maven Feature</td><td>10</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>11th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">—</td><td>11</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>12th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>12</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">—</td><td>13</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>14th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Maven Feature</td><td>14</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>15th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">—</td><td>15</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>16th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>16</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>17th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">—</td><td>17</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>1</td></tr>
                <tr><td>18th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Endless Pursuit</td><td>18</td><td>5</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>1</td></tr>
                <tr><td>19th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>19</td><td>5</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>1</td></tr>
                <tr><td>20th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Divine Blessing</td><td>20</td><td>5</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>1</td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_FR_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SEEKER_SPELLCASTING" />
            <div element="ID_FR_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SEEKER_MAVENHOOD" />
            <div element="ID_FR_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SEEKER_TEA_LEAVES" />
            <div element="ID_FR_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SEEKER_PREMONITION" />
            <div element="ID_FR_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SEEKER_SIXTH_SENSE" />
            <div element="ID_FR_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SEEKER_MAGICAL_ADAPTATION" />
            <div element="ID_FR_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SEEKER_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" />
            <div element="ID_FR_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SEEKER_DESTINED_STRIKE" />
            <div element="ID_FR_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SEEKER_ILL_OMEN" />
            <div element="ID_FR_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SEEKER_HOLD_FAST" />
            <div element="ID_FR_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_ENDLESS_PURSUIT" />
            <div element="ID_FR_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SEEKER_DIVINE_BLESSING" />
			<h3>OPTIONAL RULE: MULTICLASSING</h3>
			<p>If your group uses the optional rule on multiclassing in the Player’s Handbook (p. 163), here’s what you need to know if you choose seeker as one of your classes.</p>
			<p class="indent">Ability Score Minimum. As a multiclass character, you must have at least an Intelligence score of 13 to take a level in this class.</p>
			<p class="indent">Proficiencies Gained. If seeker isn’t your initial class, here are the proficiencies you gain when you take your first level as an artificer: light armor, shields, thieves’ tools, and one fortune telling device/set.</p>
			<p class="indent">Extra/Destined Strike. The Destined Strike feature at level 6 is a separate Action from Extra Attack, thus cannot be used interchangeably.</p>
			<p class="indent">Spell Slots. Add your levels in the seeker class to the appropriate levels from other classes to determine your available spell slots.</p>
			<div class="sidebar">
				<h5 class="caption">Reading The Weave</h5>
				<p>Each Seeker manifests their magic in a different way, usually specific to their specialty.</p>
				<ul>
					<li>It is common for Mavens of the Cunning Eye to show their third eye when using Divination magic.</li>
					<li>Mavens of the Cutting Tongue might have a glowing mouth when using a spell with just verbal components.</li>
					<li>Lurking Hand Seekers might have fingers that seem to twist with extra joints when empowering their weapons with smiting magic.</li>
					<li>Shifting constellation tattoos have been seen on the skin of Roaming Step Seekers when they are journeying from one destination to another.</li>
					<li>If you look close, the words of a Seeker of the Rotting Voice can be seen faintly floating in the air when they are casting Enchantment magic.</li>
				</ul>
				<p class="indent">Players are encouraged to create a manifestation that feels right for their character.</p>
			</div>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="hd">d8</set>
            <set name="short">The Seeker uses a combination of fast and slow magic to be the ultimate utility caster.</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_SHIELDS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" requirements="!ID_FR_TSC_MULTICLASS_SEEKER" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_CROSSBOW_HAND" requirements="!ID_FR_TSC_MULTICLASS_SEEKER" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_LONGBOW" requirements="!ID_FR_TSC_MULTICLASS_SEEKER" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_LONGSWORD" requirements="!ID_FR_TSC_MULTICLASS_SEEKER" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_RAPIER" requirements="!ID_FR_TSC_MULTICLASS_SEEKER" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SHORTSWORD" requirements="!ID_FR_TSC_MULTICLASS_SEEKER" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_THIEVES_TOOLS" />
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Tool Proficiency, Seeker" supports="Artisan tools" requirements="!ID_FR_TSC_MULTICLASS_SEEKER" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CONSTITUTION" requirements="!ID_FR_TSC_MULTICLASS_SEEKER" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_INTELLIGENCE" requirements="!ID_FR_TSC_MULTICLASS_SEEKER" />
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency, Seeker" supports="Skill,FR Seeker" number="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_FR_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SEEKER_SPELLCASTING" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_FR_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SEEKER_MAVENHOOD" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_FR_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SEEKER_TEA_LEAVES" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_FR_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SEEKER_PREMONITION" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_FR_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SEEKER_SIXTH_SENSE" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_FR_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SEEKER_MAGICAL_ADAPTATION" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_FR_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SEEKER_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" level="4" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_FR_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SEEKER_DESTINED_STRIKE" level="6" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_FR_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SEEKER_ILL_OMEN" level="7" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_FR_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SEEKER_HOLD_FAST" level="10" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_FR_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_ENDLESS_PURSUIT" level="18" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_FR_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SEEKER_DIVINE_BLESSING" level="20" />
        </rules>
        <multiclass id="ID_FR_TSC_MULTICLASS_SEEKER">
            <prerequisite>Intelligence 13</prerequisite>
            <requirements>[int:13]</requirements>
            <setters>
                <set name="multiclass proficiencies">If seeker isn’t your initial class, here are the proficiencies you gain when you take your first level as an artificer: light armor, shields, thieves’ tools, and one fortune telling device/set.</set>
            </setters>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS" />
            </rules>
        </multiclass>
    </element>
		<element name="Spellcasting" type="Class Feature" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SEEKER_SPELLCASTING">
			<description>
				<p>Through your studies and connection with the divine, you are able to use magic spells. As a seeker, your magic is generally slower than others, but creativity is your true power. See Spells Rules for the general rules of spellcasting.</p>
				<h5>CANTRIPS</h5>
				<p>At 1st level, you know two cantrips of your choice from the seeker pell list. At higher levels, you learn additional seeker cantrips of your choice, as shown in the Cantrips Known column of the Seeker table.</p>
				<h5>PREPARING AND CASTING SPELLS</h5>
				<p>The Seeker table shows how many spell slots you have per spell level to cast your seeker spells. To cast one of your seeker spells of 1st level or higher at the regular casting time, you must expend a spell slot of the spell’s level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.</p>
				<p class="indent">You prepare a list of spells at the end of each long rest from the seeker spell list. When you do so, choose a number of spells equal to your Intelligence modifier + half your seeker level, rounded down (minimum of one spell). The spells must be of a level for which you are able to cast. These spells count as Seeker spells for purposes of spellcasting and rites.</p>
				<p class="indent">You can change your list of prepared Spells when you finish a Long Rest. Preparing a new list of seeker spells requires time spent in studying omens from the divine and interpreting the meaning of these signs: at least 1 minute per spell level for each spell on your list.</p>
				<h5>SPELLCASTING ABILITY</h5>
				<p>Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for your seeker spells, since you learn your spells through dedicated Maven and memorization. You use your Intelligence whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Intelligence modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a seeker spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.</p>
				<p style="text-align: center;"><b>Spell save DC</b> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier</p>
				<p style="text-align: center;"><b>Spell attack modifier</b> = your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier</p>
				<h5>RITUAL SPELLS</h5>
				<p>You can cast any seeker spell you prepare as a ritual if that spell has the ritual tag.</p>
				<h5>SPELLCASTING FOCUS</h5>
				<p>You can use a divine focus as a spellcasting focus for your seeker spells. This divine focus can be your fortune telling device.</p>
				<h5>RITES</h5>
				<p>For any seeker spell prepared of 5th level and below, you are able to cast those spells as a Rite instead of using a spell slot. The cast time for these spells follows the format of rituals and equals the standard casting time plus 10 minutes. You regain all expended Rites when you finish a long rest.</p>
				<p class="indent">Spells cast using a Rite has an associated cost depending on what spell level it is used at, as seen in the table below.</p>
				<table>
					<tr><td>Spell Level</td><td>Rites Used</td></tr>
					<tr><td>1st &amp; 2nd</td><td>1</td></tr>
					<tr><td>3rd &amp; 4th</td><td>2</td></tr>
					<tr><td>5th</td><td>3</td></tr>
				</table>
				<p class="indent">With the power of spells 6th level and above, they cannot be cast using Rites.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet alt="Rites" usage="{{rites:uses}}/Long Rest">
				<description>For any spell prepared of 5th level and below, you are able to cast those spells as a Rite instead of using a spell slot. The cast time for these spells follows the format of rituals. 1st, 2nd, &amp; 3rd -> 1 Rite, 4th &amp; 5th -> 2 Rites.</description>
			</sheet>
            <spellcasting name="Seeker" ability="Intelligence" prepare="true">
                <list known="true">FR Seeker</list>
            </spellcasting>
			<rules>
                <stat name="rites:uses" value="level:seeker" />
                <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS_SPELLCASTING_SLOTS_FULL" requirements="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS" />
                <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_RITUAL_CASTING" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_INTERNAL_PROFICIENCY_SPELLFOCUS_GROUP_HOLY_SYMBOL" />
                <stat name="seeker:spellcasting:slots:1" value="2" level="1" />
                <stat name="seeker:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="2" />
                <stat name="seeker:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="3" />
                <stat name="seeker:spellcasting:slots:2" value="2" level="3" />
                <stat name="seeker:spellcasting:slots:2" value="1" level="4" />
                <stat name="seeker:spellcasting:slots:3" value="2" level="5" />
                <stat name="seeker:spellcasting:slots:3" value="1" level="6" />
                <stat name="seeker:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="7" />
                <stat name="seeker:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="8" />
                <stat name="seeker:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="9" />
                <stat name="seeker:spellcasting:slots:5" value="1" level="9" />
                <stat name="seeker:spellcasting:slots:5" value="1" level="10" />
                <stat name="seeker:spellcasting:slots:5" value="1" level="18" />
                <stat name="seeker:spellcasting:slots:6" value="1" level="11" />
                <stat name="seeker:spellcasting:slots:6" value="1" level="19" />
                <stat name="seeker:spellcasting:slots:7" value="1" level="13" />
                <stat name="seeker:spellcasting:slots:7" value="1" level="20" />
                <stat name="seeker:spellcasting:slots:8" value="1" level="15" />
                <stat name="seeker:spellcasting:slots:9" value="1" level="17" />
                <stat name="seeker:spellcasting:prepare" value="intelligence:modifier" />
                <stat name="seeker:spellcasting:prepare" value="level:seeker:half" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Seeker)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), 0" level="1" number="2" spellcasting="Seeker" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Seeker)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), 0" level="4" number="1" spellcasting="Seeker" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Seeker)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), 0" level="9" number="1" spellcasting="Seeker" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Seeker)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), 0" level="18" number="1" spellcasting="Seeker" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Mavenhood" type="Class Feature" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SEEKER_MAVENHOOD">
			<description>
				<p>Early on, Seekers choose a Mavenhood that helps them best listen to their patron, reveal the arcanum, travel safely to your goal, and complete your quest. Here are some of the Mavenhoods you can choose at 1st level.</p>
				<p class="indent">Choose one Mavenhood related to how you best will serve your patron: Cunning Eye, Cutting Tongue, Lurking Hand, Roaming Steps, and Rotting Voice. Each Maven is detailed at the end of the class description. Your choice grants you Maven spells and features when you choose it at 1st level and additional benefits at 3rd, 10th, and 14th level.</p>
				<div class="sidebar">
					<h5 class="caption">Maven, One Who Understands</h5>
					<p>Maven, meaning an expert or connoisseur, is a choice of subclass that focuses on different aspects of play. The Maven spell list and bonus proficiencies at level one should give you an idea of the focus of each subclass.</p>
				</div>
				<h5>MAVEN SPELLS</h5>
				<p>Each Mavenhood has a list of spells, its Maven spells, that you gain at the Seeker levels noted in the Maven description. Once you gain a Maven spell, you always have it prepared, and it doesn't count against the number of spells you can prepare each day. If you have a Maven spell that doesn't appear on the Seeker spell list, the spell is nonetheless a Seeker spell for you.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet display="false">
				<description></description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <select type="Archetype" name="Mavenhood" supports="Seeker Mavenhood" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Tea Leaves" type="Class Feature" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SEEKER_TEA_LEAVES">
			<description>
				<p>At 1st level, you have studied the greater arcanum enough to know which omens should receive attention and what can be cast aside so you may be a better guide. You have advantage on ability checks to read signs of good and ill omens.</p>
				<p class="indent">The correct path is before, The Weave knows the way and acts through you to lead others. You learn the <i>guidance</i>> cantrip, which doesn’t count against the number of seeker cantrips you know. When you cast this cantrip, you can choose a second target that you can see within 60 feet to also be affected. This cantrip lasts up to a minute with concentration or until both targets have utilized the effect of this cantrip.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description>You have advantage on ability checks to read signs of good and ill omens. When you cast guidance, you can choose a second target that you can see within 60 feet to also be affected. This cantrip lasts up to a minute with concentration or until both targets have utilized the effect of this cantrip.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GUIDANCE" spellcasting="Seeker" known="true" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Premonition" type="Class Feature" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SEEKER_PREMONITION">
			<description>
				<p>Starting at 2nd Level, your connection with the divine gives you a brief premonition allowing you to evade foes and find what others would miss. You can use your bonus action to take the Disengage, Hide, Search, or Steady Aim action.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet action="Bonus Action">
				<description>As a free action, you can add a d4 to all ability checks and saving throws until the end of your next turn. Additionally, you can use your bonus action to take the Disengage, Hide, Search, or Steady Aim action.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Sixth Sense" type="Class Feature" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SEEKER_SIXTH_SENSE">
			<description>
				<p>Also at 2nd level, you can enter a state prescience and are able to add a d4 to all ability checks and saving throws until the end of your next turn. You may use this feature a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus plus your Intelligence modifier per long rest.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet usage="{{sixth-sense:uses}}/Long Rest">
				<description>You add {{sixth-sense:bonus-dice}}d4 to all ability checks and saving throws until the end of your next turn.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
				<stat name="sixth-sense:uses" value="proficieny" />
				<stat name="sixth-sense:uses" value="intelligence:modifier" />
				<stat name="sixth-sense:bonus-dice" value="1" level="2" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Magical Adaptation" type="Class Feature" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SEEKER_MAGICAL_ADAPTATION">
			<description>
				<p>Starting at 3rd level, whenever you finish a long rest, you can replace one seeker cantrip you know with another cantrip from the seeker spell list.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description>Whenever you finish a long rest, you can replace one seeker cantrip you know with another cantrip from the seeker spell list.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Ability Score Improvement" type="Class Feature" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SEEKER_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT">
			<description>
				<p>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
				<p class="indent">Using the optional feats rule, you can forgo taking this feature to take a feat of your choice instead.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet display="false">
				<description></description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Seeker 4)" supports="Improvement Option,Seeker,4" level="4" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Seeker 8)" supports="Improvement Option,Seeker,8" level="8" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Seeker 12)" supports="Improvement Option,Seeker,12" level="12" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Seeker 16)" supports="Improvement Option,Seeker,16" level="16" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Seeker 19)" supports="Improvement Option,Seeker,19" level="19" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Destined Strike" type="Class Feature" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SEEKER_DESTINED_STRIKE">
			<description>
				<p>At 6th level, while Sixth Sense is active during your turn, you may modify a seeker cantrip with casting time of one action. After casting your cantrip you can either make one weapon attack or, if applicable, roll an additional damage dice from that cantrip and add it to the total damage.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description>While Sixth Sense is active during your turn, you may modify a seeker cantrip with casting time of one action. After casting your cantrip you can either make one weapon attack or, if applicable, roll an additional damage dice from that cantrip and add it to the total damage.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Ill Omen" type="Class Feature" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SEEKER_ILL_OMEN">
			<description>
				<p>Starting at 7th Level, you portend harm to yourself and see how to suffer the least harm. When an attacker that you can see hits you with an attack, you can use your reaction to expend one Rite to halve the attack's damage against you.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet action="Reaction" usage="1 Rite">
				<description>When an attacker that you can see hits you with an attack, you can use a Reaction and a Rite to halve the attack's damage against you.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Hold Fast" type="Class Feature" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SEEKER_HOLD_FAST">
			<description>
				<p>Beginning at 10th level, you've trained your body to go withstand certain area effects, such as a white dragon's freezing breath or a <i>cloudkill</i> spell's poison gases. When you are subjected to an effect that allows you to make a Constitution saving throw to take only half damage, you instead take no damage if you succeed on the saving throw, and only half damage if you fail.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description>When you are subjected to an effect that allows you to make a Constitution saving throw to take only half damage, you instead take no damage if you succeed on the saving throw, and only half damage if you fail.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Endless Pursuit" type="Class Feature" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_ENDLESS_PURSUIT">
			<description>
				<p>At 18th level, magic suffuses your every step. Your movement speed cannot be decreased by difficult terrain, spells, being underwater, or other effects and you cannot be restrained. By spending 5 feet of movement, you can automatically escape from being grappled. Once per long rest, your deity is able to unburden you, making your path easier. By using your Reaction, your deity strips away one negative status effect, such as paralyze or blind.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet action="Reaction">
				<description>Your movement speed cannot be decreased by difficult terrain, spells, being underwater, or other effects and you cannot be restrained. By spending 5 feet of movement, you can automatically escape from being grappled. Once per long rest, using your Reaction, your deity strips away one negative status effect, such as paralyze or blind.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Divine Blessing" type="Class Feature" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SEEKER_DIVINE_BLESSING">
			<description>
				<p>When you reach 20th level, you may call on your diety for a boon. At the end of a long rest, choose from one of the following blessings:</p>
				<ul>
					<li><b>Dragon's Strength:</b> You have advantage on three Strength Checks or Saves of your choice, cannot be knocked prone or disarmed, and add 2 damage to each melee attack.</li>
					<li><b>Fey's Grace:</b> You have advantage on three Dexterity Checks or Saves, gain 10 feet of movement speed, and do not take fall damage when falling from 100 feet or less as long as you aren't incapcitated.</li>
					<li><b>Old One's Endurance:</b> You have advantage on three Constitution Checks or Saves, and gain 30 temporary hit points.</li>
					<li><b>Lich's Cunning:</b> You have advantage on three Intelligence Checks or Saves, and gain resistance to psychic damage.</li>
					<li><b>Angel's Wisdom:</b> You have advantage on three Wisdom Checks or Saves, and you have Truesight out to 10 feet.</li>
					<li><b>Devil's Charm:</b> You have advantage on three Charisma Checks or Saves, and can ignore the verbal and somatic components of a spell once when casting a spell.</li>
				</ul>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description>At the end of a long rest, choose from one of the following blessings: Dragon's Strength, Fey's Grace, Old One's Endurance, Lich's Cunning, Angel's Wisdom, Devil's Charm</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
			</rules>
		</element>

    <!-- Mavenhood Archetypes -->    
        <element name="Maven of the Brightened Spirit" type="Archetype" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_SEEKER_MAVEN_OF_THE_BRIGHTENED_SPIRIT">
            <supports>Seeker Mavenhood</supports>
            <description>
                <p>Bringers of hope and renewal, the Mavens of the Brightened Spirit help lighten the darkest of times. Although all seekers tend towards darkness to hide their movements, Seekers that follow this Mavenhood focus on supporting the group. In this Mavenhood, many seekers gain their power and divine the future through seeing visions in a burning fire or by attaining a meditative state through energetic activities such as repetitive dances or deep breathing.</p>
                <div element="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BRIGHTENED_SPIRIT_BRIGHTENED_SPIRIT_SPELLS" />
                <div element="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BRIGHTENED_SPIRIT_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" />
                <div element="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BRIGHTENED_SPIRIT_SPIRIT_OF_THE_LIGHT" />
                <div element="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BRIGHTENED_SPIRIT_BLESSED_WARMTH" />
                <div element="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BRIGHTENED_SPIRIT_GIFT_OF_THE_MARTYR" />
            </description>
            <sheet display="false" />
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BRIGHTENED_SPIRIT_BRIGHTENED_SPIRIT_SPELLS" level="3" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BRIGHTENED_SPIRIT_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" level="3" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BRIGHTENED_SPIRIT_SPIRIT_OF_THE_LIGHT" level="3" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BRIGHTENED_SPIRIT_BLESSED_WARMTH" level="10" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BRIGHTENED_SPIRIT_GIFT_OF_THE_MARTYR" level="14" />
            </rules>
        </element>
			<element name="Brightened Spirit Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BRIGHTENED_SPIRIT_BRIGHTENED_SPIRIT_SPELLS">
				<description>
					<p>When choosing this Mavenhood, you gain access to spells that bring the light to those around you, be them friend or foe. At 1st, 3rd, 5th, 7th, and 9th level you gain access to the following spells.</p>
					<table>
						<thead>
							<tr><td>Seeker Level</td><td>Maven Spell</td></tr>
						</thead>
						<tr><td>1st</td><td><em>bless, ceremony, healing word</em></td></tr>
						<tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>calm emotions, healing spirit</em></td></tr>
						<tr><td>5th</td><td><em>daylight, revivify</em></td></tr>
						<tr><td>7th</td><td><em>aura of life, guardian of faith</em></td></tr>
						<tr><td>9th</td><td><em>dawn, greater restoration, hallow</em></td></tr>
					</table>
				</description>
				<sheet display="false" />
					<rules>
					<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLESS" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="1" />
					<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CEREMONY" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="1" />
					<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HEALING_WORD" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="1" />
					<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CALM_EMOTIONS" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="3" />
					<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HEALING_SPIRIT" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="3" />
					<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DAYLIGHT" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="5" />
					<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_REVIVIFY" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="5" />
					<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AURA_OF_LIFE" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="7" />
					<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GUARDIAN_OF_FAITH" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="7" />
					<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DAWN" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="9" />
					<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GREATER_RESTORATION" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="9" />
					<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HALLOW" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="9" />
				</rules>
			</element>
			<element name="Bonus Proficiencies" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BRIGHTENED_SPIRIT_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES">
				<description>
					<p>When you choose this Mavenhood at 1st level, you gain proficiency in medium armor. Additionally, you gain proficiency in the Medicine and Religion skills. Choose one of these two skills, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it. 6th level, you can choose a second skill that you are proficient with to add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it.</p>
				</description>
				<sheet display="false" />
				<rules>
					<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_MEDIUM_ARMOR" />
					<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_MEDICINE" />
					<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_RELIGION" />
					<select type="Class Feature" name="Skill Expertise" supports="ID_EXPERTISE_SKILL_MEDICINE|ID_EXPERTISE_SKILL_RELIGION" level="3" />
					<select type="Class Feature" name="Skill Expertise" supports="ID_EXPERTISE_SKILL_MEDICINE|ID_EXPERTISE_SKILL_RELIGION" level="6" />
				</rules>
			</element>
			<element name="Spirit of the Light" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BRIGHTENED_SPIRIT_SPIRIT_OF_THE_LIGHT">
				<description>
					<p>At 3rd level, you are blessed with a beneficent spirit from your patron. When casting Healing Spirit, either with a spell slot and using a Rite or by casting the spell as a Rite, Healing Spirit changes, as below:</p>
					<ul>
						<li>The spirit appears in a form you choose that represents your deity.</li>
						<li>This spell doesn’t require concentration; it ends either after a minute has passed since casting it, when you choose (as a free action), or you fall unconscious.</li>
						<li>When you cast this spell, choose either a skill or a save, when you heal someone with this spell, the healed target has advantage on that skill or save you chose until the spirit heals another target or the spell ends.</li>
						<li>Hostile creatures within a 10 foot radius of the Spirit cannot benefit from advantage on attacks or ability checks.</li>
					</ul>
					<p class="indent">Also at 3rd level, you may choose to reroll any 1 rolled once per use Sixth Sense. When you reroll, you may also choose to create a burst of light that blinds foes within 10 feet who fail a Constitution saving throw against your spell save DC until the end of your Sixth Sense.</p>
				</description>
				<sheet>
					<description>When casting Healing Spirit, either with a spell slot and using a Rite or by casting the spell as a Rite, Healing Spirit changes. You may choose to reroll any 1 rolled once per use Sixth Sense. When you reroll, you may also choose to create a burst of light that blinds foes within 10 feet who fail a Constitution saving throw against your spell save DC until the end of your Sixth Sense.</description>
				</sheet>
				<rules>
				</rules>
			</element>
			<element name="Blessed Warmth" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BRIGHTENED_SPIRIT_BLESSED_WARMTH">
				<description>
					<p>At 10th level, you are able to call on your deity for additional aid in the form of an avatar. As the sun rises, whether you are able to see it or not, choose a target to be blessed. This target has advantage on saves against blindness and deafness as well as being poisoned and frightened.</p>
					<p class="indent">Additionally, you learn the <i>dancing lights</i>> cantrip which does not count against your cantrip total. When you cast this cantrip, you may spend two Rites to end the cantrip early and cast either <i>mass cure wounds</i> or <i>destructive wave</i> centered on your <i>dancing lights</i>. You may not use this feature again until you have finished a long rest.</p>
				</description>
				<sheet>
					<description>As the sun rises, whether you are able to see it or not, choose a target to be blessed. This target has advantage on saves against blindness and deafness as well as being poisoned and frightened. When you cast this cantrip, you may spend two Rites to end the cantrip early and cast either mass cure wounds or destructive wave centered on your dancing lights. You may not use this feature again until you have finished a long rest.</description>
				</sheet>
				<rules>
					<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DANCING_LIGHTS" known="true" />
				</rules>
			</element>
			<element name="Gift of the Martyr" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BRIGHTENED_SPIRIT_GIFT_OF_THE_MARTYR">
				<description>
					<p>At 14th level, when healing an ally using magical means, you can choose to spend your own hit dice to increase the healing you impart. Choose a number of your hit dice up to your Intelligence modifier to increase the healing of one target you heal by 5 hit points for every hit dice spent this way.</p>
					<p class="indent">Also at 14th level, you become a vessel for the light of your patron! Once per long rest, you may spend three Rites to cast either <i>divine word</i>, <i>heal</i>, or <i>sunbeam</i>. When the spell ends, you cannot move or take actions until after your next turn, as you experience the elation of your diety's force moving through you.</p>
				</description>
				<sheet>
					<description>When healing an ally using magical means, you can spend up to {{intelligence:modifier}} of your hit dice up to increase the healing of one target you heal by 5 hit points for every hit dice spent this way. Once per long rest, you may spend three Rites to cast either divine word, heal, or sunbeam. When the spell ends, you cannot move or take actions until after your next turn.</description>
				</sheet>
				<rules>
				</rules>
			</element>


		<element name="Maven of the Cunning Eye" type="Archetype" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_SEEKER_MAVEN_OF_THE_CUNNING_EYE">
			<supports>Seeker Mavenhood</supports>
			<description>
				<p>Glimpse the future and see the world as it truly is with this Maven. Gazing into a crystal ball, vizualizing auras, and seeing patterns in burned incense are standard fortune telling methods for this Mavenhood.</p>
				<div element="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CUNNING_EYE_CUNNING_EYE_SPELLS" />
				<div element="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CUNNING_EYE_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" />
				<div element="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CUNNING_EYE_FORTUNE_TELLER" />
				<div element="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CUNNING_EYE_SECOND_SIGHT" />
				<div element="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CUNNING_EYE_UNFORESEEN_CIRCUMSTANCES" />
			</description>
			<sheet display="false" />
			<rules>
				<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CUNNING_EYE_CUNNING_EYE_SPELLS" level="1" />
				<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CUNNING_EYE_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" level="1" />
				<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CUNNING_EYE_FORTUNE_TELLER" level="3" />
				<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CUNNING_EYE_SECOND_SIGHT" level="10" />
				<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CUNNING_EYE_UNFORESEEN_CIRCUMSTANCES" level="14" />
			</rules>
		</element>
			<element name="Cunning Eye Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CUNNING_EYE_CUNNING_EYE_SPELLS">
				<description>
					<p>When choosing this Mavenhood, you gain access to spells that help you see your path and reveal what is hidden. At 1st, 3rd, 5th, 7th, and 9th level you gain access to the following spells.</p>
					<table>
						<thead>
							<tr><td>Seeker Level</td><td>Maven Spell</td></tr>
						</thead>
						<tr><td>1st</td><td><em>detect evil and good, detect magic, faerie fire</em></td></tr>
						<tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>augury, detect thoughts</em></td></tr>
						<tr><td>5th</td><td><em>dispel magic, gaseous form</em></td></tr>
						<tr><td>7th</td><td><em>arcane eye, divination</em></td></tr>
						<tr><td>9th</td><td><em>commune, scrying</em></td></tr>
					</table>
				</description>
				<sheet display="false">
					<description></description>
				</sheet>
				<rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_EVIL_AND_GOOD" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="1" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_MAGIC" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="1" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FAERIE_FIRE" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="1" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AUGURY" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="3" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_THOUGHTS" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="3" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISPEL_MAGIC" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="5" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GASEOUS_FORM" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="5" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ARCANE_EYE" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="7" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DIVINATION" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="7" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMMUNE" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="9" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SCRYING" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="9" />
				</rules>
			</element>
			<element name="Bonus Proficiencies" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CUNNING_EYE_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES">
				<description>
					<p>When you choose this Mavenhood at 1st level, you gain proficiency in Arcana and Investigation. Choose one of these two skills, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it. 6th level, you can choose a second skill that you are proficient with to add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it.</p>
				</description>
				<sheet display="false">
					<description></description>
				</sheet>
				<rules>
                    <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ARCANA" />
                    <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INVESTIGATION" />
                    <select type="Class Feature" name="Bonus Proficiency, Cunning Eye" supports="ID_EXPERTISE_SKILL_ARCANA|ID_EXPERTISE_SKILL_INVESTIGATION" level="1" />
                    <select type="Class Feature" name="Bonus Proficiency, Cunning Eye" supports="Skill,Expertise" level="6" />
				</rules>
			</element>
			<element name="Fortune Teller" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CUNNING_EYE_FORTUNE_TELLER">
				<description>
					<p>At 3rd level, showing others your abilities can sometimes be as important as the omens you portend. You may cast the cantrip <i>thaumaturgy</i> without using components once per short rest.</p>
                    <p class="indent">You also gain an addiontional way to use <i>augury</i>, twice per day you can expend a Rite to cast <i>augury</i> over the course of a minute, the spell changes to aid you and those around you.</p>
					<ul>
						<li>There is no cumulative casting effect of <i>augury</i> that could cause a random outcome.</li>
						<li>You get a sense of the next hour instead of the next 30 minutes.</li>
						<li>Depending on the outcome of the <i>augury</i> spell cast using this feature, you gain a different boon:</li>
					</ul>
					<p class="indent"><b>Weal:</b> Your confidence is bolstered! Once in the next hour, you can use your reaction to have an ally reroll any attack roll, saving throw, or ability check.</p>
					<p class="indent"><b>Woe:</b> You’re ready to face oncoming foes! Once in the next hour, you can use your bonus action to impose disadvantage on the next attack roll, saving throw, or ability check by a creature you can see.</p>
					<p class="indent"><b>Weal/Woe:</b> You steel yourself for whatever comes next! Once in the next hour, you can give yourself advantage on any attack roll, saving throw, or ability check.</p>
					<p class="indent"><b>Neither:</b> You decide your own fate! Roll a d20 and record the number rolled. Once in the next hour, you can replace any attack roll, saving throw, or ability check made by you or a creature that you can see with this foretelling roll. You must choose to do so before the roll.</p>
				</description>
				<sheet usage="1 Rite, twice/day">
					<description>You can expend a Rite to cast augury over the course of 1 minute. You get a sense of the next hour. There is no cumulative casting effect of augury that could cause a random outcome. Additionally, ou may cast the cantrip thaumaturgy without using components once per short rest.</description>
				</sheet>
				<rules>
				</rules>
			</element>
			<element name="Second Sight" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CUNNING_EYE_SECOND_SIGHT">
				<description>
					<p>At 10th level, you can use an action to increase your powers of perception. When you do so, choose one of the following benefits, which lasts until you are incapacitated, or you take a short or long rest. You can’t use the feature again until you finish a rest or spend a Rite as an action to change the ability.</p>
					<ul>
						<li><b>Tremorsense.</b> You gain tremorsense out to a range of 60 feet.</li>
						<li><b>Ethereal Sight.</b> You can see into the Ethereal Plane within 60 feet of you.</li>
						<li><b>Greater Comprehension.</b> You can read any language.</li>
						<li><b>See Invisibility.</b> You can see invisible creatures and objects within 10 feet of you that are within line of sight.</li>
					</ul>
					<p class="indent">Additionally, when casting a divination spell, you may avoid the material component, consumed or not, of that spell by using by spending a Rite once per long rest.</p>
				</description>
				<sheet action="Action" usage="1/Short Rest or 1 Rite">
					<description>Choose one of the following benefits, which lasts until you are incapacitated, or you take a short or long rest: Tremorsense, Ethereal Sight, Greater Comprehension, See Invisibility. Additionally, when casting a divination spell, you may avoid the material component, consumed or not, of that spell by using by spending a Rite once per long rest.</description>
				</sheet>
				<rules>
				</rules>
			</element>
			<element name="Unforeseen Circumstances" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CUNNING_EYE_UNFORESEEN_CIRCUMSTANCES">
				<description>
					<p>At 14th level, by expending a Rite and meditating for 1 minute, you may replace one spell from your prepared spells with a spell of an equal level from the Seeker spell list. After finishing a long rest, you may use this feature again.</p>
					<p class="indent">Additionally, you can choose to use your Fortune Teller feature by using two Rites as an Action, Bonus Action, and Reaction at the same time instead of taking one minute.</p>
				</description>
				<sheet usage="1 Rite, 1/Long Rest">
					<description>By expending a Rite and meditating for 1 minute, you may replace one spell from your prepared spells with a spell of an equal level from the Seeker spell list. Additionally, you can choose to use your Fortune Teller feature by using 2 Rites as an Action, Bonus Action, and Reaction at the same time instead of taking one minute.</description>
				</sheet>
				<rules>
				</rules>
			</element>


		<element name="Maven of the Cutting Tongue" type="Archetype" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_SEEKER_MAVEN_OF_THE_CUTTING_TONGUE">
			<supports>Seeker Mavenhood</supports>
			<description>
				<p>By asking the right questions, you can get to higher truths. By taking this Mavenhood, your questions carry more weight. Studying animal entrails and reading fire or ashes all lend themselves to omen reading for this Mavenhood.</p>
				<div element="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CUTTING_TONGUE_CUTTING_TONGUE_SPELLS" />
				<div element="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CUTTING_TONGUE_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" />
				<div element="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CUTTING_TONGUE_BLESSED_BOND" />
				<div element="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CUTTING_TONGUE_KNOW_THY_ENEMY" />
				<div element="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CUTTING_TONGUE_HOLY_HAND_DIVINE_VOICE" />
			</description>
			<sheet display="false" />
			<rules>
				<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CUTTING_TONGUE_CUTTING_TONGUE_SPELLS" level="1" />
				<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CUTTING_TONGUE_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" level="1" />
				<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CUTTING_TONGUE_BLESSED_BOND" level="3" />
				<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CUTTING_TONGUE_KNOW_THY_ENEMY" level="10" />
				<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CUTTING_TONGUE_HOLY_HAND_DIVINE_VOICE" level="14" />
			</rules>
		</element>
			<element name="Cutting Tongue Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CUTTING_TONGUE_CUTTING_TONGUE_SPELLS">
				<description>
					<p>When choosing this Maven, you gain access to spells to stop your foes and find the truth between the lies. At 1st, 3rd, 5th, 7th, and 9th level you gain access to the following spells.</p>
					<table>
						<thead>
							<tr><td>Seeker Level</td><td>Maven Spell</td></tr>
						</thead>
						<tr><td>1st</td><td><em>command, searing smite</em></td></tr>
						<tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>flame blade, zone of truth</em></td></tr>
						<tr><td>5th</td><td><em>speak with dead, tongues</em></td></tr>
						<tr><td>7th</td><td><em>compulsion, locate creature</em></td></tr>
						<tr><td>9th</td><td><em>dominate person, holy weapon</em></td></tr>
					</table>
				</description>
				<sheet display="false">
					<description></description>
				</sheet>
				<rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMMAND" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="1" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SEARING_SMITE" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="1" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FLAME_BLADE" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="3" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ZONE_OF_TRUTH" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="3" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_DEAD" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="5" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TONGUES" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="5" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMPULSION" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="7" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LOCATE_CREATURE" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="7" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DOMINATE_PERSON" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="9" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HOLY_WEAPON" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="9" />
				</rules>
			</element>
			<element name="Bonus Proficiencies" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CUTTING_TONGUE_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES">
				<description>
					<p>When you choose this Mavenhood at 1st level, you gain proficiency with martial weapons and medium armor. Additionally, you gain proficiency in the Insight and Intimidation skills. At 6th level, choose one of these skills, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it.</p>
				</description>
				<sheet display="false" />
				<rules>
                    <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_MARTIAL_WEAPONS" />
                    <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_MEDIUM_ARMOR" />
                    <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT" />
                    <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INTIMIDATION" />
                    <select type="Class Feature" name="Bonus Proficiency, Cutting Tongue" supports="ID_EXPERTISE_SKILL_INSIGHT|ID_EXPERTISE_SKILL_INTIMIDATION" level="1" />
 				</rules>
			</element>
			<element name="Blessed Bond" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CUTTING_TONGUE_BLESSED_BOND">
				<description>
					<p>At 3rd level, you become adept at finding the truths within the lies and seeing what makes your enemies tic. By using a Bonus Action, you can magically mark a sentient creature you can see within 60 feet, gaining insight into their mind. The target makes a Wisdom saving throw with a DC equal to your spell save DC. A creature can willingly choose to fail this save. On a successful save, you discern that this magic failed but the target is unaware of the attempt. On a failed save, for the next 10 minutes you gain the following bonuses against this target:</p>
					<ul>
						<li>You know what the creature is known as commonly, such as how the creature would introduce themselves to a friendly acquaintance.</li>
						<li>You know their exact location. If the creature travels to a different plane, you know which plane they went to.</li>
						<li>You have advantage on Insight checks against the target.</li>
						<li>Once before the end of this effect, if the creature is brought to 0 hit points, you can use your Reaction to have your deity stabilize the creature. Instead of dying, the creature is at 1 hit point and paralyzed until the end of your next turn. After stabilizing a creature in this way, you have advantage on Charisma checks against the creature until they have taken a rest.</li>
					</ul>
					<p class="indent">You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of once), and you regain all expended uses of it when you finish a long rest.</p>
				</description>
				<sheet usage="{{int-mod:min-one}}/Long Rest" action="Bonus Action">
					<description>You can magically mark a sentient creature you can see within 60 feet. The target makes a Wisdom saving throw. On a successful save, you discern that this magic failed but the target is unaware of the attempt. On a failed save, for the next 10 minutes you gain several bonuses against this target.</description>
				</sheet>
				<rules>
				</rules>
			</element>
			<element name="Know Thy Enemy" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CUTTING_TONGUE_KNOW_THY_ENEMY">
				<description>
					<p>At 10th level, you can prepare a target for how best to deal with a type of foe. By spending a Rite and using an Action, touch a target and pick one type of creature: Aberrations, Celestials, Dragons, Elementals, Fey, Fiends, Humanoid, or Undead. For 1 minute, any attacks on the target of this feature by creatures of the chosen type have disadvantage. The target also can't be Charmed, Frightened, or possessed by them. If the target is already Charmed, Frightened, or possessed by such a creature, the target has advantage on any new saving throw against the relevant effect. If you use this feature while it is active, the first casting of this effect stops.</p>
				</description>
				<sheet action="Action" usage="1 Rite">
					<description>Touch a target and pick one type of creature: Aberrations, Celestials, Dragons, Elementals, Fey, Fiends, Humanoid, or Undead. For 1 minute, any attacks on the target of this feature by creatures of the chosen type have disadvantage. The target also can't be Charmed, Frightened, or possessed by them.</description>
				</sheet>
				<rules>
				</rules>
			</element>
			<element name="Holy Hand, Divine Voice" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CUTTING_TONGUE_HOLY_HAND_DIVINE_VOICE">
				<description>
					<p>When you reach 14th level, you become an instrument of your divine patron, their will carried out through your hands. After finishing a long rest, choose a damage type: radiant, necrotic, cold, fire, lighting, or poison. The damage type you choose should reflect an aspect of your patron. When you deal damage to a creature, add your Intelligence modifier to the damage of the chosen type. If you are attacking your Blessed Bond target, you may change all of your weapon damage to the chosen type of damage.</p>
					<p class="indent">Additionally, you learn the cantrip <i>friends</i> which does not count against your cantrip total. When <i>friends</i> ends, the target does not realize they have been ensorcelled by this cantrip. </p>
				</description>
				<sheet usage="{{level:seeker}}/day">
					<description>After finishing a long rest, choose a damage type. When you deal damage to a creature, you do {{intelligence:modifier}} damage of the chosen type. Additionally, when you cast friends, the target does not realize it has been cast when the spell ends.</description>
				</sheet>
				<rules>
				</rules>
			</element>


		<element name="Maven of the Lurking Hand" type="Archetype" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_SEEKER_MAVEN_OF_THE_LURKING_HAND">
			<supports>Seeker Mavenhood</supports>
			<description>
				<p>Those that tasked with the subtly finding and removing threats to their patron are part of this Mavenhood. The magic that is given to a Maven of the Lurking Hand is channeled through their fingertips into their weapon to better carry out the will of their diety. Reading palms, throwing finger bones, and studying handwriting are examples of common omen reading by this Mavenhood.</p>
				<div element="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LURKING_HAND_LURKING_HAND_SPELLS" />
				<div element="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LURKING_HAND_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" />
				<div element="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LURKING_HAND_HARD_LURKER" />
				<div element="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LURKING_HAND_QUICKENED_HAND" />
				<div element="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LURKING_HAND_STRIKING_FROM_THE_SHADOWS" />
			</description>
			<sheet display="false" />
			<rules>
				<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LURKING_HAND_LURKING_HAND_SPELLS" level="1" />
				<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LURKING_HAND_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" level="1" />
				<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LURKING_HAND_HARD_LURKER" level="3" />
				<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LURKING_HAND_QUICKENED_HAND" level="10" />
				<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LURKING_HAND_STRIKING_FROM_THE_SHADOWS" level="14" />
			</rules>
		</element>
			<element name="Lurking Hand Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LURKING_HAND_LURKING_HAND_SPELLS">
				<description>
					<p>When choosing this Mavenhood, you gain access to spells that help you move without being sensed and strike hard when needed. At 1st, 3rd, 5th, 7th, and 9th level you gain access to the following spells.</p>
					<table>
						<thead>
							<tr><td>Seeker Level</td><td>Maven Spell</td></tr>
						</thead>
						<tr><td>1st</td><td><em>fog cloud, wrathful smite</em></td></tr>
						<tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>branding smite, pass without trace</em></td></tr>
						<tr><td>5th</td><td><em>blinding smite, nondetection</em></td></tr>
						<tr><td>7th</td><td><em>greater invisibility, staggering smite</em></td></tr>
						<tr><td>9th</td><td><em>banishing smite, passwall</em></td></tr>
					</table>
				</description>
				<sheet display="false">
					<description></description>
				</sheet>
				<rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FOG_CLOUD" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="1" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WRATHFUL_SMITE" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="1" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BRANDING_SMITE" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="3" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PASS_WITHOUT_TRACE" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="3" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLINDING_SMITE" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="5" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_NONDETECTION" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="5" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GREATER_INVISIBILITY" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="7" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_STAGGERING_SMITE" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="7" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BANISHING_SMITE" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="9" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PASSWALL" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="9" />
				</rules>
			</element>
			<element name="Bonus Proficiencies" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LURKING_HAND_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES">
				<description>
					<p>When you choose this Mavenhood at 1st level, you gain proficiency in Sleight of Hand and Stealth. Choose one of these two skills, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it. 6th level, you can choose a second skill that you are proficient with to add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it.</p>
				</description>
				<sheet display="false" />
				<rules>
                    <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SLEIGHTOFHAND" />
                    <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_STEALTH" />
                    <select type="Class Feature" name="Bonus Proficiency, Lurking Hand" supports="ID_EXPERTISE_SKILL_SLEIGHTOFHAND|ID_EXPERTISE_SKILL_STEALTH" level="1" />
                    <select type="Class Feature" name="Bonus Proficiency, Lurking Hand" supports="Skill,Expertise" level="6" />
				</rules>
			</element>
			<element name="Hard Lurker" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LURKING_HAND_HARD_LURKER">
				<description>
					<p>At 3rd level, your premonitions help you move quicker in danger. Add your proficiency bonus to your initiative roll.</p>
					<p class="indent">Additionally, you can gain a blessing of invisibility from your deity briefly. When taking the Hide action, you may become invisible. Your invisibility ends at the start of your next turn, when you cast a spell, or you make an attack. You may use this ability a number of times per long rest equal to your Intelligence modifier.</p>
					<p class="indent">You may empower this ability by spending a Rite to have the invisibility last until the end instead of the start of your next turn. While empowered in this way, you move at your normal walking speed.</p>
				</description>
				<sheet usage="{{intelligence:modifier}}/Long Rest">
					<description>When taking the Hide action, you may become invisible. Your invisibility ends at the start of your next turn, when you cast a spell, or you make an attack. You may empower this ability by spending a Rite to have the invisibility last until the end instead of the start of your next turn. While empowered in this way, you move at your normal walking speed.</description>
				</sheet>
				<rules>
                    <stat name="initiative" value="proficiency" level="3" />
				</rules>
			</element>
			<element name="Quickened Hand" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LURKING_HAND_QUICKENED_HAND">
				<description>
					<p>Starting at 10th level, magic comes even quicker to your finger tips. When you cast a concentration spell that uses a Bonus Action, you can instead use your Reaction to cast that spell. When you use this feature, unless the components for casting the spell were associated with a consumed cost, the components are now just somatic. You can use this feature a number of times per long rest equal to your Intelligence modifier.</p>
				</description>
				<sheet usage="{{intelligence:modifier}}/Long Rest">
					<description>When you cast a concentration spell that uses a Bonus Action, you can instead use your Reaction to cast that spell. When you use this feature, unless the components for casting the spell were associated with a consumed cost, the components are now just somatic.</description>
				</sheet>
				<rules>
				</rules>
			</element>
			<element name="Striking From The Shadows" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LURKING_HAND_STRIKING_FROM_THE_SHADOWS">
				<description>
					<p>You are your deity's divine weapon, the harm you carry out is even greater by their blessing. Starting at 14th level, when ending a concentration spell by causing damage with that spell, such as Ensaring Strike or Staggering Smite, you may roll one extra damage die from that spell's damage.</p>
					<p class="indent">Also at 14th level, you may cast the spell <i>invisibility</i> at its lowest level using a Rite. You always have <i>invisibility</i> prepared, and it doesn't count against the number of spells you can prepare each day.</p>
				</description>
				<sheet>
					<description>When ending a concentration spell by causing damage with that spell, such as Ensaring Strike or Staggering Smite, you may roll one extra damage die from that spell's damage. Additionally, you may cast the spell <i>invisibility</i> at its lowest level using a Rite.</description>
				</sheet>
				<rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INVISIBILITY" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="14" />
				</rules>
			</element>


		<element name="Maven of the Roaming Steps" type="Archetype" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_SEEKER_MAVEN_OF_THE_ROAMING_STEPS">
			<supports>Seeker Mavenhood</supports>
			<description>
				<p>Getting there is half the battle, but a seeker who is a part of this Maven can make the journey easier and quicker. Reading the movement of stars, weather patterns, and swirling waters all lend them selves as divining tools for this Mavenhood.</p>
				<div element="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROAMING_STEPS_ROAMING_STEPS_SPELLS" />
				<div element="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROAMING_STEPS_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" />
				<div element="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROAMING_STEPS_TRANSPORTER" />
				<div element="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROAMING_STEPS_SAFE_HAVEN" />
				<div element="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROAMING_STEPS_GOING_THE_DISTANCE" />
			</description>
			<sheet display="false" />
			<rules>
				<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROAMING_STEPS_ROAMING_STEPS_SPELLS" level="1" />
				<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROAMING_STEPS_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" level="1" />
				<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROAMING_STEPS_TRANSPORTER" level="3" />
				<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROAMING_STEPS_SAFE_HAVEN" level="10" />
				<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROAMING_STEPS_GOING_THE_DISTANCE" level="14" />
			</rules>
		</element>
			<element name="Roaming Steps Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROAMING_STEPS_ROAMING_STEPS_SPELLS">
				<description>
					<p>When choosing this Mavenhood, you gain access to spells that help you travel your path and get there safely. At 1st, 3rd, 5th, 7th, and 9th level you gain access to the following spells.</p>
					<table>
						<thead>
							<tr><td>Seeker Level</td><td>Maven Spell</td></tr>
						</thead>
						<tr><td>1st</td><td><em>goodberry, longstrider</em></td></tr>
						<tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>find steed, misty step</em></td></tr>
						<tr><td>5th</td><td><em>fly, tiny hut</em></td></tr>
						<tr><td>7th</td><td><em>dimension door, polymorph</em></td></tr>
						<tr><td>9th</td><td><em>far step, teleportation circle</em></td></tr>
					</table>
				</description>
				<sheet display="false" />
				<rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GOODBERRY" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="1" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LONGSTRIDER" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="1" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIND_STEED" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="3" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MISTY_STEP" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="3" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FLY" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="5" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LEOMUNDS_TINY_HUT" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="5" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DIMENSION_DOOR" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="7" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_POLYMORPH" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="7" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_FAR_STEP" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="9" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TELEPORTATION_CIRCLE" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="9" />
				</rules>
			</element>
			<element name="Bonus Proficiencies" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROAMING_STEPS_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES">
				<description>
					<p>When you choose this Mavenhood at 1st level, you gain proficiency in Survival and Perception. Choose one of these two skills, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it. 6th level, you can choose a second skill that you are proficient with to add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it.</p>
				</description>
				<sheet display="false" />
				<rules>
                    <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SURVIVAL" />
                    <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION" />
                    <select type="Class Feature" name="Bonus Proficiency, Roaming Steps" supports="ID_EXPERTISE_SKILL_PERCEPTION|ID_EXPERTISE_SKILL_SURVIVAL" level="1" />
                    <select type="Class Feature" name="Bonus Proficiency, Roaming Steps" supports="Skill,Expertise" level="6" />
				</rules>
			</element>
			<element name="Transporter" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROAMING_STEPS_TRANSPORTER">
				<description>
					<p>At 3rd level, you are able to move yourself and your allies quickly through danger. You have advantage on ability checks related to navigating and traveling to a distant destination.</p>
					<p class="indent">Additionally, movement across shorter distances become your forte. As a Bonus Action, you can teleport 10 times your proficiency bonus feet away or teleport a creature 5 times your proficiency bonus feet to a location you can see; if the creature you are teleporting is unwilling, they must make a Wisdom save against your spell DC to avoid being teleported. You can use this feature a number of times per long rest equal to your Intelligence modifier.</p>
				</description>
				<sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="{{intelligence:modifier}}/Long Rest">
					<description>you can teleport {{transporter:range:self}} feet away or teleport a creature {{transporter:range:other}} feet to a location you can see; if the creature you are teleporting is unwilling, they must make a Wisdom saving throw to avoid being teleported. Additionally, you have advantage on ability checks related to navigating and traveling to a distant destination. </description>
					<description level="10" usage="{{intelligence:modifier}}/Short Rest">you can teleport {{transporter:range:self}} feet away or teleport a creature {{transporter:range:other}} feet to a location you can see; if the creature you are teleporting is unwilling, they must make a Wisdom saving throw to avoid being teleported. Additionally, you have advantage on ability checks related to navigating and traveling to a distant destination. </description>
				</sheet>
				<rules>
                    <stat name="transporter:range:other" value="proficiency" />
                    <stat name="transporter:range:other" value="proficiency" />
                    <stat name="transporter:range:other" value="proficiency" />
                    <stat name="transporter:range:other" value="proficiency" />
                    <stat name="transporter:range:other" value="proficiency" />
                    <stat name="transporter:range:self" value="transporter:range:other" />
                    <stat name="transporter:range:self" value="transporter:range:other" />
				</rules>
			</element>
			<element name="Safe Haven" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROAMING_STEPS_SAFE_HAVEN">
				<description>
					<p>When you reach 10th level, you are able to find a safe haven no matter where you go. By using a Rite and your Reaction on your turn, you can instantly return to where you started your turn as long as you are still on the same plane of existence. After you have returned to that starting position, your movement drops to 0 and you have resistance to damage until the start of your next turn.</p>
					<p class="indent">Also at 10th level, your uses of Transporter resets after a short or long rest.</p>
				</description>
				<sheet usage="1 Rite" action="Reaction">
					<description>You can instantly return to where you started your turn as long as you are still on the same plane of existence. After you have returned to that starting position, your movement drops to 0 and you have resistance to damage until the start of your next turn.</description>
				</sheet>
				<rules>
				</rules>
			</element>
			<element name="Going The Distance" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROAMING_STEPS_GOING_THE_DISTANCE">
				<description>
					<p>At 14th level, by expending a Rite and meditating for 10 minutes, you are able to cast either <i>find the path</i>, <i>teleport</i>, or <i>phase shift</i> once. For the purposes of spellcasting, you do not need the material components for using this feature.</p>
				</description>
				<sheet usage="1 Rite">
					<description>By expending a Rite and meditating for 10 minutes, you are able to cast either find the path, teleport, or phase shift once. For the purposes of spellcasting, you do not need the material components for using this feature.</description>
				</sheet>
				<rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIND_THE_PATH" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TELEPORT" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PHASE_SHIFT" />
				</rules>
			</element>


		<element name="Maven of the Rotting Voice" type="Archetype" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_SEEKER_MAVEN_OF_THE_ROTTING_VOICE">
			<supports>Seeker Mavenhood</supports>
			<description>
				<p>Dark words come from dark hearts, the Mavens of the Rotting Voice are magically enhanced oraters. Whether sweet or acidic, their spellbinding words carry so much weight that they can even talk the dead into walking with the living. Listening to ambient spirits, burning bones, and using a ouija board are regluar practices within this Mavenhood.</p>
				<div element="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTTING_VOICE_ROTTING_VOICE_SPELLS" />
				<div element="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTTING_VOICE_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" />
				<div element="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTTING_VOICE_THE_RIGHT_WORDS" />
				<div element="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTTING_VOICE_TURN_OF_PHRASE" />
				<div element="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTTING_VOICE_HYPNOTIC_WHISPERS" />
			</description>
			<sheet display="false" />
			<rules>
				<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTTING_VOICE_ROTTING_VOICE_SPELLS" level="1" />
				<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTTING_VOICE_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" level="1" />
				<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTTING_VOICE_THE_RIGHT_WORDS" level="3" />
				<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTTING_VOICE_TURN_OF_PHRASE" level="10" />
				<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTTING_VOICE_HYPNOTIC_WHISPERS" level="14" />
			</rules>
		</element>
			<element name="Rotting Voice Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTTING_VOICE_ROTTING_VOICE_SPELLS">
				<description>
					<p>When choosing this Mavenhood, you gain access to spells that help you control your foes and enlist new friends. At 1st, 3rd, 5th, 7th, and 9th level you gain access to the following spells.</p>
					<table>
						<thead>
							<tr><td>Seeker Level</td><td>Maven Spell</td></tr>
						</thead>
						<tr><td>1st</td><td><em>charm person, dissonant whispers</em></td></tr>
						<tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>gentle repose, phantasmal force, suggestion</em></td></tr>
						<tr><td>5th</td><td><em>bestow curse, summon undead</em></td></tr>
						<tr><td>7th</td><td><em>charm monster, death ward</em></td></tr>
						<tr><td>9th</td><td><em>geas, raise dead</em></td></tr>
					</table>
				</description>
				<sheet display="false" />
				<rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CHARM_PERSON" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="1" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISSONANT_WHISPERS" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="1" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GENTLE_REPOSE" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="3" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PHANTASMAL_FORCE" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="3" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SUGGESTION" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="3" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BESTOW_CURSE" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="5" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SUMMON_UNDEAD" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="5" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CHARM_MONSTER" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="7" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DEATH_WARD" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="7" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GEAS" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="9" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RAISE_DEAD" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="9" />
				</rules>
			</element>
			<element name="Bonus Proficiencies" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTTING_VOICE_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES">
				<description>
					<p>When you choose this Mavenhood at 1st level, you gain proficiency in two of the following skills: Deception, Intimidation, Persuasion, or Persuasion. Choose one of these two skills, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it. 6th level, you can choose a second skill that you are proficient with to add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it.</p>
				</description>
				<sheet display="false" />
				<rules>
                    <select type="Proficiency" name="Bonus Proficiency, Rotting Voice" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_DECEPTION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INTIMIDATION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERSUASION" number="2" level="1" />
                    <select type="Class Feature" name="Bonus Proficiency, Rotting Voice" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_DECEPTION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INTIMIDATION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERSUASION" level="1" />
                    <select type="Class Feature" name="Bonus Proficiency, Rotting Voice" supports="Skill,Expertise" level="6" />
				</rules>
			</element>
			<element name="The Right Words" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTTING_VOICE_THE_RIGHT_WORDS">
				<description>
					<p>At 3rd level, you are blessed with just enough foreknowledge to understand the right thing to say and how to act in any social setting. Once per turn you may use one of these Right Words. When you use this feature a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, you may not use this feature again until you either finish a long rest or by spending a Rite.</p>
					<p class="indent"><b>Thoughtful Words.</b> Instead of using your Charisma modifier, you may use your Intelligence modifier for a Charisma ability check or save.</p>
					<p class="indent"><b>Whispered Words.</b> When casting an Enchantment, Illusion, or Necromancy spell that has a verbal component, if you do so, the spell doesn’t require verbal, somatic, or material components that lack a gold cost.</p>
					<p class="indent"><b>Piercing Words.</b> When forcing a creature to make an Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma saving throw, if they would normally roll with advantage, instead that creature rolls that save without advantage.</p>
				</description>
				<sheet>
					<description>Once per turn you may use one of these Right Words: Thoughtful Words, Whispered Words, or Piercing Words.</description>
				</sheet>
				<rules>
				</rules>
			</element>
			<element name="Turn of Phrase" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTTING_VOICE_TURN_OF_PHRASE">
				<description>
					<p>By 10th level, you've learned to undo your gaffes and blunders. When you cast a spell with a spell slot that fails due to the target being immune to the effect, you may use your Reaction and a Rite to not expend that spell slot.</p>
					<p class="indent">Additionally, once per long rest, you may use your Reaction to skillfully reshape the memories of listeners in your immediate area, so that each creature of your choice within 5 feet of you forgets everything you said within the last 6 seconds.</p>
				</description>
				<sheet action="Reaction" usage="1 Rite">
					<description>When you cast a spell with a spell slot that fails due to the target being immune to the effect, you may use your Reaction and a Rite to not expend that spell slot. Additionally, once per long rest, you may use your Reaction to skillfully reshape the memories of listeners in your immediate area, so that each creature of your choice within 5 feet of you forgets everything you said within the last 6 seconds.</description>
				</sheet>
				<rules>
				</rules>
			</element>
			<element name="Hypnotic Whispers" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ROTTING_VOICE_HYPNOTIC_WHISPERS">
				<description>
					<p>At 14th level, your voice vibrates with magic. Pick one creature that is rolling to save against against a spell you cast, you may spend a Rite to roll a d4 and add that to your spell save DC against that creature. You can choose to use this feature only before the DM determines whether spell succeeds or fails.</p>
				</description>
				<sheet>
					<description>Pick one creature that is rolling to save against against a spell you cast, you may spend a Rite to roll a d4 and add that to your spell save DC against that creature.</description>
				</sheet>
				<rules>
				</rules>
			</element>


		<element name="Maven of the Shifting Flesh" type="Archetype" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_SEEKER_MAVEN_OF_THE_SHIFTING_FLESH">
			<supports>Seeker Mavenhood</supports>
			<description>
				<p>Focused on enhancing and changing their own bodies. These Mavens use transformative magics to adapt to whatever situation is thrown at them. By reading facial lines, palms, irises, or even blood dripped onto paper, Mavens of the Shifting Flesh read the subtle signs of the future.</p>
				<div element="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHIFTING_FLESH_SPELLS" />
				<div element="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" />
				<div element="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_REACTIVE_ADAPTATION" />
				<div element="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HEARTY_AND_HEALTHY" />
				<div element="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHED_YOUR_SHELL" />
			</description>
			<sheet display="false" />
			<rules>
				<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHIFTING_FLESH_SPELLS" level="1" />
				<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" level="1" />
				<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_REACTIVE_ADAPTATION" level="3" />
				<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HEARTY_AND_HEALTHY" level="10" />
				<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHED_YOUR_SHELL" level="14" />
			</rules>
		</element>
			<element name="Shifting Flesh Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHIFTING_FLESH_SPELLS">
				<description>
					<p>When choosing this Mavenhood, you gain access to spells that allow you to adapt your physical body. At 1st, 3rd, 5th, 7th, and 9th level you gain access to the following spells.</p>
					<table>
						<thead>
							<tr><td>Seeker Level</td><td>Maven Spell</td></tr>
						</thead>
						<tr><td>1st</td><td><em>absorb elements, jump, longstrider</em></td></tr>
						<tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>alter self, enlarge/reduce</em></td></tr>
						<tr><td>5th</td><td><em>haste, tongues</em></td></tr>
						<tr><td>7th</td><td><em>death ward, polymorph</em></td></tr>
						<tr><td>9th</td><td><em>greater restoration, skill empowerment</em></td></tr>
					</table>
				</description>
				<sheet display="false">
					<description></description>
				</sheet>
				<rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ABSORB_ELEMENTS" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="1" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_JUMP" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="1" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LONGSTRIDER" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="1" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ALTER_SELF" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="3" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENLARGE_REDUCE" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="3" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HASTE" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="5" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TONGUES" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="5" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DEATH_WARD" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="7" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_POLYMORPH" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="7" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GREATER_RESTORATION" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="9" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SKILL_EMPOWERMENT" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="9" />
				</rules>
			</element>
			<element name="Bonus Proficiencies" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES">
				<description>
					<p>When you choose this Mavenhood at 1st level you gain proficiency in the Acrobatics and Athletics skills. Choose one of these two skills, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it. At 6th level, you can choose a second skill that you are proficient with to add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it.</p>
				</description>
				<sheet display="false">
					<description></description>
				</sheet>
				<rules>
					<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ACROBATICS" />
					<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ATHLETICS" />
					<select type="Class Feature" name="Skill Expertise" supports="ID_EXPERTISE_SKILL_ACROBATICS|ID_EXPERTISE_SKILL_ATHLETICS" level="1" />
					<select type="Class Feature" name="Skill Expertise" supports="ID_EXPERTISE_SKILL_ACROBATICS|ID_EXPERTISE_SKILL_ATHLETICS" level="6" />
				</rules>
			</element>
			<element name="Reactive Adaptation" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_REACTIVE_ADAPTATION">
				<description>
					<p>At 3rd level, during a time of stress, you gain a moment of clarity, knowing just what you need to do to overcome the challenges before you.</p>
					<p class="indent">A number of times per long rest equal to your proficiency bonus, by spending a Rite, you may use a reaction to being attacked, making a saving throw, or when asked to roll an ability check, you may use a Rite to morph your body and hone your senses to meet the challenges before you for the next 10 minutes.</p>
					<p class="indent"><b>Bending Bones.</b> If you are not wearing armor when you activate this ability, you may choose to have your AC equal 10 + your Intelligence modifier + either your Strength or Dexterity modifier (your choice).</p>
					<p class="indent"><b>Steeled Mind.</b> Add your intelligence mod to Strength and Dexterity ability checks and saving throws.</p>
					<p class="indent"><b>Hardened Shell.</b> Gain temporary hit points equal to your seeker level, these temporary hit lasts until your adaptation ends.</p>
					<p class="indent">By spending a second Rite, you can cast a transmutation spell using the appopriate spell slot. The spell must be range of Self or Touch with a casting time of one action.</p>
				</description>
				<sheet usage="{{proficiency}}/Long Rest" action="Reaction">
					<description>By spending a Rite, you may use a reaction to being attacked, making a saving throw, or when asked to roll an ability check, you may use a Rite to morph your body and hone your senses to meet the challenges before you for the next 10 minutes: Bending Bones, Steeled Mind, or Hardened Shell. By spending a second Rite, you can cast a transmutation spell using the appopriate spell slot. The spell must be range of Self or Touch with a casting time of one action.</description>
				</sheet>
				<rules>
				</rules>
			</element>
			<element name="Hearty and Healthy" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HEARTY_AND_HEALTHY">
				<description>
					<p>At 10th level, you can magically morph your body to make yourself more resilient and impart that hardiness onto others. When you use the 7th level seeker feature Ill Omen, you negate all non-magical bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage taken as your body shifts to absorb the force of the attack.</p>
					<p class="indent">Additionally, when the target of your guidance uses the bonus imparted by this feature to make a Strength or Dexterity ability check, they gain temporary hit points equal to the number on the d4 rolled if the target succeeds at the ability check.</p>
				</description>
				<sheet>
					<description>When you use Ill Omen, you negate all non-magical bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage taken as your body shifts to absorb the force of the attack. when the target of your guidance uses the bonus imparted by this feature to make a Strength or Dexterity ability check, they gain temporary hit points equal to the number on the d4 rolled if the target succeeds at the ability check.</description>
				</sheet>
				<rules>
				</rules>
			</element>
			<element name="Shed Your Shell" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHED_YOUR_SHELL">
				<description>
					<p>When you reach level 14, magical transformations are second nature, allowing you to find new ways to use them. When you cast a transmutation spell of 1st level or above on yourself using a spell slot, you may choose to have one of the following affects occur:</p>
					<ul>
						<li>As your body changes, it repairs itself. Recover hit points equal to twice the level of spell cast.</li>
						<li>Maladies fall away as you are magically enhanced. Remove a disease, poison, or the status of being blinded or deafened.</li>
						<li>You may immediately move 10 feet without without provoking opportunity attacks as your body feels renewed vigor!</li>
					</ul>
					<p class="indent">Also at 14th level, when you use a Sixth Sense, roll an extra d4 when making Strength or Dexterity ability checks.</p>
				</description>
				<sheet>
					<description>When you cast a transmutation spell of 1st level or above on yourself using a spell slot, you may choose to have one of the following affects occur: Recover hit points equal to twice the level of spell cast. Remove a disease, poison, or the status of being blinded or deafened. You may immediately move 10 feet without without provoking opportunity attacks as your body feels renewed vigor!</description>
				</sheet>
				<rules>
					<stat name="sixth-sense:bonus-dice" value="1" level="14" />
				</rules>
			</element>


        <element name="Maven of the Bitter Heart" type="Archetype" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_SEEKER_MAVEN_OF_THE_BITTER_HEART">
            <supports></supports>
            <description>
                <p>Most often mistaken for witches, due to their pension for curses and animal companions. Seekers within this Mavenhood use their summoned companions to predict the future such as by staring into their eyes or listening to the chirps and chitterings.</p>
                <div element="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BITTERHEART_BITTER_HEART_SPELLS" />
                <div element="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BITTERHEART_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" />
                <div element="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BITTERHEART_SPITE" />
                <div element="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BITTERHEART_WILD_HATRED" />
                <div element="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BITTERHEART_COVEN" />
                <div element="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BITTERHEART_HAGS_HOLD" />
            </description>
            <sheet display="false" />
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BITTERHEART_BITTER_HEART_SPELLS" level="1" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BITTERHEART_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" level="1" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BITTERHEART_SPITE" level="3" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BITTERHEART_WILD_HATRED" level="3" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BITTERHEART_COVEN" level="10" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BITTERHEART_HAGS_HOLD" level="14" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Bitter Heart Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BITTERHEART_BITTER_HEART_SPELLS">
                <description>
                    <p>When choosing this Mavenhood, you gain access to spells that let you commune with nature and spite your foes. At 1st, 3rd, 5th, 7th, and 9th level you gain access to the following spells.</p>
                    <table>
                        <thead>
                            <tr><td>Seeker Level</td><td>Maven Spell</td></tr>
                        </thead>
                        <tr><td>1st</td><td><em>animal friendship, find familiar, hex</em></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>beast sense, blindness/deafness, locate animal or plant</em></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>bestow curse, motivational speech</em></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>7th</td><td><em>charm monster, phantasmal killer</em></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>9th</td><td><em>commune with nature, contagion</em></td></tr>
                    </table>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false" />
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANIMAL_FRIENDSHIP" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="1" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIND_FAMILIAR" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="1" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HEX" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="1" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BEAST_SENSE" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="3" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLINDNESS_DEAFNESS" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="3" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LOCATE_ANIMAL_OR_PLANT" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="3" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BESTOW_CURSE" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="5" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_WOTC_ACQINC_SPELL_MOTIVATIONAL_SPEECH" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="5" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CHARM_MONSTER" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="7" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PHANTASMAL_KILLER" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="7" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMMUNE_WITH_NATURE" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="9" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONTAGION" spellcasting="Seeker" prepared="true" level="9" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Bonus Proficiencies" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BITTERHEART_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES">
                <description>
                    <p>When you choose this Mavenhood at 1st level, you gain proficiency in two of the following skills: Animal Handling, Arcana, Medicine, or Nature. Choose one of these two skills, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it. At 6th level, you can double your proficiency bonus with the other skill you chose at 1st level.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
					<select type="Proficiency" name="Bonus Proficiency" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ANIMALHANDLING|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ARCANA|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_MEDICINE|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_NATURE" number="2" />
					<select type="Class Feature" name="Expertise" supports="ID_EXPERTISE_SKILL_ANIMALHANDLING|ID_EXPERTISE_SKILL_ARCANA|ID_EXPERTISE_SKILL_MEDICINE|ID_EXPERTISE_SKILL_NATURE" level="1" />
					<select type="Class Feature" name="Expertise" supports="ID_EXPERTISE_SKILL_ANIMALHANDLING|ID_EXPERTISE_SKILL_ARCANA|ID_EXPERTISE_SKILL_MEDICINE|ID_EXPERTISE_SKILL_NATURE" level="1" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Spite" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BITTERHEART_SPITE">
                <description>
                    <p>At 3rd level, woe to those that harm you or yours. When you or an ally take damage from a creature you can see, you may use a reaction to place a curse on either the attacking creature or one of their allies.</p>
                    <p class="indent">For the next minute, you know their exact location and your Sixth Sense rolls are doubled when rolling an opposed ability check or save against the target of Spite. You can’t use Spite again until you finish a long rest or spend a Rite as reaction to use this ability again. While Spite is active, on your turn choose one of the following effects against the cursed:</p>
                    <p class="indent">Bewilder. The first attack they make is done with disadvantage.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Bleed. The target takes twice your Intelligence modifier in necrotic damage from the next source of damage.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Hunted. If the target is hidden from you, you can see where they are until the start of your next turn unless they are behind full cover.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Rust. If the target would normally be immune to a type of damage, until the start of your next turn they instead have resistance to that damage.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet action="Reaction">
                    <description>When you or an ally take damage from a creature you can see, you may use a reaction to place a curse on either the attacking creature or one of their allies. For the next minute, you know their exact location and your Sixth Sense rolls are doubled when rolling an opposed ability check or save against the target of Spite. You can’t use Spite again until you finish a long rest or spend a Rite as reaction to use this ability again. While Spite is active, on your turn choose one of the following effects against the cursed: Bewilder, Bleed, Hunted, Rust.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Wild Hatred" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BITTERHEART_WILD_HATRED">
                <description>
                    <p>Also at 3rd level, when a creature is under the effect the effect of your Spite feature, you may cast the spell summon beast without using a spell slot once per short rest. When you use this feature, instead of casting the spell at its lowest level without using a spell slot, you may cast this spell using a spell slot of a higher level using your spell slots.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>When a creature is under the effect the effect of your Spite feature, you may cast the spell summon beast without using a spell slot once per short rest. When you use this feature, instead of casting the spell at its lowest level without using a spell slot, you may cast this spell using a spell slot of a higher level using your spell slots.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Coven" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BITTERHEART_COVEN">
                <description>
                    <p>By 10th level, trust is built through actions, there is great power in being bound to others. A number of times per long rest equal to your proficiency bonus, choose a humanoid ally that you can see and cast a spell with a casting time of one action using a spell slot; that creature may use their reaction to allow the magic to flow through them as if they had cast it, following all the other rules of spell casting and Intelligence is the casting stat for your ally. If that spell requires concentration, the chosen ally will be the one that concentrates on the spell.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Additionally, once per week, by using 10 Rites and using 10 hit dice, you may cast the spell awaken without using components.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="{{proficiency}}/Long Rest">
                    <description>Choose a humanoid ally that you can see and cast a spell with a casting time of one action using a spell slot; that creature may use their reaction to allow the magic to flow through them as if they had cast it, following all the other rules of spell casting and Intelligence is the casting stat for your ally. If that spell requires concentration, the chosen ally will be the one that concentrates on the spell. Additionally, once per week, by using 10 Rites and using 10 hit dice, you may cast the spell <i>awaken</i> without using components.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
					<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AWAKEN" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Hag’s Hold" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BITTERHEART_HAGS_HOLD">
                <description>
                    <p>At 14th level, you may call upon more unusual friends. Once per long rest, you may cast any spell with the word "Summon" in its title at spell level 6. The chosen spell must normally take an action to cast and you must fulfill all other requirements of that spell such as components.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                    <description>You may cast "summon" spell at spell level 6. The chosen spell must normally take an action to cast and you must fulfill all other requirements of that spell such as components.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>


    <!-- Seeker Skills -->
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ACROBATICS">
            <supports>FR Seeker</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ARCANA">
            <supports>FR Seeker</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_DECEPTION">
            <supports>FR Seeker</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_HISTORY">
            <supports>FR Seeker</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INVESTIGATION">
            <supports>FR Seeker</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_MEDICINE">
            <supports>FR Seeker</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_RELIGION">
            <supports>FR Seeker</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION">
            <supports>FR Seeker</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERSUASION">
            <supports>FR Seeker</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SLEIGHTOFHAND">
            <supports>FR Seeker</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_STEALTH">
            <supports>FR Seeker</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SURVIVAL">
            <supports>FR Seeker</supports>
        </append>

    <!-- Seeker Spells -->

		<append id="ID_TCE_SPELL_BOOMING_BLADE">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CHILL_TOUCH">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_CONTROL_FLAMES">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIRE_BOLT">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FRIENDS">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FROSTBITE">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_TCE_SPELL_GREEN_FLAME_BLADE">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_GUST">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LIGHT">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_TCE_SPELL_LIGHTNING_LURE">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGE_HAND">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MENDING">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MESSAGE">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_TCE_SPELL_MIND_SLIVER">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MINOR_ILLUSION">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_MOLD_EARTH">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PRESTIDIGITATION">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RESISTANCE">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_SHAPE_WATER">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHOCKING_GRASP">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPARE_THE_DYING">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_THAUMATURGY">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TRUE_STRIKE">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ABSORB_ELEMENTS">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ALARM">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANIMAL_FRIENDSHIP">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLESS">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMPREHEND_LANGUAGES">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_EVIL_AND_GOOD">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_MAGIC">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_POISON_AND_DISEASE">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISGUISE_SELF">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISSONANT_WHISPERS">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENSNARING_STRIKE">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENTANGLE">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FEATHER_FALL">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIND_FAMILIAR">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GIFT_OF_ALACRITY">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GUIDING_BOLT">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HUNTERS_MARK">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_IDENTIFY">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LONGSTRIDER">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PURIFY_FOOD_AND_DRINK">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SANCTUARY">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHIELD">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SILENT_IMAGE">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_UNSEEN_SERVANT">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ZEPHYR_STRIKE">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ALTER_SELF">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ARCANE_LOCK">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ARCANISTS_MAGIC_AURA">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AUGURY">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BEAST_SENSE">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLINDNESS_DEAFNESS">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BRANDING_SMITE">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DARKNESS">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DARKVISION">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_THOUGHTS">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENHANCE_ABILITY">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENLARGE_REDUCE">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIND_TRAPS">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_WOTC_EGTW_SPELL_FORTUNES_FAVOR">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_WOTC_EGTW_SPELL_IMMOVABLE_OBJECT">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INVISIBILITY">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_KNOCK">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LESSER_RESTORATION">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LEVITATE">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LOCATE_ANIMALS_OR_PLANTS">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LOCATE_OBJECT">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MIND_SPIKE">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_TCE_SPELL_TASHAS_MIND_WHIP">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MISTY_STEP">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PASS_WITHOUT_TRACE">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PRAYER_OF_HEALING">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SEE_INVISIBILITY">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SILENCE">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPIDER_CLIMB">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SUGGESTION">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_WOTC_EGTW_SPELL_WRISTPOCKET">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BESTOW_CURSE">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CLAIRVOYANCE">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COUNTERSPELL">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CREATE_FOOD_AND_WATER">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISPEL_MAGIC">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FLY">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_LLOK_SPELL_GALDERS_TOWER">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GASEOUS_FORM">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GLYPH_OF_WARDING">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HASTE">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_TCE_SPELL_INTELLECT_FORTRESS">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGIC_CIRCLE">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAJOR_IMAGE">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_NONDETECTION">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PHANTOM_STEED">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_REMOVE_CURSE">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SENDING">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_DEAD">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_PLANTS">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_TCE_SPELL_SPIRIT_SHROUD">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_THUNDER_STEP">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LEOMUNDS_TINY_HUT">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_TINY_SERVANT">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TONGUES">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WATER_BREATHING">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WATER_WALK">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ARCANE_EYE">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AURA_OF_PURITY">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BANISHMENT">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONTROL_WATER">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DIMENSION_DOOR">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DIVINATION">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FABRICATE">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FREEDOM_OF_MOVEMENT">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GREATER_INVISIBILITY">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HALLUCINATORY_TERRAIN">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LOCATE_CREATURE">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MORDENKAINENS_PRIVATE_SANCTUM">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_LLOK_SPELL_SPEEDY_COURIER">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_STONE_SHAPE">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMMUNE">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMMUNE_WITH_NATURE">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONTACT_OTHER_PLANE">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_CONTROL_WINDS">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CREATION">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISPEL_EVIL_AND_GOOD">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GREATER_RESTORATION">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LEGEND_LORE">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MODIFY_MEMORY">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PASSWALL">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_REINCARNATE">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SCRYING">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SEEMING">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_SKILL_EMPOWERMENT">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RARYS_TELEPATHIC_BOND">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TELEKINESIS">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TELEPORTATION_CIRCLE">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_WOTC_EGTW_SPELL_TEMPORAL_SHUNT">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_TRANSMUTE_ROCK">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WALL_OF_STONE">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ARCANE_GATE">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONTINGENCY">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISINTEGRATE">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIND_THE_PATH">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FORBIDDANCE">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HEROES_FEAST">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MOVE_EARTH">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_TCE_SPELL_TASHAS_OTHERWORLDLY_GUISE">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SCATTER">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SOUL_CAGE">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TRANSPORT_VIA_PLANTS">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TRUE_SEEING">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WIND_WALK">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WORD_OF_RECALL">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_TCE_SPELL_DREAM_OF_THE_BLUE_VEIL">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ETHEREALNESS">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FORCECAGE">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PLANE_SHIFT">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SEQUESTER">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SIMULACRUM">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SYMBOL">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TELEPORT">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TEMPLE_OF_THE_GODS">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANTIMAGIC_FIELD">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANTIPATHY_SYMPATHY">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DEMIPLANE">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GLIBNESS">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HOLY_AURA">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAZE">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_MIGHTY_FORTRESS">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TELEPATHY">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FORESIGHT">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GATE">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHAPECHANGE">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TIME_STOP">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>
		<append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TRUE_POLYMORPH">
			<supports>FR Seeker</supports>
		</append>

	<!-- New Feats -->
        <element name="False Prophet" type="Feat" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_FEAT_FALSE_PROPHET">
            <description>
                <p>Your words can carry weight to those susceptible enough to your fraudulent ways. You can even be so convincing that fate itself twists to meet your false prophecies.</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>You gain proficiency in the Deception skill. If you are already proficient in the skill, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it.</li>
                    <li>You learn the cantrip <i>thaumaturgy</i> and can cast it without using components.</li>
                    <li>As an action, choose one creature who can hear you and prophesize either good or bad fortunes. Make a Charisma (Deception) check contested by the target's Wisdom (Insight) check. You make your roll with disadvantage if the target does not understand the language you speak your fortune in. If your check succeeds, your target is convinced by your words and treats the next 1 that they roll as a 20 if you predicted good fortunes or the next 20 that they roll as a 1 if you predicted bad fortune. Whether or not the target is convinced, once you use this feature, you cannot use this again until you finish a short or long rest.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Short Rest">
                <description>Choose one creature who can hear you and prophesize either good or bad fortunes. Make a Deception check contested by the target's Insight check. On a success, a good omen allow them to treat their next 1 as a 20; a bad omen: 20 as a 1. You can cast thaumaturgy without using components.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
				<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_THAUMATURGY" />
				<grant type="Feat Feature" id="ID_FR_TSC_FEAT_FEATURE_FALSE_PROPHET_DECEPTION" requirements="!ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_DECEPTION" />
				<grant type="Feat Feature" id="ID_FR_TSC_FEAT_FEATURE_FALSE_PROPHET_DECEPTION_EXPERTISE" requirements="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_DECEPTION,!ID_FR_TSC_FEAT_FEATURE_FALSE_PROPHET_DECEPTION" />
            </rules>
        </element>
			<element name="Deception" type="Feat Feature" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_FEAT_FEATURE_FALSE_PROPHET_DECEPTION">
				<description />
				<sheet display="false" />
				<rules>
					<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_DECEPTION" />
				</rules>
			</element>
			<element name="name" type="Feat Feature" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_FEAT_FEATURE_FALSE_PROPHET_DECEPTION_EXPERTISE">
				<description />
				<sheet />
				<rules>
					<stat name="deception:proficiency" value="proficiency" bonus="double" />
				</rules>
			</element>
        <element name="Oracle" type="Feat" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_FEAT_ORACLE">
            <description>
                <p>You see brief glimpses of what is to come and how to twist fate.</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>When you finish a long rest, roll a d20 and record the number rolled. You can replace any attack roll, saving throw, or ability check made by you or a creature that you can see with the foretold roll; you must choose to do so before the roll and must wait until the end of your next long rest to roll a new foretelling roll.</li>
                    <li>As a reaction, when you see a creature making an ability check or saving throw, decide if they will have good or ill fortune prior to the roll. Until the start of your next turn, choose whether that creature has a d4 added to or subtracted from all ability checks and saving throws they make. After changing fortunes twice, you cannot use this feature again until you complete a short or long rest.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="2/Short Rest" action="Reaction">
                <description>As a reaction, when you see a creature making an ability check or saving throw, decide if they will have good or ill fortune prior to the roll. Until the start of your next turn, choose whether that creature has a d4 added to or subtracted from all ability checks and saving throws they make. Additionally, when you finish a long rest, roll a d20 and record the number rolled. You can replace any attack roll, saving throw, or ability check made by you or a creature that you can see with the foretold roll. </description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Seeker's Practice" type="Feat" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_FEAT_SEEKERS_PRACTICE">
            <description>
                <p>To be good is not good enough. You trained harder and that practice shows.</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>You gain proficiency in a skill and the ability score associated with that skill increases by 1 to a maximum of 20.</li>
                    <li>When you use the ability score chosen in the first part of this feat to make either an ability check or a saving throw you may choose to add a d4 bonus prior to making your roll. You may use this feature a number of times equal to your proficiency modifier before needing to take a long rest to recover.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Seeker's Quarry" type="Feat" source="The Seeker Class" id="ID_FR_TSC_FEAT_SEEKERS_QUARRY">
            <description>
                <p>No matter the odds, the gentle breath of fate can guide you to that which you seek.</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>You have advantage on Intelligence (Investigation), Wisdom (Perception), and Wisdom (Survival) checks made to follow or track a creature.</li>
                    <li>You learn the <i>hunter's mark</i> spell and can cast it without a spell slot, and you must finish a long rest before you can cast it in this way again. You can also cast hunter's mark using any spell slots you have.</li>
                    <li>By spending 1 minute performing a magical ceremony (as if you were concentrating on a spell) name a specific creature or object that is familiar to you. You sense the direction to your target's location, as long as that target is within 5 miles of you. If the creature or object you named is in a different form, such as being under the effects of a polymorph spell, this ability doesn’t locate the target.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You have advantage on Investigation, Perception, and Survival checks made to follow or track a creature. You can cast hunter's mark once per long rest without using a spell slot. By spending 1 minute performing a magical ceremony (concentration), name a specific creature or object that is familiar to you. You sense the direction to your target's location, as long as that target is within 5 miles of you.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
				<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HUNTERS_MARK" />
            </rules>
        </element>

</elements>