<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>The Samurai Class v2.1</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="class-samurai.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/classes/class-samurai.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="The Samurai Class" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_ACROBATICPLANT_HOMEBREWERY_SOURCE_THE_SAMURAI_CLASS">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation">TSC</set>
            <set name="url">https://homebrewery.naturalcrit.com/share/l1sH7QbjXe-n</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" abbreviation="AP" url="https://www.reddit.com/user/Acrobatic_Plant2937/">u/Acrobatic_Plant2937</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20210129</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Samurai" type="Class" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_SAMURAI">
        <description>
            <p>A tiefling woman charges forward across the hills, eyes locked on her quarry. As she extends her slender naginata toward the bandits, she bursts into smoke, flowing directionessly into a dark mist. Not a few seconds later, she reappears behind the confused highwayman and her polearm once again becomes a whirling extension of her will, an instrument of death.</p>
            <p class="indent">A tall, shirtless man taps his staff into his cloth-wrapped palm, standing in calm vigil in the middle of the corridor intersection. The goblins he has cornered cower in fear, not wanting to approach the deadly man. As he crouches slightly, completely immobile, and fixes his unwavering gaze on the creatures who killed his companions, they are filled with the realization that they've already died.</p>
            <p class="indent">These warriors are all samurai. They are practitioners of ancient fighting arts that are lost to history and hard to observe, harder yet to master, and near-impossible to stand against. The chakra techniques these combatants have studied put them above the average soldier and in a martial class all of their own, by drawing natural elemental power from themselves and the world around them into their combat styles. From military generals, to champions of gladiatorial ringa, contracted assassins, mercenaries, oath-sworn veterans, and devoted guardians of ancient monasteries, samurai all employ the same concepts in their lines of work. They all use chakra energy to fuel unique augmentations to their physical abilities.</p>
            <h4>STUDENTS OF THE ANCIENTS</h4>
            <p>The arts known by Samurai are those of long-forgotten empires. Whether they learned their abilities from a powerful and ancient mentor, discovered the skills entombed in forsaken books of lore, or dedicated themselves to the service of a monastery of centuries-old and experienced traditionalists, they have rediscovered something old. Bringing something so old into the modern world makes it act as something new and revolutionary, giving samurai an edge in combat.</p>
            <h4>VARIETY IN TRADITION</h4>
            <p>Depending on how specific samurai learned to fight, they may have adopted different styles. Not every secret is ever uncovered, and different adventurers will know different methods to harness their innate energy. One might know offensive, reckless techniques, using chakra to rip effort from their defense in order to pour it into aggressive attacks, while another may have mastered concentrating their energy into momentous bursts, carrying them unhindered through the areas they kill in.</p>
            <h4>CREATING A SAMURAI</h4>
            <p>As you put together the character you will be playing, think about the journey that led them to this point. How did they learn these methods of waging war? Maybe from a mentor, scripture, as a gift from some higher being, or in an excursion to another world altogether? Or did they experiment, drawing themselves into this area of greater ability by their own will? And what gives them the ability to execute such techniques? Are they determined to right the wrongs they previously wrought? Do they hold an unmatched tenacity in their blood that pushed them to always be better? What have they sacrificed along the way? What made them choose such a violent lifestyle? And how has this affected their personality today?</p>
            <h5>QUICK BUILD</h5>
            <p>You can make a Samurai Quickly by following these suggestions. First, make strength or dexterity your highest ability score, depending on whether you want to focus on melee weapons or on archery (or finesse weapons). Your next highest ability score should be intelligence, to strengthen your Chakra abilities. Second, choose the soldier background.</p>
            <h2>CLASS FEATURES</h2>
            <p>As a samurai, you gain the following class features.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">HIT POINTS</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Hit Dice:</strong> 1d10 per samurai level</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at 1st Level:</strong> 10 + your Constitution modifier</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at Higher Levels:</strong> 1d10 (or 6) + your Constitution modifier per samurai level after 1st</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">PROFICIENCIES</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled mb">
                <li><strong>Armor:</strong> All armor, sheilds</li>
                <li><strong>Weapons:</strong> Simple Weapons, Martial Weapons</li>
                <li><strong>Tools:</strong> None</li>
            </ul>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Saving Throws:</strong> Dexterity, Intellegence</li>
                <li><strong>Skills:</strong> Choose two from Acrobatics, Athletics, History, Intimidation, Investigation, Perception, and Stealth</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">EQUIPMENT</h5>
            <p>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>(a) chain mail or (b) leather armor, a longbow, and 20 arrows</li>
                <li>(a) a longsword or (b) a glaive or (c) a sheild and any martial melee weapon</li>
                <li>(a) 2 shortswords or (b) 4 darts</li>
                <li>(a) an explorer's pack (b) a dungeoneer's pack</li>
            </ul>
			<div class="sidebar">
				<h5 class="caption">Equipment for Revised Martial Equipment</h5>
				<p>If you are using the Revised Martial Equipment 5e Supplement use the following rules.</p>
				<p><b>Equipment</b></p>
				<p class="indent">You start with the following equipment in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</p>
				<ul>
					<li>(a) chain mail or (b) leather armor, a recurve bow, and 20 arrows</li>
					<li>(a) a katana or (b) a glaive or (c) a skirmish sheild and any weapon with the melee property</li>
					<li>(a) 2 shortswords or (b) 4 throwing knives</li>
					<li>(a) an explorer's pack (b) a dungeoneer's pack</li>
				</ul>
			</div>
        <!-- class table here -->
            <h5 class="caption">THE SAMURAI</h5>
            <table class="class-features">
                <thead>
                    <tr><td class="col-5">Level</td><td class="col-10">Proficiency Bonus</td><td class="col-60 left">Features</td><td class="col-10">Chakra Points</td><td class="col-10">Stances Known</td><td class="col-10">Chakra-Fueled Movement</td><td class="col-10">Resonation Dice</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td> 1st</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Chakra, Samurai Stances</td><td>1</td><td>2</td><td>-</td><td>-</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 2nd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Fighting Style, Resonating Lethality</td><td>2</td><td>2</td><td>-</td><td>1d4</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 3rd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Samurai Discipline</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>-</td><td>1d4</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 4th</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>4</td><td>2</td><td>-</td><td>1d4</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 5th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Extra Attack, Chakra-Fueled Movement</td><td>5</td><td>3</td><td>+10 ft.</td><td>1d6</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 6th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Discipline Feature</td><td>6</td><td>3</td><td>+10 ft.</td><td>1d6</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 7th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Bushido</td><td>7</td><td>3</td><td>+10 ft.</td><td>1d6</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 8th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>8</td><td>3</td><td>+10 ft.</td><td>1d6</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 9th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Strike of the Void</td><td>9</td><td>3</td><td>+10 ft.</td><td>1d6</td></tr>
                <tr><td>10th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>10</td><td>4</td><td>+15 ft.</td><td>1d6</td></tr>
                <tr><td>11th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Discipline Feature</td><td>11</td><td>4</td><td>+15 ft.</td><td>1d8</td></tr>
                <tr><td>12th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>12</td><td>4</td><td>+15 ft.</td><td>1d8</td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Discipline Feature</td><td>13</td><td>4</td><td>+15 ft.</td><td>1d8</td></tr>
                <tr><td>14th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Unconquerable Warrior</td><td>14</td><td>4</td><td>+15 ft.</td><td>1d8</td></tr>
                <tr><td>15th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Dismantle the Weave</td><td>15</td><td>5</td><td>+20 ft.</td><td>1d8</td></tr>
                <tr><td>16th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>16</td><td>5</td><td>+20 ft.</td><td>1d8</td></tr>
                <tr><td>17th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Bushido (2 uses), Unconquerable Warrior (2 uses)</td><td>17</td><td>5</td><td>+20 ft.</td><td>1d10</td></tr>
                <tr><td>18th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Discipline Feature</td><td>18</td><td>5</td><td>+20 ft.</td><td>1d10</td></tr>
                <tr><td>19th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>19</td><td>5</td><td>+20 ft.</td><td>1d10</td></tr>
                <tr><td>20th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Transcendant Soul</td><td>30</td><td>7</td><td>+20 ft.</td><td>1d10</td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_CHAKRA" />
            <div element="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_STANCES_OF_THE_SAMURAI" />
            <div element="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_FIGHTING_STYLE" />
            <div element="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_LETHAL_RESONATION" />
            <div element="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_SAMURAI_DISCIPLINE" />
            <div element="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" />
            <div element="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_EXTRA_ATTACK" />
            <div element="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_CHAKRA_FUELED_MOVEMENT" />
            <div element="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_BUSHIDO" />
            <div element="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_STRIKE_OF_THE_VOID" />
            <div element="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_UNCONQUERABLE_WARRIOR" />
            <div element="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_DISMANTLE_THE_WEAVE" />
            <div element="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_TRANSCENDANT_SOUL" />
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="hd">d10</set>
            <set name="short">A martial class that drops in and out of elemental fighting stances that change their tactical approach.</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_MEDIUM_ARMOR" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_HEAVY_ARMOR" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_SHIELDS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_MARTIAL_WEAPONS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_DEXTERITY" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_INTELLIGENCE" />
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency, Samurai" supports="Skill, Samurai" number="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_CHAKRA" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_STANCES_OF_THE_SAMURAI" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_FIGHTING_STYLE" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_LETHAL_RESONATION" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_SAMURAI_DISCIPLINE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" level="4" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_EXTRA_ATTACK" level="5" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_CHAKRA_FUELED_MOVEMENT" level="5" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_BUSHIDO" level="7" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_STRIKE_OF_THE_VOID" level="9" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_UNCONQUERABLE_WARRIOR" level="14" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_DISMANTLE_THE_WEAVE" level="15" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_TRANSCENDANT_SOUL" level="20" />
        </rules>
    </element>
		<element name="Chakra" type="Class Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_CHAKRA">
			<description>
				<p>Starting at 1st level, your training allows you to tap into your reserve of chakra. Chakra is the force that flows through all natural things, the magic that is tethered to the world to make it continue to function. Your access to this power is represented by a number of chakra points. Your samurai level determines the number of chakra points you have, as shown in the chakra points column of the samurai table.</p>
				<p class="indent">You can spend these chakra points to fuel various chakra features. You start out knowing the Stances of the Samurai feature. You gain more chakra features as you gain levels in this class.</p>
				<p class="indent">When you spend a chakra point it is unavailable to you until after you finish a short or long rest, at which point you collect your energy back into your soul. You must spend at least 30 minutes of the rest meditating to gain your chakra points.</p>
				<p class="indent">Some of your chakra features require your target to make a saving throw to resist the feature’s effects. The DC for these saves is calculated as follows.</p>
				<p style="text-align: center;"><b>Chakra save DC</b> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier</p>
				<div class="sidebar">
					<h5 class="caption">Temporary Chakra Points</h5>
					<p>Temporary chakra points function just like normal chakra points, and are used before normal chakra points when you spend them to activate a samurai ability.</p>
					<p class="indent">Because temporary chakra points are seperate from your normal pool, they can exceed you chakra point maximum. You can receive temporary chakra points even if you are at full chakra points.</p>
					<p class="indent">Temporary chakra points do not add together, if you have temporary chakra points and receive more you decide which ones to keep.</p>
				</div>
			</description>
			<sheet usage="{{chakra:points}} chakra/Short Rest">
				<description>Your chakra save DC is {{chakra:save-dc}}.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <stat name="chakra:points" value="level:samurai" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="chakra:points" value="10" level="20" bonus="captstone" />
                <stat name="chakra:save-dc" value="8" />
                <stat name="chakra:save-dc" value="proficiency" />
                <stat name="chakra:save-dc" value="intelligence:modifier" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Stances of the Samurai" type="Class Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_STANCES_OF_THE_SAMURAI">
			<description>
				<p>Starting at 1st level you gain access to stances. You learn to alter the chakra in your body to mimic the patterns it takes in the natural world. While the stance is active, you pour your chakra out from yourself in ways that function like elements of nature, affecting things around you in the same way. You start out knowing two such stances, and learn an additional stance at 5th, 10th, and 15th level, as well as 2 more stances at 20th level as shown in the stances known column of the Samurai table. Your stances options are listed at the end of the class description. To learn a stance you must have enough chakra points to activate it.</p>
				<p class="indent">At the beginning of your turn you may choose to activate a stance, by spending the chakra points listed in the description.</p>
				<p class="indent">When you activate a stance it remains in effect for a number of rounds stated in the description. Unless otherwise noted, the stances end at the beginning of your turn on the round they are stated to end on, meaning you do not gain the benefits of that stance on that turn. This happens before you have the opportunity to activate a new stance. If you choose to activate a stance before another ends, the first stance ends prematurely and the new stance takes effect. You may choose to end a stance at the beginning of your turn.</p>
				<p class="indent">Any stance you have activated ends if you become charmed, frightened, grappled, incapicated, poisoned, prone, or restrained. While under one of these conditions you are unable to activate any stances until the effect has ended on you.</p>
				<p class="indent">Additionally, when you gain a level in this class, you can choose on of the stances that you know and replace it with another stance.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description>At the beginning of your turn you may choose to activate a stance, by spending the chakra points listed in the description. Any stance you have activated ends if you become charmed, frightened, grappled, incapicated, poisoned, prone, or restrained. While under one of these conditions you are unable to activate any stances until the effect has ended on you.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Samurai Stance" supports="Samurai Stance" number="2" level="1" allowReplace="true" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Samurai Stance" supports="Samurai Stance" level="5" allowReplace="true" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Samurai Stance" supports="Samurai Stance" level="10" allowReplace="true" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Samurai Stance" supports="Samurai Stance" level="15" allowReplace="true" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Samurai Stance" supports="Samurai Stance" number="2" level="20" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Fighting Style" type="Class Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_FIGHTING_STYLE">
			<description>
				<p>At 2nd level, you adopt a particular style of fighting as your specialty. Choose one of the following options. You can’t take a Fighting Style option more than once, even if you later get to choose again.</p>
				<h5>ARCHERY</h5>
				<p>You gain a +2 bonus to attack rolls you make with ranged weapons.</p>
                <h5>BLIND FIGHTING</h5>
                <p>You have blindsight with a range of 10 feet. Within that range, you can effectively see anything that isn’t behind total cover, even if you’re blinded or in darkness. Moreover, you can see an invisible creature within that range, unless the creature successfully hides from you.</p>
				<h5>DEFENSE</h5>
				<p>While you are wearing armor, you gain a +1 bonus to AC.</p>
				<h5>GREAT WEAPON FIGHTING</h5>
				<p>When you roll a 1 or a 2 on a damage die for an attack that you make with a melee weapon that you are wielding with two hands, you can reroll the die and must use the new roll, even if the new roll is a 1 or a 2. The weapon must have the two-handed or versatile property for you to gain this benefit.</p>
                <h5>INTERCEPTION</h5>
                <p>When a creature you can see hits a target, other than you, within 5 feet of you with an attack, you can use your reaction to reduce the damage the target takes by 1d10 + your proficiency bonus (to a minimum of 0 damage). You must be wielding a shield or a simple or martial weapon to use this reaction.</p>
				<h5>TWO-WEAPON FIGHTING</h5>
				<p>When you engage in two-weapon fighting you can add your ability modifier to the damage of the second attack.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet display="false">
				<description></description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Fighting Style" supports="Fighting Style, Samurai" />
                <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_TCE_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTER_MARTIAL_VERSATILITY" level="2" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Lethal Resonation" type="Class Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_LETHAL_RESONATION">
			<description>
				<p>Also at 2nd level, while under the effects of a stance, your weapon attacks deal an additional d4 of damage. The type is determined by the stance. This damage increases as you gain levels in the Samurai class, as shown in the resonation die column of the samurai table.</p>
				<p class="indent">The additional damage dealt is bludgeoning damage for earth, root, stone, and water stance, cold for cloud, cold, ice, mist, and snow stance, fire for air, growth, and fire stance, lightning for lightning and spark stance, piercing for rain stance, slashing for hurricane, tornado, and wind stance, and thunder for storm and thunder stance.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description>While under the effects of a stance, your weapon attacks deal an additional d{{resonation:die-type}} of damage. The type is determined by the stance.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <stat name="resonation:die-type" value="4" bonus="base" level="2" />
                <stat name="resonation:die-type" value="6" bonus="base" level="5" />
                <stat name="resonation:die-type" value="8" bonus="base" level="11" />
                <stat name="resonation:die-type" value="10" bonus="base" level="17" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Samurai Discipline" type="Class Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_SAMURAI_DISCIPLINE">
			<description>
				<p>Samurai, while they follow the same lost arts, do not all share in their styles of battle. While one might manipulate chakra in a way that strikes fear in his opponents and flame in his weapon, another may call freezing energy to her arrows as she teleports about the feild of war. A variety of styles exist, and all of them are as lethal as they are mystical.</p>
				<p class="indent">Of these different techniques, four categories stand out as common patterns taken by those who can bend the chakra force of the world to their will. Shinobi, Shugoki, Stance Weilders, and Iajatsu Warrior.</p>
				<p class="indent">At 3rd level, you choose a disciple that follows the styles you seek to master through your chakra wielding. Choose Shinobi, Shugoki, or Stance Master, both detailed in this folder. The disciple you choose grants you features at 3rd, 6th, 11th, 13th, and 18th level.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet display="false">
				<description></description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <select type="Archetype" name="Samurai Discipline" supports="Samurai Discipline" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Ability Score Improvement" type="Class Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT">
			<description>
				<p>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature. Using the optional feats rule, you can forgo taking this feature to take a feat of your choice.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet display="false">
				<description></description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
				<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Samurai 4)" supports="Improvement Option,Samurai,4" level="4" />
				<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Samurai 8)" supports="Improvement Option,Samurai,8" level="8" />
				<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Samurai 12)" supports="Improvement Option,Samurai,12" level="12" />
				<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Samurai 16)" supports="Improvement Option,Samurai,16" level="16" />
				<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Samurai 19)" supports="Improvement Option,Samurai,19" level="19" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Extra Attack" type="Class Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_EXTRA_ATTACK">
			<description>
				<p>Starting at 5th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the attack action on your turn.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description>You can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the attack action on your turn.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <stat name="extra attack:count" value="2" level="5" bonus="extra attack" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Chakra-Fueled Movement" type="Class Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_CHAKRA_FUELED_MOVEMENT">
			<description>
				<p>At 5th level, your energy in stances hurls you forward at superior speeds. While you are under the effects of a stance your movement speed increases by 10 feet. This amount increases as you gain levels in the samurai class, as shown in the Chakra-Fueled Movement column of the Samurai table.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description>While you are under the effects of a stance your movement speed increases by 10 feet.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <stat name="chakra:movement" value="10" level="5" />
                <stat name="chakra:movement" value="5" level="10" />
                <stat name="chakra:movement" value="5" level="15" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Bushido" type="Class Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_BUSHIDO">
			<description>
				<p>At 7th level, you gain the ability to push yourself beyond your limits, extending the power of a focussed assault. On your turn you may take a second action, which may only be used to take the Attack action or activate a stance ability that requires you to take the Attack action. If you hit with all the attacks available to you this turn, you may choose to take a third such action. You must finish a short or long rest before you can use this feature again. Starting at 17th level you can use this feature twice between rests.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet usage="{{bushido:uses}}/Short Rest">
				<description>On your turn you may take a second action, which may only be used to take the Attack action or activate a stance ability that requires you to take the Attack action. If you hit with all the attacks available to you this turn, you may choose to take a third such action.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <stat name="bushido:uses" value="1" level="7" />
                <stat name="bushido:uses" value="1" level="17" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Strike of the Void" type="Class Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_STRIKE_OF_THE_VOID">
			<description>
				<p>Starting at 9th level, you have learned to charge attacks with lethal chakra energy, both in and out of stances. When you make a weapon attack on your turn, you may choose to spend any number of chakra points, up to a maximum of your Intelligence modifier. If you do so and the attack hits, you add points of force damage to the attack equal to a roll of your resonation die for every point you expended.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description>When you make a weapon attack on your turn, you may choose to spend up to {{int-mod:min-one}} chakra points. If you do so and the attack hits, you add 1d{{resonation:die-type}} force damage.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Unconquerable Warrior" type="Class Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_UNCONQUERABLE_WARRIOR">
			<description>
				<p>Starting at 14th level, your mastery of chakra grants you proficiency in all saving throws. Additionally, when you make a saving throw, attack roll, or ability check, you can choose to add an amount to it equal to a roll of your resonation die. Once you have used this ability you cannot do so again until you have finished a long rest. Starting at 17th level, you can use this feature twice between rests.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet usage="{{unconquerable-warrior:uses}}/Long Rest">
				<description>When you make a saving throw, attack roll, or ability check, you can choose to add an amount to it equal to a roll of your resonation die.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_STRENGTH" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CONSTITUTION" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_WISDOM" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CHARISMA" />
                <stat name="unconquerable-warrior:uses" value="1" level="14" />
                <stat name="unconquerable-warrior:uses" value="1" level="17" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Dismantle the Weave" type="Class Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_DISMANTLE_THE_WEAVE">
			<description>
				<p>At 15th level, you gain the ability to hone your weapons with destructive chakra, capable of unraveling magic. As an action you may spend 3 chakra points to choose a target and attempt to hone your blade with rupturing energy, casting dispel magic at 3rd level. You must know the effect is present to do this, but need not know what it is. If the target is a creature you must roll to attack. On a hit, you deal your weapon’s damage in addition to dispelling one effect of your choice. If your target is an object or magical force, you may cast dispel magic as normal. If the magic is of 4th level or higher and requires a check, your bonus to that check equals your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier. You have advantage on this check if the target is a tangible magical barrier such as that created by the wall of stone or magic circle spell.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet action="Action" usage="3 chakra">
				<description>Choose a target and attempt to hone your blade with rupturing energy, casting dispel magic at 3rd level. If the target is a creature you must roll to attack. On a hit, you deal your weapon’s damage in addition to dispelling one effect of your choice. If the magic is of 4th level or higher and requires a check, your bonus to that check is +{{dismantle-weave:bonus}}. You have advantage on this check if the target is a tangible magical barrier such as that created by the wall of stone or magic circle spell.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <stat name="dismantle-weave:bonus" value="proficiency" />
                <stat name="dismantle-weave:bonus" value="intelligence:modifier" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Transcendant Soul" type="Class Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_TRANSCENDANT_SOUL">
			<description>
				<p>At 20th level, you have opened your soul to the well of chakra within you. Your maximum amount of chakra points increases to 30.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet display="false">
				<description></description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
			</rules>
		</element>

    <!-- Samurai Disciplines -->
        <element name="Shinobi" type="Archetype" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_SAMURAI_SHINOBI">
            <supports>Samurai Discipline</supports>
            <description>
                <p>Samurai who practice shinobi arts have trained to use their chakra in more subtle ways. They are able to tap into their chakra to move around the battlefield rapidly, repositioning and dropping into stealth to play with their opponents. Once a shinobi manages to become unseen, they are deadliest, as they can bend the shadows to their own will. Shinobi are trained in the use of subversive methods to avoid their opponent’s wrath and to preserve their own chakra.</p>
                <div element="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHINOBI_SHADOW_SIGHT" />
                <div element="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHINOBI_UMBRAL_STALKER" />
                <div element="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHINOBI_SEIZE_VITALITY" />
                <div element="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHINOBI_UNSHACKLED_MOBILITY" />
                <div element="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHINOBI_CHAKRAL_SHROUD" />
                <div element="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHINOBI_SHADOW_WEILDER" />
                <div element="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHINOBI_SOUL_LARCENY" />
            </description>
            <sheet display="false" />
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHINOBI_SHADOW_SIGHT" level="3" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHINOBI_UMBRAL_STALKER" level="3" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHINOBI_SEIZE_VITALITY" level="6" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHINOBI_UNSHACKLED_MOBILITY" level="6" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHINOBI_CHAKRAL_SHROUD" level="11" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHINOBI_SHADOW_WEILDER" level="13" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHINOBI_SOUL_LARCENY" level="18" />
            </rules>
        </element>
			<element name="Shadow Sight" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHINOBI_SHADOW_SIGHT">
				<description>
					<p>At 3rd level you gain darkvision out to a range of 30 feet. If you already have darkvision from your race, the range increases by 30 feet.</p>
				</description>
				<sheet display="false">
					<description></description>
				</sheet>
				<rules>
                    <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_DARKVISION_OR_INCREASE_30" />
				</rules>
			</element>
			<element name="Umbral Stalker" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHINOBI_UMBRAL_STALKER">
				<description>
					<p>Beginning at 3rd level, you gain the ability to phase into shadows. As a bonus action, you may teleport to an unoccupied space you can see within 20 feet of you that is in dim light or darkness. When you teleport in this way, you may immediately attempt to hide as a free action, even if you are only in dim light. When you gain the Chakra-Fueled movement feature at 5th level in this class, the distance you can teleport increases by the amount listed in the Chakra-Fueled movement column of the Samurai table.</p>
				</description>
				<sheet action="Bonus Action">
					<description>You may teleport to an unoccupied space you can see within {{umbral-stalker:range}} feet of you that is in dim light or darkness. When you teleport in this way, you may immediately attempt to hide as a free action, even if you are only in dim light.</description>
				</sheet>
				<rules>
                    <stat name="umbral-stalker:range" value="20" level="3" bonus="base" />
                    <stat name="umbral-stalker:range" value="20" bonus="chakra:movement" />
				</rules>
			</element>
			<element name="Seize Vitality" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHINOBI_SEIZE_VITALITY">
				<description>
					<p>Beginning at 6th level, you gain the ability to pull the chakra of your enemies into your weapons mid-combat. Whenever you score a critical hit on a creature of CR 1 or higher, you immediately gain 1 temporary chakra point.</p>
				</description>
				<sheet>
					<description>Whenever you score a critical hit on a creature of CR 1 or higher, you immediately gain 1 temporary chakra point.</description>
				</sheet>
				<rules>
				</rules>
			</element>
			<element name="Unshackled Mobility" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHINOBI_UNSHACKLED_MOBILITY">
				<description>
					<p>At 6th level, you gain climbing and swimming speeds equal to your walking speed. Additionally, you have advantage on checks made to climb difficult surfaces or swim difficult currents.</p>
				</description>
				<sheet>
					<description>You have advantage on checks made to climb difficult surfaces or swim difficult currents.</description>
				</sheet>
				<rules>
                    <stat name="speed:climb" value="speed" bonus="base" />
                    <stat name="speed:swim" value="speed" bonus="base" />
				</rules>
			</element>
			<element name="Chakral Shroud" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHINOBI_CHAKRAL_SHROUD">
				<description>
					<p>Starting at 11th level you have learned to pull your chakra apart, sundering your physical image so that you have no visible presence to detect. When you are in an area of dim light or darkness, you can use your action to become invisible. You remain invisible until you make an attack, cast a spell, or are in an area of bright light.</p>
				</description>
				<sheet action="Action">
					<description>When you are in an area of dim light or darkness, you can become invisible. You remain invisible until you make an attack, cast a spell, or are in an area of bright light.</description>
				</sheet>
				<rules>
				</rules>
			</element>
			<element name="Shadow Weilder" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHINOBI_SHADOW_WEILDER">
				<description>
					<p>At 13th level, when you have advantage on an attack roll and you activate Strike of the Void, the amount of chakra points required to apply the extra damage decreases by 2 chakra points.</p>
				</description>
				<sheet>
					<description>When you have advantage on an attack roll and you activate Strike of the Void, the amount of chakra points required to apply the extra damage decreases by 2 chakra points.</description>
				</sheet>
				<rules>
				</rules>
			</element>
			<element name="Soul Larceny" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHINOBI_SOUL_LARCENY">
				<description>
					<p>Starting at 18th level you can drain the chakra of your victims into your being. Once per turn, when you reduce a creature of at least CR 1 to 0 hit points you regain 2 chakra points. If this would exceed your maximum amount of chakra points, any excess points are instead converted to temporary chakra points.</p>
				</description>
				<sheet>
					<description>Once per turn, when you reduce a creature of at least CR 1 to 0 hit points you regain 2 chakra points. If this would exceed your maximum amount of chakra points, any excess points are instead converted to temporary chakra points.</description>
				</sheet>
				<rules>
				</rules>
			</element>

        <element name="Shugoki" type="Archetype" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_SAMURAI_SHUGOKI">
            <supports>Samurai Discipline</supports>
            <description>
                <p>Shugoki samurai use terror and physical debilitation to take on and disable multiple opponents at once, protecting those around them. They have sometimes been called guardian demons. Their brutal combat style is both respected and feared by those around them, warriors and commonfolk alike.</p>
                <div element="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHUGOKI_TERRIFYING_DEMEANOR" />
                <div element="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHUGOKI_CRIPPLING_BLOW" />
                <div element="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHUGOKI_DESIRE_TO_PRESERVE" />
                <div element="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHUGOKI_DEMONS_PRESENCE" />
                <div element="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHUGOKI_REAPING_SLASH" />
                <div element="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHUGOKI_GUARDIANS_DEMONS_EMBRACE" />
            </description>
            <sheet display="false" />
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHUGOKI_TERRIFYING_DEMEANOR" level="3" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHUGOKI_CRIPPLING_BLOW" level="3" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHUGOKI_DESIRE_TO_PRESERVE" level="6" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHUGOKI_DEMONS_PRESENCE" level="11" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHUGOKI_REAPING_SLASH" level="13" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHUGOKI_GUARDIANS_DEMONS_EMBRACE" level="18" />
            </rules>
        </element>
			<element name="Terrifying Demeanor" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHUGOKI_TERRIFYING_DEMEANOR">
				<description>
					<p>At 3rd level you gain proficiency in the Intimidation skill. If you are already proficient in Intimidation you instead gain proficiency in one other skill of your choice from the Samurai skill list.</p>
				</description>
				<sheet display="false">
					<description></description>
				</sheet>
				<rules>
                    <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency, Terrifying Demeanor" supports="Skill, Samurai" default="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INTIMIDATION" />
				</rules>
			</element>
			<element name="Crippling Blow" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHUGOKI_CRIPPLING_BLOW">
				<description>
					<p>Starting at 3rd level, you learn to target specific points of your opponent’s body, causing them to weaken. When you hit with an attack on your turn you may spend 1 chakra point. If you do so, the target must succeed on a Constitution saving throw against your chakra save DC. On a failure, the target has disadvantage on the first attack roll they make, and Strength, Dexterity, and Constitution saving throws until the end of your next turn.</p>
				</description>
				<sheet>
					<description>When you hit with an attack on your turn you may spend 1 chakra point and the target must succeed on a Constitution saving throw (DC {{chakra:save-dc}}). On a failure, the target has disadvantage on the first attack roll they make, and Strength, Dexterity, and Constitution saving throws until the end of your next turn.</description>
				</sheet>
				<rules>
				</rules>
			</element>
			<element name="Desire to Preserve" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHUGOKI_DESIRE_TO_PRESERVE">
				<description>
					<p>At 6th level, the need to protect others allows you to use the power of the demon to intervene. When a creature that you could get within 5 feet of with your movement that you can see makes an attack against a creature other than you, you may use your reaction to move up to your speed toward the target. If the attack hits, you suffer the damage instead of the original target. If the attack misses, the attacker must make a Strength saving throw against your chakra save DC. On a failed save, the attacker is knocked prone.</p>
				</description>
				<sheet action="Reaction">
					<description>When a creature that you could get within 5 feet of with your movement that you can see makes an attack against a creature other than you, you may move up to your speed toward the target. If the attack hits, you suffer the damage instead of the original target. If the attack misses, the attacker must make a Strength saving throw against your chakra save DC. On a failed save, the attacker is knocked prone.</description>
				</sheet>
				<rules>
				</rules>
			</element>
			<element name="Demon’s Presence" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHUGOKI_DEMONS_PRESENCE">
				<description>
					<p>Starting at 11th level your presence is able to deter even the most fearless of fighters. As an action, you may expend 4 chakra points. If you do so, every creature of your choice with 60 feet of you must make a Wisdom saving throw against your chakra save DC. A creature not within 20 feet of you gains a +3 bonus to the save, and every creature not within 40 feet of you gains an additional +3 bonus to the save. On a failed save, a creature is frightened of you for one minute. The creature can repeat the save at the end of each of its turns, with a bonus determined in the same way as the initial save.</p>
				</description>
				<sheet action="Action" usage="4 chakra">
					<description>Every creature of your choice with 60 feet of you must make a Wisdom saving throw (DC {{chakra:save-dc}}). A creature not within 20 feet of you gains a +3 bonus to the save, and every creature not within 40 feet of you gains an additional +3 bonus to the save. On a failed save, a creature is frightened of you for one minute. The creature can repeat the save at the end of each of its turns, with a bonus determined in the same way as the initial save.</description>
				</sheet>
				<rules>
				</rules>
			</element>
			<element name="Reaping Slash" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHUGOKI_REAPING_SLASH">
				<description>
					<p>Starting at 13th level, whenever you hit a creature who is frightened of you with a weapon attack, you gain temporary hit points equal to a roll of your resonation die.</p>
				</description>
				<sheet>
					<description>Whenever you hit a creature who is frightened of you with a weapon attack, you gain 1d{{resolution:die-type}} temporary hit points.</description>
				</sheet>
				<rules>
				</rules>
			</element>
			<element name="Guardians Demon's Embrace" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHUGOKI_GUARDIANS_DEMONS_EMBRACE">
				<description>
					<p>Starting at 18th level, you gain advantage on attacks against any creature frightened of you. Additionally, you gain the following stance. Once you have activated this stance, you can’t activate it again until you have finished a short or long rest. While in demon stance your resonance damage is psychic.</p>
					<p class="indent"><b>Demon Stance.</b> Your chakra becomes a volatile and intimidating force, ripping the confidence from your opponents and using it to feed your own life.</p>
					<p class="indent">You can spend 2 chakra points to take this stance. While in this stance, you gain 10 hit points at the beginning of each of your turns. Additionally, you radiate an aura in a 30-foot radius. The first time an enemy enters the aura or starts its turn there, the creature must succeed on a wisdom saving throw against your chakra DC or become frightened of you until this stance ends or until they leave the aura. Attack rolls against the frightened creature have advantage. The creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on a success. An enemy creature that starts its turn in the aura suffers 2d8 points of psychic damage. This stance lasts for 10 rounds.</p>
				</description>
				<sheet>
					<description>You gain advantage on attacks against any creature frightened of you.</description>
				</sheet>
				<rules>
                    <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHUGOKI_GUARDIANS_DEMONS_EMBRACE_DEMON_STANCE" level="18" />
				</rules>
			</element>
                <element name="Demon Stance" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHUGOKI_GUARDIANS_DEMONS_EMBRACE_DEMON_STANCE">
                    <description>
                        <p>Your chakra becomes a volatile and intimidating force, ripping the confidence from your opponents and using it to feed your own life.</p>
                        <p class="indent">You can spend 2 chakra points to take this stance. While in this stance, you gain 10 hit points at the beginning of each of your turns. Additionally, you radiate an aura in a 30-foot radius. The first time an enemy enters the aura or starts its turn there, the creature must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw against your chakra DC or become frightened of you until this stance ends or until they leave the aura. Attack rolls against the frightened creature have advantage. The creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on a success. An enemy creature that starts its turn in the aura suffers 2d8 points of psychic damage. This stance lasts for 10 rounds.</p>
                    </description>
                    <sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
                        <description>You can spend 2 chakra points to take this stance. While in this stance, you gain 10 hit points at the beginning of each of your turns. Additionally, you radiate an aura in a 30-foot radius. The first time an enemy enters the aura or starts its turn there, the creature must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw (DC {{chakra:save-dc}}) or become frightened of you until this stance ends or until they leave the aura. Attack rolls against the frightened creature have advantage. The creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on a success. An enemy creature that starts its turn in the aura suffers 2d8 points of psychic damage. This stance lasts for 10 rounds.</description>
                    </sheet>
                </element>

        <element name="Stance Master" type="Archetype" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_SAMURAI_STANCE_MASTER">
            <supports>Samurai Discipline</supports>
            <description>
                <p>Samurai who have learned the techniques of the stance master have focused on their combat stances. They have developed ways to further their stances, making them stronger and staying within them longer. Not only do they briefly re-tune their chakra to exert elemental energy, they fully transform it, draining their energy to summon nature to their hand.</p>
                <div element="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STANCE_MASTER_VERSATILE_ESSENCE" />
                <div element="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STANCE_MASTER_AMPLIFIED_STANCES" />
                <div element="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STANCE_MASTER_CHAKRA_INFUSED_ASSAULT" />
                <div element="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STANCE_MASTER_RETURN_TO_PERFECTION" />
                <div element="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STANCE_MASTER_CONCENTRATED_ESSENCE" />
                <div element="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STANCE_MASTER_ENERGY_SIPHON" />
                <div element="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STANCE_MASTER_CONSTANT_RESONATION" />
            </description>
            <sheet display="false" />
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STANCE_MASTER_VERSATILE_ESSENCE" level="3" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STANCE_MASTER_AMPLIFIED_STANCES" level="3" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STANCE_MASTER_CHAKRA_INFUSED_ASSAULT" level="6" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STANCE_MASTER_RETURN_TO_PERFECTION" level="6" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STANCE_MASTER_CONCENTRATED_ESSENCE" level="11" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STANCE_MASTER_ENERGY_SIPHON" level="13" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STANCE_MASTER_CONSTANT_RESONATION" level="18" />
            </rules>
        </element>
			<element name="Versatile Essence" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STANCE_MASTER_VERSATILE_ESSENCE">
				<description>
					<p>At 3rd level, you learn an additional stance of your choice, choosing from the Stances document.</p>
				</description>
				<sheet display="false">
					<description></description>
				</sheet>
				<rules>
                    <select type="Class Feature" name="Samurai Stance" supports="Samurai Stance" level="3" />
				</rules>
			</element>
			<element name="Amplified Stances" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STANCE_MASTER_AMPLIFIED_STANCES">
				<description>
					<p>Starting at 3rd level, you gain the ability to not only channel and summon natural energy, but to direct massive amounts of it from the world, to your presence. When you activate a stance, you may choose to amplify it by spending twice the required chakra points. You gain the following benefits;</p>
					<ul>
						<li>The stance lasts for twice the listed duration.</li>
						<li>Enemies suffer disadvantage on saving throws they make to resist the effects of your stances.</li>
						<li>When you become charmed, frightened, grappled, poisoned, prone, or restrained, your stance does not immediately end. Instead you must make a Constitution saving throw with a DC equal to 8 + your proficiency bonus. The DC increases by 2 if the triggering condition was grappled or prone, and by 3 if the triggering condition was restrained. On a successful save, you maintain your stance.</li>
					</ul>
					<p class="indent">You may use this feature a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier, and you regain expended uses upon finishing a long rest.</p>
				</description>
				<sheet usage="{{intelligence:modifier}}/Long Rest">
					<description>When you activate a stance, you may choose to amplify it by spending twice the required chakra points.</description>
				</sheet>
				<rules>
				</rules>
			</element>
			<element name="Chakra-Infused Assault" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STANCE_MASTER_CHAKRA_INFUSED_ASSAULT">
				<description>
					<p>Starting at 6th level, attacks you make while within a stance count as magical for the purpose of overcoming resistance and immunity to non-magical attacks and damage.</p>
				</description>
				<sheet>
					<description>Attacks you make while within a stance count as magical for the purpose of overcoming resistance and immunity to non-magical attacks and damage.</description>
				</sheet>
				<rules>
				</rules>
			</element>
			<element name="Return to Perfection" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STANCE_MASTER_RETURN_TO_PERFECTION">
				<description>
					<p>At 6th level, you have learned to fuse to chakra to fortify yourself against effects that may break your stances. You have advantage on saving throws to resist becoming charmed, frightened, grappled, poisoned, prone, or restrained.</p>
				</description>
				<sheet>
					<description>You have advantage on saving throws to resist becoming charmed, frightened, grappled, poisoned, prone, or restrained.</description>
				</sheet>
				<rules>
				</rules>
			</element>
			<element name="Concentrated Essence" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STANCE_MASTER_CONCENTRATED_ESSENCE">
				<description>
					<p>Starting at 11th level, you have learned to perserve your stances by feeding off of the energy of others. The first time on your turn when you reduce a creature to zero hit points with a weapon attack, you can choose to lengthen the duration for your current stance by one round. You may siphon energy up to a maximum number of times equal to your Intellegence modifer. Once you have expended all of these uses, you must finish a long rest to regain them.</p>
				</description>
				<sheet usage="{{intelligence:modifier}}/Long Rest">
					<description>The first time on your turn when you reduce a creature to zero hit points with a weapon attack, you can choose to lengthen the duration for your current stance by one round.</description>
				</sheet>
				<rules>
				</rules>
			</element>
			<element name="Energy Siphon" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STANCE_MASTER_ENERGY_SIPHON">
				<description>
					<p>At 13th level, you have trained yourself to stay in stances longer with less severe consequences. When a stance finishes on your turn, and you activate the same stance immediately, the cost of activation for that stance becomes 1 chakra point, regardless of the previous cost. Note that if you amplified the stance you must do so again in order to use this feature, and it costs an additional chakra point.</p>
				</description>
				<sheet>
					<description>When a stance finishes on your turn, and you activate the same stance immediately, the cost of activation for that stance becomes 1 chakra point, regardless of the previous cost. Note that if you amplified the stance you must do so again in order to use this feature, and it costs an additional chakra point.</description>
				</sheet>
				<rules>
				</rules>
			</element>
			<element name="Constant Resonation" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STANCE_MASTER_CONSTANT_RESONATION">
				<description>
					<p>Starting at 18th level, as opposed to being able to amplify stances a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier, you may now amplify stances an unlimited number of times. Additionally, you may amplify stances without paying the additional cost a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier. You regain all expended uses of amplifying stances in this way after completing a long rest.</p>
				</description>
				<sheet usage="{{intelligence:modifier}}/Long Rest">
					<description>You may now amplify stances an unlimited number of times. You may amplify stances without paying the additional cost.</description>
				</sheet>
				<rules>
				</rules>
			</element>

        <element name="Iajatsu Warrior" type="Archetype" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_SAMURAI_IAJATSU_WARRIOR">
            <supports>Samurai Discipline</supports>
            <description>
                <p>Iajastu warriors are Samurai who have mastered the art of combat. They weild their chakra in more subtle, physical ways, and are known as the most martially aggressive of all Samurai.</p>
                <div element="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_IAJATSU_WARRIOR_OPPURTUNE_STRIKE" />
                <div element="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_IAJATSU_WARRIOR_AGGRESSIVE" />
                <div element="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_IAJATSU_WARRIOR_UPGRADED_EXTRA_ATTACK" />
                <div element="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_IAJATSU_WARRIOR_VERSATILE_FIGHTER" />
                <div element="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_IAJATSU_WARRIOR_BLADE_WITH_NO_EQUAL" />
            </description>
            <sheet display="false" />
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_IAJATSU_WARRIOR_OPPURTUNE_STRIKE" level="3" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_IAJATSU_WARRIOR_AGGRESSIVE" level="6" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_IAJATSU_WARRIOR_UPGRADED_EXTRA_ATTACK" level="11" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_IAJATSU_WARRIOR_VERSATILE_FIGHTER" level="13" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_IAJATSU_WARRIOR_BLADE_WITH_NO_EQUAL" level="18" />
            </rules>
        </element>
			<element name="Oppurtune Strike" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_IAJATSU_WARRIOR_OPPURTUNE_STRIKE">
				<description>
					<p>Starting at when you choose this disciple at 3rd level, your weapon attacks score a critical hit on a roll of 19 or 20.</p>
				</description>
				<sheet>
					<description>Your weapon attacks score a critical hit on a roll of 19 or 20.</description>
				</sheet>
				<rules>
				</rules>
			</element>
			<element name="Aggressive" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_IAJATSU_WARRIOR_AGGRESSIVE">
				<description>
					<p>Beginning at 6th level, you may move up to your speed toward an enemy of your choice that you can see or hear as a bonus action. You must end this move closer to the target than where you started.</p>
				</description>
				<sheet action="Bonus Action">
					<description>You may move up to {{speed}} feet toward an enemy of your choice that you can see or hear. You must end this move closer to the target than where you started.</description>
				</sheet>
				<rules>
				</rules>
			</element>
			<element name="Upgraded Extra Attack" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_IAJATSU_WARRIOR_UPGRADED_EXTRA_ATTACK">
				<description>
					<p>Beginning at 11th level, whenever you score a critical hit on a creature on your turn you may immediately make an additional weapon attack with the same weapon as a bonus action.</p>
				</description>
				<sheet action="Bonus Action">
					<description>Whenever you score a critical hit on a creature on your turn you may immediately make an additional weapon attack with the same weapon as a bonus action.</description>
				</sheet>
				<rules>
				</rules>
			</element>
			<element name="Versatile Fighter" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_IAJATSU_WARRIOR_VERSATILE_FIGHTER">
				<description>
					<p>At 13th level, you can choose another option from the Fighting Style class feature.</p>
				</description>
				<sheet display="false">
					<description></description>
				</sheet>
				<rules>
                    <select type="Class Feature" name="Fighting Style" supports="Fighting Style, Samurai" />
				</rules>
			</element>
			<element name="Blade With No Equal" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_IAJATSU_WARRIOR_BLADE_WITH_NO_EQUAL">
				<description>
					<p>Starting at 18th level, you learn how to thoroughly punish your opponent's reaction to mistakes, in both themselves and in you. When you score a critical failure on an attack against an enemy, or an enemy scores a critical failure on an attack against you, your next attack against that enemy becomes an automatic critical on a hit.</p>
				</description>
				<sheet>
					<description>When you score a critical failure on an attack against an enemy, or an enemy scores a critical failure on an attack against you, your next attack against that enemy becomes an automatic critical on a hit.</description>
				</sheet>
				<rules>
				</rules>
			</element>


    <!-- Samurai Skills -->
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ACROBATICS">
            <supports>Samurai</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ATHLETICS">
            <supports>Samurai</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_HISTORY">
            <supports>Samurai</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INTIMIDATION">
            <supports>Samurai</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INVESTIGATION">
            <supports>Samurai</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION">
            <supports>Samurai</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_STEALTH">
            <supports>Samurai</supports>
        </append>

    <!-- Samurai Fighting Styles -->
        <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_ARCHERY">
            <supports>Samurai</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_DEFENSE">
            <supports>Samurai</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_GREAT_WEAPON_FIGHTING">
            <supports>Samurai</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_TWOWEAPON_FIGHTING">
            <supports>Samurai</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_WOTC_TCE_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTING_STYLE_BLIND_FIGHTING">
            <supports>Samurai</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_WOTC_TCE_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTING_STYLE_INTERCEPTION">
            <supports>Samurai</supports>
        </append>

    <!-- Samurai Stances -->
		<element name="Air Stance" type="Class Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_STANCE_AIR_STANCE">
            <supports>Samurai Stance</supports>
            <requirements>[chakra:points:2]</requirements>
			<description>
				<p class="flavor">Your chakra lingers in the air, ready to flow into the bodies of the fallen to preserve the flame of life within them.</p>
				<p class="indent">You can spend 1 chakra point to take this stance. While this stance is active, targets within 20 feet of you can not accumulate failed death saves. This stance does not erase failed death saves. This stance lasts for 5 rounds.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet usage="2 chakra">
				<description>While this stance is active, targets within 20 feet of you can not accumulate failed death saves. This stance does not erase failed death saves. This stance lasts for 5 rounds.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Cloud Stance" type="Class Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_STANCE_CLOUD_STANCE">
            <supports>Samurai Stance</supports>
            <requirements>[chakra:points:3]</requirements>
			<description>
				<p class="flavor">Your chakra coalesces into a cloud layer capable of suspending you and others in the air.</p>
				<p class="indent">You can spend 3 chakra points to take this stance. While this stance is active every creature within 20 feet of you gains a hovering speed equal to their walking speed. Additionally, you gain a flying speed equal to half your walking speed. When a creature within 40 feet of you would suffer fall damage, you can use your reaction to reduce the damage to none. Cloud stance lasts for 4 rounds.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet usage="3 chakra">
				<description>While this stance is active every creature within 20 feet of you gains a hovering speed equal to their walking speed. Additionally, you gain a flying speed equal to half your walking speed. When a creature within 40 feet of you would suffer fall damage, you can use your reaction to reduce the damage to none. Cloud stance lasts for 4 rounds.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Cold Stance" type="Class Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_STANCE_COLD_STANCE">
            <supports>Samurai Stance</supports>
            <requirements>[chakra:points:1]</requirements>
			<description>
				<p class="flavor">You exude an aura of freezing energy . The heat drains the will and energy from your opponents, and the freezing air shocks your allies into action.</p>
				<p class="indent">You can spend 1 chakra point to take this stance. When you enter this stance, choose a number of creatures you can see within 30 feet of you up to your Intelligence modifier. The targets must make a Constitution saving throw against your chakra save DC. On a failure, their speed is reduced by 10 feet. If you have the Chakra-Fueled Movement feature, the amount by which you reduce their speed is instead equal to your amount for that feature. This stance lasts for 10 rounds.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet usage="1 chakra">
				<description>When you enter this stance, choose up to {{intelligence:modifier}} creatures you can see within 30 feet of you up to your Intelligence modifier. The targets must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failure, their speed is reduced by {{cold-stance:penalty}} feet. If you have the Chakra-Fueled Movement feature, the amount by which you reduce their speed is instead equal to your amount for that feature. This stance lasts for 10 rounds.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <stat name="cold-stance:penalty" value="10" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="cold-stance:penalty" value="chakra:movement" bonus="base" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Earth Stance" type="Class Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_STANCE_EARTH_STANCE">
            <supports>Samurai Stance</supports>
            <requirements>[chakra:points:2]</requirements>
			<description>
				<p class="flavor">You become as resilient and unforgiving as the earth itself, unflinching at the most deadly of blows as you pull the essence of the world around you into your core.</p>
				<p class="indent">You can spend 2 chakra points to take this stance. When you are in this stance, you have advantage on Strength and Constitution saving throws, and disadvantage on Dexterity saving throws. Additionally, when you take damage you may use your reaction to reduce the taken damage by 1d12 + your Constitution modifier. Earth stance lasts for two rounds.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet usage="2 chakra" action="Reaction">
				<description>When you are in this stance, you have advantage on Strength and Constitution saving throws, and disadvantage on Dexterity saving throws. Additionally, when you take damage you may use your reaction to reduce the taken damage by 1d12 + {{constitution:modifier}}. Earth stance lasts for 2 rounds.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Fire Stance" type="Class Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_STANCE_FIRE_STANCE">
            <supports>Samurai Stance</supports>
            <requirements>[chakra:points:1],ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_LETHAL_RESONATION</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Lethal Resonation Feature</prerequisite>
			<description>
				<p class="flavor">You take on the aggressive, uncontrollable movements of flame.</p>
				<p class="indent">You can spend 1 chakra point to take this stance. While in this stance, if you have the Lethal Resonation feature from this class, you add 2 additional resonation dice to your weapon damage rolls. Whenever you land an attack in this way, you suffer fire damage equal to one roll of your resonation dice. Fire stance lasts for 2 rounds.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet usage="1 chakra">
				<description>While in this stance, if you have the Lethal Resonation feature from this class, you add 2d{{resonation:die-type}} to your weapon damage rolls. Whenever you land an attack in this way, you suffer 1d{{resonation:die-type}} fire damage. Fire stance lasts for 2 rounds.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Hurricane Stance" type="Class Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_STANCE_HURRICANE_STANCE">
            <supports>Samurai Stance</supports>
            <requirements>[chakra:points:1]</requirements>
			<description>
				<p class="flavor">Your chakra coalesces into a mote of power, connected to you and ready to fly forward, pulling you across the battlefield.</p>
				<p class="indent">You can spend 1 chakra point to take this stance. When you hit a target with a ranged attack in this stance, you can use your reaction to teleport to an unoccupied space within 5 feet of your weapon or piece of ammunition. Hurricane stance lasts for 1 round.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet usage="1 chakra" action="Reaction">
				<description>When you hit a target with a ranged attack in this stance, you can use your reaction to teleport to an unoccupied space within 5 feet of your weapon or piece of ammunition. Hurricane stance lasts for 1 round.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Growth Stance" type="Class Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_STANCE_GROWTH_STANCE">
            <supports>Samurai Stance</supports>
            <requirements>[chakra:points:4]</requirements>
			<description>
				<p class="flavor">Your chakra pours away from you to mirror the effects of time and healing energy on the wounds around you, healing over even the most deadly injuries</p>
				<p class="indent">You can spend 4 chakra points to take this stance. While you are in this stance, every creature who starts their turn within 10 feet of you regains hit points equal to a roll of 2 of your resonation dice at the start of their turn. Growth stance lasts for 2 rounds.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet usage="4 chakra">
				<description>While you are in this stance, every creature who starts their turn within 10 feet of you regains 2d{{resonation:die-type}} hit points at the start of their turn. Growth stance lasts for 2 rounds.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Ice Stance" type="Class Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_STANCE_ICE_STANCE">
            <supports>Samurai Stance</supports>
            <requirements>[chakra:points:5]</requirements>
			<description>
				<p class="flavor">Your weapon carries the lethal chill of winter, capable of solidifying any and all who are willing to stand in your way.</p>
				<p class="indent">You can spend 5 chakra points to take this stance. While in this stance you can, as an action, force a creature within 5 feet of you to make a Constitution saving throw against your chakra save DC. On a failure, the creature becomes restrained as ice begins to creep from it's wounds. At the end of it's next turn the creature must repeat the save, ending the effect on itself on a success. On a failed save, the creature becomes petrified until this stance ends, or you take this action option again. Ice stance lasts for 10 rounds.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet usage="5 chakra" action="Action">
				<description>While in this stance you can, as an action, force a creature within 5 feet of you to make a Constitution saving throw. On a failure, the creature becomes restrained as ice begins to creep from it's wounds. At the end of it's next turn the creature must repeat the save, ending the effect on itself on a success. On a failed save, the creature becomes petrified until this stance ends, or you take this action option again. Ice stance lasts for 10 rounds.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Lightning Stance" type="Class Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_STANCE_LIGHTNING_STANCE">
            <supports>Samurai Stance</supports>
            <requirements>[chakra:points:2]</requirements>
			<description>
				<p class="flavor">Your strikes fly with the speed of lighting, and your aggression transfers and jumps, bolstered with an electrical current.</p>
				<p class="indent">You can spend 2 chakra points to enter this stance. While in this stance you may, as an action, move up to 10 feet into reach of one enemy you can see and take a single melee weapon attack against them. If this attack hits, you may immediately take this action again, though you must target a different enemy. This ability can chain up to a maximum number of times equal to your Intellegence modifier, to target all different enemies. If you have the Chakra-Fueled Movement feature the distance you can move between targets increases by the amount shown in the Chakra-Fueled Movement column of the Samurai table. Lightning stance lasts until for one round.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet usage="2 chakra" action="Action">
				<description>While in this stance you may, as an action, move up to {{lightning-stance:range}} feet into reach of one enemy you can see and take a single melee weapon attack against them. If this attack hits, you may immediately take this action again, though you must target a different enemy, up to a total of {{intelligence:modifier}} times. Lightning stance lasts until for 1 round.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <stat name="lightning-stance:range" value="10" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="lightning-stance:range" value="chakra:movement" bonus="base" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Mist Stance" type="Class Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_STANCE_MIST_STANCE">
            <supports>Samurai Stance</supports>
            <requirements>[chakra:points:2]</requirements>
			<description>
				<p class="flavor">You call forth mist around you, and link your chakra into so that you can shepard yourself from place to place.</p>
				<p class="indent">You can spend 2 chakra points to enter this stance. When you enter this stance, a cloud of chakral mist spreads outwards in a 20 foot radius from you. The area it covers is lightly obscured. While in this stance and within the mist you may, as a bonus action, teleport to any unoccupied space in the cloud. If you have the Chakra-Fueled Movement feature, the radius of the mist increases by your amount for that feature. The cloud disappears when this stance ends. If the cloud is dispersed bya strong wind the stance ends prematurely. Mist stance lasts for three rounds.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet usage="2 chakra" action="Bonus Action">
				<description>When you enter this stance, a cloud of chakral mist spreads outwards in a {{mist-stance:range}} foot radius from you. The area it covers is lightly obscured. While in this stance and within the mist you may, as a bonus action, teleport to any unoccupied space in the cloud. The cloud disappears when this stance ends. If the cloud is dispersed bya strong wind the stance ends prematurely. Mist stance lasts for 3 rounds.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <stat name="mist-stance:range" value="20" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="mist-stance:range" value="chakra:movement" bonus="chakra movement" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Rain Stance" type="Class Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_STANCE_RAIN_STANCE">
            <supports>Samurai Stance</supports>
            <requirements>[chakra:points:1]</requirements>
			<description>
				<p class="flavor">You push your chakra into the ground, molding it around your opponents. It falls into the earth and molds it into a melting trap, in the same way as a rainstorm.</p>
				<p class="indent">You can spend 1 chakra point to enter this stance. When you enter this stance, choose a number of creatures you can see within 20 feet of you up to your Intelligence modifier. The targets must succeed on a Strength saving throw against your chakra save DC. On a failed save, a target becomes restrained until this stance ends. As an action, a target can make a Strength check against your chakra save DC, breaking free from the effect on a success. Rain stance lasts for three rounds.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet usage="1 chakra">
				<description>When you enter this stance, choose up to {{intelligence:modifier}} creatures you can see within 20 feet of you. The targets must succeed on a Strength saving throw. On a failed save, a target becomes restrained until this stance ends. As an action, a target can make a Strength check against your chakra save DC, breaking free from the effect on a success. Rain stance lasts for 3 rounds.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Root Stance" type="Class Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_STANCE_ROOT_STANCE">
            <supports>Samurai Stance</supports>
            <requirements>[chakra:points:1]</requirements>
			<description>
				<p class="flavor">You become as secure, undeniable, and imposing as a tree as your chakra. As your energy roots you to the ground, you become that much more deadly in your stable position</p>
				<p class="indent">You can spend 1 chakra point to enter this stance. While in this stance you have a 10 foot reach on any melee weapon attacks, and ranged weapon attacks you make are not at disadvantage at long range. While in this stance, your speed becomes 0. If you are moved from the position you activated the stance in the stance ends. Root stance lasts for 10 rounds.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet usage="1 chakra">
				<description>While in this stance you have a 10 foot reach on any melee weapon attacks, and ranged weapon attacks you make are not at disadvantage at long range. While in this stance, your speed becomes 0. If you are moved from the position you activated the stance in the stance ends. Root stance lasts for 10 rounds.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Snow Stance" type="Class Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_STANCE_SNOW_STANCE">
            <supports>Samurai Stance</supports>
            <requirements>[chakra:points:1]</requirements>
			<description>
				<p class="flavor">Your chakra blows you apart into flurries of snow, separating your form so you may avoid incoming blows.</p>
				<p class="indent">You can spend 1 chakra point to take this stance. While in this stance, all attacks made against you suffer disadvantage. Additionally, while this stance is active, you must subtract 1d4 from all attack rolls that you make. This stance lasts for two rounds.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet usage="1 chakra">
				<description>While in this stance, all attacks made against you suffer disadvantage. Additionally, while this stance is active, you must subtract 1d4 from all attack rolls that you make. This stance lasts for 2 rounds.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Spark Stance" type="Class Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_STANCE_SPARK_STANCE">
            <supports>Samurai Stance</supports>
            <requirements>[chakra:points:1]</requirements>
			<description>
				<p class="flavor">You put a spark of chakral energy into your allies, pushing your energy through them</p>
				<p class="indent">You can spend 1 chakra point to take this stance. When you activate this stance, choose a number of creatures up to your Intellegence modifier. While this stance is active the target's speed is increased by 10 feet. If you have the Chakra-Fueled Movement feature, their speed is instead increased by your amount for that feature. This stance lasts for 10 rounds.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet usage="1 chakra">
				<description>When you activate this stance, choose up to {{intelligence:modifier}} creatures. While this stance is active the targets' speed is increased by {{spark-stance:speed}} feet. This stance lasts for 10 rounds.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <stat name="spark-stance:speed" value="10" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="spark-stance:speed" value="chakra:movement" bonus="base" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Stone Stance" type="Class Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_STANCE_STONE_STANCE">
            <supports>Samurai Stance</supports>
            <requirements>[chakra:points:3]</requirements>
			<description>
				<p class="flavor">Your determination and tenacity make you as immortal as stone itself, wearing down but never destroyed as your skin hardens and your now-crushing attacks demand attention.</p>
				<p class="indent">You can spend 3 chakra points to enter this stance. While in this stance, at the beginning of each of your turns when you have at least one hit point remaining, you gain a number of hit points equal to your proficiency bonus. Attacks made by creatures hostile to you and in your melee range against targets other than you have disadvantage, and melee attacks made against you have advantage. Stone stance for 10 rounds.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet usage="3 chakra">
				<description>While in this stance, at the beginning of each of your turns when you have at least one hit point remaining, you gain {{proficiency}} hit points. Attacks made by creatures hostile to you and in your melee range against targets other than you have disadvantage, and melee attacks made against you have advantage. Stone stance for 10 rounds.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Storm Stance" type="Class Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_STANCE_STORM_STANCE">
            <supports>Samurai Stance</supports>
            <requirements>[chakra:points:3]</requirements>
			<description>
				<p class="flavor">You let loose a projectile, and use your chakra to replicate it into a thunderous volley as omnipresent and inescapable as a raging tempest, flying from you as quick as the wind.</p>
				<p class="indent">You can spend 3 chakra points to take this stance. While in this stance, you can, as an action, select a target within the short range of a weapon you are holding that has the ammunition property. The target, and every creature within 5 feet of the target must make a Dexterity saving throw. A target suffers 1d4 attacks with the weapon you are holding on a failure, and a target suffers one attack on a success. These attacks only expend one piece of ammunition for your weapon. This stance lasts for one round.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet usage="3 chakra" action="Action">
				<description>While in this stance, you can, as an action, select a target within the short range of a weapon you are holding that has the ammunition property. The target, and every creature within 5 feet of the target must make a Dexterity saving throw. A target suffers 1d4 attacks with the weapon you are holding on a failure, and a target suffers one attack on a success. These attacks only expend one piece of ammunition for your weapon. This stance lasts for 1 round.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Thunder Stance" type="Class Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_STANCE_THUNDER_STANCE">
            <supports>Samurai Stance</supports>
            <requirements>[chakra:points:2]</requirements>
			<description>
				<p class="flavor">Your aggression extends into a form as fast, dominant, and explosive as a storm. It releases dangerous energy in a way too difficult to escape, even for you.</p>
				<p class="indent">You can spend 2 chakra points to take this stance. While in this stance, as an action you can target every creature within 5 feet of you. The targets must succeed on a Strength saving throw against your chakra save DC or be pushed 25 feet away from you. If a target collides with a wall or other solid surface over the course of the movement they suffer 2d6 points of bludgeoning damage. This stance lasts for 2 rounds.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet usage="2 chakra">
				<description>While in this stance, as an action you can target every creature within 5 feet of you. The targets must succeed on a Strength saving throw or be pushed 25 feet away from you. If a target collides with a wall or other solid surface over the course of the movement they suffer 2d6 points of bludgeoning damage. This stance lasts for 2 rounds.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Tornado Stance" type="Class Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_STANCE_TORNADO_STANCE">
            <supports>Samurai Stance</supports>
            <requirements>[chakra:points:1]</requirements>
			<description>
				<p class="flavor">You throw your chakra outward, before pulling it violently inwards again, and your opponents with it.</p>
				<p class="indent">You can spend 1 chakra point to take this stance. While in this stance, as an action you can target every creature within 25 feet of you. The targets must succeed on a Strength saving throw against your chakra save DC or be pulled 25 feet toward you. This stance lasts for 2 rounds.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet usage="1 chakra" action="Action">
				<description>While in this stance, as an action you can target every creature within 25 feet of you. The targets must succeed on a Strength saving throw or be pulled 25 feet toward you. This stance lasts for 2 rounds.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Water Stance" type="Class Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_STANCE_WATER_STANCE">
            <supports>Samurai Stance</supports>
            <requirements>[chakra:points:1]</requirements>
			<description>
				<p class="flavor">Your strikes carry with them a crashing wave, the energy of their descent transferring into your opponents, and forcing them to the ground.</p>
				<p class="indent">You can spend 1 chakra point to take this stance. While in this stance, you may use a bonus action, targeting one creature you have hit with a weapon attack this turn, to force the target to make a Strength saving throw against your chakra save DC. On a failure, they are knocked prone. Water stance lasts for one round.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet usage="1 chakra" action="Bonus Action">
				<description>While in this stance, you may use a bonus action, targeting one creature you have hit with a weapon attack this turn, to force the target to make a Strength saving throw. On a failure, they are knocked prone. Water stance lasts for 1 round.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Wind Stance" type="Class Feature" source="The Samurai Class" id="ID_AP_TSC_CLASS_FEATURE_SAMURAI_STANCE_WIND_STANCE">
            <supports>Samurai Stance</supports>
            <requirements>[chakra:points:2]</requirements>
			<description>
				<p class="flavor">You move with the grace and flow of the wind, stepping gingerly, with borrowed elegance as the currents push you from danger.</p>
				<p class="indent">You can spend 2 chakra points to take this stance. When you are in this stance, you may take the Dash action as a bonus action. Addition, taking the Dash action on your turn, whether with this feature or not, allows you to ignore effects from difficult terrain until the end of your turn. Opportunity attacks made against you have disadvantage, and you have advantage on dexterity saving throws. Wind Stance lasts for one round.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet usage="2 chakra" action="Bonus Action">
				<description>When you are in this stance, you may take the Dash action as a bonus action. Addition, taking the Dash action on your turn, whether with this feature or not, allows you to ignore effects from difficult terrain until the end of your turn. Opportunity attacks made against you have disadvantage, and you have advantage on dexterity saving throws. Wind Stance lasts for 1 round.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
			</rules>
		</element>

	<element name="Darkvision or Increase 30" type="Grants" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_DARKVISION_OR_INCREASE_30">
		<rules>
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_DARKVISION_INCREASE_30_DARKVISION" requirements="!ID_VISION_DARKVISION" />
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_DARKVISION_INCREASE_30_DARKVISION_INCREASE" requirements="ID_VISION_DARKVISION" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Darkvision" type="Grants" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_DARKVISION_INCREASE_30_DARKVISION">
		<rules>
			<grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_DARKVISION" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Darkvision Increase 30" type="Grants" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_DARKVISION_INCREASE_30_DARKVISION_INCREASE">
		<rules>
			<stat name="darkvision:increase" value="30" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_DARKVISION_INCREASE_30_DARKVISION" />
			<stat name="darkvision:range" value="darkvision:increase" bonus="increase" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_DARKVISION_INCREASE_30_DARKVISION" />
		</rules>
	</element>


</elements>