<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>The Tactician Class</name>
        <update version="0.0.2">
            <file name="class-tactician.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/classes/class-tactician.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="The Tactician Class" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_MRSILVERS_HOMEBREWERY_SOURCE_The Tactician Class">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation"></set>
            <set name="url">https://homebrewery.naturalcrit.com/share/S1iWuqdkL</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author"  url="https://www.reddit.com/user/Mr-Silvers">u/Mr-Silvers</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20200407</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Tactician" type="Class" source="The Tactician Class" id="ID_MRSILVER_TACTICIAN_CLASS_TACTICIAN">
        <description>
            <p>Arrows pelt against the elf’s shield as she retreats into the valley. As the orcish raiders charge in pursuit, she signals for archers hidden in the hills to ready their bows in ambush.</p>
            <p class="indent">A half-orc flashes a sinister grin as his whip cripples the cultist. He barks orders at his allies to finish off the dazed enemy while it is still reeling from the blow.</p>
            <p class="indent">A human man summons an arcane eye to spy upon the enemy encampments, taking notes of their resources for the coming siege.</p>
            <p class="indent">Tacticians are philosophers of battle who take the saying "brains over brawn" to heart. Whether they learned of warfare through expensive tutors or firsthand experience on the battlefield, all tacticians know that a battle is never fought with strength of arms and magic alone.</p>
            <h4>RESOURCEFUL THINKERS</h4>
            <p>Tacticians are well taught in the arts of war, oftentimes beginning their studies at a young age. To their adept minds, even the smallest of skirmishes is an intricate game of chess where every resource needs to be accounted for.</p>
            <p class="indent">Tacticians use their massive font of knowledge to fight smart rather than hard. They focus their attention on key positions or enemies, using stratagems and coordinating attacks with their allies to lock down the battlefield and turn the tide of war in their favor.</p>
            <p class="indent">While tacticians make their own plans, they also focus on undermining the enemy’s strengths and tactics, ensuring that the tactician’s allies can fight with advantage at all times.</p>
            <h4>SCHOLARS AND WARRIORS</h4>
            <p>Tacticians approach warfare with the academical mindset of a wizard pursuing the secrets of the arcane. They look upon war and battle as a puzzle that can be conquered through mental acumen, formulating philosophical ideas from what they observe. Not all scholars of war are tacticians, as many of their numbers are content with working from the safe confines of a command tent. Tacticians may be scholars first but they are still warriors at heart, taking up arms next to their soldiers on the battlefield without hesitation.</p>
            <h4>CREATING A TACTICIAN</h4>
            <p>As you build your tactician, ask yourself what brought you down the path of warfare. Were you perhaps born into a noble family with longstanding history of military service? Are you a soldier who rose above your rank thanks to an innate talent for tactical planning? Or were you a scholar that studied the intricacies and philosophies of war for some reason, personal or otherwise?</p>
            <p class="indent">Regardless of their origins, all tacticians are defined by their reliance on mental aptitude over strength of body. Consider that the path to becoming a tactician is paved by diligent study of the art of war. Where did you study, and who were your teachers? Perhaps you studied at a prestigious military academy run by the country’s military? Or perhaps you were simply thrust into the throes of war and distinguished yourself enough to catch the attention of a mentor? In the end, your most powerful weapon is your vast intellect and the ability to keep a cool head in any situation.</p>
            <h5>QUICK BUILD</h5>
            <p>You can make a tactician quickly by following these suggestions. First, Intelligence should be your highest ability score, followed by Dexterity (tacticians planning on becoming commanders may wish to focus on Strength instead). Second, choose the noble background.</p>
            <h2>CLASS FEATURES</h2>
            <p>As an tactician, you gain the following class features.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">HIT POINTS</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Hit Dice:</strong> 1d8 per tactician level</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at 1st Level:</strong> 8 + your Constitution modifier</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at Higher Levels:</strong> 1d8 (or 5) + your Constitution modifier per tactician level after 1st</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">PROFICIENCIES</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled mb">
                <li><strong>Armor:</strong> Light armor, medium armor, shields</li>
                <li><strong>Weapons:</strong> Simple weapons, hand crossbows, heavy crossbows, rapiers, scimitars, shortswords, whips</li>
                <li><strong>Tools:</strong> Cartographer’s tools</li>
            </ul>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Saving Throws:</strong> Intelligence, Wisdom</li>
                <li><strong>Skills:</strong> Choose three from Animal Handling, Athletics, Deception, History, Insight, Investigation, Medicine, Nature, Perception, Persuasion and Religion</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">EQUIPMENT</h5>
            <p>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>(a) a rapier or (b) a short sword and a shield</li>
                <li>(a) a set of leather armor or (b) a suit of scale mail</li>
                <li>(a) a diplomat’s pack, (b) an explorer’s pack or (c) a scholar’s pack</li>
                <li>cartographer’s tools, a light crossbow and 20 bolts</li>
            </ul>
        <!-- class table here -->
            <h5 class="caption">THE TACTICIAN</h5>
            <table class="class-features">
                <thead>
                    <tr><td class="col-5">Level</td><td class="col-10">Proficiency Bonus</td><td class="col-60 left">Features</td><td class="col-10">Stratagems Known</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td> 1st</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Points of Interest, Tactical Combat (d4)</td><td>─</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 2nd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Art of War, Expertise</td><td>2</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 3rd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Discipline of War</td><td>2</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 4th</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>3</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 5th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Extra Reaction, Tactical Thinking</td><td>3</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 6th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Expertise, Tactical Combat (d6)</td><td>4</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 7th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Discipline Feature</td><td>4</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 8th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>5</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 9th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Art of War (x2)</td><td>5</td></tr>
                <tr><td>10th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>6</td></tr>
                <tr><td>11th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Extra Reaction (x2)</td><td>6</td></tr>
                <tr><td>12th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>7</td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Take the Initiative, Tactical Combat (d8)</td><td>7</td></tr>
                <tr><td>14th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Discipline Feature</td><td>8</td></tr>
                <tr><td>15th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Intellectual Superiority</td><td>8</td></tr>
                <tr><td>16th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>9</td></tr>
                <tr><td>17th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Art of War (x3)</td><td>9</td></tr>
                <tr><td>18th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Discipline Feature</td><td>10</td></tr>
                <tr><td>19th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>10</td></tr>
                <tr><td>20th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Warmaster</td><td>10</td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_POINTS_OF_INTEREST" />
            <div element="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_TACTICAL_COMBAT" />
            <div element="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_ART_OF_WAR" />
            <div element="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_EXPERTISE" />
            <div element="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_DISCIPLINE_OF_WAR" />
            <div element="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" />
            <div element="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_EXTRA_REACTION" />
            <div element="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_TACTICAL_THINKING" />
            <div element="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_TAKE_THE_INITIATIVE" />
            <div element="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_INTELLECTUAL_SUPERIORITY" />
            <div element="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_WARMASTER" />
            <h3>RULES FOR MULTICLASSING</h3>
            <p>In order to multiclass in or out of tactician, you must have both Dexterity and Intelligence scores of 13 or higher. You gain the following proficiencies for multiclassing into tactician.</p>
            <ul>
                <li>Light armor, medium armor, shields, simple weapons, rapiers, shortswords, whips, one skill from the class’ skill list, cartographer’s tools.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="short">A philosopher of battle that uses brains over brawn.</set>
            <set name="hd">d8</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" requirements="!ID_MRSILVER_TACTICIAN_MULTICLASS_TACTICIAN" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_MEDIUM_ARMOR" requirements="!ID_MRSILVER_TACTICIAN_MULTICLASS_TACTICIAN" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_SHIELDS" requirements="!ID_MRSILVER_TACTICIAN_MULTICLASS_TACTICIAN" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" requirements="!ID_MRSILVER_TACTICIAN_MULTICLASS_TACTICIAN" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_CROSSBOW_HAND" requirements="!ID_MRSILVER_TACTICIAN_MULTICLASS_TACTICIAN" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_CROSSBOW_HEAVY" requirements="!ID_MRSILVER_TACTICIAN_MULTICLASS_TACTICIAN" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_RAPIER" requirements="!ID_MRSILVER_TACTICIAN_MULTICLASS_TACTICIAN" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SHORTSWORD" requirements="!ID_MRSILVER_TACTICIAN_MULTICLASS_TACTICIAN" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_WHIP" requirements="!ID_MRSILVER_TACTICIAN_MULTICLASS_TACTICIAN" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_CARTOGRAPHERS_TOOLS" requirements="!ID_MRSILVER_TACTICIAN_MULTICLASS_TACTICIAN" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_INTELLIGENCE" requirements="!ID_MRSILVER_TACTICIAN_MULTICLASS_TACTICIAN" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_WISDOM" requirements="!ID_MRSILVER_TACTICIAN_MULTICLASS_TACTICIAN" />
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency (Tactician)" number="3" supports="Skill,Tactician" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_POINTS_OF_INTEREST" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_TACTICAL_COMBAT" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_ART_OF_WAR" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_EXPERTISE" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_DISCIPLINE_OF_WAR" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" level="4" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_EXTRA_REACTION" level="5" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_TACTICAL_THINKING" level="5" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_TAKE_THE_INITIATIVE" level="13" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_INTELLECTUAL_SUPERIORITY" level="15" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_WARMASTER" level="20" />
        </rules>
        <multiclass id="ID_MRSILVER_TACTICIAN_MULTICLASS_TACTICIAN">
            <prerequisite>Dexterity 13, Intelligence 13</prerequisite>
            <requirements>[dex:13],[int:13]</requirements>
            <setters>
                <set name="multiclass proficiencies">Light armor, medium armor, shields, simple weapons, rapiers, shortswords, whips, one skill from the class’ skill list, cartographer’s tools</set>
            </setters>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_MEDIUM_ARMOR" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_SHIELDS" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_RAPIER" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SHORTSWORD" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_WHIP" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_CARTOGRAPHERS_TOOLS" />
                <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency (Tactician)" supports="Skill,Tactician" />
            </rules>
        </multiclass>
    </element>
        <element name="Points of Interest" type="Class Feature" source="The Tactician Class" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_POINTS_OF_INTEREST">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 1st level, you can mark specific landmarks or creatures as points of interest.</p>
                <p class="indent">Using a bonus action, you can target a number of 10 by 10 feet squares that you can see and mark each square as a point of interest, up to a number of points of interest equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of one). Alternatively, you can mark a single creature as a point of interest. If you possess a map of a specific area, including one you’ve created yourself using cartographer’s tools, you can mark specific areas or landmarks on the map as your points of interest without having to see them.</p>
                <p class="indent">These points of interest remain marked by you until you use this feature again or willingly end the effect (no action required). Whenever specific events transpire around a point of interest, you may immediately use your reaction as specified below. You must be able to see or hear the creature to take this reaction.</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>When a creature either moves through or ends its turn within a square that you’ve marked as a point of interest, you can immediately use your reaction to make a single weapon attack against the creature if it is within range.</li>
                    <li>When a creature marked as one of your points of interest moves, uses an action or is the target of an attack or spell, you can immediately use your reaction to make a single weapon attack against the creature if it is within range. You make this attack immediately before the action or movement that triggered the reaction takes place.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>You can target up to {{points-of-interest:uses}} 10 by 10 feet squares that you can see and mark each square as a point of interest. Alternatively, you can mark a single creature as a point of interest. Whenever specific events transpire around a point of interest, you may immediately use your reaction as specified below. You must be able to see or hear the creature to take this reaction. When a creature either moves through or ends its turn within a square that you’ve marked as a point of interest, you can immediately use your reaction to make a single weapon attack against the creature if it is within range. When a creature marked as one of your points of interest moves, uses an action or is the target of an attack or spell, you can immediately use your reaction to make a single weapon attack against the creature if it is within range. You make this attack immediately before the action or movement that triggered the reaction takes place.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="points-of-interest:uses" value="1" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="points-of-interest:uses" value="intelligence:modifier" bonus="base" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Tactical Combat" type="Class Feature" source="The Tactician Class" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_TACTICAL_COMBAT">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 1st level, you’ve learned special techniques to take aim for weak spots in the enemy’s defense, fueled by special dice called tactical dice. You have a number of these tactical dice, which are d4s, equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of one).</p>
                <p class="indent">When you hit a creature with an attack, you can expend one of your tactical dice and add it to the damage roll. The attack must use a finesse or ranged weapon. Additionally, you choose one of the effects below to impose on the target.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong>Cripple.</strong> You cripple the creature’s legs, wings or similar appendages. Until the end of its next turn, the creature’s speed is halved, and any time it makes a Dexterity saving throw, it must roll your tactical dice and subtract the result from the roll.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong>Pierce.</strong> You create an opening in the creature’s defenses. Until the end of the target’s next turn, each creature that makes an attack against the target adds your tactical dice to its attack roll.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong>Weaken.</strong> You debilitate and weaken the creature. Until the end of its next turn, whenever the target creature makes an attack roll or ability check, it must roll your tactical dice and subtract the result from the roll.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use a tactical dice, it becomes unavailable to you until you finish a long rest. Your tactical dice become stronger as you gain levels in this class, turning into d6s at 6th level and d8s at 13th level.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="{{tactical-dice:count}} Dice/Long Rest">
                <description usage="{{tactical-dice:count}} Dice/Long Rest">You have {{tactical-dice:count}} tactical dice, which are d{{tactical-dice:die-type}}s. When you hit a creature with an attack, you can expend one of your tactical dice and add it to the damage roll. The attack must use a finesse or ranged weapon. Additionally, you choose one of the following effects: Cripple, Pierce or Weaken.</description>
                <description usage="{{tactical-dice:count}} Dice/Short Rest" level="5">You have {{tactical-dice:count}} tactical dice, which are d{{tactical-dice:die-type}}s. When you hit a creature with an attack, you can expend one of your tactical dice and add it to the damage roll. The attack must use a finesse or ranged weapon. Additionally, you choose one of the following effects: Cripple, Pierce or Weaken.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="tactical-dice:count" value="1" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="tactical-dice:count" value="intelligence:modifier" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="tactical-dice:die-type" value="4" bonus="base" level="1" />
                <stat name="tactical-dice:die-type" value="6" bonus="base" level="6" />
                <stat name="tactical-dice:die-type" value="8" bonus="base" level="13" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Art of War" type="Class Feature" source="The Tactician Class" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_ART_OF_WAR">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at the 2nd level, you can formulate stratagems to aid allies in battle. You know 2 stratagems of your choice from the list of stratagems detailed at the end of the class description. When you gain certain levels in this class, you learn additional stratagems as shown in the Stratagems Known column of the Tactician table. Whenever you gain a level in this class, you can exchange 1 stratagem you know for another one.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can use this feature once, either immediately after you roll for initiative, as a bonus action on your turn or as a reaction triggered by a point of interest. At 9th level, you can use this feature twice. At 17th level, you use this feature three times. You regain all uses when you finish a short or long rest.</p>
                <p class="indent">Saving Throws. Some of your stratagems require the target to make a saving throw to resist the stratagem’s effects. The saving throw DC is calculated as follows:</p>
                <center>
                    <p><strong>Stratagem Save DC</strong> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier</p>
                </center>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="{{art-of-war:uses}}/Short Rest">
                <description>Your Stratagem Save DC is {{stratagem:save-dc}}. You can use this feature immediately after you roll for initiative, as a bonus action on your turn, or as a reaction triggered by a point of interest.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="art-of-war:uses" value="1" level="2" />
                <stat name="art-of-war:uses" value="1" level="9" />
                <stat name="art-of-war:uses" value="1" level="17" />
                <stat name="stratagem:save-dc" value="8" />
                <stat name="stratagem:save-dc" value="proficiency" />
                <stat name="stratagem:save-dc" value="intelligence:modifier" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Stratagem" supports="Tactician Stratagem" number="2" level="2" allowReplace="true" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Stratagem" supports="Tactician Stratagem" level="4" allowReplace="true" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Stratagem" supports="Tactician Stratagem" level="6" allowReplace="true" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Stratagem" supports="Tactician Stratagem" level="8" allowReplace="true" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Stratagem" supports="Tactician Stratagem" level="10" allowReplace="true" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Stratagem" supports="Tactician Stratagem" level="12" allowReplace="true" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Stratagem" supports="Tactician Stratagem" level="14" allowReplace="true" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Stratagem" supports="Tactician Stratagem" level="16" allowReplace="true" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Stratagem" supports="Tactician Stratagem" level="18" allowReplace="true" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Expertise" type="Class Feature" source="The Tactician Class" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_EXPERTISE">
            <description>
                <p>At 2nd level, choose two of your skill proficiencies, or one of your skill proficiencies and one of your artisan’s tools proficiencies. Your proficiency bonus is doubled for any ability check you make that uses either of the chosen proficiencies.</p>
                <p class="indent">At 6th level, you can choose 2 more proficiencies (in skills or with artisan’s tools) to gain this benefit.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Your proficiency bonus is doubled for any ability check you make that uses either of the chosen proficiencies.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Expertise (Tactician)" level="1" number="2" supports="ID_INTERNAL_SUPPORT_EXPERTISE"/>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Expertise (Tactician)" level="6" number="2" supports="ID_INTERNAL_SUPPORT_EXPERTISE"/>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Discipline of War" type="Class Feature" source="The Tactician Class" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_DISCIPLINE_OF_WAR">
            <description>
                <p>At 3rd level, you choose a discipline that determines the focus of your analytical abilities: Commander, Taskmaster, Guerilla or Mystic Sage, all detailed at the end of the class description. Your discipline choice grants you features at 3rd level and then again at 7th, 14th and 18th level.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Archetype" name="Discipline of War" supports="Discipline of War" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Ability Score Improvement" type="Class Feature" source="The Tactician Class" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 10th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Tactician 4)" supports="Improvement Option,Tactician,4" level="4" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Tactician 8)" supports="Improvement Option,Tactician,8" level="8" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Tactician 10)" supports="Improvement Option,Tactician,10" level="10" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Tactician 12)" supports="Improvement Option,Tactician,12" level="12" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Tactician 16)" supports="Improvement Option,Tactician,16" level="16" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Tactician 19)" supports="Improvement Option,Tactician,19" level="19" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Extra Reaction" type="Class Feature" source="The Tactician Class" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_EXTRA_REACTION">
            <description>
                <p>At 5th level, you can take one additional reaction once per round on top of your normal reaction. You can only use this extra reaction to make a weapon attack, use an item, execute a stratagem or use a class feature that requires a reaction, and you can still only take one reaction per turn.</p>
                <p class="indent">When you reach 11th level in this class, you can take two additional reactions per round.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can take one additional reaction once per round on top of your normal reaction. You can only use this extra reaction to make a weapon attack, use an item, execute a stratagem or use a class feature that requires a reaction, and you can still only take one reaction per turn.</description>
                <description level="11">You can take two additional reactions per round on top of your normal reaction. You can only use these extra reactions to make a weapon attack, use an item, execute a stratagem or use a class feature that requires a reaction, and you can still only take one reaction per turn.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Tactical Thinking" type="Class Feature" source="The Tactician Class" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_TACTICAL_THINKING">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 5th level, you regain all of your tactical dice when you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Take the Initiative" type="Class Feature" source="The Tactician Class" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_TAKE_THE_INITIATIVE">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 13th level, you and each willing creature of your choice can treat a roll of 9 or lower on its initiative roll as a 10. A creature must be able to see or hear you to gain this benefit.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You and each willing creature of your choice can treat a roll of 9 or lower on its initiative roll as a 10. A creature must be able to see or hear you to gain this benefit.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Intellectual Superiority" type="Class Feature" source="The Tactician Class" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_INTELLECTUAL_SUPERIORITY">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 15th level, you’ve accumulated enough battlefield experience to know where to strike for most damage, and how to best avoid taking it yourself. You can add half your Intelligence modifier (rounded down, minimum of one) to any damage roll or saving throw you make that doesn’t already use your Intelligence modifier.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can add half your Intelligence modifier (rounded down, minimum of one) to any damage roll or saving throw you make that doesn’t already use your Intelligence modifier.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Warmaster" type="Class Feature" source="The Tactician Class" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_WARMASTER">
            <description>
                <p>At 20th level, you have completely mastered the art of war. Your Intelligence score increases by 4 and your maximum in that ability is now 24. Additionally, when you roll for initiative and have no tactical dice remaining, you regain 1 tactical dice.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you roll for initiative and have no tactical dice remaining, you regain 1 tactical dice.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="intelligence" value="4" />
                <stat name="intelligence:max" value="4" />
            </rules>
        </element>

        <element name="Commander" type="Archetype" source="The Tactician Class" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_DISCIPLINE_OF_WAR_COMMANDER">
            <supports>Discipline of War</supports>
            <description>
                <p>Commanders are exemplars who take up arms and lead their soldiers from the frontlines rather than from a command tent. Inspiring and fearless, a commander’s duty is to the soldiers first and any sovereign or ideal second, raising their allies above and beyond their own strength.</p>
                <div element="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COMMANDER_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" />
                <div element="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COMMANDER_FIGHTING_STYLE" />
                <div element="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COMMANDER_STRATEGIC_CLOUT" />
                <div element="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COMMANDER_INTUITIVE_ACUMEN" />
                <div element="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COMMANDER_UNFALTERING_LOYALTY" />
                <div element="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COMMANDER_ELITE_TASK_FORCE" />
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COMMANDER_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" level="3" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COMMANDER_FIGHTING_STYLE" level="3" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COMMANDER_STRATEGIC_CLOUT" level="3" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COMMANDER_INTUITIVE_ACUMEN" level="7" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COMMANDER_UNFALTERING_LOYALTY" level="14" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COMMANDER_ELITE_TASK_FORCE" level="18" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Bonus Proficiencies" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Tactician Class" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COMMANDER_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES">
                <description>
                    <p>Starting at the 3rd level, you gain proficiency with heavy armor and martial weapons.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_HEAVY_ARMOR" />
                    <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_MARTIAL_WEAPONS" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Fighting Style" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Tactician Class" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COMMANDER_FIGHTING_STYLE">
                <description>
                    <p>Once you reach 3rd level, you adopt a fighting style as your specialty. Choose one of the following options. You can’t take a Fighting Style option more than once, even if you later get to choose again.</p>
                    <h5 class="caption">ARCHERY</h5>
                    <p>You gain a +2 bonus to attack rolls you make with ranged weapons.</p>
                    <h5 class="caption">DEFENSE</h5>
                    <p>While you are wearing armor, you gain a +1 bonus to AC.</p>
                    <h5 class="caption">DUELING</h5>
                    <p>When you are wielding a melee weapon in one hand and no other weapons, you gain a +2 bonus to damage rolls with that weapon.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <select type="Class Feature" name="Fighting Style (Commander)" supports="Fighting Style,Tactician Commander" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Strategic Clout" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Tactician Class" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COMMANDER_STRATEGIC_CLOUT">
                <description>
                    <p>Also at 3rd level, you learn to lead not only by word and wit, but also by example. You can now use your tactical dice with any weapon you are proficient with regardless of type. Additionally, when a creature triggers a reaction from your Points of Interest, you can choose one creature that can see and hear you. That creature can use its reaction to make a weapon attack against the creature instead of you.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>You can now use your tactical dice with any weapon you are proficient with regardless of type. Additionally, when a creature triggers a reaction from your Points of Interest, you can choose one creature that can see and hear you. That creature can use its reaction to make a weapon attack against the creature instead of you.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Intuitive Acumen" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Tactician Class" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COMMANDER_INTUITIVE_ACUMEN">
                <description>
                    <p>At the 7th level, your guard never falters even when seemingly engrossed in other activities.</p>
                    <p class="indent">You can make Intelligence (Investigation) and Wisdom (Perception) checks without penalty even when partaking in social or strenuous activities that normally requires your full attention, such as heavy physical labour or intense conversations. You make such checks without garnering attention from other nearby creatures, appearing no different from how you would normally appear during selected activities.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Additionally, if you spend 1 minute conversing with a creature, that creature makes Charisma (Deception) and Dexterity (Sleight of Hand) checks at disadvantage when contested by your Wisdom (Insight) or Wisdom (Perception) checks.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>You can make Investigation and Perception checks without penalty even when partaking in social or strenuous activities that normally requires your full attention, such as heavy physical labour or intense conversations. You make such checks without garnering attention from other nearby creatures, appearing no different from how you would normally appear during selected activities. Additionally, if you spend 1 minute conversing with a creature, that creature makes Deception and Sleight of Hand checks at disadvantage when contested by your Insight or Perception checks.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Unfaltering Loyalty" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Tactician Class" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COMMANDER_UNFALTERING_LOYALTY">
                <description>
                    <p>Beginning at the 14th level, your loyalty to your soldiers and allies becomes absolute.</p>
                    <p class="indent">You gain immunity to the charmed condition. Whenever a creature within 60 feet is forced to make a saving throw against being charmed, you can use your reaction to grant it advantage on the saving throw if it can see or hear you.</p>
                    <p class="indent">You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier and regain all uses after you finish a long rest.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet action="Reaction" usage="{{intelligence:modifier}}/Long Rest">
                    <description>You have immunity to the charmed condition. Whenever a creature within 60 feet is forced to make a saving throw against being charmed, you can use your reaction to grant it advantage on the saving throw if it can see or hear you.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Elite Task Force" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Tactician Class" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COMMANDER_ELITE_TASK_FORCE">
                <description>
                    <p>At the 18th level, your leadership allows you and your allies to work as a unit that is stronger than the sum of its parts.</p>
                    <p class="indent">When you grant an ally a weapon attack using Strategic Clout, it has advantage on the attack roll. On hit, the ally rolls all damage dice twice and can choose which roll to use.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>When you grant an ally a weapon attack using Strategic Clout, it has advantage on the attack roll. On hit, the ally rolls all damage dice twice and can choose which roll to use.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>


        <element name="Taskmaster" type="Archetype" source="The Tactician Class" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_DISCIPLINE_OF_WAR_TASKMASTER">
            <supports>Discipline of War</supports>
            <description>
                <p>Taskmasters are tacticians who aren’t satisfied with simply defeating their enemy; they wish to absolutely crush anyone who opposes them. Typically ambitious and borderline ruthless, taskmasters accept nothing less than perfection from their subordinates and take charge whenever the opportunity arises, using their intellectual prowess and every resource at their disposal to break the enemy’s spirit without mercy.</p>
                <div element="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TASKMASTER_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" />
                <div element="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TASKMASTER_BRUTAL_PRECISION" />
                <div element="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TASKMASTER_RELENTLESS_ASSAULT" />
                <div element="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TASKMASTER_TYRANTS_CHARISMA" />
                <div element="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TASKMASTER_DEMORALIZING_PRESENCE" />
                <div element="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TASKMASTER_RUTHLESS_SUPERIORITY" />
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TASKMASTER_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" level="3" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TASKMASTER_BRUTAL_PRECISION" level="3" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TASKMASTER_RELENTLESS_ASSAULT" level="3" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TASKMASTER_TYRANTS_CHARISMA" level="7" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TASKMASTER_DEMORALIZING_PRESENCE" level="14" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TASKMASTER_RUTHLESS_SUPERIORITY" level="18" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Bonus Proficiencies" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Tactician Class" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TASKMASTER_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES">
                <description>
                    <p>Starting at the 3rd level, you gain proficiency in the Intimidation skill if you don’t already have it. Additionally, you gain proficiency with two gaming sets of your choice, as well as one set of artisan’s tools of your choice.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INTIMIDATION" />
                    <select type="Proficiency" name="Gaming Set (Taskmaster)" number="2" supports="Gaming Set" />
                    <select type="Proficiency" name="Artisan Tool (Taskmaster)" supports="Artisan tool" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Brutal Precision" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Tactician Class" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TASKMASTER_BRUTAL_PRECISION">
                <description>
                    <p>At 3rd level, your attacks with ranged weapons and weapons that have the finesse property score a critical hit on a roll of 19 or 20.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>Your attacks with ranged weapons and weapons that have the finesse property score a critical hit on a roll of 19 or 20.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Relentless Assault" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Tactician Class" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TASKMASTER_RELENTLESS_ASSAULT">
                <description>
                    <p>Also at 3rd level, you can weave around for a second strike after weakening an enemy. When you take the Attack action on your turn and expend a tactical dice, you can make one additional attack with the same weapon as a bonus action.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                    <description>When you take the Attack action on your turn and expend a tactical dice, you can make one additional attack with the same weapon as a bonus action.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Tyrant’s Charisma" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Tactician Class" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TASKMASTER_TYRANTS_CHARISMA">
                <description>
                    <p>Beginning at the 7th level, you’ve gained the menacing yet also alluring aura of a conqueror.</p>
                    <p class="indent">If you spend at least 1 minute speaking to an individual, you can make a Charisma (Intimidation) check contested by the target creature’s Wisdom (Insight). If you succeed on your skill check, the creature is frightened of you until it can no longer see or hear you. While frightened this way, the creature is also charmed by you and regards you as superior to them in every concievable way, and it can still move closer to you as long as you allow it to. If you or an ally does anything to harm the creature, this effect immediately ends. Once this effect ends, the creature does not know it was charmed by you, and it does not know that you intentionally attempted to intimidate it.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you cannot do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                    <description>If you spend at least 1 minute speaking to an individual, you can make a Intimidation check contested by the target creature’s Insight. If you succeed on your skill check, the creature is frightened of you until it can no longer see or hear you. While frightened this way, the creature is also charmed by you and regards you as superior to them in every concievable way, and it can still move closer to you as long as you allow it to.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Demoralizing Presence" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Tactician Class" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TASKMASTER_DEMORALIZING_PRESENCE">
                <description>
                    <p>At the 14th level, your presence on the battlefield saps the enemy’s will to fight. When a creature you can see rolls for initiative, you can force it to roll at disadvantage. A creature immune to the frightened condition cannot be the target of this effect.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>When a creature you can see rolls for initiative, you can force it to roll at disadvantage. A creature immune to the frightened condition cannot be the target of this effect.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Ruthless Superiority" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Tactician Class" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TASKMASTER_RUTHLESS_SUPERIORITY">
                <description>
                    <p>At 18th level, each foe bested spurs you and your allies onwards to victory.</p>
                    <p class="indent">When you reduce a creature to 0 hit points or score a critical hit with a weapon attack, one creature of your choice that can see and hear you can immediately use its reaction to move up to its speed and make a weapon attack with advantage against a creature within range.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>When you reduce a creature to 0 hit points or score a critical hit with a weapon attack, one creature of your choice that can see and hear you can immediately use its reaction to move up to its speed and make a weapon attack with advantage against a creature within range.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>


        <element name="Guerilla" type="Archetype" source="The Tactician Class" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_DISCIPLINE_OF_WAR_GUERILLA">
            <supports>Discipline of War</supports>
            <description>
                <p>Not all tacticians are born into riches and privilege, learning their trade at prestigious academies or under the tutelage of wisened scholars. Some are taught the harsh lessons of war from the perspective of a less fortunate, forced to adapt to their circumstances or die trying. These tacticians learn to stack the odds in their favor, using any means necessary to bring down foes that greatly outmatch them in skill and numbers.</p>
                <div element="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GUERILLA_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" />
                <div element="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GUERILLA_HIT_AND_RUN" />
                <div element="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GUERILLA_LETHAL_AMBUSH" />
                <div element="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GUERILLA_CODED_COMMUNICATION" />
                <div element="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GUERILLA_SWIFT_FEET" />
                <div element="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GUERILLA_CRY_HAVOC" />
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GUERILLA_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" level="3" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GUERILLA_HIT_AND_RUN" level="3" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GUERILLA_LETHAL_AMBUSH" level="3" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GUERILLA_CODED_COMMUNICATION" level="7" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GUERILLA_SWIFT_FEET" level="14" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GUERILLA_CRY_HAVOC" level="18" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Bonus Proficiencies" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Tactician Class" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GUERILLA_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES">
                <description>
                    <p>Starting at 3rd level, you gain proficiency in the Stealth skill if you don’t already have it. Additionally, you gain proficiency with the longbow.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_STEALTH" />
                    <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_LONGBOW" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Hit and Run" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Tactician Class" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GUERILLA_HIT_AND_RUN">
                <description>
                    <p>At 3rd level, you learn to strike at every opportunity you get and disappear before the enemy can retaliate.</p>
                    <p class="indent">You have advantage on opportunity attacks. Additionally when you hit with a creature with an attack, that creature cannot make opportunity attacks against you until the end of your next turn.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>You have advantage on opportunity attacks. Additionally when you hit with a creature with an attack, that creature cannot make opportunity attacks against you until the end of your next turn.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Lethal Ambush" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Tactician Class" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GUERILLA_LETHAL_AMBUSH">
                <description>
                    <p>Also at 3rd level, any ambush led by you becomes remarkably deadlier. When you surprise a creature in combat, each creature of your choice can add your tactical dice to the damage of any attack they make before the start of the next round.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>When you surprise a creature in combat, each creature of your choice can add your tactical dice to the damage of any attack they make before the start of the next round.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Coded Communication" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Tactician Class" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GUERILLA_CODED_COMMUNICATION">
                <description>
                    <p>At 7th level, you develop a verbal code that allows allies to communicate without having to worry about eavesdropping.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Over the course of one hour, you can teach a number of creatures equal to twice your Intelligence modifier (minimum of two) a unique code consisting of noises and gestures. Only creatures you teach can understand this code, and magic cannot be used to decipher it. Even if a creature knows this code, it cannot teach it to others. You can create a new code at any time. Doing so replaces the old code, and creatures have to learn the new code to understand it.</p>
                    <p class="indent">If a creature has reason to be suspicious, such as if the noises made are unnatural to the area, it can make a Wisdom (Insight) check contested by the speaker’s Charisma (Performance) check when an ally speaks in this code. If a creature succeeds on this check, it knows that the noises were artificially created but not what they mean or imply.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>Over the course of one hour, you can teach up to {{coded-communication:targets}} creatures a unique code consisting of noises and gestures. Only creatures you teach can understand this code, and magic cannot be used to decipher it. A suspicious creature can make an Insight check contested by your Performance check to determine if the noises are unnatural to the area.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="coded-communication:targets:base" value="1" bonus="base" />
                    <stat name="coded-communication:targets:base" value="intelligence:modifier" bonus="base" />
                    <stat name="coded-communication:targets" value="coded-communication:targets:base" />
                    <stat name="coded-communication:targets" value="coded-communication:targets:base" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Swift Feet" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Tactician Class" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GUERILLA_SWIFT_FEET">
                <description>
                    <p>At 14th level, your training in guerilla warfare grants your proficiency in Dexterity saving throws. If you’re already proficient, you instead gain proficiency in your choice of Strength or Constitution saving throws.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <select type="Proficiency" name="Swift Feet" optional="true" default="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_DEXTERITY" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_DEXTERITY|ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_STRENGTH|ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CONSTITUTION" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Cry Havoc" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Tactician Class" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GUERILLA_CRY_HAVOC">
                <description>
                    <p>At 18th level, you can expend any number of your tactical dice when rolling for initiative. For each tactical dice expended this way, choose one creature. The creature can take two turns during the first round of combat, the first at its initiative + your tactical dice and the second at its normal initiative. You can’t use this feature if you’re surprised.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>You can expend any number of your tactical dice when rolling for initiative. For each tactical dice expended this way, choose one creature. The creature can take two turns during the first round of combat, the first at its initiative + your tactical dice and the second at its normal initiative. You can’t use this feature if you’re surprised.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>


        <element name="Mystic Sage" type="Archetype" source="The Tactician Class" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_DISCIPLINE_OF_WAR_MYSTIC_SAGE">
            <supports>Discipline of War</supports>
            <description>
                <p>Some tacticians choose to pursue arcane prowess to tie in with their mental acumen. These tacticians typically focus on learning spells from the conjuration and divination schools of magic, picking up spells that will aid them with the logistics of warfare and give them the upper hand on their enemies in the field of intelligence.</p>
                <div element="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MYSTIC_SAGE_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" />
                <div element="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MYSTIC_SAGE_SPELLCASTING" />
                <div element="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MYSTIC_SAGE_TACTICAL_MAGIC" />
                <div element="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MYSTIC_SAGE_WAR_SCRYING" />
                <div element="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MYSTIC_SAGE_SUMMON_LEGION" />
                <div element="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MYSTIC_SAGE_ARCANE_WARFARE" />
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MYSTIC_SAGE_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" level="3" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MYSTIC_SAGE_SPELLCASTING" level="3" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MYSTIC_SAGE_TACTICAL_MAGIC" level="3" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MYSTIC_SAGE_WAR_SCRYING" level="7" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MYSTIC_SAGE_SUMMON_LEGION" level="14" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MYSTIC_SAGE_ARCANE_WARFARE" level="18" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Bonus Proficiencies" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Tactician Class" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MYSTIC_SAGE_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES">
                <description>
                    <p>Starting at the 3rd level, you gain proficiency in the Arcana skill if you don’t already have it. You also gain proficiency with two musical instruments of your choice, and learn two languages of your choice.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ARCANA" />
                    <select type="Proficiency" name="Musical Instrument (Mystic Sage)" supports="Musical Instrument" number="2" />
                    <select type="Language" name="Language (Mystic Sage)" number="2" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Spellcasting" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Tactician Class" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MYSTIC_SAGE_SPELLCASTING">
                <description>
                    <p>When you reach 3rd Level, you augment your mental acumen with the ability to cast spells. See chapter 10 of the <em>Player’s Handbook</em> for the general rules of spellcasting and chapter 11 for the wizard spell list.</p>
                    <h5>CANTRIPS</h5>
                    <p>You learn two cantrips of your choice from the wizard spell list. You learn an additional wizard⁠ cantrip of your choice at 10th level.</p>
                    <h5>SPELL SLOTS</h5>
                    <p>The Mystic Sage Spellcasting table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your wizard spells of 1st Level and higher. To cast one of these spells⁠, you must expend a slot of the spell’s level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.</p>
                    <p class="indent">For example, if you know the 1st-level spell fog cloud and have a 1st-level and a 2nd-level spell slot available, you can cast fog cloud⁠ using either slot.</p>
                    <h5>SPELLS⁠ KNOWN OF 1ST-LEVEL AND HIGHER</h5>
                    <p>You know three 1st-level wizard spells of your choice, two of which you must choose from the conjuration and divination school⁠ on the wizard spell list.</p>
                    <p class="indent">The Spells Known column of the Mystic Sage Spellcasting table shows when you learn more wizard spells⁠ of 1st Level or higher. Each of these spells⁠ must be an conjuration or divination spell of your choice, and must be of a level for which you have spell slots. For instance, when you reach 7th level in this class, you can learn one new spell of 1st or 2nd level.</p>
                    <p class="indent">The Spells you learn at 8th, 14th, and 20th level can come from any school of magic.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Whenever you gain a level in this class, you can replace one of the wizard spells⁠ you know with another spell of your choice from the wizard⁠ spell list. The new spell must be of a level for which you have Spell Slots, and it must be a conjuration or divination vocation spell, unless you’re replacing the spell you gained at 3rd, 8th, 14th, or 20th level from any school of magic.</p>
                    <h5>SPELLCASTING⁠ ABILITY</h5>
                    <p>Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for your wizard spells⁠, since you learn your spells⁠ through study and memorization. You use your Intelligence whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting⁠ ability. In addition, you use your Intelligence modifier when setting⁠ the saving throw DC for a wizard spell you cast and when making an Attack roll with one.</p>
                    <center>
                        <p><strong>Spell save DC</strong> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier</p>
                        <p><strong>Spell Attack modifier</strong> = your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier</p>
                    </center>
                </description>
                <spellcasting name="Mystic Sage" ability="Intelligence" prepare="false">
                    <list>Wizard,(Conjuration||Divination)</list>
                </spellcasting>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="mystic sage:spellcasting:slots:1" value="2" level="3" />
                    <stat name="mystic sage:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="4" />
                    <stat name="mystic sage:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="7" />
                    <stat name="mystic sage:spellcasting:slots:2" value="2" level="7" />
                    <stat name="mystic sage:spellcasting:slots:2" value="1" level="10" />
                    <stat name="mystic sage:spellcasting:slots:3" value="2" level="13" />
                    <stat name="mystic sage:spellcasting:slots:3" value="1" level="16" />
                    <stat name="mystic sage:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="19" />
                    <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Mystic Sage)" supports="Wizard, 0" level="3" number="2" spellcasting="Mystic Sage" />
                    <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Mystic Sage)" supports="Wizard, 0" level="10" number="1" spellcasting="Mystic Sage" />
                    <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Mystic Sage)" supports="Wizard, 1" level="3" number="1" spellcasting="Mystic Sage" allowReplace="false" />
                    <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Mystic Sage)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), 1" level="3" number="2" spellcasting="Mystic Sage" />
                    <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Mystic Sage)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="4" spellcasting="Mystic Sage"/>
                    <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Mystic Sage)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="7" spellcasting="Mystic Sage"/>
                    <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Mystic Sage)" supports="(Wizard||$(spellcasting:list)), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="8" spellcasting="Mystic Sage"/>
                    <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Mystic Sage)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="10" spellcasting="Mystic Sage"/>
                    <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Mystic Sage)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="11" spellcasting="Mystic Sage"/>
                    <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Mystic Sage)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="13" spellcasting="Mystic Sage"/>
                    <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Mystic Sage)" supports="(Wizard||$(spellcasting:list)), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="14" spellcasting="Mystic Sage"/>
                    <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Mystic Sage)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="16" spellcasting="Mystic Sage"/>
                    <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Mystic Sage)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="19" spellcasting="Mystic Sage"/>
                    <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Mystic Sage)" supports="(Wizard||$(spellcasting:list)), $(spellcasting:slots)" level="20" spellcasting="Mystic Sage"/>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Tactical Magic" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Tactician Class" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MYSTIC_SAGE_TACTICAL_MAGIC">
                <description>
                    <p>At 3rd level, you can now use your tactical dice with any spell attack you make. Additionally, you can use an arcane focus as a spellcasting focus for your Mystic Sage spells, and if a Mystic Sage spell you know has the ritual tag, you can cast it as a ritual.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>You can now use your tactical dice with any spell attack you make. Additionally, you can use an arcane focus as a spellcasting focus for your Mystic Sage spells, and if a Mystic Sage spell you know has the ritual tag, you can cast it as a ritual.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
        			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_RITUAL_CASTING" />
        			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_INTERNAL_PROFICIENCY_SPELLFOCUS_GROUP_ARCANE_FOCUS" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="War Scrying" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Tactician Class" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MYSTIC_SAGE_WAR_SCRYING">
                <description>
                    <p>Beginning at the 7th level, you become an expert at identifying arcane threats. You can now use your reaction granted by Extra Reaction to identify spells as they are being cast, and do so with advantage at all times.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Additionally, when you successfully identify a spell that requires a creature to make a saving throw, you can grant one affected creature advantage on its saving throw. You can do this a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier and regain all uses when you finish a long rest.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="{{intelligence:modifier}}/Long Rest">
                    <description>You can now use your reaction granted by Extra Reaction to identify spells as they are being cast, and do so with advantage at all times. Additionally, when you successfully identify a spell that requires a creature to make a saving throw, you can grant one affected creature advantage on its saving throw.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Summon Legion" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Tactician Class" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MYSTIC_SAGE_SUMMON_LEGION">
                <description>
                    <p>At the 14th level, you can summon spectral soldiers to attend you in battle. You learn the <em>spirit guardians</em> spell and can cast it without requiring material components. It counts as a Mystic Sage spell for you but doesn’t count towards the number of Mystic Sage spells you know. To you, the guardians appear as spectral warriors carrying your or your sovereign’s crest, and the spell deals force damage rather than radiant or necrotic damage.</p>
                    <div class="reference">
                        <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPIRIT_GUARDIANS" />
                    </div>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>You can cast spirit guardians without material components. To you, the guardians appear as spectral warriors carrying your or your sovereign’s crest, and the spell deals force damage rather than radiant or necrotic damage.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPIRIT_GUARDIANS" spellcasting="Mystic Sage" known="true" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Arcane Warfare" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Tactician Class" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MYSTIC_SAGE_ARCANE_WARFARE">
                <description>
                    <p>At the 18th level, you learn the ultimate spells for warfare logistics. You can cast arcane gate, teleport and teleportation circle once each without expending a spell slot, and regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="1 Each/Long Rest">
                    <description>You can cast arcane gate, teleport and teleportation circle once each without expending a spell slot.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ARCANE_GATE" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TELEPORT" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TELEPORTATION_CIRCLE" />
                </rules>
            </element>

  <!-- Tactician Skills -->
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ANIMALHANDLING">
        <supports>Tacitician</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ATHLETICS">
        <supports>Tacitician</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_DECEPTION">
        <supports>Tacitician</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_HISTORY">
        <supports>Tacitician</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT">
        <supports>Tacitician</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INVESTIGATION">
        <supports>Tacitician</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_MEDICINE">
        <supports>Tacitician</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_NATURE">
        <supports>Tacitician</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION">
        <supports>Tacitician</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERSUASION">
        <supports>Tacitician</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_RELIGION">
        <supports>Tacitician</supports>
    </append>

  <!-- Commander Fighting Styles -->
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_ARCHERY">
        <supports>Tactician Commander</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_DEFENSE">
        <supports>Tactician Commander</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_DUELING">
        <supports>Tactician Commander</supports>
    </append>

  <!-- Tactician Stratagems -->
    <element name="Battlefield Survey" type="Class Feature" source="The Tactician Class" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_CLASS_FEATURE_STRATAGEM_BATTLEFIELD_SURVEY">
        <supports>Tactician Stratagem</supports>
        <requirements></requirements>
        <prerequisite></prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p>One creature of your choice can immediately make a Wisdom (Perception) check to look for hidden enemies or traps. As part of activating this stratagem, you can mark any number of 10 by 10 foot squares as points of interest (up to the maximum amount). If you do, the creature makes the Wisdom (Perception) check with advantage.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="Art of War">
            <description>One creature of your choice can immediately make a Perception check to look for hidden enemies or traps. As part of activating this stratagem, you can mark up to {{points-of-interest:uses}} 10 by 10 foot squares as points of interest. If you do, the creature makes the Perception check with advantage.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Brace" type="Class Feature" source="The Tactician Class" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_CLASS_FEATURE_STRATAGEM_BRACE">
        <supports>Tactician Stratagem</supports>
        <requirements>[level:6]</requirements>
        <prerequisite>6th level</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 6th level</p>
            <p>Choose a number of creatures that can hear you equal to 1 + your Intelligence modifier. If an affected creature takes damage before the start of the next round, it can use its reaction to reduce the damage by 1d10 + half your Tactician level. Additionally, any chosen creature can still act on its turn if it’s surprised during combat, but only to take the Dodge action.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="Art of War">
            <description>Choose up to {{brace:creatures}} creatures that can hear. If an affected creature takes damage before the start of the next round, it can use its reaction to reduce the damage by 1d10 + {{level:tactician:half}}. Additionally, any chosen creature can still act on its turn if it’s surprised during combat, but only to take the Dodge action.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="brace:creatures" value="1" />
            <stat name="brace:creatures" value="intelligence:modifier" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Cautious Engagement" type="Class Feature" source="The Tactician Class" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_CLASS_FEATURE_STRATAGEM_CAUTIOUS_ENGAGEMENT">
        <supports>Tactician Stratagem</supports>
        <requirements></requirements>
        <prerequisite></prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p>Each creature of your choice that can hear you has advantage on saving throws against traps and advantage on Wisdom (Perception) and Intelligence (Investigation) checks if it moves only half its speed or less on its turn. These benefits lasts for one minute or until you execute another stratagem.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="Art of War">
            <description>Each creature of your choice that can hear you has advantage on saving throws against traps and advantage on Perception and Investigation checks if it moves only half its speed or less on its turn. These benefits lasts for one minute or until you execute another stratagem.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Charge/Retreat" type="Class Feature" source="The Tactician Class" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_CLASS_FEATURE_STRATAGEM_CHARGE_RETREAT">
        <supports>Tactician Stratagem</supports>
        <requirements></requirements>
        <prerequisite></prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p>Each creature of your choice that can hear you can move an additional 15 feet when it takes the Dash or Disengage action on its turn. These benefits lasts for one minute or until you execute another stratagem.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="Art of War">
            <description>Each creature of your choice that can hear you can move an additional 15 feet when it takes the Dash or Disengage action on its turn. These benefits lasts for one minute or until you execute another stratagem.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Final Stand" type="Class Feature" source="The Tactician Class" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_CLASS_FEATURE_STRATAGEM_FINAL_STAND">
        <supports>Tactician Stratagem</supports>
        <requirements>[level:12]</requirements>
        <prerequisite>12th level</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 12th level</p>
            <p>Choose a number of creatures that can hear you equal to 1 + your Intelligence modifier. A creature gains temporary hit points equal to 1d10 + your Tactician level, and while it has these temporary hit points it is immune to the frightened condition. These benefits lasts for one minute or until you execute another stratagem.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="Art of War">
            <description>Choose up to {{final-stand:creatures}} creatures that can hear. Each creature gains 1d10 + {{level:tactician}} temporary hit points, and while it has these temporary hit points it is immune to the frightened condition. These benefits lasts for one minute or until you execute another stratagem.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="final-stand:creatures" value="1" />
            <stat name="final-stand:creatures" value="intelligence:modifier" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Hold the Line" type="Class Feature" source="The Tactician Class" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_CLASS_FEATURE_STRATAGEM_HOLD_THE_LINE">
        <supports>Tactician Stratagem</supports>
        <requirements>[level:12]</requirements>
        <prerequisite>12th level</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 12th level</p>
            <p>Each creature of your choice that can hear you gains a bonus to its AC equal to half your Intelligence modifier (rounded down, minimum of one). A creature loses this bonus if it moves or teleports, and cannot regain this benefit until you execute this stratagem again. These benefits otherwise lasts for one minute or until you execute another stratagem.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="Art of War">
            <description>Each creature of your choice that can hear you gains a bonus to its AC equal to half your Intelligence modifier (rounded down, minimum of one). A creature loses this bonus if it moves or teleports, and cannot regain this benefit until you execute this stratagem again. These benefits otherwise lasts for one minute or until you execute another stratagem.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Misdirection" type="Class Feature" source="The Tactician Class" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_CLASS_FEATURE_STRATAGEM_MISDIRECTION">
        <supports>Tactician Stratagem</supports>
        <requirements>[level:6]</requirements>
        <prerequisite>6th level</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 6th level</p>
            <p>Each creature of your choice must make an Intelligence saving throw or be tricked as you and your allies assume a lax stance full of openings. Each creature that fails the saving throw provokes opportunity attacks if it moves within reach of another creature until the start of the next round.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="Art of War">
            <description>Each creature of your choice must make an Intelligence saving throw or be tricked as you and your allies assume a lax stance full of openings. Each creature that fails the saving throw provokes opportunity attacks if it moves within reach of another creature until the start of the next round.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Press the Advantage" type="Class Feature" source="The Tactician Class" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_CLASS_FEATURE_STRATAGEM_PRESS_THE_ADVANTAGE">
        <supports>Tactician Stratagem</supports>
        <requirements>[level:6]</requirements>
        <prerequisite>6th level</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 6th level</p>
            <p>Choose a number of creatures that you can see equal to 1 + your Intelligence modifier. A chosen creature has its speed doubled until the end of its next turn, and if it hits a creature with an attack in this time, it deals additional damage equal to your Intelligence modifier.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="Art of War">
            <description>Choose up to {{press-the-advantage:creatures}} creatures that you can see. A chosen creature has its speed doubled until the end of its next turn, and if it hits a creature with an attack in this time, it deals {{intelligence:modifier}} additional damage.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="press-the-advantage:creatures" value="1" />
            <stat name="press-the-advantage:creatures" value="intelligence:modifier" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Remobilize" type="Class Feature" source="The Tactician Class" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_CLASS_FEATURE_STRATAGEM_REMOBILIZE">
        <supports>Tactician Stratagem</supports>
        <requirements></requirements>
        <prerequisite></prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p>Each creature of your choice that can hear you can immediately move up to its speed without provoking opportunity attacks. A creature ignores difficult terrain while taking this movement.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="Art of War">
            <description>Each creature of your choice that can hear you can immediately move up to its speed without provoking opportunity attacks. A creature ignores difficult terrain while taking this movement.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Scrutinize" type="Class Feature" source="The Tactician Class" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_CLASS_FEATURE_STRATAGEM_SCRUTINIZE">
        <supports>Tactician Stratagem</supports>
        <requirements></requirements>
        <prerequisite></prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p>Choose a number of creatures equal to your Intelligence modifier. Each of those creature must make an Intelligence saving throw. On a failed save, you unravel the target’s strategies and if it forces a creature to make a saving throw before the end of your next turn, the targeted creature has advantage on the saving throw.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="Art of War">
            <description>Choose up to {{intelligence:modifier}} creatures. Each of those creature must make an Intelligence saving throw. On a failed save, you unravel the target’s strategies and if it forces a creature to make a saving throw before the end of your next turn, the targeted creature has advantage on the saving throw.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Seek and Destroy" type="Class Feature" source="The Tactician Class" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_CLASS_FEATURE_STRATAGEM_SEEK_AND_DESTROY">
        <supports>Tactician Stratagem</supports>
        <requirements>[level:6]</requirements>
        <prerequisite>6th level</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 6th level</p>
            <p>Each creature of your choice gains a bonus to its passive perception equal to your proficiency bonus, and can take the Search action as a bonus action on its turn. These benefits lasts for one minute or until you execute another stratagem.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="Art of War">
            <description>Each creature of your choice gains +{{proficiency}} bonus to its passive perception, and can take the Search action as a bonus action on its turn. These benefits lasts for one minute or until you execute another stratagem.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Show of Force" type="Class Feature" source="The Tactician Class" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_CLASS_FEATURE_STRATAGEM_SHOW_OF_FORCE">
        <supports>Tactician Stratagem</supports>
        <requirements>[level:12]</requirements>
        <prerequisite>12th level</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 12th level</p>
            <p>Choose a number of creatures that you can see equal to 1 + your Intelligence modifier. When a chosen ally deals damage to a creature before the start of the next round, the damaged creature must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be frightened by the ally until the end of its next turn.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="Art of War">
            <description>Choose up to {{show-of-force:creatures}} creatures that you can see. When a chosen ally deals damage to a creature before the start of the next round, the damaged creature must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be frightened by the ally until the end of its next turn.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="show-of-force:creatures" value="1" />
            <stat name="show-of-force:creatures" value="intelligence:modifier" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Shuffle Initiative" type="Class Feature" source="The Tactician Class" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_CLASS_FEATURE_STRATAGEM_SHUFFLE_INITIATIVE">
        <supports>Tactician Stratagem</supports>
        <requirements></requirements>
        <prerequisite></prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p>Two willing creatures of your choice can swap places in the initiative order.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="Art of War">
            <description>Two willing creatures of your choice can swap places in the initiative order.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Suppressive Fire" type="Class Feature" source="The Tactician Class" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_CLASS_FEATURE_STRATAGEM_SUPPRESSIVE_FIRE">
        <supports>Tactician Stratagem</supports>
        <requirements>[level:6]</requirements>
        <prerequisite>6th level</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 6th level</p>
            <p>Each willing creature that can hear you can immediately use its reaction to lay down suppressive fire in a 5 foot radius sphere centered on a point you both can see. A creature must be wielding a ranged weapon or know at least one spell that requires a spell attack roll in order to take this reaction. Each creature of your choice within range of the suppressive fire cannot take reactions and loses half its speed until the end of its next turn. The radius of the suppressive fire increases by 5 foot for each ally above one that takes this reaction.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="Art of War">
            <description>Each willing creature that can hear you can immediately use its reaction to lay down suppressive fire in a 5 foot radius sphere centered on a point you both can see. A creature must be wielding a ranged weapon or know at least one spell that requires a spell attack roll in order to take this reaction. Each creature of your choice within range of the suppressive fire cannot take reactions and loses half its speed until the end of its next turn. The radius of the suppressive fire increases by 5 foot for each ally above one that takes this reaction.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Threat Assessment" type="Class Feature" source="The Tactician Class" id="ID_MRSILVERS_TACTICIAN_CLASS_FEATURE_STRATAGEM_THREAT_ASSESSMENT">
        <supports>Tactician Stratagem</supports>
        <requirements>[level:12]</requirements>
        <prerequisite>12th level</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 12th level</p>
            <p>You quickly pan the battlefield to gauge the enemy’s abilities. Choose a number of creatures equal to your Intelligence modifier. Each of those creature must make an Intelligence saving throw. On a failed save, you learn if the creature has melee or ranged attacks, and whether it has any spellcasting ability or not. You do not learn how much or what kind of damage it would deal with the attacks, or what spells it knows if it has a spellcasting ability.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="Art of War">
            <description>Choose up to {{intelligence:modifier}} creatures. Each of those creature must make an Intelligence saving throw. On a failed save, you learn if the creature has melee or ranged attacks, and whether it has any spellcasting ability or not.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

</elements>