<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Commander Class</name>
        <update version="0.0.3">
            <file name="class-commander.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/classes/class-commander.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="The Commander" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_AEYANA_GMBINDER_SOURCE_The Commander">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p>Version 2.8</p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation"></set>
            <set name="url">https://www.gmbinder.com/share/-LthH-sNFxIuClVT52hC</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" url="https://www.gmbinder.com/profile/witchfire">Aeyana</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20200118</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Commander" type="Class" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_COMMANDER">
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">The most important words a man can say are, “I will do better.” These are not the most important words any man can say. I am a man, and they are what I needed to say.</p>
            <p class="indent flavor">The ancient code of the Knights Radiant says "journey before destination." Some may call it a simple platitude, but it is far more. A journey will have pain and failure. It is not only the steps forward that we must accept. It is the stumbles. The trials. The knowledge that we will fail. That we will hurt those around us.</p>
            <p class="indent flavor">But if we stop, if we accept the person we are when we fall, the journey ends. That failure becomes our destination.</p>
            <p class="indent flavor">To love the journey is to accept no such end. I have found, through painful experience, that the most important step a person can take is always the next one.</p>
            <p class="flavor" style="text-align: right;">— Brandon Sanderson, Oathbringer</p>
            <p>A beloved human in a feather hat blows into a golden minotaur horn, the deep sound resonating for miles around. The mighty trumpet awakens his crew with a sense of heroic resolve, signaling the path onwards. His promise for gold pushes them through damp sands, past shambling skeletons, and into a pitch black cavern.</p>
            <p class="indent">Seven devils rise from the depths of hell, walking through an infernal gate to the mortal plane. At their front marches an armored tiefling. The embers of hatred and vengeance glow in her eyes, plainly visible through her black visor. She wields a greatsword of iron, red hot from the lava it was forged in, and upon her head a crown of black flames as the group marches away from Avernus.</p>
            <p class="indent">The sound of cloven hooves rampages down a hallway, a warning for the gang of entrenched smugglers. An armor clad dwarf trails behind his sneering warthog, metal chain in one hand, and shield in the other. The insignia of the king’s army reflects off his brightly polished metal. As he lets out a war cry in his king’s name, the warthog joins in on the call.</p>
            <p class="indent">These are all powerful leaders with the voice to command. Whether they coordinate with their companions to overcome armies, bring terror with a cursed name, or lead with an animal companion at their side, commanders lead the way to victory.</p>
            <h4>STRENGTH IN NUMBERS</h4>
            <p>On the battlefield, commanders merge martial training with an overbearing cpresence. They rarely ever fight alone, instead preferring to fight alongside their most trusted companions. When they are not engaged in combat, a commander still uses their reputation and charisma to influence others, branding them with a reputation as powerful leaders, dreadful tyrants, or trustworthy allies.</p>
            <p class="indent">A commander leads at the front of a group, using its voice to mold the flow of combat. Despite being fully capable swordsmen, commanders shift some focus away from their own fight to aid others. Commanders rally their companions under a common cause, and their might both inspires allies and demoralizes enemies. If all else fails, a commander can rely on their strong armor and stronger heart to defend themselves from harm.</p>
            <h4>RISE TO THE OCCASION</h4>
            <p>Commanders come from nearly every walk of life, ranging from the local guide to the distinguished diplomat and even to crime lords. At the highest levels of society, a great number of kings and queens are commanders due to their influential nature. The details of each commander’s brand of leadership vary between one another. Some lead through diplomacy and camaraderie while others exert terror. A few will find their knack for leadership to come naturally, and perfect it through years of experience. Others require years of formal training at an institution using long established techniques.</p>
            <p class="indent">There are a wide variety of factors that may drive a commander to a life of adventure. For some it is simply the desire to meet new people or explore far lands. Others set out with a more specific goal in mind, one that requires the aid of other adventurers. Sometimes, a commander will be pushed to adventure as their offical duty, usually an order from a formal or divine power. Despite an individual’s reason for adventuring, all commanders find comfort alongside groups of adventurers.</p>
            <h4>CREATING YOUR COMMANDER</h4>
            <p>When creating a commander, consider what about you conjures a powerful influence. What causes others to instinctively pay attention to you? Perhaps you have a powerful voice that demands attention? Or do you draw people using your charming personality? Or maybe you’re full of old stories you can share with everyone, from the humble peasant to the privileged king. Does your name strike fear and terror in the hearts of mortals? Or is it one associated with heroism and courage? What defining event brought about your current reputation?</p>
            <p class="indent">Consider the events that forced you into a life of adventure. Were you coaxed into a journey by someone else? Or were you forced from your home, causing you to find companionship among adventurers? Perhaps you felt it was a duty for safety and honor? Or do you have a calling so strong you’re willing to trample anyone that stands in your way?</p>
            <h5>QUICK BUILD</h5>
            <p>You can make a commander quickly by following these suggestions. First, make Strength or Dexterity your highest ability score, depending on whether you want to focus on melee weapons or on archery (or finesse weapons). Your next-highest score should be Charisma. Second, choose the noble background.</p>
            <h2>CLASS FEATURES</h2>
            <p>As an commander, you gain the following class features.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">HIT POINTS</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Hit Dice:</strong> 1d10 per commander level</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at 1st Level:</strong> 10 + your Constitution modifier</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at Higher Levels:</strong> 1d10 (or 6) + your Constitution modifier per commander level after 1st</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">PROFICIENCIES</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled mb">
                <li><strong>Armor:</strong> All armor, shields</li>
                <li><strong>Weapons:</strong> Simple weapons, martial weapons</li>
                <li><strong>Tools:</strong> Land vehicles</li>
            </ul>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Saving Throws:</strong> Wisdom, Charisma</li>
                <li><strong>Skills:</strong> Choose two from Animal Handling, History, Insight, Medicine, Nature, Intimidation, Perception, and Persuasion.</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">EQUIPMENT</h5>
            <p>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>(a) a martial melee weapon and a shield or (b) any two melee weapons</li>
                <li>(a) a heavy crossbow and 20 bolts or (b) two handaxes</li>
                <li>(a) a chain shirt or (b) chain mail</li>
                <li>(a) a diplomat’s pack or (b) an explorer’s pack</li>
            </ul>
            <p>Alternatively, you can ignore the equipment from your class and background, and start with 5d4 x 10 gp.</p>
        <!-- class table here -->
            <h5 class="caption">THE COMMANDER</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td class="col-5">Level</td><td class="col-5">Proficiency Bonus</td><td	class="left">Features</td><td class="col-5">Rally Bonus</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1st</td><td>+2</td><td>Somatic Communication, Commander’s Decrees</td><td>+2</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2nd</td><td>+2</td><td>Inspiring Rally, Dauntless Action</td><td>+2</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3rd</td><td>+2</td><td>Commander’s Discipline</td><td>+2</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4th</td><td>+2</td><td>Ability Score Improvement, Call to Arms</td><td>+2</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5th</td><td>+3</td><td>Extra Attack</td><td>+2</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6th</td><td>+3</td><td>Commander’s Discipline Feature</td><td>+2</td></tr>
                <tr><td>7th</td><td>+3</td><td>Lead by Example, Rally (2 uses)</td><td>+3</td></tr>
                <tr><td>8th</td><td>+3</td><td>Ability Score Improvement</td><td>+3</td></tr>
                <tr><td>9th</td><td>+4</td><td>Sovereign Reputation</td><td>+3</td></tr>
                <tr><td>10th</td><td>+4</td><td>Mantle of Heroism</td><td>+3</td></tr>
                <tr><td>11th</td><td>+4</td><td>Commander’s Decrees (2 targets)</td><td>+3</td></tr>
                <tr><td>12th</td><td>+4</td><td>Ability Score Improvement</td><td>+3</td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td>+5</td><td>Commander’s Discipline Feature</td><td>+3</td></tr>
                <tr><td>14th</td><td>+5</td><td>Rally (3 uses)</td><td>+4</td></tr>
                <tr><td>15th</td><td>+5</td><td>Unwavering Conviction</td><td>+4</td></tr>
                <tr><td>16th</td><td>+5</td><td>Ability Score Improvement</td><td>+4</td></tr>
                <tr><td>17th</td><td>+6</td><td>Commander’s Decrees (3 targets)</td><td>+4</td></tr>
                <tr><td>18th</td><td>+6</td><td>Commander’s Discipline Feature</td><td>+4</td></tr>
                <tr><td>19th</td><td>+6</td><td>Ability Score Improvement</td><td>+4</td></tr>
                <tr><td>20th</td><td>+6</td><td>Commander Luminary</td><td>+4</td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_SOMATIC_COMMUNICATION" />
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_COMMANDERS_DECREES" />
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_INSPIRING_RALLY" />
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_DAUNTLESS_ACTION" />
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_COMMANDERS_DISCIPLINE" />
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" />
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_CALL_TO_ARMS" />
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_EXTRA_ATTACK" />
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_LEAD_BY_EXAMPLE" />
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_SOVEREIGN_REPUTATION" />
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_MANTLE_OF_HEROISM" />
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_UNWAVERING_CONVICTION" />
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_COMMANDER_LUMINARY" />
            <h3>MULTICLASSING</h3>
            <p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Strength 13 and Charisma 13</p>
            <p><strong>Proficiencies Gained:</strong> Light armor, medium armor, shields, simple weapons, and martial weapons.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="hd">d10</set>
            <set name="short">A balanced class for legendary heroes, honored diplomats, and nefarious warlords.</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_MEDIUM_ARMOR" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_HEAVY_ARMOR" requirements="!ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_MULTICLASS_COMMANDER" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_SHIELDS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_MARTIAL_WEAPONS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_VEHICLES_LAND" requirements="!ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_MULTICLASS_COMMANDER" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_WISDOM" requirements="!ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_MULTICLASS_COMMANDER" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CHARISMA" requirements="!ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_MULTICLASS_COMMANDER" />
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency, Commander" supports="Skill, Commander" number="2" requirements="!ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_MULTICLASS_COMMANDER" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_SOMATIC_COMMUNICATION" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_COMMANDERS_DECREES" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_INSPIRING_RALLY" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_DAUNTLESS_ACTION" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_COMMANDERS_DISCIPLINE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" level="4" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_CALL_TO_ARMS" level="4" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_EXTRA_ATTACK" level="5" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_LEAD_BY_EXAMPLE" level="7" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_SOVEREIGN_REPUTATION" level="9" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_MANTLE_OF_HEROISM" level="10" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_UNWAVERING_CONVICTION" level="15" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_COMMANDER_LUMINARY" level="20" />
            <stat name="cha-mod:min-one" value="1" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="cha-mod:min-one" value="charisma:modifier" bonus="base" />
        </rules>
        <multiclass id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_MULTICLASS_COMMANDER">
            <prerequisite>Strength 13 and Charisma 13</prerequisite>
            <requirements>[str:13],[cha:13]</requirements>
            <setters>
                <set name="multiclass proficiencies">Light armor, medium armor, shields, simple weapons, and martial weapons.</set>
            </setters>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS" />
            </rules>
        </multiclass>
    </element>

        <element name="Somatic Communication" type="Class Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_SOMATIC_COMMUNICATION">
            <description>
                <p>You know a set of somatic gestures that can be used for basic communication. Using a free hand, you can communicate simple messages to nearby creatures. Any creature that knows your set of gestures and can see you understands your simple messages. Generally, members belonging to the same organization (such as an adventuring guild or crime syndicate) know and utilize the same set of gestures.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can teach your set of gestures to other creatures, allowing them to understand your gestures. Over the span of one hour, you can teach a number of creatures who share a language with you equal to your proficiency bonus. After 7 days of adventuring alongside you, a friendly creature that knows your gestures becomes proficient with them and is able to communicate using the same gestures.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Using a free hand, you can communicate simple messages to nearby creatures. Any creature that knows your set of gestures and can see you understands your messages as if you were speaking. You can teach your set of gestures to {{cha-mod:min-one}} creatures over an hour, provided you share a language.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Commander’s Decrees" type="Class Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_COMMANDERS_DECREES">
            <description>
                <p>You enact your leadership by issuing decrees that push your allies to the peak of their abilities. When you issue a decree, select either Additional Attack, Attentive Guard, or Sharpened Focus.</p>
                <p class="indent">You issue a decree as an action, choosing one creature other than yourself within 30 feet of you. The creature gains the decree’s effects if it can understand you (either verbally or through your somatic gestures) and if it isn’t already under the effects of another decree. If you can make multiple attacks on your turn, such as using Extra Attack, you can forgo one of your attacks to use this feature as part of your Attack action. For instance, at 5th level you can either attack twice, or attack once and issue a decree.</p>
                <p class="indent">At higher levels in this class, you can issue additional decrees when you use this feature. At 11th level you can issue two decrees on your turn, and at 17th level you can issue three decrees on your turn. You can split up your movement to move in between each issuance.</p>
                <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_DECREE_ADDITIONAL_ATTACK" />
                <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_DECREE_ATTENTIVE_GUARD" />
                <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_DECREE_SHARPENED_FOCUS" />
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>You can forgo an attack to issue a Decree to a creature you can see within 60 feet. You can issue {{decrees:uses}} decrees per turn.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="decrees:uses" value="1" level="2" />
                <stat name="decrees:uses" value="1" level="11" />
                <stat name="decrees:uses" value="1" level="17" />
                <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_DECREE_ADDITIONAL_ATTACK" level="1" />
                <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_DECREE_ATTENTIVE_GUARD" level="1" />
                <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_DECREE_SHARPENED_FOCUS" level="1" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Decree: Additional Attack" type="Class Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_DECREE_ADDITIONAL_ATTACK">
                <description>
                    <p>You greatly amplify your ally’s offensive capabilities. Your ally gains one attack during its next turn, either as an additional attack if it takes the Attack action, or using its bonus action to make the attack. If your ally doesn’t make the attack before the end of its next turn, the attack is lost.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Decree" alt="Additional Attack">
                    <description>Your ally gains one attack during its next turn, either as an additional attack if it takes the Attack action, or using its bonus action to make the attack. If your ally doesn’t make the attack before the end of its next turn, the attack is lost.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Decree: Attentive Guard" type="Class Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_DECREE_ATTENTIVE_GUARD">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>Until the start of your next turn, you brace your ally against incoming danger. Your ally has advantage on Dexterity saving throws against effects you can see, and attack rolls against your ally have disadvantage if you can see the attacker.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Decree" alt="Attentive Guard">
                    <description>Your ally has advantage on Dexterity saving throws against effects you can see, and attack rolls against your ally have disadvantage if you can see the attacker.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Decree: Sharpened Focus" type="Class Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_DECREE_SHARPENED_FOCUS">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>You enhance your ally’s focus to increase their chance of success. Once before the start of your next turn, your ally can roll a d4 and add the result to one attack roll or subtract the result from one creature’s saving throw against their effect.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Decree" alt="Attentive Guard">
                    <description>Once before the start of your next turn, your ally can roll a d4 and add the result to one attack roll or subtract the result from one creature’s saving throw against their effect.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
        <element name="Inspiring Rally" type="Class Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_INSPIRING_RALLY">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 2nd level, by chanting a war cry, reciting an inspiring passage, or uttering words of inspiration, you unite nearby allies with your powerful rally. You start your rally as a bonus action, selecting yourself and a number of creatures within 30 feet up to your Charisma modifier (minimum of 1). Each creature is rallied by you until your rally ends. While rallied and within 60 feet of you, each creature gains the following.</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>The creature has advantage on saving throws to resist being frightened.</li>
                    <li>The creature can add your rally bonus to any ability check or saving throw that doesn’t include its proficiency bonus. If your rally bonus is higher than the creature’s proficiency bonus, it can forgo adding its proficiency bonus to an ability check or saving throw to add your rally bonus instead. Your rally bonus is shown for your commander level in the Commander table.</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">Your rally lasts for one minute and ends early if you’re unable to speak, if you fall unconscious, or if you become incapacitated. It also ends on a creature if it falls unconscious, if the creature becomes incapacitated, or if either of you willingly end the effect. You must finish a short or long rest before you can use your rally again.</p>
                <p class="indent">Starting at 7th level in this class, you can use your rally twice between rests. Starting at 14th level, you can use your rally three times between rests. When you use this feature, you can spend additional uses to increase the number of targets: each use after the first increases the amount by your Charisma modifier (minimum increase of +1). You regain all spent uses when you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="{{rally:uses}}/Short Rest">
                <description>Select up to {{rally:targets}} willing creatures within 30 feet of you that can hear you. While rallied and within 60 feet of you, each creature has advantage on saving throws to resist being frightened and can add a +{{rally:bonus}} bonus to ability checks and saving throws that doesn’t include its proficiency bonus. Your rally lasts for 1 minute. You can use multiple uses of your rally, adding {{cha-mod:min-one}} affected creatures per additional use.</description>
                <description level="20">Select up to {{rally:targets}} willing creatures within 30 feet of you that can hear you. While rallied and within 60 feet of you, each creature has advantage on saving throws to resist being frightened and can add a +{{rally:bonus}} bonus to ability checks and saving throws that doesn’t include its proficiency bonus. Your rally lasts for 1 hour. You can use multiple uses of your rally, adding {{cha-mod:min-one}} affected creatures per additional use.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="rally:uses" value="1" level="1" />
                <stat name="rally:uses" value="1" level="7" />
                <stat name="rally:uses" value="1" level="14" />
                <stat name="rally:bonus" value="1" level="2" />
                <stat name="rally:bonus" value="1" level="5" />
                <stat name="rally:bonus" value="1" level="9" />
                <stat name="rally:bonus" value="1" level="13" />
                <stat name="rally:targets" value="cha-mod:min-one" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Dauntless Action" type="Class Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_DAUNTLESS_ACTION">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 2nd level, if you make no more than one attack on your turn, you can use your bonus action to take the Dash, Disengage, or Help action.</p>
                <p class="indent">If you are using the Guard optional rule, you can take the Dash, Help, or Guard action</p>
                <div class="sidebar">
                    <h5 class="caption">OPTIONAL RULE: GUARD</h5>
                    <p>As an optional rule, a creature who wants to protect a nearby ally can take the Guard action on its turn. This action is also added to the list of actions a commander can take using its Dauntless Action.</p>
                    <h5 class="caption">GUARD</h5>
                    <p>When you take the Guard action, you forgo your own safety to protect a nearby creature, interposing yourself between the creature and harm. The creature you guard must be no more than one size larger than you.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Until the start of your next turn, the guarded creature has advantage on Dexterity saving throws, and attacks against it have disadvantage if you can see the attacker, but all attacks against you have advantage. This effect ends if the guarded creature is ever more than 5 feet from you.</p>
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>If you make no more than one attack on your turn, you can use your bonus action to take the Dash, Disengage, or Help (or Guard, if used) action.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Commander’s Discipline" type="Class Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_COMMANDERS_DISCIPLINE">
            <description>
                <p>The specific tools and methods a commander uses to lead are known as its discipline. Your archetype is defined by your choice of discipline, each of which augments your abilities.</p>
                <p class="indent">At 3rd level, you choose an archetype that you strive to emulate in your particular style of leadership, such as the Captain. The archetype you choose grants you features at 3rd level and again at 6th, 13th, and 18th levels in this class.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Archetype" name="Commander’s Discipline" supports="Commander Discipline" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Ability Score Improvement" type="Class Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
                <p class="indent">Using the optional feats rule, you can forgo taking this feature to take a feat of your choice instead.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Commander 4)" supports="Improvement Option,Commander,4" level="4" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Commander 8)" supports="Improvement Option,Commander,8" level="8" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Commander 12)" supports="Improvement Option,Commander,12" level="12" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Commander 16)" supports="Improvement Option,Commander,16" level="16" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Commander 19)" supports="Improvement Option,Commander,19" level="19" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Call to Arms" type="Class Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_CALL_TO_ARMS">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 4th level, if you aren’t surprised when you roll initiative, you can call for nearby allies to join you. You energize yourself and each friendly creature within 30 feet, granting each creature an additional 10 feet of movement speed for the first round of combat. A creature may not gain this benefit multiple times during the same round.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>If you aren’t surprised when you roll initiative, you grant yourself and each friendly creature within 30 feet an additional 10 feet of movement speed for the first round of combat. A creature may not gain this benefit multiple times during the same round.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Extra Attack" type="Class Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_EXTRA_ATTACK">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 5th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="extra attack:count" value="2" level="5" bonus="extra attack" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Lead By Example" type="Class Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_LEAD_BY_EXAMPLE">
            <description>
                <p>At 7th level, as you strive to keep yourself and your allies safe, your leadership drives you to respond to threats quickly. You can give yourself a bonus to your initiative rolls equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum of +0). If your initiative roll equals another creature’s roll, you decide if you take your turns before or after that creature.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can give yourself a +{{charisma:modifier}} bonus to your initiative rolls. If your initiative roll equals another creature’s, you decide if you take your turns before or after that creature.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Sovereign Reputation" type="Class Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_SOVEREIGN_REPUTATION">
            <description>
                <p>At 9th level, your fame (or infamy) grants you an edge when addressing others. You gain proficiency with the Charisma (Persuasion) and Charisma (Intimidation) skills. If you already have one or both of these proficiencies, you gain proficiency with an equal number of other skills of your choice.</p>
                <p class="indent">Your proficiency bonus is doubled for any ability check that uses your proficiency in Persuasion or Intimidation.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Your proficiency bonus is doubled for any ability check that uses your proficiency in Persuasion or Intimidation.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency, Sovereign Reputation" supports="Skill, Commander" default="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INTIMIDATION" />
                <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency, Sovereign Reputation" supports="Skill, Commander" default="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERSUASION" />
                <stat name="intimidation:proficiency" value="proficiency" bonus="double" />
                <stat name="persuasion:proficiency" value="proficiency" bonus="double" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Mantle of Heroism" type="Class Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_MANTLE_OF_HEROISM">
            <description>
                <p>At 10th level, your allies can break free of debilitating effects faster while they’re rallied.</p>
                <p class="indent">At the end of your turn, each creature rallied by you other than yourself can repeat a saving throw that it would make on its next turn to end a specific effect on itself, such as a <i>hold person</i> spell. The ability used and save DC for each creature’s roll are equal to those of the original effect. On success, a creature successfully ends the effect on itself. On a failed save, a creature doesn’t suffer any harmful effects.</p>
                <p class="indent">To qualify, an effect must not require a creature’s bonus action or action to make its roll, and any other requirements necessary for the saving throw must also be met. A creature under multiple eligible effects must select one before rolling.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>At the end of your turn, each creature rallied by you other than yourself can repeat a saving throw that it would make on its next turn to end a specific effect on itself. The ability used and save DC for each creature’s roll are equal to those of the original effect. To qualify, an effect must not require a creature’s bonus action or action to make its roll, and any other requirements necessary for the saving throw must also be met. A creature under multiple eligible effects must select one before rolling.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Unwavering Conviction" type="Class Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_UNWAVERING_CONVICTION">
            <description>
                <p>At 15th level, your steadfast mind cannot be penetrated by effects that would alter it. You can’t be frightened, and you gain a bonus to your Wisdom saving throws equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum of +0).</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can’t be frightened, and you gain a +{{charisma:modifier}} bonus to your Wisdom saving throws.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Commander Luminary" type="Class Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_COMMANDER_COMMANDER_LUMINARY">
            <description>
                <p>At 20th level, you are an exemplary master of valor and leadership. Your rally’s effects last for 1 hour, instead of 1 minute. If you have no uses of your rally left when you roll initiative, you gain one use of it.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>If you have no uses of your rally left when you roll initiative, you gain one use of it.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

  <!-- Commander Disciplines -->        
    <element name="Captain" type="Archetype" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_COMMANDER_CAPTAIN">
        <supports>Commander Discipline</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Captains have a knack for pushing others to perform at the absolute best of their abilities. A captain doesn’t necessarily find success in any individual’s actions, but rather in a shared victory among their friends. In battle, they use their powerful voice to mold the flow of combat.</p>
            <p class="indent">A small party of combatants led by an experienced captain operates like a well oiled machine.</p>
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CAPTAIN_ARTFUL_SPEAKER" />
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CAPTAIN_CAPTAINS_DIRECTIVES" />
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CAPTAIN_COMPELLING_MANEUVER" />
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CAPTAIN_CAPTAINS_RIGHT_HAND" />
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CAPTAIN_LEAD_THE_CHARGE" />
         </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CAPTAIN_ARTFUL_SPEAKER" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CAPTAIN_CAPTAINS_DIRECTIVES" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CAPTAIN_COMPELLING_MANEUVER" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CAPTAIN_CAPTAINS_RIGHT_HAND" level="13" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CAPTAIN_LEAD_THE_CHARGE" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Artful Speaker" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CAPTAIN_ARTFUL_SPEAKER">
            <description>
                <p>At 3rd level, you are proficient in the Persuasion skill. If you are already proficient with it, you instead gain proficiency in one other skill from the class’s skill list.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency, Artful Speaker" supports="Skill, Commander" default="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERSUASION" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Captain’s Directives" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CAPTAIN_CAPTAINS_DIRECTIVES">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 3rd level, your expect leadership lets you control the battlefield in different ways. You learn two additional decrees: Captain’s Anger and Captain’s Navigation. When you issue a decree, you can issue either of these instead.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_CAPTAIN_DIRECTIVE_CAPTAINS_ANGER" level="3" />
                <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_CAPTAIN_DIRECTIVE_CAPTAINS_NAVIGATION" level="3" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Decree: Captain’s Anger" type="Class Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_CAPTAIN_DIRECTIVE_CAPTAINS_ANGER">
                <description>
                    <p>You entice your ally to unleash the full potential of their attack or damaging effect. Once before the start of your next turn, your ally can grant themselves a 2d8 bonus to one damage roll. If the damaging effect affects multiple creatures, one creature of your ally’s choice takes the bonus damage, or two creatures of your ally’s choice each take 1d8 damage.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Decree" alt="Captain’s Anger">
                    <description>Once before the start of your next turn, your ally can grant themselves a 2d8 bonus to one damage roll. If the damaging effect affects multiple creatures, one creature of your ally’s choice takes the bonus damage, or two creatures of your ally’s choice each take 1d8 damage.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Decree: Captain’s Navigation" type="Class Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_CLASS_FEATURE_CAPTAIN_DIRECTIVE_CAPTAINS_NAVIGATION">
                <description>
                    <p>You help coordinate your ally’s motions across the battlefield. Until the start of your next turn, your ally can move unimpeded across difficult terrain, and their movement does not provoke attacks of opportunity from creatures you can see.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Decree" alt="Captain’s Navigation">
                    <description>Until the start of your next turn, your ally can move unimpeded across difficult terrain, and their movement does not provoke attacks of opportunity from creatures you can see.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
        <element name="Compelling Maneuver" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CAPTAIN_COMPELLING_MANEUVER">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, your command moves your allies to better position themselves on the battlefield.</p>
                <p class="indent">When you issue a decree, the target of the decree can immediately use its reaction to move up to half its speed without triggering attacks of opportunity. If the creature ends this movement at least 5 feet from where it started, it also gains advantage on its next attack roll before the decree’s effects end.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you issue a decree, the target of the decree can immediately use its reaction to move up to half its speed without triggering attacks of opportunity. If the creature ends this movement at least 5 feet from where it started, it also gains advantage on its next attack roll before the decree’s effects end.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Captain’s Right Hand" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CAPTAIN_CAPTAINS_RIGHT_HAND">
            <description>
                <p>At 13th level, your ability to aid others is unprecedented. When you take the Help action to aid an ally in attacking a creature, the target of that attack can be within 30 feet of you, rather than 5 feet of you.</p>
                <p class="indent">Furthermore, when you take the Help action, if the creature you help makes its roll with advantage, you can grant it the ability to roll an additional d20 for its check or attack roll. You can grant this bonus a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum of once), and regain all uses at the end of a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="{{cha-mod:min-one}}/Long Rest">
                <description>When you take the Help action to aid an ally in attacking a creature, the target of that attack can be within 30 feet of you, rather than 5 feet of you. Furthermore, when you take the Help action, if the creature you help makes its roll with advantage, you can grant it the ability to roll an additional d20 for its check or attack roll. You can grant this bonus {{cha-mod:min-one}} times per long rest.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Lead the Charge" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CAPTAIN_LEAD_THE_CHARGE">
            <description>
                <p>At 18th level, using your bonus action, you can expend one use of your rally to guide your allies in a combined effort, rather than the normal effects. Select a friendly creature within 60 feet, other than yourself. The creature can take one additional action on its next turn, on top of its regular action and a possible bonus action.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can spend additional uses of your rally to target one additional creature per use after the first. The creatures must be within 30 feet of each other when you target them.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="Rally">
                <description>You can expend one use of your rally to select a friendly creature within 60 feet, other than yourself. The creature can take one additional action on its next turn, on top of its regular action and a possible bonus action. You can spend additional uses of your rally to target one additional creature per use after the first. The creatures must be within 30 feet of each other when you target them.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    <element name="Huntmaster" type="Archetype" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_COMMANDER_HUNTMASTER">
        <supports>Commander Discipline</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Huntmasters are warriors who lead dangerous expeditions. To a huntmaster, their tact is a means of survival. Where a Ranger relies upon their keen senses to survive in the wilderness, a huntmaster uses determination and companionship to face the unknown. The bond between a huntmaster and its allies transcends even life and death.</p>
            <p class="indent">Aided by the help of a wild companion, a huntmaster always fights surrounded by allies. A party led by a huntmaster has the determination to face even the most impossible of odds.</p>
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTMASTER_HUNTERS_TRAINING" />
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTMASTER_KINDRED_COMPANION" />
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTMASTER_DIRE_TACTICS" />
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTMASTER_CALL_THE_HUNT" />
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTMASTER_HUNTMASTERS_UNYIELDING_CHARGE" />
         </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTMASTER_HUNTERS_TRAINING" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTMASTER_KINDRED_COMPANION" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTMASTER_DIRE_TACTICS" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTMASTER_CALL_THE_HUNT" level="13" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTMASTER_HUNTMASTERS_UNYIELDING_CHARGE" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Hunter’s Training" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTMASTER_HUNTERS_TRAINING">
            <description>
                <p>At 3rd level, you gain proficiency in one of the following skills: Animal Handling, Medicine, Nature, Perception, or Survival.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency, Hunter’s Training" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ANIMALHANDLING|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_MEDICINE|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_NATURE|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SURVIVAL" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Kindred Companion" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTMASTER_KINDRED_COMPANION">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 3rd level, you are able to create a bond with a worldly animal: your bonded beast. The bonded beast has its own personality, is loyal to you and your companions, and follows your commands. It can take the form of any Medium beast that can’t fly, but uses the bonded beast stat block while it’s tamed by you. The bonded beast is either a Beast of Strength or a Beast of Grace, which determines its skill proficiency and unique trait.</p>
                <p class="indent">The bonded beast stat block uses your proficiency bonus (PB) in multiple locations. This represents the training you undergo alongside your bonded beast. It also uses your Charisma modifier to determine the bonded beast’s hit points and AC, which represents the creature following your lead to avoid harm.</p>
                <p class="indent">A bonded beast is an extension of its master’s command. When you use your rally, you can rally the bonded beast if it’s within range, without counting towards the total number of rallied creatures. You can also issue decrees to the bonded beast as you would any other creature.</p>
                <p class="indent">In combat the bonded beast shares your initiative count, but it takes its turn immediately after yours. It can move and use its reaction on its own, but the only action it takes on its turn is the Dodge action, unless you use a bonus action on your turn to command it to take an action from its stat block or some other action. If you are incapacitated or if the bonded beast is away from you, it can take actions on its own.</p>
                <p class="indent">Your bonded beast has a number of hit dice (which are d8s) equal to your level in this class. If it dies, you must spend 8 hours and 100 gp’s worth of supplies to locate a new beast and tame it. At the DM’s discretion, the beast you create a new bond with is one that is local to your current area.</p>
                <div class="reference">
                    <h5>YOUR BEAST’S PERSONALITY</h5>
                    <p></p>
                    <p class="indent"></p>
                    <h5 class="caption">BONDED BEAST TRAITS</h5>
                    <table>
                        <thead>
                            <tr><td>d6</td><td>Personality Trait</td></tr>
                        </thead>
                        <tr><td>1</td><td>I am always hungry. I can sense food a mile away, it’s always there... taunting me.</td></tr>
                        <tr><td>2</td><td>Despite my braveness in battle, I whimper and whine when my best friend isn’t around.</td></tr>
                        <tr><td>3</td><td>My curiosity often gets the better of me. I always stick my nose where it doesn’t belong.</td></tr>
                        <tr><td>4</td><td>I have a sworn duty to protect my friends. If anyone approaches them, I get defensive.</td></tr>
                        <tr><td>5</td><td>I am incredibly stubborn. When I’m tired I sit still and refuse to move.</td></tr>
                        <tr><td>6</td><td>Whenever I do something good, I expect a treat in return. If I don’t get one I hold a grudge.</td></tr>
                    </table>
                </div>
                <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_COMPANION_SPIRIT_COMPANION" />
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you use your rally, you can rally the bonded beast if it’s within range, without counting towards the total number of rallied creatures. You can also issue decrees to the bonded beast as you would any other creature. In combat the bonded beast shares your initiative count, but it takes its turn immediately after yours. It can move and use its reaction on its own, but the only action it takes on its turn is the Dodge action, unless you use a bonus action on your turn to command it to take an action from its stat block or some other action. If you are incapacitated or if the bonded beast is away from you, it can take actions on its own. Your bonded beast has {{bonded-beast:hd}} hit dice (d8s).</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Companion" name="Huntmaster Spirit Companion" supports="Huntmaster Commander" />
                <stat name="bonded-beast:hd" value="level:commander" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Dire Tactics" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTMASTER_DIRE_TACTICS">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, you can combine efforts with your beastly companion to coordinate an assault. When you attack a creature, you temporarily distract it from the bonded beast until the start of your next turn.</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>On its turn, the bonded beast’s movement doesn’t provoke attacks of opportunity from distracted creatures.</li>
                    <li>If the bonded beast hits a distracted creature with its thrash attack, it rends the creature with primal ferocity, dealing bonus damage equal to your proficiency bonus.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you attack a creature, you temporarily distract it from the bonded beast until the start of your next turn. On its turn, the bonded beast’s movement doesn’t provoke attacks of opportunity from distracted creatures. If the bonded beast hits a distracted creature with its thrash attack, it rends the creature with primal ferocity, dealing {{proficiency}} bonus damage.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Call the Hunt" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTMASTER_CALL_THE_HUNT">
            <description>
                <p>At 13th level, your rally gives allies the strength to power through old injuries. When you start your rally, you can target unconscious creatures in range who would otherwise be able to hear you. Each creature you rally, including yourself, gains 2d6 hit points. An unconscious creature regains these hit points before being rallied.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you start your rally, you can target unconscious creatures in range who would otherwise be able to hear you. Each creature you rally, including yourself, gains 2d6 hit points. An unconscious creature regains these hit points before being rallied.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Huntmaster’s Unyielding Charge" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HUNTMASTER_HUNTMASTERS_UNYIELDING_CHARGE">
            <description>
                <p>At 18th level, the determination you share with others causes you and your allies to disregard otherwise fatal wounds. If you or a rallied creature would drop to 0 hit points while using your rally, that creature can make a Constitution saving throw against a save DC equal to 10 or half the damage taken, whichever is greater. If the creature succeeds on its saving throw, it drops to 1 hit point instead.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Rally">
                <description>If you or a rallied creature would drop to 0 hit points while using your rally, that creature can make a Constitution saving throw against a save DC equal to 10 or half the damage taken, whichever is greater. If the creature succeeds on its saving throw, it drops to 1 hit point instead.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    <element name="Dread Lord" type="Archetype" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_COMMANDER_DREAD_LORD">
        <supports>Commander Discipline</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Bards tell tales of infamous chieftains leading campaigns of terror, conquerors whose name alone causes fear in mortal creatures. Wherever a dread lord goes, an army of blood thirsty warriors is sure to follow. Dread Lords trample anyone that dares stand in their path, using savagery and ruthlessness as a means to an end.</p>
            <p class="indent">The stench of death is ever present around a dread lord’s company, as their name carries with it a mortal fear. The only people who survive an encounter with a dread lord are those purposefully left behind to spread the tale.</p>
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAD_LORD_MENACING" />
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAD_LORD_INCITE_VIOLENCE" />
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAD_LORD_CAMPAIGN_OF_TERROR" />
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAD_LORD_SMITE_THE_WEAK" />
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAD_LORD_DREAD_LORDS_REVENGE" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAD_LORD_MENACING" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAD_LORD_INCITE_VIOLENCE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAD_LORD_CAMPAIGN_OF_TERROR" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAD_LORD_SMITE_THE_WEAK" level="13" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAD_LORD_DREAD_LORDS_REVENGE" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Menacing" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAD_LORD_MENACING">
            <description>
                <p>At 3rd level, you are proficient in the Intimidation skill. If you are already proficient with it, you instead gain proficiency in one other skill from the class’s skill list.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency, Menacing" supports="Skill, Commander" default="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INTIMIDATION" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Incite Violence" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAD_LORD_INCITE_VIOLENCE">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 3rd level, you gain an additional way to use your dauntless action: to provoke nearby creatures towards attacking another.</p>
                <p class="indent">If you make no more than one attack on your turn, you can use your bonus action to point at a creature within 30 feet, marking it for death. The next time one of your allies hits the marked creature with an attack, the attack deals 1d8 bonus psychic damage and the attacker gains temporary hit points equal to your proficiency bonus. This effect is lost if none of your allies hit the creature with an attack before the start of your next turn.</p>
                <p class="indent">The bonus damage dealt by this feature increases to 2d8 when you reach 13th level in this class.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="Dauntless Action">
                <description>If you make no more than one attack on your turn, you can point at a creature within 30 feet, marking it for death. The next time one of your allies hits the marked creature with an attack, the attack deals {{incite-violence:damage-dice}}d8 bonus psychic damage and the attacker gains {{proficiency}} temporary hit points. This effect is lost if none of your allies hit the creature with an attack before the start of your next turn.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="incite-violence:damage-dice" value="1" level="3" />
                <stat name="incite-violence:damage-dice" value="1" level="13" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Campaign of Terror" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAD_LORD_CAMPAIGN_OF_TERROR">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, when you use your rally, you rile your companions into a frenzy against an opponent. As part of the same bonus action you use to start your rally, you can point at a creature within 60 feet and target it with this feature.</p>
                <p class="indent">The target must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw against a save DC equal to 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier. On a failed save, the creature is frightened of you for your rally’s duration, and while frightened this way, grants you and each creature rallied by you advantage on attack rolls and Intimidation checks against it. The frightened creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of its turns, ending the condition on itself on success.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="Rally">
                <description>When you use your rally, you can force a creature within 60 feet to make a Wisdom saving throw (DC {{campaign-of-terror:save-dc}}) or be frightened of you for the rally’s duration, and each creature rallied by you has advantage on attack rolls and Intimidation checks against it. The frightened creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of its turns, ending the condition on itself on success.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="campaign-of-terror:targets" value="1" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="campaign-of-terror:targets" value="charisma:modifier" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="campaign-of-terror:save-dc" value="8" />
                <stat name="campaign-of-terror:save-dc" value="proficiency" />
                <stat name="campaign-of-terror:save-dc" value="charisma:modifier" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Smite the Weak" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAD_LORD_SMITE_THE_WEAK">
            <description>
                <p>At 13th level, your attacks are exceptionally devastating to weak creatures. You gain the following bonuses against any creature whose hit points are less than or equal to your level in this class + your Charisma score.</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>When you target the weak creature with a weapon attack, you make your attack with advantage.</li>
                    <li>If you hit the weak creature with a melee weapon, the creature is vulnerable to all damage from your attack.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You have advantage on melee attacks against a creature if its hit points are equal to or less than {{smite-the-weak:hp}}, and if you hit it with an attack, the creature is vulnerable to all damage from the attack.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="smite-the-weak:hp" value="level:commander" />
                <stat name="smite-the-weak:hp" value="charisma:modifier" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Dread Lord’s Revenge" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DREAD_LORD_DREAD_LORDS_REVENGE">
            <description>
                <p>At 18th level, your dreaded reputation can permeate the most hardened of minds. Other creatures can’t gain advantage on saving throws made to resist being frightened by you, and if a creature’s Intelligence score is 4 or higher, you ignore any immunity it may have to the Frightened condition.</p>
                <p class="indent">In addition, your melee attacks deal an extra 2d6 psychic damage to any creature frightened of you.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Other creatures can’t gain advantage on saving throws made to resist being frightened by you. If a creature’s Intelligence score is 4 or higher, you also ignore any immunity to the Frightened condition it may have. Your melee attacks deal an additional 2d6 psychic damage to any creature frightened of you.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

  <!-- Commander Skills -->
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ANIMALHANDLING">
        <supports>Commander</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_HISTORY">
        <supports>Commander</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT">
        <supports>Commander</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_MEDICINE">
        <supports>Commander</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_NATURE">
        <supports>Commander</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INTIMIDATION">
        <supports>Commander</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION">
        <supports>Commander</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERSUASION">
        <supports>Commander</supports>
    </append>

  <!-- Huntmaster Companion -->
    <element name="Spirit Companion" type="Companion" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_COMPANION_SPIRIT_COMPANION">
        <supports>Huntmaster Commander</supports>
		<description>
            <p class="flavor">Small or Medium celestial, fey, or fiend, lawful neutral</p>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Armor Class</strong> 12 + your Charisma modifier</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points</strong> equal to five times your level in this class + your Charisma modifier + the bonded beast’s Constitution modifier</li>
                <li><strong>Speed</strong> 30 ft., climb or swim 30 ft. (your choice)</li>
            </ul>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>STR</td><td>DEX</td><td>CON</td><td>INT</td><td>WIS</td><td>CHA</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>14 (+2)</td><td>14 (+2</td><td>13 (+1)</td><td>4 (-2)</td><td>12 (+1)</td><td>10 (0)</td></tr>
            </table>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Saving Throws</strong> Dex +4, Wis +3</li>
                <li><strong>Skills</strong> Perception +3, Stealth +4</li>
                <li><strong>Senses</strong> darkvision 60ft., passive Perception 13</li>
                <li><strong>Languages</strong> Understands your somatic gestures and the languages you speak, and can convey simple ideas using its body language.</li>
            </ul>
            <p><strong><em>Born of Unity.</em></strong> If the spirit companion has died within the last hour, you can use your bonus action to touch it and expend a use of your rally. The spirit companion returns to life after 1 minute with all of its hit points restored.</p>
            <p><strong><em>Might of the Master.</em></strong> The following numbers increase by 1 when your proficiency bonus increases by 1: the spirit companion’s skill and saving throw bonuses (above) and the bonuses to hit and damage of its thrash attack.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">Actions (Requires your Command)</h5>
            <p><strong><em>Thrash.</em></strong> <em>Melee Weapon Attack:</em> +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. <em>Hit:</em> 1d6 + 2 bludgeoning, piercing, or slashing damage, which ignores resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage.</p>
            <p><strong><em>Gain Resolve (3/day).</em></strong> The spirit companion gains temporary hit points equal to your 1d8 + half your level in this class.</p>
            <div class="sidebar">
                <h5 class="caption">ABOUT SPIRIT COMPANIONS</h5>
                <p>The appearance of a spirit companion is most often animal-like in form. For instance, a spirit companion may appear to be a bear, a lion, a wolf, or even a dragon. Its largest size may range anywhere from 3 feet at the shortest to 8 feet at the tallest. Because to their otherworldly nature, some spirit companions have features that give them a unique appearance. For instance, a celestial may have a shimmering aura around it, a fey may have bright patterns in its fur, and a fiend may have a demonic appearance.</p>
                <p class="indent">A spirit companion has its own personality unique from its commander’s. Its bond is always the commander it travels with. You can select a trait for the spirit companion from the following table.</p>
                <h5 class="caption">SPIRIT COMPANION TRAITS</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>d6</td><td>Personality Trait</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1</td><td>I am always hungry. I can sense food a mile away, it’s there waiting for me.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>2</td><td>Despite my braveness in battle, I whimper and whine when my best friend isn’t around.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3</td><td>My curiosity often gets the better of me. I always stick my nose where it doesn’t belong.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>4</td><td>I have a sworn duty to protect my friends. If anyone approaches them, I get defensive.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5</td><td>I am incredibly stubborn. When I’m tired I sit down and refuse to move.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>6</td><td>I expect a treat any time I do something good!</td></tr>
                </table>
            </div>
        </description>
		<setters>
			<set name="strength">14</set>
			<set name="dexterity">14</set>
			<set name="constitution">13</set>
			<set name="intelligence">4</set>
			<set name="wisdom">12</set>
			<set name="charisma">10</set>
			<set name="ac">12 + your Charisma modifier</set>
			<set name="hp">equals five times your commander level</set>
			<set name="speed">30 ft., climb or swim 30 ft.</set>
            <set name="senses">Darkvision 60ft., passive Perception 13</set>
			<set name="languages">Understands your somatic gestures and the languages you speak, and can convey simple ideas using its body language.</set>
			<set name="skills">Perception +3, Stealth +4</set>
            <set name="saves">Dex +4, Wis +3</set>
			<set name="type">Celestial, fey, or fiend</set>
			<set name="size">Small or Medium</set>
			<set name="alignment">lawful neutral</set>
			<set name="challenge">1</set>
            <set name="traits">ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_COMPANION_TRAIT_SPIRIT_COMPANION_BORN_OF_UNITY,ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_COMPANION_TRAIT_SPIRIT_COMPANION_MIGHT_OF_THE_MASTER</set>
			<set name="actions">ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_COMPANION_ACTION_SPIRIT_COMPANION_THRASH,ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_COMPANION_ACTION_SPIRIT_COMPANION_GAIN_RESOLVE</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="companion:ac" value="12" />
            <stat name="companion:ac" value="charisma:modifier" />
			<stat name="companion:hp:max" value="level:commander" />
			<stat name="companion:hp:max" value="level:commander" />
			<stat name="companion:hp:max" value="level:commander" />
			<stat name="companion:hp:max" value="level:commander" />
			<stat name="companion:hp:max" value="level:commander" />
			<stat name="companion:hp:max" value="charisma:modifier" />
			<stat name="companion:hp:max" value="companion:constitution:modifier" />
			<stat name="companion:speed" value="30" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="companion:proficiency" value="proficiency" />
			<stat name="companion:stealth:proficiency" value="companion:proficiency" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="companion:perception:proficiency" value="companion:proficiency" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="companion:dexterity:save:proficiency" value="companion:proficiency" bonus="proficiency" />
			<stat name="companion:wisdom:save:proficiency" value="companion:proficiency" bonus="proficiency" />
		</rules>
	</element>
        <element name="Born of Unity" type="Companion Trait" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_COMPANION_TRAIT_SPIRIT_COMPANION_BORN_OF_UNITY">
            <description>
                <p>If the spirit companion has died within the last hour, you can use your bonus action to touch it and expend a use of your rally. The spirit companion returns to life after 1 minute with all of its hit points restored.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>If the spirit companion has died within the last hour, you can use your bonus action to touch it and expend a use of your rally. The spirit companion returns to life after 1 minute with all of its hit points restored.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Might of the Master" type="Companion Trait" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_COMPANION_TRAIT_SPIRIT_COMPANION_MIGHT_OF_THE_MASTER">
            <description>
                <p>The following numbers increase by 1 when your proficiency bonus increases by 1: the spirit companion’s skill and saving throw bonuses (above) and the bonuses to hit and damage of its thrash attack.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Total melee attack bonus is 2 + your proficiency.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Thrash" type="Companion Action" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_COMPANION_ACTION_SPIRIT_COMPANION_THRASH">
            <description>
                <p>Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 1d6 + 2 bludgeoning, piercing, or slashing damage, which ignores resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 1d6 + 2 bludgeoning, piercing, or slashing damage, which ignores resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Gain Resolve (3/day)" type="Companion Action" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_COMPANION_ACTION_SPIRIT_COMPANION_GAIN_RESOLVE">
            <description>
                <p>The spirit companion gains temporary hit points equal to your 1d8 + half your level in this class.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>The spirit companion gains temporary hit points equal to your 1d8 + half your level in this class.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    <!-- Bonus Magic Item -->
        <element name="Bannerlord’s Standard" type="Magic Item" source="The Commander" id="ID_AEYANA_COMMANDER_MAGIC_ITEM_Bannerlord’s Standard">
            <description>
                <p>This soft lace ribbon shimmers brilliantly when held up to a light, emitting a subtle glow that invokes feelings of unity and valor. To attune to the ribbon, a commander must tie it to an item: either a wooden pole or a two-handed weapon that has the reach property. If you tie it to a non-magical weapon, the weapon’s attacks count as magical.</p>
                <p class="indent">While holding an item that has the ribbon attached, you can use your rally once without spending a use of it, even if you have no uses left. You must finish a long rest before you can do so again. If you have a feature that expends a use of your rally, you can use that feature instead.</p>
                <p class="indent">While tied, the ribbon projects the illusory image of a 10-foot long banner. You can use your bonus action and speak the ribbon’s command word to conjure the illusory image, to dismiss it, or to alter the banner’s appearance. You can change its size, shape, color, and any symbols or writing on it.</p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
                <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
                <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
                <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
                <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
                <set name="attunement" addition="by a commander">true</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
</elements>