<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>The Null Class</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="class-null.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/classes/class-null.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="The Null Class" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_EMBERWING_GMBINDER_SOURCE_THE_NULL_CLASS">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation">TNC</set>
            <set name="url">https://www.gmbinder.com/share/-MIC1_3tTc_d9H3C6lLy</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" abbreviation="EW" url="https://www.gmbinder.com/profile/emberwing">Emberwing</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20201029</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Null" type="Class" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_NULL">
        <description>
            <p>Ember is running.</p>
            <p class="indent">This is nothing new; he has been running for the vast majority of his life. He was running when he became the thing that he is now, running from something so deeply repressed that he will never know its name. In those days it was from some sort of fear, fear of losing something or gaining something or feeling something; he knows that much for sure. He still remembers the sensation, the sudden rush of blood, the mind straying in its mad directions, the repressed thunder of the heart.</p>
            <p class="indent">Ember has not felt fear in a long time. Fear is a distinctly humanoid property, and these days he is closer associated with older, colder things - the flow of entropy, the impartial cataclysm, the nothing in the space between stars. He wonders, at times, whether he misses it.</p>
            <p class="indent">He shakes these thoughts away; he is working. He stops, steadies himself. He focuses the null inside him, and fills it with brilliant, crackling energy. Then, raising his hand towards he approaching dragon, he fires a burst of black magic.</p>
            <p class="indent">Ember is a null, a rare being possessed by a strange nothingness inside of him. This emptiness, known to most as a null from which its bearers gain their name, drains much of what is considered the self of its holder, but it also allows its bearer to draw and contain numerous strange powers within themselves, granting them incredible magical abilities.</p>
            <h4>EMPTY SOUL</h4>
            <p>A null cannot escape the emptiness within them. The absence that exists where a soul and a self should be defines their existence, sapping at their emotions and will, devouring the very things that make them sentient.</p>
            <p class="indent">Despite this, the null can grant its bearer incredible power, allowing them to fill themselves with odd fragments of accreted magic, or to simply expel their physical null against their opponents in destructive bursts. Those nulls that can effectively wield their power are generally incredibly strong wills, with the ability to exert even the dwindling pieces of themselves onto nothingness and make something out of it.</p>
            <p class="indent">Extraordinary events are necessary to make a null - to rip pieces of a living being from themselves without killing them is incredibly difficult - and their existence is incredibly rare, often leading to them being poorly understood in the world. Rarely is a null not feared as a strange and hollow beast.</p>
            <h4>ETERNALLY SEEKING</h4>
            <p>The null, almost unfailingly, leads the wielder to adventure. It is an unnatural thing, and those affected must find some way to face the reality of their emptiness. The desire to find some way to fill themselves, to exert their will on the world and prove that they still mean something, is the driving force of many nulls.</p>
            <p class="indent">Often, a lack of empathy causes a null to go about this in strange ways. Many stories exist of nulls stealing the lives of others, or calling horrors to their sides as friends.</p>
            <p class="indent">Adventure, whatever its nature, gives the null a way to grow, to understand themselves, and perhaps even to feel, making it an attractive prospect to most nulls.</p>
            <h4>CREATING A NULL</h4>
            <p>When creating your null character, consider before anything else how you gained your null. Were you born empty, branded a mistake of creation? Do yearn for nothing more than to become ordinary and find a way to fill their null? Or were you shaped by external events - vile necromantic rituals shattering pieces of your personality and being, encounters with maddening beings from the Far Realms destroying sanity and self, foolish bargains with devils resulting in the loss of a soul? Or were you the cause of their own null, consciously ripping out pieces of yourself that you wished forgotten, or unconsciously discarding a trauma so great that it is better to become nothing than to face it again?</p>
            <p class="indent">How does your null affect your personality? Are you cold and distant, struggling to connect with other creatures with more complete selves? Can you still laugh, still sing and dance and love? Many nulls can become lonely, unable to form meaningful connections because of their reputations and strange personalities, but still yearning for a relationship to fill their emptiness. Do you try to compensate for your vanishing self by trying to experience everything, learn everything, feel everything? Or do you find yourself becoming more and more withdrawn each day, spending more time staring at the stillness of your null?</p>
            <p class="indent">Consider also the way you attempt to deal with the emptiness of your null. Do you do everything in your power to avoid it, filling it with any and every experience you can find? Does it drive you to seek companionship? Or perhaps you at peace with your null, accepting it as a part of what you now are.</p>
            <h5>QUICK BUILD</h5>
            <p>You can make a null quickly by following these suggestions. First, Charisma should be your highest ability score, followed by Constitution. Second, choose the Outlander background. Third, choose the hollow and null sculptor accretions.</p>
            <h4>OPTIONAL RULE: MULTICLASSING</h4>
            <p>To multiclass in or out of this class, you require a Charisma score of 13. You gain proficiency with light armor and simple weapons if you multiclass into this class.</p>
            <h2>CLASS FEATURES</h2>
            <p>As a null, you gain the following class features.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">HIT POINTS</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Hit Dice:</strong> 1d8 per null level</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at 1st Level:</strong> 8 + your Constitution modifier</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at Higher Levels:</strong> 1d8 (or 5) + your Constitution modifier per null level after 1st</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">PROFICIENCIES</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled mb">
                <li><strong>Armor:</strong> Light armor</li>
                <li><strong>Weapons:</strong> Simple weapons</li>
                <li><strong>Tools:</strong> None</li>
            </ul>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Saving Throws:</strong> Charisma, Constitution</li>
                <li><strong>Skills:</strong> Choose any two</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">EQUIPMENT</h5>
            <p>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>(a) a simple weapon or (b) a light crossbow and 20 bolts</li>
                <li>(a) a dungeoneer’s pack or (b) an explorer’s pack</li>
                <li>Leather armor, any simple weapon, and two daggers</li>
            </ul>
        <!-- class table here -->
            <h5 class="caption">THE NULL</h5>
            <table class="class-features">
                <thead>
                    <tr><td class="col-5">Level</td><td class="col-10">Proficiency Bonus</td><td class="col-60 left">Features</td><td class="col-10">Null Burst</td><td class="col-10">Accretions Known</td><td class="col-10">Exert Self Uses</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td> 1st</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Rift Magic, Stillness</td><td>1d10</td><td>2</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 2nd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Exert Self</td><td>1d10</td><td>3</td><td>2</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 3rd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Nullity</td><td>1d10</td><td>4</td><td>2</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 4th</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>1d10</td><td>5</td><td>2</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 5th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Improved Null Burst</td><td>2d10</td><td>6</td><td>3</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 6th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Nullity Feature</td><td>2d10</td><td>7</td><td>3</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 7th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">─</td><td>2d10</td><td>8</td><td>3</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 8th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>2d10</td><td>9</td><td>3</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 9th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Malformed Burst</td><td>2d10</td><td>10</td><td>4</td></tr>
                <tr><td>10th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Nullity Feature</td><td>2d10</td><td>10</td><td>4</td></tr>
                <tr><td>11th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Vacuum Born</td><td>3d10</td><td>11</td><td>4</td></tr>
                <tr><td>12th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>3d10</td><td>11</td><td>4</td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">─</td><td>3d10</td><td>12</td><td>5</td></tr>
                <tr><td>14th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Nullity Feature</td><td>3d10</td><td>12</td><td>5</td></tr>
                <tr><td>15th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Empty Being</td><td>3d10</td><td>13</td><td>5</td></tr>
                <tr><td>16th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>3d10</td><td>13</td><td>5</td></tr>
                <tr><td>17th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">─</td><td>4d10</td><td>14</td><td>6</td></tr>
                <tr><td>18th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Absence</td><td>4d10</td><td>14</td><td>6</td></tr>
                <tr><td>19th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>4d10</td><td>15</td><td>6</td></tr>
                <tr><td>20th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Nothing</td><td>4d10</td><td>15</td><td>6</td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_RIFT_MAGIC" />
            <div element="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_STILLNESS" />
            <div element="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_EXERT_SELF" />
            <div element="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_NULLITY" />
            <div element="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" />
            <div element="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_IMPROVED_NULL_BURST" />
            <div element="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_MALFORMED_BURST" />
            <div element="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_VACUUM_BORN" />
            <div element="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_EMPTY_BEING" />
            <div element="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_ABSENCE" />
            <div element="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_NOTHING" />
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="hd">d8</set>
            <set name="short">A magic wielder that gathers energy into the emptiness inside them.</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CHARISMA" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CONSTITUTION" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS" />
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency, Null" supports="Skill" number="2" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_RIFT_MAGIC" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_STILLNESS" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_EXERT_SELF" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_NULLITY" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" level="4" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_IMPROVED_NULL_BURST" level="5" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_MALFORMED_BURST" level="9" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_VACUUM_BORN" level="11" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_EMPTY_BEING" level="15" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_ABSENCE" level="18" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_NOTHING" level="20" />
        </rules>
            <multiclass id="ID_EW_TNC_MULTICLASS_NULL">
                <prerequisite>Charisma 13</prerequisite>
                <requirements>[cha:13]</requirements>
                <setters>
                    <set name="multiclass proficiencies">You gain proficiency with light armor and simple weapons if you multiclass into this class.</set>
                </setters>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS" />
                    <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" />
                    <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" />
                </rules>
            </multiclass>
    </element>    
        <element name="Rift Magic" type="Class Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_RIFT_MAGIC">
            <description>
                <p>At 1st level, your null has drawn strange energy into itself which you can use to perform magic.</p>
                <h5>NULL BURST</h5>
                <p>As an action, you target a creature within 120 feet of you and expel a dark purple orb of unstable energy towards the creature, your physical null. Make a ranged spell attack against the creature. On a hit, the target takes 1d10 force damage. You must perform verbal and somatic components to use this action.</p>
                <p class="indent">The damage of your null burst increases by 1d10 at 5th level (2d10), 11th level (3d10), and 17th level (4d10).</p>
                <h5>ACCRETIONS</h5>
                <p>You can fill your empty body with odd powers from secret places in the depths of the world, granting you numerous benefits. When you roll initiative, or as a bonus action on your turn, you can use one of these accretions, which lasts until you use a different accretion, you choose to dismiss it (no action required), you are incapacitated, or by a condition specified by the accretion.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use an accretion, you cannot use it again until you complete a long rest.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can only have one accretion active at a time. Accretions are detailed at the end of the class feature section.</p>
                <h5>RIFT MAGIC ABILITY</h5>
                <p>Since your magic comes from exerting your will on otherwise emptiness, Charisma is your rift magic ability for your rift magic. You use Charisma whenever a rift magic feature refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Charisma modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a rift magic feature or when making an attack roll with one.</p>
                <p style="text-align: center"><b>Spell save DC</b> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier</p>
                <p style="text-align: center"><b>Spell attack modifier</b> = your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier</p>
                <h5>ACCRETIONS KNOWN</h5>
                <p>You know two accretions of your choice, and learn more as you gain levels in this class, as shown in the accretions known column of the class table. If an accretion has a level prerequisite, it refers to your level in this class.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, when you gain a level in this class, you can choose one accretion you know and replace it with another which you can learn.</p>
                <h5>EMPTY MAGIC</h5>
                <p>Your magic is channeled through your body’s null, which focuses and internalises the strange energies of the world. As a result, you do not need a spellcasting focus for any of your rift magic. If a rift magic feature would allow you to cast a spell that requires material components, you do not need to provide them, unless those materials components are costly.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>When you roll initiative, or as a bonus action on your turn, you can use one of your accretions. Your spell attack bonus is +{{rift-magic:attack}}. Your rift magic save DC is {{rift-magic:save-dc}}.</description>
            </sheet>
            <spellcasting name="Rift Magic" ability="Charisma" prepare="false">
                <list>Rift Magic</list>
            </spellcasting>
            <rules>
                <stat name="rift-magic:attack" value="proficiency"/>
                <stat name="rift-magic:attack" value="charisma:modifier"/>
                <stat name="rift-magic:save-dc" value="8" />
                <stat name="rift-magic:save-dc" value="rift-magic:attack" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Null Accretion" supports="Null Accretion" number="2" allowReplace="true" level="1" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Null Accretion" supports="Null Accretion" allowReplace="true" level="2" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Null Accretion" supports="Null Accretion" allowReplace="true" level="3" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Null Accretion" supports="Null Accretion" allowReplace="true" level="4" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Null Accretion" supports="Null Accretion" allowReplace="true" level="5" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Null Accretion" supports="Null Accretion" allowReplace="true" level="6" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Null Accretion" supports="Null Accretion" allowReplace="true" level="7" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Null Accretion" supports="Null Accretion" allowReplace="true" level="8" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Null Accretion" supports="Null Accretion" allowReplace="true" level="9" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Null Accretion" supports="Null Accretion" allowReplace="true" level="11" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Null Accretion" supports="Null Accretion" allowReplace="true" level="13" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Null Accretion" supports="Null Accretion" allowReplace="true" level="15" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Null Accretion" supports="Null Accretion" allowReplace="true" level="17" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Null Accretion" supports="Null Accretion" allowReplace="true" level="19" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Null Burst" type="Class Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_RIFT_MAGIC_NULL_BURST">
                <description>
                    <p>As an action, you target a creature within 120 feet of you and expel a dark purple orb of unstable energy towards the creature, your physical null. Make a ranged spell attack against the creature. On a hit, the target takes 1d10 force damage. You must perform verbal and somatic components to use this action.</p>
                    <p class="indent">The damage of your null burst increases by 1d10 at 5th level (2d10), 11th level (3d10), and 17th level (4d10).</p>
                </description>
                <sheet action="Action">
                    <description>You make a ranged spell attack (V, S) against a creature within 120 feet of you. On a hit, the target takes {{null-burst:damage-dice}}d10 force damage.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="null-burst:damage-dice" value="1" level="1" />
                    <stat name="null-burst:damage-dice" value="1" level="5" />
                    <stat name="null-burst:damage-dice" value="1" level="11" />
                    <stat name="null-burst:damage-dice" value="1" level="17" />
                </rules>
            </element>
        <element name="Stillness" type="Class Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_STILLNESS">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 1st level, you can spend a moment becoming still to accrete additional power. When you roll initiative, you can choose to reduce your movement speed to zero for your first turn. If you do, you can restore the usage of one accretion and immediately activate that accretion.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you roll initiative, you can choose to reduce your movement speed to zero for your first turn. If you do, you can restore the usage of one accretion and immediately activate that accretion.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Exert Self" type="Class Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_EXERT_SELF">
            <description>
                <p>At 2nd level, your experience with rift magic allows you to occasionally exert greater amounts of will onto it, granting it additional power. When you use a feature granted by your rift magic, you can expend a use of this feature in order to imbue one of the following benefits. You have two uses of this feature at 2nd level, and gain more as you gain levels in this class, as shown in the exert self column of the class table. You regain all expended uses when you complete a long rest.</p>
                <h5>GRATIFY</h5>
                <p>When you use an accretion, the benefits of your accretion last only until the end of your next turn, but you do not need to end any other accretions that are already active.</p>
                <h5>MAXIMISE</h5>
                <p>When you use a rift magic feature which involves rolling dice, you treat all dice rolled in the rift magic feature as having rolled their maximum value.</p>
                <h5>SACRIFICE</h5>
                <p>When you use a rift magic feature that does damage, you can reduce your hit points and your maximum hit points by any amount. If you do so, you increase the damage of the rift magic feature by that amount.</p>
                <h5>SEEK</h5>
                <p>When you use a rift magic feature which involves at least one attack roll, all attacks made in the rift magic feature have advantage.</p>
                <h5>SHAPE</h5>
                <p>When you use a rift magic feature which affects multiple creatures, you can designate a number of creatures up to your Charisma modifier to be unaffected by the feature.</p>
                <h5>SHATTER</h5>
                <p>When you use a rift magic feature which requires a saving throw, you can give one creature disadvantage on the save.</p>
                <h5>SPEED</h5>
                <p>When you use a rift magic feature which requires an action to use, it takes a bonus action instead for this usage. You cannot use the same feature that you used in your bonus action in your action, and if you used your bonus action to cast a spell, the normal rules for bonus action spellcasting apply.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="{{exert-self:uses}}/Long Rest">
                <description>When you use an accretion action or null burst, you can expend a use of this feature in order to imbue one of the following benefits: Gratify, Maximise, Sacrifice, Seek, Shape, Shatter, or Speed.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="exert-self:uses" value="2" level="2" />
                <stat name="exert-self:uses" value="1" level="5" />
                <stat name="exert-self:uses" value="1" level="9" />
                <stat name="exert-self:uses" value="1" level="13" />
                <stat name="exert-self:uses" value="1" level="17" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Nullity" type="Class Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_NULLITY">
            <description>
                <p>At 3rd level, you choose the manner in which you choose to face the emptiness inside of you - the Caller, the Grafter, or the Void, detailed at the end of the class features. Your choice grants you features at this level and again at levels 6, 10, and 14.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Archetype" name="Nullity" supports="Nullity" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Ability Score Improvement" type="Class Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
                <p class="indent">Using the optional feats rule, you can forgo taking this feature to take a feat of your choice instead.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Null 4)" supports="Improvement Option,Null,4" level="4" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Null 8)" supports="Improvement Option,Null,8" level="8" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Null 12)" supports="Improvement Option,Null,12" level="12" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Null 16)" supports="Improvement Option,Null,16" level="16" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Null 19)" supports="Improvement Option,Null,19" level="19" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Improved Null Burst" type="Class Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_IMPROVED_NULL_BURST">
            <description>
                <p>At 5th level, creatures are unable to entirely avoid the damage of your null burst. Whenever you cast a null burst that is unaffected by the effect of any accretions, you deal half the damage of the burst to a creature on a missed attack roll.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Whenever you cast a null burst that is unaffected by the effect of any accretions, you deal half the damage of the burst to a creature on a missed attack roll.</description>
                <description level="18">Whenever you cast a null burst, you deal half the damage of the burst to a creature on a missed attack roll.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Malformed Burst" type="Class Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_MALFORMED_BURST">
            <description>
                <p>At 9th level, you have accreted numerous odd effects into your null burst that can increase its potency. When you use your action to cast a null burst that is unaffected by any accretions, you can choose to activate one or a combination of the following effects:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>You can cause the null burst to explode in a minor detonation just before it reaches your target creature. Rather than you making an attack, the target must then succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or take the damage of your null burst, or half as much on a sucessful save.</li>
                    <li>You can change the damage type of your null burst to one of acid, cold, fire, lightning, or poison.</li>
                    <li>You can fill the null burst with greater energy at the cost of its stability. You increase the damage dice by 1d10, but attack rolls made with it are at disadvantage, and saving throws made against it are made at advantage.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Null Burst">
                <description>When you use your action to cast a null burst that is unaffected by any accretions, you can choose to activate one or a combination of effects.</description>
                <description level="18">When you use your action to cast a null burst, you can choose to activate one or a combination of effects.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Vacuum Born" type="Class Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_VACUUM_BORN">
            <description>
                <p>At 11th level, you can have two accretions active at any time instead of one, or three if you are also using the gratify option of exert self. Whenever you would activate one accretion, you can instead activate two.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can have two accretions active at any time instead of one, or three if you are also using the gratify option of exert self. Whenever you would activate one accretion, you can instead activate two.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Empty Being" type="Class Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_EMPTY_BEING">
            <description>
                <p>At 15th level, you no longer need to sleep, and you gain the benefits of a long rest by doing 8 hours of light activity. Furthermore, you do not need to eat, drink, or breathe.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You no longer need to sleep, and you gain the benefits of a long rest by doing 8 hours of light activity. Furthermore, you do not need to eat, drink, or breathe.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Absence" type="Class Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_ABSENCE">
            <description>
                <p>At 18th level, your mastery over your null burst has increased. You can use your improved null burst and malformed burst features on your null burst even if it is affected by an accretion.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Nothing" type="Class Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_NOTHING">
            <description>
                <p>At 20th level, you are a well of strange magic, barely clinging to the last vestiges of yourself. You have unlimited uses of your known accretions.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You have unlimited uses of your known accretions.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>

    <element name="The Caller" type="Archetype" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_ARCHETYPE_NULL_THE_CALLER">
        <supports>Nullity</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You fill your emptiness with created things - creatures that you call to do your bidding, bound friends, even the lost and weary souls that still haunt the ground beneath you. In doing so, you try to fill your null with companionship, and drown the loneliness of your lost soul.</p>
            <div element="ID_EW_TNC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_CALLER_CREATED_COMPANION" />
            <div element="ID_EW_TNC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_CALLER_FRIEND_OF_THE_EMPTY" />
            <div element="ID_EW_TNC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_CALLER_WHISPER_TO_THE_FALLEN" />
            <div element="ID_EW_TNC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_CALLER_LET_NOTHING_GO" />
            <div element="ID_EW_TNC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_CALLER_BIND_TO_SERVICE" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EW_TNC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_CALLER_CREATED_COMPANION" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EW_TNC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_CALLER_FRIEND_OF_THE_EMPTY" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EW_TNC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_CALLER_WHISPER_TO_THE_FALLEN" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EW_TNC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_CALLER_LET_NOTHING_GO" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EW_TNC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_CALLER_BIND_TO_SERVICE" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Created Companion" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_CALLER_CREATED_COMPANION">
            <description>
                <p>At 3rd level, you can call a companion which remains at your side at all times. You can cast the find familiar spell at will, without expending a spell slot or material components.</p>
                <div class="reference">
                    <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIND_FAMILIAR" />
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can cast the <i>find familiar</i> spell at will, without expending a spell slot or material components.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIND_FAMILIAR" spellcasting="Rift Magic" known="true" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Friend of the Empty" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_CALLER_FRIEND_OF_THE_EMPTY">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, you gain a greater control over the creatures that you summon with your rift magic. If a creature would usually become hostile to you and your companions after you end the accretion that summons it, it instead remains friendly to you and your allies as if the accretion lasted for its full duration. After this time, the creature becomes hostile as normal.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>If a creature would usually become hostile to you and your companions after you end the accretion that summons it, it instead remains friendly to you and your allies as if the accretion lasted for its full duration. After this time, the creature becomes hostile as normal.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Whisper to the Fallen" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_CALLER_WHISPER_TO_THE_FALLEN">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 6th level, you can cast the <i>speak with dead</i> spell at will, without expending a spell slot or material components.</p>
                <div class="reference">
                    <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_DEAD" />
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can cast the speak with dead spell at will, without expending a spell slot or material components.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_DEAD" spellcasting="Rift Magic" known="true" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Let Nothing Go" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_CALLER_LET_NOTHING_GO">
            <description>
                <p>At 10th level, you learn to reinforce the strength of the companions that you summon, preventing them from leaving your side. You can cast <i>life transference</i> at will, as long as it targets either your familiar or a creature summoned by one of your accretions.</p>
                <div class="reference">
                    <div element="ID_XGTE_SPELL_LIFE_TRANSFERENCE" />
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can cast life transference at will, as long as it targets either your familiar or a creature summoned by one of your accretions.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_LIFE_TRANSFERENCE" spellcasting="Rift Magic" known="true" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Bind to Service" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_CALLER_BIND_TO_SERVICE">
            <description>
                <p>At 14th level, you can attempt to force any creature to join your service. You can cast dominate monster as an 8th level spell. While you concentrate on the spell, the dominated monster is a valid target of your let nothing go feature.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you cannot use it again until you complete a long rest.</p>
                <div class="reference">
                    <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_DOMINATE_MONSTER" />
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You can cast dominate monster as an 8th level spell. While you concentrate on the spell, the dominated monster is a valid target of your let nothing go feature.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DOMINATE_MONSTER" spellcasting="Rift Magic" known="true" />
            </rules>
        </element>

    <element name="The Grafter" type="Archetype" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_ARCHETYPE_NULL_THE_GRAFTER">
        <supports>Nullity</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You fill your emptiness with stolen things - fragments of the lives of other people, pieces of memories that you have claimed from another, possessions and discarded parts. In doing so, you attempt to deny your null, constantly creating and destroying new identities for yourself, avoiding the truth of the emptiness within you.</p>
            <div element="ID_EW_TNC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_GRAFTER_SOULCATCHER" />
            <div element="ID_EW_TNC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_GRAFTER_SHIFTING_SKIN" />
            <div element="ID_EW_TNC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_GRAFTER_THIEF_OF_TIME" />
            <div element="ID_EW_TNC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_GRAFTER_MIND_EATER" />
            <div element="ID_EW_TNC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_GRAFTER_AMALGAMATION" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EW_TNC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_GRAFTER_SOULCATCHER" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EW_TNC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_GRAFTER_SHIFTING_SKIN" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EW_TNC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_GRAFTER_THIEF_OF_TIME" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EW_TNC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_GRAFTER_MIND_EATER" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EW_TNC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_GRAFTER_AMALGAMATION" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Soulcatcher" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_GRAFTER_SOULCATCHER">
            <description>
                <p>At 3rd level, you can capture the souls of the creatures that you destroy. As a reaction when a humanoid creature dies within 30 feet of you, you can capture their soul, storing it within the emptiness inside. You can capture a number of souls up to your Charisma modifier.</p>
                <p class="indent">As a bonus action, you can devour one of the souls that you have captured to gain its experience, making your next ability check, saving throw, or attack roll with advantage.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Reaction">
                <description>When a humanoid creature dies within 30 feet of you, you can capture their soul, storing it within the emptiness inside. You can capture up to {{charisma:modifier}} souls at a time. As a bonus action, you can devour one of the souls that you have captured to gain its experience, making your next ability check, saving throw, or attack roll with advantage.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Shifting Skin" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_GRAFTER_SHIFTING_SKIN">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, you have learned to easily adopt new forms and faces. You can cast <i>disguise self</i> at will, without expending a spell slot.</p>
                <div class="reference">
                    <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISGUISE_SELF" />
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can cast disguise self at will, without expending a spell slot.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISGUISE_SELF" spellcasting="Rift Magic" known="true" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Thief of Time" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_GRAFTER_THIEF_OF_TIME">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 6th level, you instinctively steal fragments of the lives that you end, adding them to your own. Whenever you reduce a creature to zero hit points, you gain temporary hit points equal to your Charisma modifier + your null level (minimum of 1).</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Whenever you reduce a creature to zero hit points, you gain {{thief-of-time:temp-hp}} temporary hit points.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="thief-of-time:temp-hp" value="charisma:modifier" />
                <stat name="thief-of-time:temp-hp" value="level:null" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Mind Eater" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_GRAFTER_MIND_EATER">
            <description>
                <p>At 10th level, you can manipulate the souls you have caught to gain their darkest truths and better reshape your identities. By consuming one of the souls you have captured, you can gain the memories that that soul had in life.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can only have the memories of one soul at a time, and when you try to capture those of another, you lose those of the first.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>By consuming one of the souls you have captured, you can gain the memories that that soul had in life. You can only have the memories of one soul at a time.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Amalgamation" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_GRAFTER_AMALGAMATION">
            <description>
                <p>At 14th level, you can consume all the souls that you have captured to transform into a horrid amalgamation of beings. In this state, you gain the following benefits:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>You gain twenty temporary hit points for each soul consumed.</li>
                    <li>A creature you damage with your null burst must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be frightened of you.</li>
                    <li>You become Large, if you were not already.</li>
                    <li>Thief of Time restores hit points instead of granting temporary hit points.</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">The benefits of this feature end after one minute, or after you run out of temporary hit points gained by this feature. Once you use this feature, you cannot use it again until you complete a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You can consume all the souls that you have captured and transform for up to 1 minute or run out of temporary hit points. You gain: 20 temporary hit points. A creature you damage with your null burst must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be frightened of you. You become Large. Thief of Time restores hit points.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>

    <element name="The Void" type="Archetype" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_ARCHETYPE_NULL_THE_VOID">
        <supports>Nullity</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You do not attempt to fill your emptiness at all; instead you accept it, understand it, and develop the power that it grants you. In doing so, you begin to better manipulate the strength of your own null.</p>
            <div element="ID_EW_TNC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_VOID_EMPOWERED_NULL_BURST" />
            <div element="ID_EW_TNC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_VOID_SILENCE_OF_THE_VOID" />
            <div element="ID_EW_TNC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_VOID_STAGNANT_RESTORATION" />
            <div element="ID_EW_TNC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_VOID_NULL_MIND" />
            <div element="ID_EW_TNC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_VOID_RESONANT_CHANNEL" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EW_TNC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_VOID_EMPOWERED_NULL_BURST" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EW_TNC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_VOID_SILENCE_OF_THE_VOID" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EW_TNC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_VOID_STAGNANT_RESTORATION" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EW_TNC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_VOID_NULL_MIND" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EW_TNC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_VOID_RESONANT_CHANNEL" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Empowered Null Burst" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_VOID_EMPOWERED_NULL_BURST">
            <description>
                <p>At 3rd level, your acceptance of your emptiness strengthens your null burst. You may add your Charisma modifier (minimum of +1) to one damage roll of the null burst.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You add +{{null-burst:bonus-damage}} to one damage roll of the null burst.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="null-burst:bonus-damage" value="1" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="null-burst:bonus-damage" value="charisma:modifier" bonus="base" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Silence of the Void" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_VOID_SILENCE_OF_THE_VOID">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, you no longer make sound when you move, granting you advantage on Stealth checks against a creature perceiving you through noise. Furthermore, if any spells you cast through your rift magic feature would require verbal components, they no longer do.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You no longer make sound when you move, granting you advantage on Stealth checks against a creature perceiving you through noise. Furthermore, if any spells you cast through your rift magic feature would require verbal components, they no longer do.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Stagnant Restoration" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_VOID_STAGNANT_RESTORATION">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 6th level, you can regain one usage of exert self when you complete a short rest. Once you use this feature, you can’t do so again until you complete a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You can regain one usage of exert self when you complete a short rest.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Null Mind" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_VOID_NULL_MIND">
            <description>
                <p>At 10th level, you permanently exude a field of emptiness around yourself, making you difficult to harm with mind affecting magic. You become immune to the Charmed and Frightened conditions.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You are immune to the Charmed and Frightened conditions.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Resonant Channel" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_VOID_RESONANT_CHANNEL">
            <description>
                <p>At 14th level, you can form a dark purple link to a creature within 90 feet of you as an action. When you do so, that creature becomes joined to the emptiness within you, which stores and amplifies the experiences of the creature. While this connection exists, the creature takes no damage and cannot recover any hit points. Instead, any hit points recovered or damaged taken are stored within you. The link lasts for up to one minute, until you use your action to end it, or until you lose concentration, as if concentrating on a spell. If you use your action to end the link, or if a full minute passes, the creature takes damage and recovers hit points equal to twice the amount stored. If you choose to end your concentration with no action, or you cast another spell which requires concentration, the link ends without effect. If another creature causes you to lose concentration on the link, such as by dealing damage to you and causing you to fail a concentration save or by incapacitating you, they choose which of the previous effects occur.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you cannot use it again until you complete a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest" action="Action">
                <description>You form a link to a creature within 90 feet of you for up to 1 minute. While this connection exists, the creature takes no damage and cannot recover any hit points. Instead, any hit points recovered or damaged taken are stored within you.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>

    <!-- Null Accretions -->
        <element name="Hollow" type="Class Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_ACCRETION_HOLLOW">
            <supports>Null Accretion</supports>
            <description>
                <p>While you have this accretion active, your null is emptied, and you become light and dexterous. You gain a +3 bonus to your AC, and your movement speed increases by 10 feet. Furthermore, when you are hit by an attack, you can use your reaction to allow the attack to pass harmlessly through you, dealing no damage or secondary effects. Once you use your reaction in this way, the accretion ends.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Accretion" action="Reaction">
                <description>You gain a +3 bonus to your AC, and your movement speed increases by 10 feet. Furthermore, when you are hit by an attack, you can use your reaction to allow the attack to pass harmlessly through you, dealing no damage or secondary effects. Once you use your reaction in this way, the accretion ends.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Null Blade" type="Class Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_ACCRETION_NULL_BLADE">
            <supports>Null Accretion</supports>
            <description>
                <p>While you have this accretion active, you can form your null into weapons and armour. Your unarmoured AC becomes 10 + your Charisma modifier + your Dexterity modifier, and when you cast null burst, you can make a melee spell attack against a creature within 5 feet of you. On a hit, the creature takes the damage of your null burst. After this, you can reduce the damage dice of your null burst by 1d10 and attack a second time, provided that this does not reduce the damage to 0.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Accretion">
                <description>Your unarmoured AC becomes {{null-blade:ac}}, and when you cast null burst, you can make a melee spell attack against a creature within 5 feet of you. On a hit, the creature takes the damage of your null burst. After this, you can reduce the damage dice of your null burst by 1d10 and attack a second time, provided that this does not reduce the damage to 0.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="null-blade:ac" value="10" />
                <stat name="null-blade:ac" value="charisma:modifier" />
                <stat name="null-blade:ac" value="dexterity:modifier" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Null Sculptor" type="Class Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_ACCRETION_NULL_SCULPTOR">
            <supports>Null Accretion</supports>
            <description>
                <p>While you have this accretion active, you gain greater control over the shape and effects of your null burst. When you cast null burst, you can hurl the dark orb to an area within its range, causing it to explode on impact. When you do so, creatures within 10 feet of the area must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or take the damage of your null burst.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Accretion">
                <description>When you cast null burst, you can hurl the dark orb to an area within its range, causing it to explode on impact. When you do so, creatures within 10 feet of the area must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw (DC {{rift-magic:save-dc}}) or take the damage of your null burst.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Serpent Aspect" type="Class Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_ACCRETION_SERPENT_ASPECT">
            <supports>Null Accretion</supports>
            <description>
                <p>While you have this accretion active, you fill yourself with weird and otherworldly charm. You can cast the <i>charm person</i> spell at will. If a creature succeeds on the saving throw, you cannot target them again during this usage of the accretion.</p>
                <div class="reference">
                    <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_CHARM_PERSON" />
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Accretion">
                <description>You can cast the charm person spell at will. If a creature succeeds on the saving throw, you cannot target them again during this usage of the accretion.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CHARM_PERSON" spellcasting="Rift Magic" known="true" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Shadowcall" type="Class Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_ACCRETION_SHADOWCALL">
            <supports>Null Accretion</supports>
            <description>
                <p>While you have this accretion active, you can conjure strange shadows into being. You can cast the silent image spell at will.</p>
                <div class="reference">
                    <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_SILENT_IMAGE" />
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Accretion">
                <description>You can cast the silent image spell at will.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SILENT_IMAGE" spellcasting="Rift Magic" known="true" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Summon Eye" type="Class Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_ACCRETION_SUMMON_EYE">
            <supports>Null Accretion</supports>
            <description>
                <p>While you have this accretion active, you can use your action to summon a gazer to an unoccuped space within 5 feet of you. After doing so, you cannot do so again for the duration of this accretion. The gazer is friendly to you and your companions while this accretion is active. If the accretion ends, the gazer becomes hostile to you and all creatures it can see, and goes about attacking the nearest creature to it.</p>
                <p class="indent">In combat, the gazer takes its turn immediately after yours. It obeys any verbal commands you issue, no action required. If you don’t issue any commands, the gazer uses its action to attack the nearest hostile creature.</p>
                <p class="indent">This accretion ends after 1 minute. You cannot have more than one gazer summoned at a time.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Accretion" action="Action">
                <description>You can summon a gazer to an unoccuped space within 5 feet of you. After doing so, you cannot do so again for the duration of this accretion. This accretion ends after 1 minute. You cannot have more than one gazer summoned at a time.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Toughen" type="Class Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_ACCRETION_TOUGHEN">
            <supports>Null Accretion</supports>
            <description>
                <p>While you have this accretion active, your movement speed is reduced to zero as you fill your null with heavy, solid defenses. You gain temporary hit points equal to three times your level in this class, and you become resistant to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage from nonmagical sources. The accretion ends after you lose all the temporary hit points, and any remaining temporary hit points are lost if the accretion ends.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Accretion">
                <description>Your movement speed is reduced to zero. You gaint {{toughen:temp-hp}} temporary hit points and you become resistant to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage from nonmagical sources. The accretion ends after you lose all the temporary hit points, and any remaining temporary hit points are lost if the accretion ends.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="toughen:temp-hp" value="level:null" />
                <stat name="toughen:temp-hp" value="level:null" />
                <stat name="toughen:temp-hp" value="level:null" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Crawl" type="Class Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_ACCRETION_CRAWL">
            <supports>Null Accretion</supports>
            <requirements>[level:null:3]</requirements>
            <prerequisite>3rd Level</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 3rd Level</p>
                <p class="indent">While you have this accretion active, you can cause your null to cling to surfaces. You can cast the <i>spider climb</i> spell at will.</p>
                <div class="reference">
                    <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPIDER_CLIMB" />
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Accretion">
                <description>You can cast the spider climb spell at will.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPIDER_CLIMB" spellcasting="Rift Magic" known="true" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Darken" type="Class Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_ACCRETION_DARKEN">
            <supports>Null Accretion</supports>
            <requirements>[level:null:3]</requirements>
            <prerequisite>3rd Level</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 3rd Level</p>
                <p class="indent">While you have this accretion active, you can absorb the light from regions around you, consuming it in your null and leaving the affected area shrouded in darkness. You can cast the <i>darkness</i> spell at will.</p>
                <div class="reference">
                    <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_DARKNESS" />
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Accretion">
                <description>You can cast the darkness spell at will.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DARKNESS" spellcasting="Rift Magic" known="true" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Devouring Null" type="Class Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_ACCRETION_DEVOURING_NULL">
            <supports>Null Accretion</supports>
            <requirements>[level:null:3]</requirements>
            <prerequisite>3rd Level</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 3rd Level</p>
                <p class="indent">While you have this accretion active, you can allow your null to consume parts of you, empowering your magic. When you roll damage with your null burst, you can expend any number of hit dice. Roll any expended dice, adding your Constitution modifier to each, and add them to the damage of the null burst.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Accretion">
                <description>When you roll damage with your null burst, you can expend any number of hit dice. Roll any expended dice, adding {{constitution:modifier}} to each, and add them to the damage of the null burst.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="See" type="Class Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_ACCRETION_SEE">
            <supports>Null Accretion</supports>
            <requirements>[level:null:3]</requirements>
            <prerequisite>3rd Level</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 3rd Level</p>
                <p class="indent">While you have this accretion active, you can exert your null to see through solid objects, viewing them as ghostly, transparent images outlined in faint light.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Accretion">
                <description>You can see through solid objects, viewing them as ghostly, transparent images outlined in faint light.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Vanish" type="Class Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_ACCRETION_VANISH">
            <supports>Null Accretion</supports>
            <requirements>[level:null:3]</requirements>
            <prerequisite>3rd Level</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 3rd Level</p>
                <p class="indent">While you have this accretion active, your null shrouds you, turning you invisible. This accretion ends after one hour, or when you make an attack or cast a spell.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Accretion">
                <description>You turn invisible. This accretion ends after one hour, or when you make an attack or cast a spell.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Ascend" type="Class Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_ACCRETION_ASCEND">
            <supports>Null Accretion</supports>
            <requirements>[level:null:5]</requirements>
            <prerequisite>5th Level</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 5th Level</p>
                <p class="indent">While you have this accretion active, you fill yourself with lightness and gain a flying speed of 30 feet.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Accretion">
                <description>You gain a flying speed of 30 feet.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Null Strike" type="Class Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_ACCRETION_NULL_STRIKE">
            <supports>Null Accretion</supports>
            <requirements>[level:null:5]</requirements>
            <prerequisite>5th Level</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 5th Level</p>
                <p class="indent">While you have this accretion active, you can channel your null into your blows. Once per turn, when you hit with a creature with a melee weapon attack, you can add the damage of your null burst (excluding any features which affect null burst).</p>
                <p class="indent">While you have this accretion active, you can treat all other accretions as if gratify had been applied to them.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Accretion">
                <description>Once per turn, when you hit with a creature with a melee weapon attack, you can add the damage of your null burst (excluding any features which affect null burst). You can treat all other accretions as if gratify had been applied to them.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Roiling Null" type="Class Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_ACCRETION_ROILING_NULL">
            <supports>Null Accretion</supports>
            <requirements>[level:null:5]</requirements>
            <prerequisite>5th Level</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 5th Level</p>
                <p class="indent">While you have this accretion active, you fill your null with energy. You gain a pool of d6s equal to your null level. Once per turn, when you roll damage for your null burst, you can increase the damage against one creature by expending dice from the pool. You can spend a number of dice equal to half your null level or less. Roll the spent dice and increase the damage of the null burst by that amount. Once you expend all the dice in the pool, the accretion ends. If you end the accretion before using all the dice, the pool disappears.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Accretion">
                <description>You gain a pool of {{level:null}} d6s. Once per turn, when you roll damage for your null burst, you can increase the damage against one creature by expending dice from the pool, up to {{level:null:half}} dice. Once you expend all the dice in the pool, the accretion ends. If you end the accretion before using all the dice, the pool disappears.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Spell Eater" type="Class Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_ACCRETION_SPELL_EATER">
            <supports>Null Accretion</supports>
            <requirements>[level:null:5]</requirements>
            <prerequisite>5th Level</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 5th Level</p>
                <p class="indent">While you have this accretion active, you can project your null to attempt to devour magic. When a creature that you can see within 60 feet of you casts a spell, you can use your reaction to attempt to disrupt the magic. Make a Charisma check with a DC equal to 10 + the spell’s level. On a success, the spell fails and has no effect. On a failure, you take necrotic damage equal to the DC. This accretion ends after one minute.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Accretion" action="Reaction">
                <description>When a creature that you can see within 60 feet of you casts a spell, you can use your reaction to make a Charisma check with a DC equal to 10 + the spell’s level. On a success, the spell fails and has no effect. On a failure, you take necrotic damage equal to the DC. This accretion ends after one minute.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Whisperer" type="Class Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_ACCRETION_WHISPERER">
            <supports>Null Accretion</supports>
            <requirements>[level:null:5]</requirements>
            <prerequisite>5th Level</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 5th Level</p>
                <p class="indent">While you have this accretion active, you can use your action to summon a gibbering mouther to an unoccupied space within 5 feet of you. After doing so, you cannot do so again for the duration of this accretion.</p>
                <p class="indent">While this accretion is active, the gibbering mouther is friendly to you and your companions, and creatures of your choice are unaffected by its Aberrant Ground and Gibbering features. The gibbering mouther take its turn immediately after you and attempts to attack the nearest hostile creature each turn.</p>
                <p class="indent">The accretion ends after 1 minute. You cannot have more than one gibbering mouther summoned at a time.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Accretion" action="Action">
                <description>You can summon a gibbering mouther to an unoccupied space within 5 feet of you. After doing so, you cannot do so again for the duration of this accretion. The accretion ends after 1 minute. You cannot have more than one gibbering mouther summoned at a time.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Consume" type="Class Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_ACCRETION_CONSUME">
            <supports>Null Accretion</supports>
            <requirements>[level:null:7]</requirements>
            <prerequisite>7th Level</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 7th Level</p>
                <p class="indent">While you have this accretion active, you can attempt to wrap and consume a creature within your null. As an action, you can target a creature within 60 feet of you. The creature must make a Charisma saving throw or disappear within your null, vanishing from sight. While there, the creature is incapacitated.</p>
                <p class="indent">Each time you take damage, you must succeed on a Constitution saving throw with a DC equal to 10 or the damage taken, whichever is higher. On a failure, you expel the creature consumed to the nearest unoccupied space.</p>
                <p class="indent">This accretion lasts until you expel a consumed creature, or for 1 minute, after which the creature is expelled.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Accretion" action="Action">
                <description>You can target a creature within 60 feet of you. The creature must make a Charisma saving throw(DC {{rift-magic:save-dc}}) or disappear within your null, vanishing from sight. While there, the creature is incapacitated. Each time you take damage, you must succeed on a Constitution saving throw with a DC equal to 10 or the damage taken, whichever is higher. On a failure, you expel the creature consumed to the nearest unoccupied space. This accretion lasts until you expel a consumed creature, or for 1 minute, after which the creature is expelled.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Empty" type="Class Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_ACCRETION_EMPTY">
            <supports>Null Accretion</supports>
            <requirements>[level:null:7]</requirements>
            <prerequisite>7th Level</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 7th Level</p>
                <p class="indent">While you have this accretion active, your null shrouds you, turning you invisible. This accretion ends after one minute.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Accretion">
                <description>You turn invisible. This accretion ends after one minute.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Project Null" type="Class Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_ACCRETION_PROJECT_NULL">
            <supports>Null Accretion</supports>
            <requirements>[level:null:7]</requirements>
            <prerequisite>7th Level</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 7th Level</p>
                <p class="indent">While you have this accretion active, you project a portion of your null to an unoccupied space within 30 feet of you. The null takes a shape of your choosing, though it is generally dark, consuming light in its space. Whenever you cast your null burst, you can do so from the space of your projected null.</p>
                <p class="indent">As a bonus action on your turn, you can move your projected null up to 30 feet. If you ram the null into a creature, the creature must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or take the damage of your null burst, excluding any features that affect null burst. The accretion ends after one minute.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Accretion" action="Bonus Action">
                <description>You project a portion of your null to an unoccupied space within 30 feet of you. The null takes a shape of your choosing, though it is generally dark, consuming light in its space. Whenever you cast your null burst, you can do so from the space of your projected null. As a bonus action on your turn, you can move your projected null up to 30 feet. If you ram the null into a creature, the creature must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw (DC {{rift-magic:save-dc}}) or take the damage of your null burst, excluding any features that affect null burst. The accretion ends after one minute.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Call of the Deep" type="Class Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_ACCRETION_CALL_OF_THE_DEEP">
            <supports>Null Accretion</supports>
            <requirements>[level:null:9]</requirements>
            <prerequisite>9th Level</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 9th Level</p>
                <p class="indent">While you have this accretion active, you can use your action to summon a chuul to an unoccuped space within 5 feet of you. After doing so, you cannot do so again for the duration of this accretion. The chuul is friendly to you and your companions while this accretion is active. If the accretion ends, the chuul becomes hostile to you and all creatures it can see, and goes about attacking the nearest creature to it.</p>
                <p class="indent">In combat, the chuul takes its turn immediately after yours. It obeys any verbal commands you issue, no action required. If you don’t issue any commands, the chuul uses its action to attack the nearest hostile creature.</p>
                <p class="indent">This accretion ends after 1 minute. You cannot have more than one chuul summoned at a time.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Accretion" action="Action">
                <description>You can summon a chuul to an unoccuped space within 5 feet of you. After doing so, you cannot do so again for the duration of this accretion. This accretion ends after 1 minute. You cannot have more than one chuul summoned at a time.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Event Horizon" type="Class Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_ACCRETION_EVENT_HORIZON">
            <supports>Null Accretion</supports>
            <requirements>[level:null:9]</requirements>
            <prerequisite>9th Level</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 9th Level</p>
                <p class="indent">While you have this accretion active, you radiate odd energy around you in a 20 foot radius disc. Any creatures that start their turn in the disc must succeed on a Constititution saving throw or take radiant damage equal to your null level. This accretion ends after 1 minute.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Accretion">
                <description>You radiate odd energy around you in a 20 foot radius disc. Any creatures that start their turn in the disc must succeed on a Constititution saving throw (DC {{rift-magic:save-dc}}) or take {{level:null}} radiant damage. This accretion ends after 1 minute.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Mind Ravage" type="Class Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_ACCRETION_MIND_RAVAGE">
            <supports>Null Accretion</supports>
            <requirements>[level:null:9]</requirements>
            <prerequisite>9th Level</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 9th Level</p>
                <p class="indent">While you have this accretion active, you can attempt to consume the memories of another creature within your null. As an action, you target one creature within 30 feet of you, which must make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failure, the creature is stunned until the start of your next turn, and you can cause it to forget one event that occurred within the last 24 hours. Once you do, the accretion ends.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Accretion" action="Action">
                <description>You target one creature within 30 feet of you, which must make a Wisdom saving throw (DC {{rift-magic:save-dc}}). On a failure, the creature is stunned until the start of your next turn, and you can cause it to forget one event that occurred within the last 24 hours. Once you do, the accretion ends.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Null Chain" type="Class Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_ACCRETION_NULL_CHAIN">
            <supports>Null Accretion</supports>
            <requirements>[level:null:9]</requirements>
            <prerequisite>9th Level</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 9th Level</p>
                <p class="indent">While you have this accretion active, your null burst can leap between targets. If you hit a target with your null burst, you can repeat the attack against another target within range.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Accretion">
                <description>If you hit a target with your null burst, you can repeat the attack against another target within range.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Shadowstep" type="Class Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_ACCRETION_SHADOWSTEP">
            <supports>Null Accretion</supports>
            <requirements>[level:null:9]</requirements>
            <prerequisite>9th Level</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 9th Level</p>
                <p class="indent">While you have this accretion active, your null makes you almost incorporeal. You can cast the <i>misty step</i> spell at will. This accretion ends after 1 minute.</p>
                <div class="reference">
                    <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_MISTY_STEP" />
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Accretion">
                <description>You can cast misty step at will. This accretion ends after 1 minute.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MISTY_STEP" spellcasting="Rift Magic" known="true" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Black Null" type="Class Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_ACCRETION_BLACK_NULL">
            <supports>Null Accretion</supports>
            <requirements>[level:null:13]</requirements>
            <prerequisite>13th Level</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 13th level</p>
                <p class="indent">While you have this accretion active, shadows seep into your null burst. Creatures that you hit with your null burst become blinded until the start of your next turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Accretion">
                <description>Creatures that you hit with your null burst become blinded until the start of your next turn.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Discorporate" type="Class Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_ACCRETION_DISCORPORATE">
            <supports>Null Accretion</supports>
            <requirements>[level:null:13]</requirements>
            <prerequisite>13th Level</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 13th level</p>
                <p class="indent">While you have this accretion active, your null’s emptiness seeks out other worlds. You can cast <i>etherealness</i>, after which the accretion ends.</p>
                <div class="reference">
                    <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_ETHEREALNESS" />
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Accretion">
                <description>You can cast etherealness, after which the accretion ends.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ETHEREALNESS" spellcasting="Rift Magic" known="true" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Elemental Null" type="Class Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_ACCRETION_ELEMENTAL_NULL">
            <supports>Null Accretion</supports>
            <requirements>[level:null:13]</requirements>
            <prerequisite>13th Level</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 13th level</p>
                <p class="indent">While you have this accretion active, your null is filled with the various powers of the elements. You can use your action cast the <i>investiture of flame</i>, <i>investiture of ice</i>, <i>investiture of stone</i>, or <i>investiture of wind</i> spell. The accretion lasts for the duration of the spell you cast, after which it ends.</p>
                <div class="reference">
                    <div element="ID_XGTE_SPELL_INVESTITURE_OF_FLAME" />
                    <div element="ID_XGTE_SPELL_INVESTITURE_OF_ICE" />
                    <div element="ID_XGTE_SPELL_INVESTITURE_OF_STONE" />
                    <div element="ID_XGTE_SPELL_INVESTITURE_OF_WIND" />
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Accretion" action="Action">
                <description>You can cast investiture of flame, investiture of ice, investiture of stone, or investiture of wind. The accretion lasts for the duration of the spell you cast, after which it ends.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_INVESTITURE_OF_FLAME" spellcasting="Rift Magic" known="true" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_INVESTITURE_OF_ICE" spellcasting="Rift Magic" known="true" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_INVESTITURE_OF_STONE" spellcasting="Rift Magic" known="true" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_INVESTITURE_OF_WIND" spellcasting="Rift Magic" known="true" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Open Cosmos" type="Class Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_ACCRETION_OPEN_COSMOS">
            <supports>Null Accretion</supports>
            <requirements>[level:null:13]</requirements>
            <prerequisite>13th Level</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 13th level</p>
                <p class="indent">While you have this accretion active, you fill your null with the strange horrors of the distant cosmos. You can cast the <i>Evard’s black tentacles</i> spell at will. If you are in the spell’s area, your null burst is empowered, dealing an additional 1d10 damage on a hit.</p>
                <div class="reference">
                    <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_EVARDS_BLACK_TENTACLES" />
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Accretion">
                <description>You can cast Evard’s black tentacles at will. If you are in the spell’s area, your null burst is empowered, dealing an additional 1d10 damage on a hit.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_EVARDS_BLACK_TENTACLES" spellcasting="Rift Magic" known="true" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Radiant Null" type="Class Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_ACCRETION_RADIANT_NULL">
            <supports>Null Accretion</supports>
            <requirements>[level:null:13]</requirements>
            <prerequisite>13th Level</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 13th level</p>
                <p class="indent">While you have this accretion active, you fill your null with the blinding, brilliant light of the stars. You can use an action to cast the <i>sunbeam</i> spell at 6th level. Instead of its ordinary duration, the spell does not require concentration, and it lasts for as long as this accretion remains active. The accretion ends after one minute.</p>
                <div class="reference">
                    <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_SUNBEAM" />
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Accretion" action="Action">
                <description>You can cast sunbeam at 6th level. Instead of its ordinary duration, the spell does not require concentration, and it lasts for as long as this accretion remains active. The accretion ends after one minute.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SUNBEAM" spellcasting="Rift Magic" known="true" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="The Dead Walk" type="Class Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_ACCRETION_THE_DEAD_WALK">
            <supports>Null Accretion</supports>
            <requirements>[level:null:13]</requirements>
            <prerequisite>13th Level</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 13th level</p>
                <p class="indent">While you have this accretion active, your null can seek out and animate other empty creatures. You can cast the <i>create undead</i> spell, as if from a spell slot of half your null level (rounded up). Once you do so, you cannot do so again for the duration of the accretion. Rather than needing to reassert your control every 24 hours, the summoned creatures remain under your control until the accretion ends.</p>
                <p class="indent">You cannot have more than one group of undead from this accretion at the same time.</p>
                <div class="reference">
                    <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_CREATE_UNDEAD" />
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Accretion">
                <description>You can cast create undead as a {{level:null:half:up}}th-level spell. Once you do so, you cannot do so again for the duration of the accretion. Rather than needing to reassert your control every 24 hours, the summoned creatures remain under your control until the accretion ends. You cannot have more than one group of undead from this accretion at the same time.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CREATE_UNDEAD" spellcasting="Rift Magic" known="true" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Entropic Null" type="Class Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_ACCRETION_ENTROPIC_NULL">
            <supports>Null Accretion</supports>
            <requirements>[level:null:17]</requirements>
            <prerequisite>17th Level</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 17th Level</p>
                <p class="indent">While you have this accretion active, withering entropy seeps into your null burst. Your null burst deals necrotic damage, and when you successfully hit a creature with a null burst, it must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or gain one level of exhaustion. Any exhaustion caused in this way ends when the accretion ends.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Accretion">
                <description>Your null burst deals necrotic damage, and when you successfully hit a creature with a null burst, it must succeed on a Constitution saving throw (DC {{rift-magic:save-dc}}) or gain one level of exhaustion. Any exhaustion caused in this way ends when the accretion ends.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Maddening Null" type="Class Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_ACCRETION_MADDENING_NULL">
            <supports>Null Accretion</supports>
            <description>
                <p>While you have this accretion active, your null absorbs incomprehensible horrors. You can use your action to target a creature within 120 feet of you and project these horrors onto it. The creature must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or become frightened of you for the duration of the accretion. At the end of each of the target’s turns while frightened, it must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or take 4d10 psychic damage. On a successful save, the effect ends.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Accretion" action="Action">
                <description>You can use your action to target a creature within 120 feet of you to make a Wisdom saving throw (DC {{rift-magic:save-dc}}) or become frightened of you for the duration of the accretion. At the end of each of the target’s turns while frightened, it must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or take 4d10 psychic damage. On a successful save, the effect ends.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Null Field" type="Class Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_ACCRETION_NULL_FIELD">
            <supports>Null Accretion</supports>
            <requirements>[level:null:17]</requirements>
            <prerequisite>17th Level</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 17th Level</p>
                <p class="indent">While you have this accretion active, your null expels as a field around you, consuming anything that comes within its reach. The null extends to a radius of 30 feet around you. When you activate this accretion, you can choose whether a creature in that radius is pushed to the outside or trapped within the field.</p>
                <p class="indent">Nothing can physically pass into the null, and matter entering is immediately consumed by the null. Magic inside the null field is also devoured, as if by an <i>antimagic field</i> spell. Creatures inside the null field must succeed on a Constitution saving throw at the start of each of their turns or have their movement reduced to zero and become incapacitated until the end of their turn as your null slowly consumes them. Creatures are capable of freely exiting the null, if they can do so, but they may not reenter.</p>
                <p class="indent">While you use this accretion, you are suspended, barely conscious, just above the ground. Your movement speed is reduced to zero, and you are incapacitated for the duration of the accretion.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Accretion">
                <description>The null extends to a radius of 30 feet around you. When you activate this accretion, you can choose whether a creature in that radius is pushed to the outside or trapped within the field. While you use this accretion, you are suspended, barely conscious, just above the ground. Your movement speed is reduced to zero, and you are incapacitated for the duration of the accretion.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Null Waves" type="Class Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_ACCRETION_NULL_WAVES">
            <supports>Null Accretion</supports>
            <requirements>[level:null:17]</requirements>
            <prerequisite>17th Level</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 17th Level</p>
                <p class="indent">You fill your null with crackling, strange energy. While you have this accretion active, your null burst explodes in a 20 foot radius sphere around you. Creatures within the sphere must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or take the damage of your null burst, or half as much on a successful save.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Accretion">
                <description>Your null burst explodes in a 20 foot radius sphere around you. Creatures within the sphere must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw (DC {{rift-magic:save-dc}}) or take the damage of your null burst, or half as much on a successful save.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Singularity" type="Class Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_ACCRETION_SINGULARITY">
            <supports>Null Accretion</supports>
            <requirements>[level:null:17]</requirements>
            <prerequisite>17th Level</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 17th Level</p>
                <p class="indent">While you have this accretion active, you allow your null to consume you and manifest into space. You transform into a 2 foot diameter sphere of pure black, your null given form. This null acts as a Sphere of Annihilation, though you can still be harmed. In this state, you are incapacitated, and can use your turn only to move up to your movement.</p>
                <p class="indent">While in this state, you have resistance to all damage, and your AC increases by 5.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Accretion">
                <description>You transform into a 2 foot diameter sphere of pure black, your null given form. This null acts as a Sphere of Annihilation, though you can still be harmed. In this state, you are incapacitated, and can use your turn only to move up to your movement. While in this state, you have resistance to all damage, and your AC increases by 5.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Speaker for the Dead" type="Class Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_ACCRETION_SPEAKER_FOR_THE_DEAD">
            <supports>Null Accretion</supports>
            <requirements>[level:null:17]</requirements>
            <prerequisite>17th Level</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 17th Level</p>
                <p class="indent">While you have this accretion active, you fill your null with the power of the grave, granting volatile power over death. You can use your action to target a creature that you can see within 60 feet of you and speak a horrid word. Make a Constitution ability check, contested by a Constitution ability check from the creature that you targeted. The loser of this contest takes 100 necrotic damage, and if this damage reduces it to 0 hit points, it immediately dies.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Accretion" action="Action">
                <description>You can target a creature that you can see within 60 feet of you. Make a Constitution ability check, contested by a Constitution ability check from the creature that you targeted. The loser of this contest takes 100 necrotic damage, and if this damage reduces it to 0 hit points, it immediately dies.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Truth of the Void" type="Class Feature" source="The Null Class" id="ID_EW_TNC_CLASS_FEATURE_NULL_ACCRETION_TRUTH_OF_THE_VOID">
            <supports>Null Accretion</supports>
            <requirements>[level:null:17]</requirements>
            <prerequisite>17th Level</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 17th Level</p>
                <p class="indent">While you have this accretion active, your null fills with knowledge accreted from beyond the world. For the duration of the accretion, you have advantage on attack rolls, ability checks, and saving throws. Additionally, other creatures have disadvantage on attack rolls against you.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Accretion">
                <description>For the duration of the accretion, you have advantage on attack rolls, ability checks, and saving throws. Additionally, other creatures have disadvantage on attack rolls against you.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
</elements>