<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>The Savant Class</name>
        <update version="0.0.4">
            <file name="class-savant.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/classes/class-savant.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="The Savant Class" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_GM_BINDER_SOURCE_THE_SAVANT_CLASS">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation"></set>
            <set name="url">https://www.gmbinder.com/share/-M0ZVK6ndhFyImQPF_aJ</set>
            <set name="image">https://i.pinimg.com/originals/c2/61/57/c261573afe0dca8cfc58747a6917bd9b.jpg</set>
            <set name="author" abbreviation="LL" url="https://www.reddit.com/u/laserllama">u/laserllama</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20200404</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Savant" type="Class" source="The Savant Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_CLASS_SAVANT">
        <description>
            <p>The slender elf cleans his glasses with the corner of his cloak as the dust settles around him. He was the first person to set foot in this ancient temple in hundreds of years. His benefactor had paid him a great deal to find this place, and after months of pouring over forgotten tomes he had finally figured out it’s long lost location. Now he had a choice to make, would he report back to his benefactor so they could strip the temple of it’s valuables? Or would he keep it’s location hidden, and preserve the knowledge found here himself? For to a savant, knowledge is more precious than gold coins.</p>
            <p class="indent">The elderly warrior assessed the state of his men, they were exhausted and almost out of supplies. This was the tenth day of the siege, and the warrior knew at this point no relief was coming. He was too old to be of use in battle, but if his men followed his orders to the letter, and without hesitation, they just might still have a fighting chance. He stood up, and for what may be the last time, drew his sword.</p>
            <p class="indent">A young dwarf bends over his unconscious comrade in the midst of battle, his hands shaking as he examines the unconscious dwarf’s wounds. His clan had spent a great deal of their fortune to send him to the best university gold could buy. All those hours spent in lectures, libraries, and observation; all for this moment. He thought back to what he had learned about field medicine from his professors and began to dress the dwarf’s wounds.</p>
            <h4>GREAT MINDS</h4>
            <p>There are many intelligent people in the world, but few are true savants. Born with with an innate desire to learn all they can, and the potential for a genius level intellect, they spend their lives studying anything that those around them are willing to teach them. Savants are often recognized at an early age, and in their hunger for knowledge, they are drawn to great libraries and universities. They will do anything to access the troves of knowledge that lie in hidden in forbidden places, for savants, no price is too steep to pay for knowledge.</p>
            <p class="indent">Despite their aptitude for learning, most savants seek to better themselves without having to rely on others. Savants reject the patronage of gods and other powerful beings, and in turn they view wizardry as a path for the weak willed. Relying on their great minds alone, they strive for perfection.</p>
            <h4>INTENSE SPECIALIZATION</h4>
            <p>Savants tend to be hyper focused on their chosen area of expertise. They obsess over it, learning all they can about the subject. Once they reach the climax of learning in that specialty and there is nothing anyone else can teach them, they do not move on. Instead they will go to great lengths, risking life and limb, to advance their chosen field of study.</p>
            <p class="indent">Often doing so at great cost to themselves, savants will not stop researching, experimenting, and theorizing until they have made an indelible mark in their academic discipline. A savants ultimate goal in life is to discover some previously unknown truth about the universe.</p>
            <h5>QUICK BUILD</h5>
            <p>You can make a Savant quickly by following these suggestions. First, put your highest ability score in Intelligence, followed by Wisdom . Second, choose either the noble or sage background from the <em>Player’s Handbook</em>.</p>
            <h2>CLASS FEATURES</h2>
            <p>As a savant, you gain the following class features.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">HIT POINTS</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Hit Dice:</strong> 1d8 per savant level</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at 1st Level:</strong> 8 + your Constitution modifier</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at Higher Levels:</strong> 1d8 (or 5) + your Constitution modifier per savant level after 1st</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">PROFICIENCIES</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled mb">
                <li><strong>Armor:</strong> Light Armor</li>
                <li><strong>Weapons:</strong> Simple weapons and hand crossbows</li>
                <li><strong>Tools:</strong> One set of artisan’s tools of your choice</li>
            </ul>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Saving Throws:</strong> Intelligence, Wisdom</li>
                <li><strong>Skills:</strong> Choose three from Arcana, History, Insight, Investigation, Medicine, Nature, Perception, Persuasion, Religion, and Sleight of Hand.</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">EQUIPMENT</h5>
            <p>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>any two simple weapons of your choice</li>
                <li>a light crossbow and 20 bolts</li>
                <li>one set of artisan’s tools of your choice</li>
                <li>leather armor and a scholar’s pack</li>
            </ul>
        <!-- class table here -->
            <h5 class="caption">THE SAVANT</h5>
            <table class="class-features">
                <thead>
                    <tr><td class="col-5">Level</td><td class="col-10">Proficiency Bonus</td><td class="col-10">Intellect Die</td><td class="col-60 left">Features</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td> 1st</td><td>+2</td><td>─</td><td class="left">Astute Defense, Savant’s Analysis</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 2nd</td><td>+2</td><td>1d4</td><td class="left">Intellect Dice</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 3rd</td><td>+2</td><td>1d4</td><td class="left">Academic Discipline</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 4th</td><td>+2</td><td>1d4</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 5th</td><td>+3</td><td>1d6</td><td class="left">─</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 6th</td><td>+3</td><td>1d6</td><td class="left">Mental Refresh</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 7th</td><td>+3</td><td>1d6</td><td class="left">Ever Vigilant</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 8th</td><td>+3</td><td>1d6</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 9th</td><td>+4</td><td>1d6</td><td class="left">Academic Discipline Feature</td></tr>
                <tr><td>10th</td><td>+4</td><td>1d8</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td></tr>
                <tr><td>11th</td><td>+4</td><td>1d8</td><td class="left">Reliable Talent</td></tr>
                <tr><td>12th</td><td>+4</td><td>1d8</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td>+5</td><td>1d8</td><td class="left">Academic Discipline Feature</td></tr>
                <tr><td>14th</td><td>+5</td><td>1d8</td><td class="left">Ascended Mind</td></tr>
                <tr><td>15th</td><td>+5</td><td>1d10</td><td class="left">Master of Mind and Body</td></tr>
                <tr><td>16th</td><td>+5</td><td>1d10</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td></tr>
                <tr><td>17th</td><td>+6</td><td>1d10</td><td class="left">Academic Discipline Feature</td></tr>
                <tr><td>18th</td><td>+6</td><td>1d10</td><td class="left">Elusive</td></tr>
                <tr><td>19th</td><td>+6</td><td>1d10</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td></tr>
                <tr><td>20th</td><td>+6</td><td>1d10</td><td class="left">Undisputed Genius</td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_CLASS_FEATURE_SAVANT_ASTUTE_DEFENSE" />
            <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_CLASS_FEATURE_SAVANT_INTELLECT_DICE" />
            <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_CLASS_FEATURE_SAVANT_ACADEMIC_DISCIPLINE" />
            <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_CLASS_FEATURE_SAVANT_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" />
            <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_CLASS_FEATURE_SAVANT_SAVANTS_ANALYSIS" />
            <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_CLASS_FEATURE_SAVANT_MENTAL_REFRESH" />
            <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_CLASS_FEATURE_SAVANT_EVER_VIGILANT" />
            <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_CLASS_FEATURE_SAVANT_RELIABLE_TALENT" />
            <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_CLASS_FEATURE_SAVANT_ASCENDED_MIND" />
            <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_CLASS_FEATURE_SAVANT_FORCEFUL_WILL" />
            <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_CLASS_FEATURE_SAVANT_ELUSIVE" />
            <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_CLASS_FEATURE_SAVANT_UNDISPUTED_GENIUS" />
            <div class="sidebar">
                <h5>OPTIONAL RULE: MULTICLASSING</h5>
                <p>If your group uses the optional rule on multiclassing in the <em>Player’s Handbook</em>, here’s what you need to know if you choose the savant as one of your classes.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Minimum.</em></strong> As a multiclass character, you must have at least a 13 in both Intelligence and Wisdom to take a level in this class, or to take a level in another class if you are already a savant.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Proficiencies Gained.</em></strong> If savant isn’t your initial class, you gain two skill proficiencies from the savant list when you take your first level in this class.</p>
            </div>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="short">An Intelligence-based class with an innate desire to learn.</set>
            <set name="hd">d8</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" requirements ="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_MULTICLASS_SAVANT" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" requirements ="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_MULTICLASS_SAVANT" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_CROSSBOW_HAND" requirements="!ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_MULTICLASS_SAVANT"/>
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Tool Proficiency, Savant" supports="Artisan Tools" requirements ="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_MULTICLASS_SAVANT" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_INTELLIGENCE" requirements ="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_MULTICLASS_SAVANT" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_WISDOM" requirements ="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_MULTICLASS_SAVANT" />
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency, Savant" supports="Skill,laserllama Savant" number="3" requirements ="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_MULTICLASS_SAVANT" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_CLASS_FEATURE_SAVANT_ASTUTE_DEFENSE" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_CLASS_FEATURE_SAVANT_SAVANTS_ANALYSIS" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_CLASS_FEATURE_SAVANT_INTELLECT_DICE" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_CLASS_FEATURE_SAVANT_ACADEMIC_DISCIPLINE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_CLASS_FEATURE_SAVANT_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" level="4" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_CLASS_FEATURE_SAVANT_MENTAL_REFRESH" level="6" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_CLASS_FEATURE_SAVANT_EVER_VIGILANT" level="7" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_CLASS_FEATURE_SAVANT_RELIABLE_TALENT" level="11" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_CLASS_FEATURE_SAVANT_ASCENDED_MIND" level="14" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_CLASS_FEATURE_SAVANT_FORCEFUL_WILL" level="15" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_CLASS_FEATURE_SAVANT_ELUSIVE" level="18" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_CLASS_FEATURE_SAVANT_UNDISPUTED_GENIUS" level="20" />
        </rules>
        <multiclass id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_MULTICLASS_SAVANT">
            <prerequisite>Intelligence 13, Wisdom 13</prerequisite>
            <requirements>[int:13],[wis:13]</requirements>
            <setters>
                <set name="multiclass proficiencies">If savant isn’t your initial class, you gain two skill proficiencies from the savant list when you take your first level in this class.</set>
            </setters>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS" />
                <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency, Savant" supports="laserllama Savant" number="2" />
            </rules>
        </multiclass>
    </element>
        <element name="Astute Defense" type="Class Feature" source="The Savant Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_CLASS_FEATURE_SAVANT_ASTUTE_DEFENSE">
            <description>
                <p>At 1st level, your observant way of fighting allows you to predict your enemies attacks with lightning fast accuracy. When you are not wearing any armor or using a shield your armor class is equal to 10 + your Intelligence modifier + your Wisdom modifier.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You may use your Intelligence modifier in place of Strength or Dexterity for attack rolls as long as you are proficient with the weapon.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="ac:astute defense savant:base" value="10" />
                <stat name="ac:astute defense savant:intelligence" value="intelligence:modifier" />
                <stat name="ac:astute defense savant:wisdom" value="wisdom:modifier" />
                <stat name="ac:astute defense savant" value="ac:astute defense savant:base" />
                <stat name="ac:astute defense savant" value="ac:astute defense savant:intelligence" />
                <stat name="ac:astute defense savant" value="ac:astute defense savant:wisdom" />
                <stat name="ac:calculation" value="ac:astute defense savant" bonus="calculation" equipped="[armor:none],[shield:none]" alt="Astute Defense (Savant)" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Savant’s Analysis" type="Class Feature" source="The Savant Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_CLASS_FEATURE_SAVANT_SAVANTS_ANALYSIS">
            <description>
                <p>You can use your observational skills to learn information about your enemeies. Starting at 1st level, you can use a bonus action on your turn to make an Intelligence check to analyze a creature you can see. Choose one fact would like to learn about the enemy creature; one of it’s ability score, it’s armor class, an immunity, resistance, vulnerability, language, sense, or skill proficiency.</p>
                <p class="indent">Make an Intelligence check (using an applicable skill if deemed appropriate by the Dungeon Master), the DC is equal to 5 + the creature’s Challenge Rating. On a success you learn the information about the creature.</p>
                <p class="indent">You may use this feature a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier. You regain all uses when you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="{{intelligence:modifier}}/Short Rest" action="Bonus Action">
                <description>You can make an Intelligence check to analyze a creature you can see. You learn one fact: an ability score, immunity, resistance, vulnerability, language, sense, skill, or armor class. Make an Intelligence check (use an applicable skill if appropriate), the DC is equal to 5 + the creature’s Challenge Rating. On a success you surmise the information about the creature.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Intellect Dice" type="Class Feature" source="The Savant Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_CLASS_FEATURE_SAVANT_INTELLECT_DICE">
            <description>
                <p>At 2nd level, you are able use your observational skills to aid your allies in combat. You gain a number of Intellect Dice equal to your Intelligence modifier + your Wisdom modifier. Your Savant level determines the size of the dice, as shown in the Intellect Dice column of the Savant Table. You regain all spent Intellect Dice when you complete a short or long rest.</p>
                <p class="indent">Some Savant abilities allow you to expend more than one Intellect Die. When you do, the maximum amount you can expend at one time is equal to your Wisdom modifier + your Charisma modifier, and represents the amount of mental force you can exert at one time.</p>
                <p class="indent">If one of your Savant abilities requires a creature to make a saving throw, you the following Intellect Save DC formula.</p>
                <center>
                    <p><strong>Intellect Save DC</strong> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier</p>
                </center>
                <h5>INTELLECT ABILITIES</h5>
                <p>Starting at 2nd level, you gain the following abilities:</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Information Recall.</em></strong> When you make an Intelligence based skill check, before you roll, you can choose expend Intellect Dice to add to the skill check. Roll the Intellect Dice and add them to the result of the skill check.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Iron Mind.</em></strong> When you are forced to make an Intelligence saving throw, you can use your reaction to expend Intellect Dice to add to the saving throw. You must choose how many you spend before you roll. Roll the Intellect Dice and add them to the result of the skill check.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Discerning Strike.</em></strong> As a bonus action on your turn you can spend one or more Intellect Dice to mark an enemy creature, highlighting it’s weak points for you and your allies. The next weapon attack that hits the marked creature deals additional damage equal to the Intellect Dice you spent. Roll the Intellect Dice and add them to the result of the damage roll.</p>
                <p class="indent">If you take damage before the creature you marked is hit with a weapon attack, you must make a Constitution saving throw, to maintain your focus (as you would to concentrate on a spell). On a failure, you can no longer focus on the creatures weak points, your ability fails, and any Intellect Dice you spent are wasted.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="{{intellect-dice:uses}} Dice/Short Rest">
                <description>Your Intellect Die is a d{{intellect-dice:die-type}} and your Intellect Save DC is {{intellect-dice:save-dc}}.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="intellect-dice:die-type" value="4" bonus="base" level="2" />
                <stat name="intellect-dice:die-type" value="6" bonus="base" level="5" />
                <stat name="intellect-dice:die-type" value="8" bonus="base" level="10" />
                <stat name="intellect-dice:die-type" value="10" bonus="base" level="15" />
                <stat name="intellect-dice:uses" value="intelligence:modifier" />
                <stat name="intellect-dice:uses" value="wisdom:modifier" />
                <stat name="intellect-dice:save-dc" value="8" />
                <stat name="intellect-dice:save-dc" value="intelligence:modifier" />
                <stat name="intellect-dice:save-dc" value="proficiency" />
                <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_CLASS_FEATURE_INTELLECT_DICE_INFORMATION_RECALL" />
                <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_CLASS_FEATURE_INTELLECT_DICE_IRON_MIND" />
                <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_CLASS_FEATURE_INTELLECT_DICE_DISCERNING_STRIKE" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Information Recall" type="Class Feature" source="The Savant Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_CLASS_FEATURE_INTELLECT_DICE_INFORMATION_RECALL">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>When you make an Intelligence based skill check, before you roll, you can choose expend Intellect Dice to add to the skill check. Roll the Intellect Dice and add them to the result of the skill check.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Intellect Dice">
                    <description>When you make an Intelligence based skill check, before you roll, you can choose expend Intellect Dice to add to the skill check. Roll the Intellect Dice and add them to the result of the skill check.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Iron Mind" type="Class Feature" source="The Savant Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_CLASS_FEATURE_INTELLECT_DICE_IRON_MIND">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>When you are forced to make an Intelligence saving throw, you can use your reaction to expend Intellect Dice to add to the saving throw. You must choose how many you spend before you roll. Roll the Intellect Dice and add them to the result of the skill check.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet action="Reaction" usage="Intellect Dice">
                    <description>When you are forced to make an Intelligence saving throw, you can expend Intellect Dice to add to the saving throw. You must choose how many you spend before you roll. Roll the Intellect Dice and add them to the result of the skill check.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Discerning Strike" type="Class Feature" source="The Savant Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_CLASS_FEATURE_INTELLECT_DICE_DISCERNING_STRIKE">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>As a bonus action on your turn you can spend one or more Intellect Dice to mark an enemy creature, highlighting it’s weak points for you and your allies. The next weapon attack that hits the marked creature deals additional damage equal to the Intellect Dice you spent. Roll the Intellect Dice and add them to the result of the damage roll.</p>
                    <p class="indent">If you take damage before the creature you marked is hit with a weapon attack, you must make a Constitution saving throw, to maintain your focus (as you would to concentrate on a spell). On a failure, you can no longer focus on the creatures weak points, your ability fails, and any Intellect Dice you spent are wasted.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="Intellect Dice">
                    <description>You can spend one or more Intellect Dice to mark an enemy creature, highlighting it’s weak points for you and your allies. The next weapon attack that hits the marked creature deals additional damage equal to the Intellect Dice you spent. Roll the Intellect Dice and add them to the result of the damage roll. If you take damage before the creature you marked is hit with a weapon attack, you must make a Constitution saving throw, to maintain your focus (as you would to concentrate on a spell). On a failure, you can no longer focus on the creatures weak points, your ability fails, and any Intellect Dice you spent are wasted.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
        <element name="Academic Discipline" type="Class Feature" source="The Savant Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_CLASS_FEATURE_SAVANT_ACADEMIC_DISCIPLINE">
            <description>
                <p>At 3rd level, choose your academic discipline. This is your chosen field of study, and you have devoted your life to learning all there is to know about this field. Choose one of the following Academic Disciplines; Naturalist, Philosopher, Physician, or Tactician.</p>
                <p class="indent">Your Academic Discipline grants you features at 3rd level and then again at 9th, 13th, and 17th level, and they are detailed at the end of this class description.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Archetype" name="Academic Discipline" supports="Savant Academic Discipline" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Ability Score Improvement" type="Class Feature" source="The Savant Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_CLASS_FEATURE_SAVANT_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 10th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Savant 4)" supports="Improvement Option,Savant,4" level="4" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Savant 8)" supports="Improvement Option,Savant,8" level="8" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Savant 10)" supports="Improvement Option,Savant,10" level="10" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Savant 12)" supports="Improvement Option,Savant,12" level="12" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Savant 16)" supports="Improvement Option,Savant,16" level="16" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Savant 19)" supports="Improvement Option,Savant,19" level="19" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Mental Refresh" type="Class Feature" source="The Savant Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_CLASS_FEATURE_SAVANT_MENTAL_REFRESH">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 6th level, you’ve learned special techniques that refocus your mind and clear away fatigue and distracting thoughts. As an action on your turn, you can regain a number of spent Intellect Dice equal to your Wisdom modifier.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this ability you must complete a long rest before you can use it again.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You can regain {{wisdom:modifier}} Intellect Dice.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Ever Vigilant" type="Class Feature" source="The Savant Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_CLASS_FEATURE_SAVANT_EVER_VIGILANT">
            <description>
                <p>At 7th level, your lightning fast ability to process the world around you makes it impossible to catch you off guard. You have advantage on initiative rolls, and you are immune to the surprised condition while you are conscious.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You have advantage on initiative rolls, and you are immune to the surprised condition while you are conscious.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Reliable Talent" type="Class Feature" source="The Savant Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_CLASS_FEATURE_SAVANT_RELIABLE_TALENT">
            <description>
                <p>By 11th level, your knowledge of your areas of expertise is nearly perfect. Whenever you make an ability check that lets you add your Proficiency Bonus, you can treat a d20 roll of 9 or lower as a 10.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Whenever you make an ability check that lets you add your Proficiency Bonus, you can treat a d20 roll of 9 or lower as a 10.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Ascended Mind" type="Class Feature" source="The Savant Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_CLASS_FEATURE_SAVANT_ASCENDED_MIND">
            <description>
                <p>At 14th level, your mastery over your own mind grants you supernatural perceptive abilities. As an action, spend an Intellect Dice, for each Die you expend you gain one of the following abilities for the next minute:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>You gain Truesight out to 30 ft.</li>
                    <li>You notice secret doors hidden by magic within 30 ft.</li>
                    <li>You can see into the Ethereal Plane out to 30ft.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="Intellect Dice">
                <description>You gain the following benefits for one minute: your passive perception is at least 20; you gain Truesight to 30 feet; you notice secret doors hidden by magic within 30 feet; and you can see into the Ethereal Plane out to 30 feet.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Master of Mind and Body" type="Class Feature" source="The Savant Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_CLASS_FEATURE_SAVANT_FORCEFUL_WILL">
            <description>
                <p>At 15th level, your mastery over your mind allows you to command your body to react in ways beyond your normal capabilities. Your <em>Iron Mind</em> ability now applies to Strength and Dexterity saving throws.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Your Iron Mind ability now applies to Strength and Dexterity saving throws.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Elusive" type="Class Feature" source="The Savant Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_CLASS_FEATURE_SAVANT_ELUSIVE">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 18th level, your advanced mental acuity allows you predict enemy attacks before they happen. It is impossible for attack rolls to have advantage against you while you are conscious.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>It is impossible for attack rolls to have advantage against you while you are conscious.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Undisputed Genius" type="Class Feature" source="The Savant Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_CLASS_FEATURE_SAVANT_UNDISPUTED_GENIUS">
            <description>
                <p>At 20th level, your intellect grows far beyond mortal limits, increasing to legendary levels. Your Intelligence and Wisdom scores each increase by 4. Your maximum for those scores is now 24.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="intelligence" value="4" />
                <stat name="intelligence:max" value="4" />
                <stat name="wisdom" value="4" />
                <stat name="wisdom:max" value="4" />
            </rules>
        </element>

  <!-- Archetypes -->
    <element name="Naturalist" type="Archetype" source="The Savant Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_NATURALIST">
        <supports>Savant Academic Discipline</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The Naturalist’s classroom begins at the very edges of civilization. They study the environments, flora, and fauna that live beyond the influence of civilized peoples. They are experts at anticipating weather patterns, predicting the movements of herds of wild animals, and knowing the difference between an edible plant and a toxic one.</p>
            <p class="indent">Naturalists are highly sought after to guides for adventuring parties. They can safely navigate dangerous environments; arid deserts, jagged mountain ranges, and treacherous jungles, the naturalist is at home in all.</p>
            <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NATURALIST_STUDENT_OF_NATURE" />
            <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NATURALIST_OUTDOORSMAN" />
            <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NATURALIST_CONSERVATIONIST" />
            <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NATURALIST_WILD_INSIGHTS" />
            <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NATURALIST_MASTER_NATURALIST" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NATURALIST_STUDENT_OF_NATURE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NATURALIST_OUTDOORSMAN" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NATURALIST_CONSERVATIONIST" level="9" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NATURALIST_WILD_INSIGHTS" level="13" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NATURALIST_MASTER_NATURALIST" level="17" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Student of Nature" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Savant Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NATURALIST_STUDENT_OF_NATURE">
            <description>
                <p>At 3rd level your choice to dedicate yourself to the study of nature and all the plants and animals of the natural world grants you a unique insight into the ways of the wild. When you choose this Academic Discipline you gain proficiency in the nature skill. If you already have proficiency in nature you gain expertise, which means you add double your proficiency bonus to any nature checks you make.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, you ignore difficult terrain caused by natural features, and you cannot become lost while in a natural environment as long as you can see the sky.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You ignore difficult terrain caused by natural features, and you cannot become lost while in a natural environment as long as you can see the sky</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_OR_DOUBLE_NATURE" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Outdoorsman" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Savant Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NATURALIST_OUTDOORSMAN">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 3rd level, your specialization as a Naturalist makes you an invaluable guide in the wilds. As an action on your turn you may expend an Intellect Die to educate a friendly creature and grant them one of the following effects for ten minutes:</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Animal Tamer.</em></strong> The creature gains proficiency in the animal handling skill and has advantages on rolls to maintain control of their mount.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Diver.</em></strong> The creatures gains a swim speed equal to their movement speed and they can hold their breath a number of minutes equal to three times their Constitution score.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Enhanced Movement.</em></strong> The creature’s movement speed increases by 10 ft., and it only costs them 5 ft. of movement to get up from the prone condition.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Mountaineer.</em></strong> The creature gains a climb speed equal to their movement speed, and they reduce any falling damage they take by an amount equal to your savant level.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Natural Camouflage.</em></strong> The creature gains proficiency in the stealth skill and has advantage on rolls to hide in natural environments.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Tracker.</em></strong> The creature gains proficiency in the survival skill, and has advantage on rolls to track a creature they have seen in the past hour.</p>
                <p class="indent">A creature can only be under one of these effects at a time. If you grant them the benefits of a new effect, the previous one immediately ends. As you gain savant levels, this ability to help others survive in the wild becomes more potent. At 9th level, these effects last for 1 hour, and at 13th level these effects last until the end of the creature’s next long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="Intellect Dice">
                <description>You may educate a friendly creature and grant them one of the following effects for ten minutes: Animal Tamer, Diver, Enhanced Movement, Mountaineer, Natural Camouflage, or Tracker. A creature can only be under one of these effects at a time.</description>
                <description level="9">You may educate a friendly creature and grant them one of the following effects for ten minutes: Animal Tamer, Diver, Enhanced Movement, Mountaineer, Natural Camouflage, or Tracker. A creature can only be under one of these effects at a time.</description>
                <description level="13">You may educate a friendly creature and grant them one of the following effects until the end of the creature’s next long rest: Animal Tamer, Diver, Enhanced Movement, Mountaineer, Natural Camouflage, or Tracker. A creature can only be under one of these effects at a time.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Conservationist" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Savant Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NATURALIST_CONSERVATIONIST">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 9th level, your time spent learning about the natural flora and fauna has enamored them to you. When a beast, monstrosity, or plant attacks you, as a reaction you may expend one Intellect Die and force the creature to make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, the creature must choose a new target or lose the attack.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Reaction" usage="Intellect Die">
                <description>When a beast, monstrosity, or plant attacks you, you can force the creature to make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, the creature must choose a new target or lose the attack.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Wild Insights" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Savant Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NATURALIST_WILD_INSIGHTS">
            <description>
                <p>At 13th level, you’ve come to understand the animals of the natural world in a way that few civilized peoples do. As an action on your turn you can touch a beast and attempt to charm it as if casting the <em>dominate beast</em> spell.</p>
                <p class="indent">You may use this feature a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier. You regain all uses when you finish a short or long rest.</p>
                <div class="reference">
                    <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_DOMINATE_BEAST" />
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="{{intelligence:modifier}}/Short Rest">
                <description>You can touch a beast and attempt to charm it as if casting the dominate beast spell.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DOMINATE_BEAST" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Master Naturalist" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Savant Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NATURALIST_MASTER_NATURALIST">
            <description>
                <p>By 17th level, you have become one of the leading authorities on the natural world. At the end of a short or long rest, you can attune yourself to one of the following natural environments: arctic, coast, desert, forest, grassland, jungle, mountain, swamp, or underdark. While in that environment you gain the following benefits:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>You gain the benefits of all of your Outdoorsman effects.</li>
                    <li>You add your Intelligence modifier to your initiative rolls.</li>
                    <li>You have advantage on Intelligence and Wisdom checks related to the environment you are attuned to.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>At the end of a short or long rest, you can attune yourself to one of the following natural environments: arctic, coast, desert, forest, grassland, jungle, mountain, swamp, or underdark. While in that environment you gain the following benefits: you gain the benefits of all of your Outdoorsman effects; you add {{intelligence:modifier}} to your initiative rolls; you have advantage on Intelligence and Wisdom checks related to the environment you are attuned to.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>


    <element name="Philosopher" type="Archetype" source="The Savant Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_PHILOSOPHER">
        <supports>Savant Academic Discipline</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Philosophy is the purest of the Academic Disciplines that a savant can pursue. They spend their lives pondering the deep questions of existence. What is the purpose of life? Why did the gods create the multiverse? What is the nature of the material plane and the planes that surround it?</p>
            <p class="indent">Through their study of mathematics, physics, natural sciences, and public speaking, they seek to perfect their knowledge of reality and their place in it. Philosophers make invaluable advisors and thinkers when they are on your side. They range from the humble village elders to the advisors of great kings.</p>
            <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHILOSOPHER_STUDENT_OF_THOUGHT" />
            <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHILOSOPHER_CONFOUNDING_THEOREM" />
            <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHILOSOPHER_FORCEFUL_PERSONALITY" />
            <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHILOSOPHER_SUPREME_UNDERSTANDING" />
            <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHILOSOPHER_MASTER_PHILOSOPHER" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHILOSOPHER_STUDENT_OF_THOUGHT" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHILOSOPHER_CONFOUNDING_THEOREM" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHILOSOPHER_FORCEFUL_PERSONALITY" level="9" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHILOSOPHER_SUPREME_UNDERSTANDING" level="13" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHILOSOPHER_MASTER_PHILOSOPHER" level="17" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Student of Thought" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Savant Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHILOSOPHER_STUDENT_OF_THOUGHT">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 3rd level, your time spent studying the fundamental nature of knowledge has provided you with great insights into the world. When you choose this Academic Discipline you gain proficiency in both the Arcana and Religion skills. If you already have proficiency in one of those skills you gain expertise, which means you add double your proficiency bonus to any check you make with that skill.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, your time studying the nature of existence allows you to gain additional types of information with your <em>Savant’s Analysis</em> feature. You can now use your Savant’s Analysis to attempt to learn the target’s alignment, creature type, plane of origin, or spellcasting ability (if it has one).</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can now use your Savant’s Analysis to attempt to learn the target’s alignment, creature type, plane of origin, or spellcasting ability (if it has one).</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_OR_DOUBLE_ARCANA" />
                <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_OR_DOUBLE_RELIGION" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Confounding Theorem" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Savant Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHILOSOPHER_CONFOUNDING_THEOREM">
            <description>
                <p>At 3rd level, your mastery over the spoken word allows you to twist your speech in such a way that sows confusion in the minds of your enemies. As an action on your turn, expend an Intellect Die and force a creature within 30 ft., that can hear to you, to make an Intelligence saving throw against your Intellect save DC.</p>
                <p class="indent">On a failed save, they take psychic damage equal to your Intellect Die roll, and the next attack against that creature before the beginning of your next turn has advantage.</p>
                <p class="indent">As a bonus action when you use this ability, you can expend a number of additional Intellect Dice, up to your Intelligence modifier, to target more creatures with your <em>Confounding Theorem</em>. For each additional Intellect Die you expend, you can target one additional creature as long as they are within 30 ft., and can hear you.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="Intellect Dice">
                <description>As an action on your turn, expend an Intellect Die and force a creature within 30 ft., that can hear to you, to make an Intelligence saving throw against your Intellect save DC. On a failed save, they take psychic damage equal to your Intellect Die roll, and the next attack against that creature before the beginning of your next turn has advantage. As a bonus action when you use this ability, you can expend up to {{intelligence:modifier}} additional Intellect Dice to target more creatures with your Confounding Theorem. For each additional Intellect Die you expend, you can target one additional creature as long as they are within 30 ft., and can hear you.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Forceful Personality" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Savant Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHILOSOPHER_FORCEFUL_PERSONALITY">
            <description>
                <p>You have spent much time contemplating your existence and your place in the universe. Your confidence in your purpose is unwavering. Starting at 9th level you gain proficiency in Charisma saving throws, and you are always under the effects of the <em>protection from evil and good</em> spell while you are conscious.</p>
                <div class="reference">
                    <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_PROTECTION_FROM_EVIL_AND_GOOD" />
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You are always under the effects of the protection from evil and good spell while you are conscious.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CHARISMA" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PROTECTION_FROM_EVIL_AND_GOOD" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Supreme Understanding" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Savant Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHILOSOPHER_SUPREME_UNDERSTANDING">
            <description>
                <p>At 13th level, your understanding of the nature of reality extends to the creatures around you. At the end of a long rest, you can designate a number of friendly creatures equal to your Wisdom modifier. They gain proficiency in Wisdom saving throws until the end of their next long rest.</p>
                <p class="indent">If the target of this ability already has proficiency in Wisdom saving throws, they gain proficiency in your choice of Intelligence or Charisma saving throws instead.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, you can use your <em>Iron Mind</em> feature when you are forced to make a Wisdom or Charisma saving throw. You must follow all other restrictions of the feature.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>At the end of a long rest, you can designate up to {{wisdom:modifier}} friendly creatures. They gain proficiency in Wisdom saving throws until the end of their next long rest. If the target of this ability already has proficiency in Wisdom saving throws, they gain proficiency in your choice of Intelligence or Charisma saving throws instead. Additionally, you can use your Iron Mind feature when you are forced to make a Wisdom or Charisma saving throw. You must follow all other restrictions of the feature.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Master Philosopher" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Savant Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHILOSOPHER_MASTER_PHILOSOPHER">
            <description>
                <p>At 17th level, your mastery over the nature of reality ascends beyond the mundane and into the language of the multiverse itself. When you finish a long rest, you focus your mind and learn one Power Word. As an action on your turn, you speak the Power Word aloud, and the spell of the same name takes effect as if cast by you.</p>
                <p class="indent">Choose one of the following spells; <em>power word heal</em>, <em>power word kill</em>, power word pain, or <em>power word stun</em>. You can use this ability once per long rest at no cost. Every additional time you use it after the first, you gain one level of exhaustion.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you finish a long rest, you focus your mind and learn one Power Word. As an action on your turn, you speak the Power Word aloud, and the spell of the same name takes effect as if cast by you. Choose one of the following spells; power word heal, power word kill, power word pain, or power word stun. You can use this ability once per long rest at no cost. Every additional time you use it after the first, you gain one level of exhaustion.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_POWER_WORD_HEAL" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_POWER_WORD_KILL" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_POWER_WORD_STUN" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_POWER_WORD_PAIN" />
            </rules>
        </element>


    <element name="Physician" type="Archetype" source="The Savant Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_PHYSICIAN">
        <supports>Savant Academic Discipline</supports>
        <description>
            <p>For all of history, there have been those who study how living things work. Clerics and priests of gods of life and healing, necromancers and liches who seek to raise the dead, and deadly assassins and warriors who learn the most vulnerable points to strike. Unlike all of these, the Physicians of the world use knowledge and mundane science to heal wounds, cure disease, and improve the quality of life for those that cannot afford the luxury of magical healing.</p>
            <p class="indent">Physicians are specialists who have focused their research on the body. Primarily, how it functions and how to repair it when damaged. Physicians do not rely on divine or arcane magic to heal, but through a combination of knowledge, focus, and precision they dress wounds, perform surgeries, and save lives.</p>
            <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHYSICIAN_STUDENT_OF_MEDICINE" />
            <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHYSICIAN_COMBAT_MEDIC" />
            <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHYSICIAN_MEDICAL_NEUTRALITY" />
            <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHYSICIAN_RESUSCITATE" />
            <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHYSICIAN_MASTER_PHYSICIAN" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHYSICIAN_STUDENT_OF_MEDICINE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHYSICIAN_COMBAT_MEDIC" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHYSICIAN_MEDICAL_NEUTRALITY" level="9" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHYSICIAN_RESUSCITATE" level="13" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHYSICIAN_MASTER_PHYSICIAN" level="17" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Student of Medicine" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Savant Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHYSICIAN_STUDENT_OF_MEDICINE">
            <description>
                <p>When you choose this Academic Discipline at 3rd level you gain proficiency with the herbalism kit and in the Medicine skill. If you already have either of these proficiencies you gain expertise, which means you add double your proficiency bonus to any checks you make. Your specialized training allows you to utilize mundane healing equipment to it’s fullest potential. When you stabilize a creature with a healer’s kit, your knowledge allows you to stimulate additional healing. Upon use, the creature regains hit points equal to your Intelligence modifier.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, your time studying anatomy allows you to gain additional types of information with your Savant’s Analysis feature. You can use your Savant’s Analysis to make a Wisdom (Medicine) check and attempt to learn how many hit points the creature currently has, or the creature’s hit point maximum.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you stabilize a creature with a healer’s kit, your knowledge allows you to stimulate additional healing. Upon use, the creature regains {{intelligence:modifier}} hit points. Additionally, you can use your Savant’s Analysis to make a Medicine check and attempt to learn how many hit points the creature currently has, or the creature’s hit point maximum.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_OR_DOUBLE_MEDICINE" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHYSICIAN_STUDENT_OF_MEDICINE_HERBALISM_KIT_PROFICIENCY" requirements="!ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_HERBALISM_KIT" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHYSICIAN_STUDENT_OF_MEDICINE_HERBALISM_KIT_EXPERTISE" requirements="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_HERBALISM_KIT,!ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHYSICIAN_STUDENT_OF_MEDICINE_HERBALISM_KIT_PROFICIENCY" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Student of Medicine: Herbalism Kit Proficiency" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Savant Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHYSICIAN_STUDENT_OF_MEDICINE_HERBALISM_KIT_PROFICIENCY">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description />
                <sheet display="false" />
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_HERBALISM_KIT" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Student of Medicine: Herbalism Kit Expertise" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Savant Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHYSICIAN_STUDENT_OF_MEDICINE_HERBALISM_KIT_EXPERTISE">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description />
                <sheet alt="Herbalism Kit Expertise">
                    <description>You double your proficiency when making a check using an Herbalism kit.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="herbalism kit:proficiency" bonus="double" />
                </rules>
            </element>
        <element name="Combat Medic" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Savant Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHYSICIAN_COMBAT_MEDIC">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 3rd level you gain the following abilities. As an action on your turn you can use one of the following abilities by touching a creature:</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Adrenaline Boost.</em></strong> Choose how many Intellect Dice you wish to spend. The creature can use it’s reaction to make a saving throw to attempt to end one condition currently affecting it, adding your Intellect Dice to their saving throw.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Dress Wounds.</em></strong> Choose how many Intellect Dice you wish to spend. Roll the dice, and the creature immediately regains hit points equal to the roll + your Intelligence modifier.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Healing Surge.</em></strong> You stimulate natural healing in a creature. As a free action, the creature can expend one of their hit die to regain hit points equal to the roll + their Constitution modifier + your Intelligence modifier.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHYSICIAN_ADRENALINE_BOOST" level="3" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHYSICIAN_DRESS_WOUNDS" level="3" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHYSICIAN_HEALING_SURGE" level="3" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Adrenaline Boost" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Savant Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHYSICIAN_ADRENALINE_BOOST">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>Choose how many Intellect Dice you wish to spend. The creature can use it’s reaction to make a saving throw to attempt to end one condition currently affecting it, adding your Intellect Dice to their saving throw.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Intellect Dice">
                    <description>Choose how many Intellect Dice you wish to spend. The creature can use it’s reaction to make a saving throw to attempt to end one condition currently affecting it, adding your Intellect Dice to their saving throw.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Dress Wounds" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Savant Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHYSICIAN_DRESS_WOUNDS">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>Choose how many Intellect Dice you wish to spend. Roll the dice, and the creature immediately regains hit points equal to the roll + your Intelligence modifier.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Intellect Dice">
                    <description>Choose how many Intellect Dice you wish to spend. Roll the dice, and the creature immediately regains hit points equal to the roll + {{intelligence:modifier}}.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Healing Surge" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Savant Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHYSICIAN_HEALING_SURGE">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>You stimulate natural healing in a creature. As a free action, the creature can expend one of their hit die to regain hit points equal to the roll + their Constitution modifier + your Intelligence modifier.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Intellect Dice">
                    <description>You stimulate natural healing in a creature. As a free action, the creature can expend one of their hit die to regain hit points equal to the roll + their Constitution modifier + {{intelligence:modifier}}.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
        <element name="Medical Neutrality" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Savant Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHYSICIAN_MEDICAL_NEUTRALITY">
            <description>
                <p>At 9th level your focus on keeping your allies in top condition allows you to move about the battlefield unscathed. If you use your action to use a healer’s kit, herbalism kit, or any of the actions you gained from your Combat Medic ability, you are under the effects of the Dodge action until the beginning of your next turn, and your movement doesn’t provoke opportunity attacks.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>If you use your action to use a healer’s kit, herbalism kit, or any of the actions you gained from your Combat Medic ability, you are under the effects of the Dodge action until the beginning of your next turn, and your movement doesn’t provoke opportunity attacks.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Resuscitate" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Savant Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHYSICIAN_RESUSCITATE">
            <description>
                <p>At 13th level your knowledge has advanced to the point that you can stave off death itself, if only for a time. As an action you can touch a creature that has died within the last minute and attempt to resuscitate them as if casting the <em>revivify</em> spell.</p>
                <p class="indent">You may use this feature a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier. You regain all uses when you finish a short or long rest.</p>
                <div class="reference">
                    <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_REVIVIFY" />
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="{{intelligence:modifier}}/Short Rest">
                <description>You can touch a creature that has died within the last minute and attempt to resuscitate them as if casting the revivify spell.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_REVIVIFY" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Master Physician" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Savant Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHYSICIAN_MASTER_PHYSICIAN">
            <description>
                <p>By 17th level your knowledge of medicine is peerless. When one of your abilities heals a friendly creature or grants them temporary hit points, they gain additional hit points equal to your savant level.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, any hit dice expended during a short rest with you are treated as their maximum roll.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When one of your abilities heals a friendly creature or grants them temporary hit points, they gain {{level:savant}} additional hit points. Additionally, any hit dice expended during a short rest with you are treated as their maximum roll.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>


    <element name="Tactician" type="Archetype" source="The Savant Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_TACTICIAN">
        <supports>Savant Academic Discipline</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Every successful king, conquerer, or rebellion has a master strategist that is directly responsible for their success in battle. Tacticians are always thinking one step ahead of their enemies, and have a plan for every eventuality. They focus on the big picture, ensuring that they not only win each battle, but the war itself.</p>
            <p class="indent">You have spent your time studying the art of war and long forgotten histories of conquest and glory. You know the strategies that lead to glory, and those that end in ruin. Alone you are no threat, but with powerful allies to command, you are a force to be reckoned with.</p>
            <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_STUDENT_OF_WAR" />
            <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_STRATEGIC_COMMAND" />
            <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_UNWAVERING_RESOLVE" />
            <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_DEFENSIVE_COMMAND" />
            <div element="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_MASTER_TACTICIAN" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_STUDENT_OF_WAR" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_STRATEGIC_COMMAND" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_UNWAVERING_RESOLVE" level="9" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_DEFENSIVE_COMMAND" level="13" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_MASTER_TACTICIAN" level="17" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Student of War" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Savant Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_STUDENT_OF_WAR">
            <description>
                <p>When you dedicate yourself to this Academic Discipline you gain the skills necessary to lead others on the battlefield. Starting at 3rd level your time studying the histories of kingdoms and wars long forgotten grants you proficiency in the history skill. If you already have proficiency in history you gain expertise, which means you add double your proficiency bonus to any history checks you make.</p>
                <p class="indent">Unlike other savants, you have spent some of your time preparing to directly engage in battle. You gain proficiency in medium armor and all martial weapons that lack the heavy property.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, when you deal damage to an enemy creature with a melee attack, you can use your <em>Savant’s Analysis</em> ability as a free action, targeting the creature you damaged.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Reaction">
                <description>When you deal damage to an enemy creature with a melee attack, you can use your Savant’s Analysis ability as a free action, targeting the creature you damaged.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_OR_DOUBLE_HISTORY" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_MEDIUM_ARMOR" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_BATTLEAXE" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_FLAIL" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_LONGSWORD" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_MORNINGSTAR" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_RAPIER" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SCIMITAR" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SHORTSWORD" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_TRIDENT" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_WAR_PICK" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_WARHAMMER" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_WHIP" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_BLOWGUN" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_LONGBOW" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_NET" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Strategic Command" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Savant Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_STRATEGIC_COMMAND">
            <description>
                <p>At 3rd level, allied creatures have come to respect you enough to listen to your commands on the battlefield. As an action on your turn, you can expend an Intellect Die to issue a command to a friendly creature. They must be within 30 ft. and be able to see or hear you. The next time the friendly creature takes the attack action they make an additional attack. The additional attack must be made before the beginning of your next turn.</p>
                <p class="indent">Starting at 9th level, as an action, you may to expend up to two Intellect Dice to issue two separate commands, at 13th level you can expend three Intellect Dice to issue three commands, and finally at 17th level, you can expend four Intellect Dice at once to issue four commands. You cannot target the same creature with more then one command.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="Intellect Dice">
                <description>You can expend an Intellect Dice to issue a command to a friendly creature. They must be within 30 ft. and be able to see or hear you. The next time the friendly creature takes the attack action they make an additional attack. The additional attack must be made before the beginning of your next turn.</description>
                <description level="9" usage="Inellect Dice">You can up to two Intellect Dice to issue two commands to two friendly creatures. They must be within 30 ft. and be able to see or hear you. The next time the friendly creature takes the attack action they make an additional attack. The additional attack must be made before the beginning of your next turn.</description>
                <description level="13" usage="Inellect Dice">You can up to three Intellect Dice to issue three commands to three friendly creatures. They must be within 30 ft. and be able to see or hear you. The next time the friendly creature takes the attack action they make an additional attack. The additional attack must be made before the beginning of your next turn.</description>
                <description level="17" usage="Inellect Dice">You can up to four Intellect Dice to issue four commands to four friendly creatures. They must be within 30 ft. and be able to see or hear you. The next time the friendly creature takes the attack action they make an additional attack. The additional attack must be made before the beginning of your next turn.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Unwavering Resolve" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Savant Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_UNWAVERING_RESOLVE">
            <description>
                <p>At 9th level, your position as a leader does not afford you the comfort of succumbing to your base instincts. You are immune to the charmed and frightened conditions, and any friendly creatures within 15 ft. of you have advantage on saving throws against being charmed or frightened.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You are immune to the charmed and frightened conditions, and any friendly creatures within 15 ft. of you have advantage on saving throws against the charmed and frightened conditions.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Defensive Command" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Savant Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_DEFENSIVE_COMMAND">
            <description>
                <p>At 13th level, when an allied creature within 15 ft. of you is targeted with an weapon attack, spell attack, or forced to make a Dexterity saving throw, you can use your reaction to issue a defensive command. Any friendly creature within 15 ft., that can see or hear you gains a bonus to their armor class equal to your Intelligence modifier until the beginning of your next turn.</p>
                <p class="indent">You may use this feature a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier. You regain all uses when you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Reaction" usage="{{intelligence:modifier}}/Short Rest">
                <description>When an allied creature within 15 ft. of you is targeted with an weapon attack, spell attack, or forced to make a Dexterity saving throw, you can use your reaction to issue a defensive command. Any conscious friendly creature within 15 ft., that can see or hear you gains a +{{intelligence:modifier}} bonus to their armor class until the beginning of your next turn.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Master Tactician" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Savant Class" id="ID_LASERLLAMA_SAVANT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TACTICIAN_MASTER_TACTICIAN">
            <description>
                <p>At 17th level your tactical mind ranks among the greatest commanders of history, and your ability to spot weakness in your foes is unmatched. When you target an enemy creature with your <em>Discerning Strike</em> ability, the first attack that targets that creature before the beginning of your next turn has advantage.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, your commands bolster your allies resolve. Any friendly creature that is targeted by either your Strategic or Defensive Commands immediately gains temporary hit points equal to your savant level + your Charisma modifier.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you target an enemy creature with your Discerning Strike ability, the first attack that targets that creature before the beginning of your next turn has advantage. Additionally, any friendly creature that is targeted by either your Strategic or Defensive Commands immediately gains {{master-tactician:temp-hp}} temporary hit points.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="master-tactician:temp-hp" value="level:savant" />
                <stat name="master-tactician:temp-hp" value="charisma:modifier" />
            </rules>
        </element>


  <!-- Savant Skill Options -->
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ARCANA">
        <supports>laserllama Savant</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_HISTORY">
        <supports>laserllama Savant</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT">
        <supports>laserllama Savant</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INVESTIGATION">
        <supports>laserllama Savant</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_MEDICINE">
        <supports>laserllama Savant</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_NATURE">
        <supports>laserllama Savant</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION">
        <supports>laserllama Savant</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERSUASION">
        <supports>laserllama Savant</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_RELIGION">
        <supports>laserllama Savant</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SLEIGHTOFHAND">
        <supports>laserllama Savant</supports>
    </append>
</elements>