<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Civil Theory Philosopher Personal Theory</name>
        <author url="https://www.gmbinder.com/share/-Lki_INBU_Qa4G_VnUkp">GM Binder</author>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="philosopher-civil-theory.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/subclasses/philosopher/philosopher-civil-theory.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Civil Theory" type="Archetype" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_PHILOSOPHER_CIVIL_THEORY">
        <supports>Personal Theory</supports>
        <description>
            <h5>DIPLOMATS AND PACIFISTS</h5>
            <p>Philosophers of the Civil Theory take on a more nuanced view of the world than their peers - we live in neither the worst nor the best iteration in the multiverse, and our actions have observable consequences leading to a better or worse future.</p>
            <p class="indent">However, all should strive for the common goal of civility and peace, the strongest observable virtues. Those who act against it must regretfully be dealt with for the benefit of the majority.</p>
            <div element="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SIT_DOWN_AND_SHUT_UP" />
            <div element="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GET_AWAY_AND_STAY_AWAY" />
            <div element="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MIND_OVER_MATTER" />
            <div element="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_EVERREADY_EMISSARY" />
            <div element="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HELFENFREUDE" />
            <div element="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CHAMPION_OF_CIVILITY" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SIT_DOWN_AND_SHUT_UP" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GET_AWAY_AND_STAY_AWAY" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MIND_OVER_MATTER" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_EVERREADY_EMISSARY" level="11" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HELFENFREUDE" level="15" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CHAMPION_OF_CIVILITY" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    
        <element name="Sit Down and Shut Up" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SIT_DOWN_AND_SHUT_UP">
            <description>
                <p>hen you choose to study this theory at 1st level, you begin to learn to ignore the barbarism present in most discourse.</p>
                <p class="indent">You always have the Sanctuary spell prepared, and when you cast it using your Theorycraft, the duration increases to one hour.</p>
                <p class="indent">Also at first level, you gain proficiency in two of the following skills of your choice: Deception, Intimidation, Persuasion. Whenever you make a skill check to stop hostilities preemptively, you gain advantage on the check.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You always have the Sanctuary spell prepared, and when you cast it using your Theorycraft, the duration increases to one hour. Whenever you make a skill check to stop hostilities preemptively, you gain advantage on the check.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SANCTUARY" prepared="true" />
                <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency (Civil Theory)" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_DECEPTION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INTIMIDATION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERSUASION" number="2" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Get Away and Stay Away" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GET_AWAY_AND_STAY_AWAY">
            <description>
                <p>Regrettably, not all creatures are willing to listen peacefully, and many are too capable of inflicting harm.</p>
                <p class="indent">At 7th level, rather than following in the ways of your violent colleagues, you learn a way to mitigate damage to all parties.</p>
                <p class="indent">Whenever you deal damage with an attack, you may choose to push the creature you hit by 10 feet. A creature may only be affected this way once per turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Whenever you deal damage with an attack, you may choose to push the creature you hit by 10 feet. A creature may only be affected this way once per turn.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Mind Over Matter" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MIND_OVER_MATTER">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 7th level, you learn to rely more on your wits, grits, and worldly wisdom to overcome difficulties.</p>
                <p class="indent">Whenever you make a skill check, you may choose to gain a bonus equal to your choice of intelligence, charisma, or wisdom modifiers. You may do this twice, and regain the ability to do so after taking a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="2/Short Rest">
                <description>Whenever you make a skill check, you may choose to gain a bonus equal to your choice of intelligence, charisma, or wisdom modifiers.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Ever-Ready Emissary" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_EVERREADY_EMISSARY">
            <description>
                <p>At 11th level, you learn to keep your ear to the ground to always be open for civil dialogue or political discourse, ready to bat away anything obstructing the ideal of Civility or disturb study of the Theory.</p>
                <p class="indent">You are constantly under the effects of <i>detect thoughts</i> out to a range of 15 feet, no concentration required.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you take your action to probe deeper into a creature’s mind, you may not do so again until after you complete a long or short rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
                <description>You are constantly under the effects of detect thoughts out to a range of 15 feet, no concentration required. Once you take your action to probe deeper into a creature’s mind, you may not do so again until after you complete a long or short rest.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Helfenfreude" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HELFENFREUDE">
            <description>
                <p>At 15th level, you learn to draw power from your aspiration to worldly peace, seeing it as proof of your theory.</p>
                <p class="indent">When you expend a use of your Theorycraft feature and do not deal damage, you may immediately regain the expended use.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you may not do so again until after you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>When you expend a use of your Theorycraft feature and do not deal damage, you may immediately regain the expended use.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Champion of Civility" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CHAMPION_OF_CIVILITY">
            <description>
                <p>Civility is a lasting ideal, not a fleeting moment, and if you are to live out your theory, you must conduct your entire life like so. Your ability to shrug off misplaced malicious intent is your proof of the truth of the Civil Theory.</p>
                <p class="indent">At 18th level, you gain resistance to damage from and advantage on saving throws against effects from creatures that you have not damaged or forced to make a saving throw in the past 24 hours.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You gain resistance to damage from and advantage on saving throws against effects from creatures that you have not damaged or forced to make a saving throw in the past 24 hours.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
</elements>