<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Balasar’s Guide to Exploration</name>
        <update version="0.0.2">
            <file name="cleric-faith-mentor.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aurorabuilder/elements/master/cleric-faith-mentor.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_CLERIC">
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">"You think its easy receiving your power from the Gods? I thought you wizards were intelligent!"</p>
            <p>Many go about their days without being affected directly by a deity. Due to this, not everyone sees how a cleric must be, feeling the ever-present touch of a divine being.</p>
            <p class="indent">To be a cleric is not just to be devout to a deity. Where a cleric is touched by a deity and feels their ever-present touch, a cultist is one who reveres a deity is if they have divine power.</p>
            <p class="indent">Does a person become a cleric because their normal lives already embody the qualities of that deity? Or does a cleric start to reflect those qualities after a divine experience? Ultimately, that is up to you, dear adventurer.</p>
            <h4>FAITH</h4>
            <p>A cleric’s faith is what drives them to pursue divinity. Their magic comes from their faith, granted by the worship of their deity. Over the course of their life, there might be events that shake their faith down to the core. This could provide an interesting arc of events to take place. Although some clerics stray from the light of their deity, most do come back with a newfound strength.</p>
            <p class="indent">How strong is the faith of your cleric? Do they believe everything their deity has done to be in good attentions, even with obvious flaws? Do they lack the fundamental beliefs that their deity holds?</p>
            <p class="indent">Use the Faith table for more information.</p>
            <h4>MENTOR</h4>
            <p>Often times, temples have high priests that teach young acolytes the ways of worship. The bond of an apprentice, a mentor, and a divine spirit helps make the foundation for a priest to show their signs of being a cleric.</p>
            <p class="indent">Mentors come in many shapes and forms, or possibly deceased and obtained sainthood. It is up to you and your organization of what your mentor is, who they were, and their outcome.</p>
            <p class="indent">Use the Mentor table for further information.</p>
        </description>
        <rules>
            <select type="List" name="Faith (Cleric)">
                <item id="1">I lack the blatant oversight of their faults. I still choose to worship</item>
                <item id="2">My deity has done some wrongs, but they have done more good. I wish to spread more good in their name</item>
                <item id="3">The deity I worship has not provided any evidence that they exist in the world. I want to create miracles for them so others will worship too</item>
                <item id="4">My deity has only done good - or I choose to ignore the bad. I follow blindly</item>
                <item id="5">I only commune and pray to my deity when it is beneficial to me</item>
                <item id="6">I do not believe my deity exists, but am still granted divine magic for a reason unknown to me</item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="Mentor (Cleric)">
                <item id="1">My mentor was the holy symbol of my deity, such as a flaming sword for Tempus</item>
                <item id="2">The mentor was burned at the stake in a village for protesting a crime. They became a saint for the church</item>
                <item id="3">Unknown to me, my mentor was a celestial in disguise</item>
                <item id="4">My mentor was a normal humanoid, seeking to create quality clerics, such as myself</item>
                <item id="5">An ethereal spirit wanders the temple halls, and guided me to my path</item>
                <item id="6">My temple does not allow mentors. Instead, I taught myself. You should not rely on others to find your faith</item>
            </select>
        </rules>
    </append>
    
</elements>