<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Martial Artist Class v.17</name>
        <update version="0.0.2">
            <file name="class-martial-artist.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/classes/class-martial-artist/class-martial-artist.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Martial Artist" type="Class" source="The Martial Artist" id="ID_AO_MA_CLASS_MARTIAL_ARTIST">
        <description>
            <p>Her fists a blur as they deflect an incoming hail of arrows, a half-elf springs over a barricade and throws herself into the massed ranks of hobgoblins on the other side. She whirls through them, each blow seeming to be more deadly than the last, until at last she stands alone.</p>
            <p class="indent">A group of explorers has fought their way through the jungle to the abandoned temple, and has stopped outside to prepare to enter. As the others tend to minor wounds and sharpen their weapons, one of their number, a tattoo-covered human, begins to go through a series of graceful poses. One by one, the others begin to follow his lead, until, fortified and recentered, they all pass through the dark door before them.</p>
            <p class="indent">The Land’s Defenders are finally facing the Dread Archmage. As they draws weapons and prepares magics, he cackles and releases a storm of fire towards the group. But a black-clad halfling leaps from the shadows into the very path of the flame, shielding their friends from the worst of the effects. The archmage recoils to see the small figure so nearby, and they swiftly close the remaining distance to pummel him with blows so quick and accurate as to confound his spellcasting.</p>
            <h4>FLEXIBILITY AND BREADTH</h4>
            <p>Martial Artists have studied to be able to harness an energy known as ki that flows through all living bodies. Though very similar to Monks, Martial Artists have sacrificed some of the focus on stunning their enemies, and in return have gained a far greater flexibility to use their ki for a wide variety of techniques. They can choose to focus their physical and mental training not just on attacking and defensive moves, but also on expanding their senses, infiltration, or mobility.</p>
            <h4>FOCUS AND DEDICATION</h4>
            <p>Martial artists follow many different traditions. One of them might learn techniques honed by an oppressed people who learned to wield their very chains against the overlords who enslaved them; while another might have studied in a mountaintop monestary, taught by veterans of a horrible conflict who had turned to asceticism.</p>
            <p class="indent">But each martial artist, whether they’re aesthete noble who insists on artistry in all things or a self-taught street brawler, pushes their body beyond its normal limits through study of a magical energy that most traditions call ki. Martial artists harness this power within themselves to create magical effects and exceed their bodies’ physical capabilities, and some of their special attacks can hinder the flow of ki in their opponents. Using this energy, martial artists channel uncanny speed and strength into their unarmed strikes. As they gain experience, their martial training and their mastery of ki gives them more power over their own bodies and those of their foes.</p>
            <p class="indent">Still, each martial artist is unique. Like Monks, each select a monastic tradition, a Way which gives them extra abilities and features. But in addition, each one studies their choice of individual techniques available to all Ways. One martial artist might focus on techniques to guide and aid their allies; another might hone their defensive techniques to become almost untouchable in battle; while yet another might develop such an array of different attacks that their enemies never know what will come next.</p>
            <p class="indent">With so many options to choose from, a martial artist is most effective when they have the wits to choose the right tool for each job. Though their attacks are physical rather than arcane, in some ways they have more in common with a Wizard than with a Barbarian. Like a Wizard with her spells, they must choose wisely which techniques to learn; then, in combat, choose which to use. This path of training and discipline is not for everyone, but its rewards can be great.</p>
            <h2>CLASS FEATURES</h2>
            <p>As an martial artist, you gain the following class features.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">HIT POINTS</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Hit Dice:</strong> 1d10 per martial artist level</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at 1st Level:</strong> 10 + your Constitution modifier</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at Higher Levels:</strong> 1d10 (or 6) + your Constitution modifier per martial artist level after 1st</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">PROFICIENCIES</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled mb">
                <li><strong>Armor:</strong> None</li>
                <li><strong>Weapons:</strong> Simple weapons, shortswords</li>
                <li><strong>Tools:</strong> Choose one set of artisan’s tools or one instrument</li>
            </ul>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Saving Throws:</strong> Strength, Dexterity</li>
                <li><strong>Skills:</strong> Choose two from Acrobatics, Athletics, History, Insight, Religion, and Stealth</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">EQUIPMENT</h5>
            <p>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>(a) a shortsword or (b) any simple weapon</li>
                <li>(a) a dungeoneer’s pack or (b) an explorer’s pack</li>
                <li>10 darts</li>
            </ul>
        <!-- class table here -->
            <h5 class="caption">THE MARTIAL ARTIST</h5>
            <table class="class-features">
                <thead>
                    <tr><td class="col-5">Level</td><td class="col-10">Proficiency Bonus</td><td class="col-60 left">Features</td><td class="col-10">col2</td><td class="col-10">col3</td><td class="col-10">col2</td><td class="col-10">col3</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td> 1st</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Unarmored Defense, Martial Arts, Techniques</td><td>1d4</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>1</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 2nd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Unarmored Movement, Ki, Basic Ki Techniques</td><td>1d4</td><td>2</td><td>+10ft</td><td>2</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 3rd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Monastic Tradition *</td><td>1d4</td><td>3</td><td>+10ft</td><td>2</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 4th</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement, Novice Ki Techniques</td><td>1d4</td><td>4</td><td>+10ft</td><td>3</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 5th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Extra Attack</td><td>1d6</td><td>5</td><td>+10ft</td><td>4</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 6th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Monastic Tradition feature, Ki-Empowered Strikes</td><td>1d6</td><td>6</td><td>+15ft</td><td>5</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 7th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Evasion *</td><td>1d6</td><td>7</td><td>+15ft</td><td>5</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 8th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>1d6</td><td>8</td><td>+15ft</td><td>6</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 9th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">—</td><td>1d6</td><td>9</td><td>+15ft</td><td>7</td></tr>
                <tr><td>10th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Monastic Tradition feature (from L11)</td><td>1d6</td><td>10</td><td>+20ft</td><td>8</td></tr>
                <tr><td>11th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Improved Basic Ki Techniques *</td><td>1d8</td><td>11</td><td>+20ft</td><td>8</td></tr>
                <tr><td>12th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>1d8</td><td>12</td><td>+20ft</td><td>9</td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">—</td><td>1d8</td><td>13</td><td>+20ft</td><td>10</td></tr>
                <tr><td>14th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Diamond Soul *</td><td>1d8</td><td>14</td><td>+25ft</td><td>10</td></tr>
                <tr><td>15th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">—</td><td>1d8</td><td>15</td><td>+25ft</td><td>11</td></tr>
                <tr><td>16th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>1d8</td><td>16</td><td>+25ft</td><td>12</td></tr>
                <tr><td>17th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Monastic Tradition feature *</td><td>1d10</td><td>17</td><td>+25ft</td><td>12</td></tr>
                <tr><td>18th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">—</td><td>1d10</td><td>18</td><td>+30ft</td><td>13</td></tr>
                <tr><td>19th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>1d10</td><td>19</td><td>+30ft</td><td>14</td></tr>
                <tr><td>20th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Flexible Technique *</td><td>1d10</td><td>20</td><td>+30ft</td><td>14 (+1 flexible)</td></tr>
            </table>
            <p>* : These features come in lieu of an additional technique known at their respective levels (3, 7, 11, 14, 17, and 20).</p>
            <div element="ID_AO_MA_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_ARTIST_UNARMORED_DEFENSE" />
            <div element="ID_AO_MA_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_ARTIST_MARTIAL_ARTS" />
            <div element="ID_AO_MA_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_ARTIST_TECHNIQUES" />
            <div element="ID_AO_MA_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_ARTIST_UNARMORED_MOVEMENT" />
            <div element="ID_AO_MA_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_ARTIST_KI" />
            <div element="ID_AO_MA_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_ARTIST_MONASTIC_TRADITION" />
            <div element="ID_AO_MA_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_ARTIST_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" />
            <div element="ID_AO_MA_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_ARTIST_NOVICE_KI_TECHNIQUES" />
            <div element="ID_AO_MA_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_ARTIST_EXTRA_ATTACK" />
            <div element="ID_AO_MA_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_ARTIST_KI_EMPOWERED_STRIKES" />
            <div element="ID_AO_MA_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_ARTIST_EVASION" />
            <div element="ID_AO_MA_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_ARTIST_IMPROVED_KI_TECHNIQUES" />
            <div element="ID_AO_MA_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_ARTIST_DIAMOND_SOUL" />
            <div element="ID_AO_MA_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_ARTIST_FLEXIBLE_TECHNIQUE" />
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="hd">d10</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SHORTSWORD" />
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Tool Proficiency, Martial Artist" supports="Artisan tools||Musical Instrument" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_STRENGTH" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_DEXTERITY" />
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency, Martial Artist" supports="Skill, Martial Artist" number="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AO_MA_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_ARTIST_UNARMORED_DEFENSE" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AO_MA_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_ARTIST_MARTIAL_ARTS" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AO_MA_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_ARTIST_TECHNIQUES" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AO_MA_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_ARTIST_UNARMORED_MOVEMENT" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AO_MA_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_ARTIST_KI" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AO_MA_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_ARTIST_MONASTIC_TRADITION" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AO_MA_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_ARTIST_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" level="4" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AO_MA_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_ARTIST_NOVICE_KI_TECHNIQUES" level="4" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AO_MA_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_ARTIST_EXTRA_ATTACK" level="5" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AO_MA_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_ARTIST_KI_EMPOWERED_STRIKES" level="5" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AO_MA_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_ARTIST_EVASION" level="7" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AO_MA_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_ARTIST_IMPROVED_KI_TECHNIQUES" level="11" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AO_MA_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_ARTIST_DIAMOND_SOUL" level="14" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AO_MA_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_ARTIST_FLEXIBLE_TECHNIQUE" level="20" />
            <!-- support for monk monastic tradition features that use monk level -->
            <stat name="level:monk" value="level:martial artist" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Unarmored Defense" type="Class Feature" source="The Martial Artist" id="ID_AO_MA_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_ARTIST_UNARMORED_DEFENSE">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 1st level, while you are wearing no armor and not wielding a shield, your AC equals 10 + your Dexterity modifier + your Wisdom modifier.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
    			<description>While you are wearing no armor and not wielding a shield, your AC equals {{ac:unarmored defense martial artist}}.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="ac:unarmored defense martial artist:base" value="10" />
                <stat name="ac:unarmored defense martial artist:dexterity" value="dexterity:modifier" />
                <stat name="ac:unarmored defense martial artist:wisdom" value="wisdom:modifier" />
                <stat name="ac:unarmored defense martial artist" value="ac:unarmored defense martial artist:base" />
                <stat name="ac:unarmored defense martial artist" value="ac:unarmored defense martial artist:dexterity" />
                <stat name="ac:unarmored defense martial artist" value="ac:unarmored defense martial artist:wisdom" />
                <stat name="ac:calculation" value="ac:unarmored defense martial artist" bonus="calculation" equipped="[armor:none],[shield:none]" alt="Unarmored Defense (Martial Artist)" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Martial Arts" type="Class Feature" source="The Martial Artist" id="ID_AO_MA_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_ARTIST_MARTIAL_ARTS">
            <description>
                <p>Your practice of martial arts gives you mastery of combat styles that use unarmed attacks and martial artist weapons, which are shortswords and any simple melee weapons that don’t have the two-handed or heavy property.</p>
                <p class="indent">You gain the following benefits while you are unarmed or wielding only martial artist weapons and you aren’t wearing armor or wielding a shield.</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>You can use Dexterity instead of Strength for the attack and damage rolls of your unarmed attacks and martial artist weapons.</li>
                    <li>You can roll a d4 in place of the normal damage of your unarmed attack or martial artist weapon. You can use a larger die as you gain martial artist levels, as shown in the Martial Arts column of the Martial Artist table.</li>
                    <li>You can use any feature which protects you or your allies despite lacking the right weapon(s), armor, or shield to do so. Examples: Defensive Duelist; Protection fighting style.</li>
                    <li>You can make one unarmed or one-handed martial artist weapon attack as a bonus action.</li>
                    <li>When you take the Dodge action, you get the usual benefit, but it lasts a bit longer. Until the end of your next turn, any attack roll made against you has disadvantage if you can see the attacker, and you make Dexterity saving throws with advantage. You lose this benefit if you are incapacitated or if your speed drops to 0.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Your unarmed strike does 1d{{martial arts:dice}}+{{martial arts:damage}} damage. You can use Strength or Dexterity for these attacks.
                When you use the Attack action with an unarmed strike or a monk weapon on your turn, you can make one unarmed strike as a bonus action. For example, if you take the Attack action and attack with a quarterstaff, you can also make an unarmed strike as a bonus action, assuming you haven’t already taken a bonus action this turn.
                You can use any feature which protects you or your allies despite lacking the right weapon(s), armor, or shield to do so.
                When you take the Dodge action, until the end of your next turn, any attack roll made against you has disadvantage if you can see the attacker, and you make Dexterity saving throws with advantage. You lose this benefit if you are incapacitated or if your speed drops to 0.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="martial arts:attack" value="strength:modifier" bonus="martial arts" />
                <stat name="martial arts:attack" value="dexterity:modifier" bonus="martial arts" />
                <stat name="martial arts:damage" value="strength:modifier" bonus="martial arts" />
                <stat name="martial arts:damage" value="dexterity:modifier" bonus="martial arts" />
                <stat name="martial arts:dice" value="4" bonus="martial arts" />
                <stat name="martial arts:dice" value="6" bonus="martial arts" level="5" />
                <stat name="martial arts:dice" value="8" bonus="martial arts" level="11" />
                <stat name="martial arts:dice" value="10" bonus="martial arts" level="17" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Techniques" type="Class Feature" source="The Martial Artist" id="ID_AO_MA_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_ARTIST_TECHNIQUES">
            <description>
                <p>In your study of martial and meditative arts, your dedicated practice has let you choose between certain special techniques to master.</p>
                <p class="indent">At 1st level, you can choose one technique from the options detailed at the end of the class description. As you gain levels as a martial artist , you learn additional techniques, as shown in the Techniques Known column of the Martial Artist table.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, when you gain a level in this class, you can choose one of the optional techniques you know and replace it with another technique. You can not replace a technique that is a prerequisite for another technique you know, and the replacement must have a level prerequisite lower than that of some technique you could learn.</p>
                <p class="indent">If a technique has prerequisites, you must meet them to learn it. You can learn the technique at the same time that you meet its prerequisites. A level prerequisite refers to your level in this class. When a technique lets you cast a spell, your spellcasting ability is Wisdom.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you gain a level in this class, you can choose one of the optional techniques you know and replace it with another technique. You can not replace a technique that is a prerequisite for another technique you know, and the replacement must have a level prerequisite lower than that of some technique you could learn.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Martial Artist Technique" supports="Martial Artist Technique" allowReplace="true" level="1" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Martial Artist Technique" supports="Martial Artist Technique" allowReplace="true" level="2" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Martial Artist Technique" supports="Martial Artist Technique" allowReplace="true" level="4" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Martial Artist Technique" supports="Martial Artist Technique" allowReplace="true" level="5" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Martial Artist Technique" supports="Martial Artist Technique" allowReplace="true" level="6" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Martial Artist Technique" supports="Martial Artist Technique" allowReplace="true" level="8" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Martial Artist Technique" supports="Martial Artist Technique" allowReplace="true" level="9" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Martial Artist Technique" supports="Martial Artist Technique" allowReplace="true" level="10" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Martial Artist Technique" supports="Martial Artist Technique" allowReplace="true" level="12" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Martial Artist Technique" supports="Martial Artist Technique" allowReplace="true" level="13" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Martial Artist Technique" supports="Martial Artist Technique" allowReplace="true" level="15" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Martial Artist Technique" supports="Martial Artist Technique" allowReplace="true" level="16" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Martial Artist Technique" supports="Martial Artist Technique" allowReplace="true" level="18" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Martial Artist Technique" supports="Martial Artist Technique" allowReplace="true" level="19" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Martial Artist Flexible Technique" supports="Martial Artist Technique" allowReplace="true" level="20" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Unarmored Movement" type="Class Feature" source="The Martial Artist" id="ID_AO_MA_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_ARTIST_UNARMORED_MOVEMENT">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 2nd level, your speed increases by 10 feet while you are not wearing armor or wielding a shield. This bonus increases when you reach certain martial artist levels, as shown in the Martial Artist table.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Your speed increases by {{monk:unarmored movement}} feet while you are not wearing armor or wielding a shield.</description>
                <description level="9">Your speed increases by {{monk:unarmored movement}} feet while you are not wearing armor or wielding a shield. You gain the ability to move along vertical surfaces and across liquids on your turn without falling during the move.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="martial artist:unarmored movement" value="10" bonus="unarmored movement" level="2" />
                <stat name="martial artist:unarmored movement" value="15" bonus="unarmored movement" level="6" />
                <stat name="martial artist:unarmored movement" value="20" bonus="unarmored movement" level="10" />
                <stat name="martial artist:unarmored movement" value="25" bonus="unarmored movement" level="14" />
                <stat name="martial artist:unarmored movement" value="30" bonus="unarmored movement" level="18" />

                <stat name="innate speed:misc" value="martial artist:unarmored movement" bonus="unarmored movement" equipped="[armor:none],[shield:none]" requirements="[innate speed:1]" />
                <stat name="innate speed:climb:misc" value="martial artist:unarmored movement" bonus="unarmored movement" equipped="[armor:none],[shield:none]" requirements="[innate speed:climb:1]" />
                <stat name="innate speed:fly:misc" value="martial artist:unarmored movement" bonus="unarmored movement" equipped="[armor:none],[shield:none]" requirements="[innate speed:fly:1]" />
                <stat name="innate speed:swim:misc" value="martial artist:unarmored movement" bonus="unarmored movement" equipped="[armor:none],[shield:none]" requirements="[innate speed:swim:1]" />
                <stat name="innate speed:burrow:misc" value="martial artist:unarmored movement" bonus="unarmored movement" equipped="[armor:none],[shield:none]" requirements="[innate speed:burrow:1]" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Ki" type="Class Feature" source="The Martial Artist" id="ID_AO_MA_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_ARTIST_KI">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 2nd level, your training allows you to harness the mystic energy of ki, and to use the basic ki techniques below. Your access to this energy is represented the maximum ki points in the Ki Points column of the Martial Artist table.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can spend these points to fuel the basic ki techniques below, as well as many of the techniques you will choose.</p>
                <p class="indent">When you spend a ki point, it is unavailable until you finish a short or long rest, at the end of which you draw all of your expended ki back into yourself. You must spend at least 30 minutes of the rest meditating to regain your ki points.</p>
                <p class="indent">Some of your ki features, as well as certain martial arts techniques (below), require your target to make a saving throw to resist the feature’s effects. The DC is calculated as:</p>
                <p style="text-align: center;"><b>Ki save DC</b> = 8 + proficiency bonus + Wisdom modifier</p>
                <h5>BASIC (ACTIVE) KI TECHNIQUES</h5>
                <h5 class="caption">Flurry of Blows</h5>
                <p>As a bonus action, you can spend 1 ki point to make two unarmed attacks.</p>
                <h5 class="caption">Focused Breathing</h5>
                <p>As an action, you can regain up to your wisdom modifier in ki points. Once you do this, you cannot do so again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
                <p class="indent">As a bonus action, you can clear your mind and focus on your breathing. Once before the start of your next turn, when you would use a technique (including basic or novice ki techniques), you reduce the ki cost of that technique by 1 (to a minimum of 0).</p>
                <h5 class="caption">Patient Defense</h5>
                <p>As a bonus action, you can spend 1 ki point to take the Dodge action. As noted above, the benefits lasts until the end of your next turn.</p>
                <h5 class="caption">Step of the Wind</h5>
                <p class="indent">As a bonus action, you can spend 1 ki point to take the Dash or Disengage action.</p>
                <p class="indent">When you do, for the rest of this turn, your jump distance is doubled, and your melee attacks get +2 to attack and damage if you’ve moved since your last attack.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You have {{ki:points}} Ki Points and your Ki DC is {{ki:dc}}.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="ki:points" value="level:martial artist" />
                <stat name="ki:dc" value="8" />
                <stat name="ki:dc" value="proficiency" />
                <stat name="ki:dc" value="wisdom:modifier" />
                <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AO_MA_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_ARTIST_BASIC_TECHNIQUE_FLURRY_OF_BLOWS" level="2" />
                <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AO_MA_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_ARTIST_BASIC_TECHNIQUE_FOCUSED_BREATHING" level="2" />
                <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AO_MA_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_ARTIST_BASIC_TECHNIQUE_PATIENT_DEFENSE" level="2" />
                <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AO_MA_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_ARTIST_BASIC_TECHNIQUE_STEP_OF_THE_WIND" level="2" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Flurry of Blows" type="Class Feature" source="The Martial Artist" id="ID_AO_MA_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_ARTIST_BASIC_TECHNIQUE_FLURRY_OF_BLOWS">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>As a bonus action, you can spend 1 ki point to make two unarmed attacks.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="1 Ki" action="Bonus Action">
                    <description>You make two unarmed attacks.</description>
                    <description level="11">You make three unarmed attacks. The third attack cannot be replaced or augmented using monastic tradition features.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Focused Breathing" type="Class Feature" source="The Martial Artist" id="ID_AO_MA_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_ARTIST_BASIC_TECHNIQUE_FOCUSED_BREATHING">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>As an action, you can regain up to your wisdom modifier in ki points. Once you do this, you cannot do so again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
                    <p class="indent">As a bonus action, you can clear your mind and focus on your breathing. Once before the start of your next turn, when you would use a technique (including basic or novice ki techniques), you reduce the ki cost of that technique by 1 (to a minimum of 0).</p>
                </description>
                <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Short Rest">
                    <description>You regain up to {{wisdom:modifier}} ki points.
                    As a bonus action, you can clear your mind and focus on your breathing. Once before the start of your next turn, when you would use a technique, you reduce the ki cost of that technique by 1 (to a minimum of 0).</description>
                    <description level="11">You regain up to {{wisdom:modifier}} ki points.
                    As a bonus action, you can clear your mind and focus on your breathing. Once before the start of your next turn, when you would use a technique, you reduce the ki cost of that technique by 1 (to a minimum of 0).
                    You can use your reaction one extra time before the start of your next turn. This costs 1 ki unless your Monastic Tradition lets you use your reaction extra times. (You can never react more than once to the same triggering event.)</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Patient Defense" type="Class Feature" source="The Martial Artist" id="ID_AO_MA_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_ARTIST_BASIC_TECHNIQUE_PATIENT_DEFENSE">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>As a bonus action, you can spend 1 ki point to take the Dodge action. As noted above, the benefits last until the end of your next turn.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="1 Ki">
                    <description>You take the Dodge action. The benefits last until the end of your next turn.</description>
                    <description level="11">You take the Dodge action. The benefits last until the end of your next turn.
                    You can use your reaction one extra time before the start of your next turn. This costs 1 ki unless your Monastic Tradition lets you use your reaction extra times. (You can never react more than once to the same triggering event.)</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Step of the Wind" type="Class Feature" source="The Martial Artist" id="ID_AO_MA_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_ARTIST_BASIC_TECHNIQUE_STEP_OF_THE_WIND">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>As a bonus action, you can spend 1 ki point to take the Dash or Disengage action.</p>
                    <p class="indent">When you do, for the rest of this turn, your jump distance is doubled, and your melee attacks get +2 to attack and damage if you’ve moved since your last attack.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="1 Ki">
                    <description>You can take the Dash or Disengage action. When you do, for the rest of this turn, your jump distance is doubled, and your melee attacks get +2 to attack and damage if you’ve moved since your last attack.</description>
                    <description level="11">You take the Dash and Disengage actions. When you do, for the rest of this turn, your jump distance is doubled, and your melee attacks get +2 to attack and damage if you’ve moved since your last attack.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
        <element name="Monastic Tradition" type="Class Feature" source="The Martial Artist" id="ID_AO_MA_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_ARTIST_MONASTIC_TRADITION">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 3rd level, you commit yourself to a monastic (aka martial arts) tradition, chosen from the list of available traditions for the Monk class.</p>
                <p class="indent">Your tradition grants you features at 3rd level and again at 6th, 10th, and 17th level. Note that 10th level is one level earlier than a Monk would gain the corresponding feature. Anywhere the rules for your tradition say "Monk", you can replace it with "Martial Artist".</p>
                <p class="indent">There are a few new rules regarding traditions:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Kensei monks can use strikes when they hit with a martial artist melee weapon.</li>
                    <li>Tradition features that add effects to unarmed strikes, such as Way of the Open Hand’s Open Hand Technique or Quivering Palm, count as strike techniques and thus cannot be combined with other strike techniques.</li>
                    <li>Any tradition feature which spends 2 or more ki to cast a spell counts as a technique for Focused Breathing. Once you have used focused breathing to cast a given spell twice, you cannot reduce that spell’s ki cost again until you finish a short or long rest.</li>
                    <li>See the end of this document for optional rules to simplify choosing techniques for each monastic tradition.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false" />
            <rules>
                <select type="Archetype" name="Monastic Tradition" supports="Martial Artist Monastic Tradition" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Ability Score Improvement" type="Class Feature" source="The Martial Artist" id="ID_AO_MA_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_ARTIST_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or increase two abilities by 1, or take a Feat from the Feat List. You can’t get an ability above 20 using an ASI.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false" />
            <rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Martial Artist 4)" supports="Improvement Option,Martial Artist,4" level="4" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Martial Artist 8)" supports="Improvement Option,Martial Artist,8" level="8" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Martial Artist 12)" supports="Improvement Option,Martial Artist,12" level="12" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Martial Artist 16)" supports="Improvement Option,Martial Artist,16" level="16" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Martial Artist 19)" supports="Improvement Option,Martial Artist,19" level="19" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Novice (Reactive) Ki Techniques" type="Class Feature" source="The Martial Artist" id="ID_AO_MA_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_ARTIST_NOVICE_KI_TECHNIQUES">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 4th level, you have access to any of the following techniques that you meet the prerequisites for:</p>
                <h5 class="caption">Critical Strike (novice ki technique)</h5>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 17 Wisdom or 17 Dexterity or 11th level</p>
                <p class="indent">When you make a critical hit with an unarmed attack, you can spend 1 ki point to roll your martial arts die and see the amount. If you then choose to use a strike technique that requires the target to make a saving throw, subtract the amount from the saving throw result. Otherwise, add the amount as extra damage.</p>
                <h5 class="caption">Tumbling Dodge (novice ki technique)</h5>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 17 Dexterity or 11th level</p>
                <p class="indent">When your speed is not 0, and a creature you can see hits you with a melee attack, you can use your reaction to try to dodge. Roll your martial arts die; if you get 4 or higher, you can use 5 feet of movement without provoking opportunity attacks. If you successfully move 5 feet, the attack misses.</p>
                <h5 class="caption">Ki Shield (novice ki technique)</h5>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 17 Wisdom or 11th level</p>
                <p class="indent">After rolling a saving throw you aren’t proficient in, you can use your reaction and spend 1 ki point to add your Wisdom modifier to the result.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false" />
            <rules>
                <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AO_MA_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_ARTIST_NOVICE_TECHNIQUE_CRITICAL_STRIKE" requirement="[wis:17]||[dex:17]||[level:martial artist:11]" />
                <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AO_MA_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_ARTIST_NOVICE_TECHNIQUE_TUMBLING_DODGE" requirement="[dex:17]||[level:martial artist:11]" />
                <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_AO_MA_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_ARTIST_NOVICE_TECHNIQUE_KI_SHIELD" requirement="[wis:17]||[level:martial artist:11]" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Critical Strike" type="Class Feature" source="The Martial Artist" id="ID_AO_MA_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_ARTIST_NOVICE_TECHNIQUE_CRITICAL_STRIKE">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <requirements>[wis:17]||[dex:17]||[level:martial artist:11]</requirements>
                <prerequisite>17 Wisdom or 17 Dexterity or 11th level</prerequisite>
                <description>
                    <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 17 Wisdom or 17 Dexterity or 11th level</p>
                    <p class="indent">When you make a critical hit with an unarmed attack, you can spend 1 ki point to roll your martial arts die and see the amount. If you then choose to use a strike technique that requires the target to make a saving throw, subtract the amount from the saving throw result. Otherwise, add the amount as extra damage.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="1 Ki">
                    <description>When you make a critical hit with an unarmed attack, roll your martial arts die and see the amount. If you then choose to use a strike technique that requires the target to make a saving throw, subtract the amount from the saving throw result. Otherwise, add the amount as extra damage.</description>
                    <description level="11">When you make a critical hit with an unarmed attack, roll your martial arts die and see the amount. If you then choose to use a strike technique that requires the target to make a saving throw, subtract the amount from the saving throw result and add the amount as extra damage.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Tumbling Dodge" type="Class Feature" source="The Martial Artist" id="ID_AO_MA_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_ARTIST_NOVICE_TECHNIQUE_TUMBLING_DODGE">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <requirements>[dex:17]||[level:martial artist:11]</requirements>
                <prerequisite>17 Dexterity or 11th level</prerequisite>
                <description>
                    <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 17 Dexterity or 11th level</p>
                    <p class="indent">When your speed is not 0, and a creature you can see hits you with a melee attack, you can use your reaction to try to dodge. Roll your martial arts die; if you get 4 or higher, you can use 5 feet of movement without provoking opportunity attacks. If you successfully move 5 feet, the attack misses.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet action="Reaction">
                    <description>When your speed is not 0, and a creature you can see hits you with a melee attack, you can try to dodge. Roll your martial arts die; if you get 4 or higher, you can use {{tumbling-dodge:movement}} feet of movement without provoking opportunity attacks. If you successfully move at least 5 feet, the attack misses.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="tumbling-dodge:movement" value="5" level="4" />
                    <stat name="tumbling-dodge:movement" value="5" level="11" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Ki Shield" type="Class Feature" source="The Martial Artist" id="ID_AO_MA_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_ARTIST_NOVICE_TECHNIQUE_KI_SHIELD">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <requirements>[wis:17]||[level:martial artist:11]</requirements>
                <prerequisite>17 Wisdom or 11th level</prerequisite>
                <description>
                    <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 17 Wisdom or 11th level</p>
                    <p class="indent">After rolling a saving throw you aren’t proficient in, you can use your reaction and spend 1 ki point to add your Wisdom modifier to the result.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet action="Reaction" usage="1 Ki">
                    <description>After rolling a saving throw you aren’t proficient in, you can use your reaction and spend 1 ki point to {{wisdom:modifier}} to the result.</description>
                    <description level="11">After rolling a saving throw, you can use your reaction and spend 1 ki point to add {{wisdom:modifier}} to the result. If you spend 2 ki total, it does not use your reaction.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
        <element name="Extra Attack" type="Class Feature" source="The Martial Artist" id="ID_AO_MA_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_ARTIST_EXTRA_ATTACK">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 5th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn. If you already have or later gain this ability from another source, you can replace it with an extra tehnique.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="extra attack:count" value="2" level="5" bonus="extra attack" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Ki-Empowered Strikes" type="Class Feature" source="The Martial Artist" id="ID_AO_MA_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_ARTIST_KI_EMPOWERED_STRIKES">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 6th level, your unarmed strikes count as magical for the purpose of overcoming resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Your unarmed strikes count as magical for the purpose of overcoming resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Evasion" type="Class Feature" source="The Martial Artist" id="ID_AO_MA_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_ARTIST_EVASION">
            <description>
                <p>At 7th level, your instinctive agility lets you dodge out of the way of certain area effects, such as a blue dragon’s lightning breath or a fireball spell. When you are subjected to an effect that allows you to make a Dexterity saving throw to take only half damage, you instead take no damage if you succeed on the saving throw, and only half damage if you fail.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you are subjected to an effect that allows you to make a Dexterity saving throw to take only half damage, you instead take no damage if you succeed on the saving throw, and only half damage if you fail.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Improved Ki Techniques" type="Class Feature" source="The Martial Artist" id="ID_AO_MA_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_ARTIST_IMPROVED_KI_TECHNIQUES">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 11th level, basic/novice ki techniques all improve:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>When you use Flurry of Blows, you can make a total of three unarmed attacks. The third attack cannot be replaced or augmented using monastic tradition features.</li>
                    <li>When you use Step of the Wind, you get the benefits of both the Disengage and Dash actions. Likewise, when you use Critical Strike, you get both benefits: both subtracting from any saving throw and adding to damage.</li>
                    <li>When you use Patient Defense or Focused Breathing, you can use your reaction one extra time before the start of your next turn. This costs 1 ki unless your Monastic Tradition lets you use your reaction extra times. (You can never react more than once to the same triggering event.)</li>
                    <li>You can use up to 10 feet of movement with Tumbling Dodge (when you roll a 4 or higher).</li>
                    <li>Ki Shield works on saving throws you’re proficient in. If you spend 2 ki total, it does not use your reaction.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false" />
        </element>
        <element name="Diamond Soul" type="Class Feature" source="The Martial Artist" id="ID_AO_MA_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_ARTIST_DIAMOND_SOUL">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 14th level, your mastery of ki grants you proficiency in all saving throws.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false" />
            <rules>
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CONSTITUTION" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_INTELLIGENCE" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_WISDOM" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CHARISMA" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Flexible Technique" type="Class Feature" source="The Martial Artist" id="ID_AO_MA_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_ARTIST_FLEXIBLE_TECHNIQUE">
            <description>
                <p>At 20th level, when you take a short rest, you can forego all the normal benefits of the rest to learn a technique of your choice. When you learn a new flexible technique in this manner, you forget any previous flexible technique you knew. Once you have used this feature, you can not do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
                <p class="indent">If you use this feature to learn a technique that requires 18th level as a prerequisite, you can not use this feature again for 1 year.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>When you take a short rest, you can forego all the normal benefits of the rest to learn a technique of your choice. When you learn a new flexible technique in this manner, you forget any previous flexible technique you knew. If you use this feature to learn a technique that requires 18th level as a prerequisite, you can not use this feature again for 1 year.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>

    <!-- Martial Artist skills -->
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ACROBATICS">
            <supports>Martial Artist</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ATHLETICS">
            <supports>Martial Artist</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_HISTORY">
            <supports>Martial Artist</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT">
            <supports>Martial Artist</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_RELIGION">
            <supports>Martial Artist</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_STEALTH">
            <supports>Martial Artist</supports>
        </append>

</elements>