<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Martial Artist Magic Items v.18.2</name>
        <update version="0.0.3">
            <file name="items-magic.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/classes/class-martial-artist/items-magic.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Belt of Martial Arts" type="Magic Item" source="The Martial Artist" id="ID_AO_MA_MAGIC_ITEM_BELT_OF_MARTIAL_ARTS">
        <description>
            <p>While attuned to such a belt, you know one or more additional Martial Arts techniques. The rarity (and in some cases, the color) of the item depends on the technique or techniques available. A belt which grants more than one technique will still generally only grant one technique with the maximum level prerequisite shown.</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Number of techniques</td><td>Max level prerequisite</td><td>Rarity</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1 (Specific)</td><td>1</td><td>Common (Can be attuned by Rangers, Rogues, Fighters, or Barbarians, if they are not wearing medium or heavy armor)</td></tr>
                <tr><td>1 (Any)</td><td>2</td><td>Uncommon</td></tr>
                <tr><td>1 (Specific)</td><td>5</td><td>Uncommon (also increases your ki point maximum by 1)</td></tr>
                <tr><td>1 (Any)</td><td>8</td><td>Rare</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2 (Any)</td><td>10</td><td>Very Rare</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2 (Specific)</td><td>13</td><td>Very Rare (also increases your ki point maximum by 2, 1 minor beneficial property [DMG p219])</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3 (Specific)</td><td>18</td><td>Legendary (also increases your ki point maximum by 4, 1 minor and 1 major beneficial property)</td></tr>
            </table>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous item</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="slot">waist</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous item</set>
            <set name="rarity">rarity varies</set>
            <set name="attunement" addition=" by a Martial Artist">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Manual of Martial Arts" type="Magic Item" source="The Martial Artist" id="ID_AO_MA_MAGIC_ITEM_MANUAL_OF_MARTIAL_ARTS">
        <description>
            <p>This book or scroll (or tapestry, mosaic, etc.) offers instructions on one or more martial arts techniques.</p>
            <p class="indent">If a martial artist spends 48 hours over a period of 6 days or fewer studying the contents and practicing its guidelines, they permanently learn the given technique(s). The manual then loses its magic, but regains it in a decade.</p>
            <p class="indent">A non-martial artist may be able to gain the same benefits, if they can pass a Dexterity or Wisdom check (DM’s discretion) with a DC equal to 15 plus half the maximum level prerequisite of the technique(s). In any case, this takes a total of 120 hours of study time over 14 days or fewer.</p>
            <p class="indent">If you ever study another manual of martial arts, you lose any techniques you learned from the first one.</p>
            <p class="indent">The rarity of such a manual is one level rarer than a corresponding belt of martial arts would be.</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Number of techniques</td><td>Max level prerequisite</td><td>Rarity</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1 (Specific)</td><td>1</td><td>Uncommon (Can be attuned by Rangers, Rogues, Fighters, or Barbarians, if they are not wearing medium or heavy armor)</td></tr>
                <tr><td>1 (Any)</td><td>2</td><td>Rare</td></tr>
                <tr><td>1 (Specific)</td><td>5</td><td>Rare (also increases your ki point maximum by 1)</td></tr>
                <tr><td>1 (Any)</td><td>8</td><td>Very Rare</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2 (Any)</td><td>10</td><td>Legendary</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2 (Specific)</td><td>13</td><td>Legendary (also increases your ki point maximum by 2, 1 minor beneficial property [DMG p219])</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3 (Specific)</td><td>18</td><td>Legendary (also increases your ki point maximum by 4, 1 minor and 1 major beneficial property)</td></tr>
            </table>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous item</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="slot"></set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous item</set>
            <set name="rarity">various rarities</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Iron Knuckles" type="Magic Item" source="The Martial Artist" id="ID_AO_MA_MAGIC_ITEM_IRON_KNUCKLES">
        <description>
            <p>When wearing these magical knuckles, you get +3 to your Strength, up to a maximum of 20. Your unarmed attacks can do 1d4 bludgeoning damage, and have a +1 bonus to attack &amp; damage; but your weapon attacks have -1 to attack &amp; damage.</p>
            <p class="indent">If you are a Martial Artist, gain the advantages (and drawbacks) of the Iron Body and Pushy techniques. If you already know both of these, choose an extra technique. If you have the Iron Palms technique, use 1d20 not 1d10 for the damage reduction.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Weapon</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="slot"></set>
            <set name="type">Weapon</set>
            <set name="rarity">rare</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Quarterstaff of Shelter" type="Magic Item" source="The Martial Artist" id="ID_AO_MA_MAGIC_ITEM_QUARTERSTAFF_OF_SHELTER">
        <description>
            <p>If you are wielding this quarterstaff, you can open it into a parasol at one end. When it is open, you can not use it as a weapon, but your fall speed is 60 feet; you take no fall damage; and you have 3/4 cover against radiant, poison, or acid damage from ranged attacks, spells, or effects. It can be opened as an action or as a reaction to being targeted by such an attack, spell, or effect. It can be closed as a bonus action.</p>
            <p class="indent">The above effects do not require attunement, but they do require having spent 10 minutes of familiarizing oneself with the mechanism. If, however, this item is attuned by a martial artist, it gains a +1 bonus to attack and damage, and gives its owner understanding of the Protective Stance technique. If the holder already knows that technique, they may use Patient Defense without spending ki.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Weapon</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="slot">onehand</set>
            <set name="type">Weapon</set>
            <set name="rarity">rare</set>
            <set name="attunement" addition="by a martial artist">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Boots of Sidestep" type="Magic Item" source="The Martial Artist" id="ID_AO_MA_MAGIC_ITEM_BOOTS_OF_SIDESTEP">
        <description>
            <p>When you wear these split-toed boots, and are not wearing medium or heavy armor, they provide the ability to disengage, dodge, or dash as a bonus action or as a reaction to being targeted by an opportunity attack. If this ability is used to dash, opportunity attacks against the wearer are made at disadvantage until the end of the turn. If this ability is used to disengage in response to an opportunity attack, the attack automatically misses. Once you have used this ability, you can not do so again until the following dawn.</p>
            <p class="indent">If you are a Martial Artist, then when you wear these boots, you gain the benefits of the Slippery Escape and Twist of the Rapids techniques. If you already know the Slippery Escape technique, you gain the ability to use Step of the Wind without spending ki. If you already know the Twist of the Rapids technique, you can use Patient Defense for no ki.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous item</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="slot">feet</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous item</set>
            <set name="rarity">rare</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Dominating Whip" type="Magic Item" source="The Martial Artist" id="ID_AO_MA_MAGIC_ITEM_DOMINATING_WHIP">
        <description>
            <p class="indent">This black leather bullwhip is considered a martial artist weapon. You gain a +2 bonus to its attacks and damage rolls.</p>
            <p class="indent">This item has up to 7 charges. It regains 1d6+1 charges at sunset. When you hit with it, you can expend 1 charge to gain the effect of Bonding Strike, or 2 charges to gain the effect of Subduing Strike. In both cases, the duration of any effects is tripled.</p>
            <p class="indent">When wielded by a martial artist, this weapon gains additional properties:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>The wielder is able to use the Bonding Strike and Subduing Strike techniques. If they already know either of these techniques, they can choose other strike techniques they could learn, gaining the ability to use these techniques until attunement ends.</li>
                <li>When they hit with this weapon, the wielder can use the weapon for a strike technique. This costs 1 ki point, plus the technique’s normal ki cost.</li>
                <li>The wielder can spend 3 ki to add one charge to this weapon, as a free action.</li>
            </ul>
            <p class="indent">Curse (DMs option): Some, but not all, examples of this item were used in an ancient conflict against a holy order, and that order’s patron deity was able to impose a powerful curse on the ones which were used in this manner. If such an item is used to help enslave any creature (that is, to force it to perform work useful to others against its will), the curse is activated for 7 years. While this curse is activated, anyone attuned to this weapon will not voluntarily unattune from it.</p>
            <p class="indent">Remove Curse will deactivate, but not remove, this curse. While under this curse:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>They find healing magic to be painful; whenever they magically recover hit points, they must succeed on a DC 18 Constitution saving throw, or be stunned until the end of their next turn.</li>
                <li>They are vulnerable to radiant damage, but they find suffering this damage pleasurable.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Weapon (whip)</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="slot">onehand</set>
            <set name="type">Weapon (whip)</set>
            <set name="rarity">very rare</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
</elements>