<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Circle of the Constellations Alpha Druid Circle</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="alpha-druid-circle-of-the-constellations.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/subclasses/alpha-druid/alpha-druid-circle-of-the-constellations.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
        <element name="Circle of the Constellations" type="Archetype" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_ALPHA_DRUID_CIRCLE_OF_THE_CONSTELLATIONS">
            <supports>Alpha Druid Circle</supports>
            <description>
                <p>One of the smallest circles, druids of the Circle of the Constellations are empowered by the power of the cosmos. Its legendary constellations have earned their place upon its black tapestry but still they yearn to do more.</p>
                <p class="indent">There are many different reasons why they seek the darkness. Some venture there to show that even the darkest places are not without light. Others to create new legends that will last for eternities for all to see. A few even seek to expand its reach, striving to keep the careful balance between light and dark.</p>
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_CONSTELLATIONS_CIRCLE_SPELLS" />
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_CONSTELLATIONS_POWERFUL_FRAGMENTS" />
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_CONSTELLATIONS_WRITTEN_IN_THE_STARS" />
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_CONSTELLATIONS_COSMIC_TALES" />
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_CONSTELLATIONS_LIVING_CONSTELLATIONS" />
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_CONSTELLATIONS_HEARTH_OF_MOON_AND_STARS" />
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_CONSTELLATIONS_CELESTIAL_BODY" />
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_CONSTELLATIONS_CIRCLE_SPELLS" level="2" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_CONSTELLATIONS_POWERFUL_FRAGMENTS" level="2" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_CONSTELLATIONS_WRITTEN_IN_THE_STARS" level="2" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_CONSTELLATIONS_COSMIC_TALES" level="6" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_CONSTELLATIONS_LIVING_CONSTELLATIONS" level="10" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_CONSTELLATIONS_HEARTH_OF_MOON_AND_STARS" level="14" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_CONSTELLATIONS_CELESTIAL_BODY" level="18" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Circle Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_CONSTELLATIONS_CIRCLE_SPELLS">
                <description>
                    <p>You gain circle spells at the druid levels listed.</p>
                    <h5 class="caption">Constellation Spells</h5>
                    <table>
                        <thead>
                            <tr><td>Druid Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                        </thead>
                        <tr><td>2nd</td><td><i>guiding bolt, magic missile</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>3rd</td><td><i>darkness, moonbeam</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>5th</td><td><i>crusader’s mantle, fly</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>7th</td><td><i>divination, guardian of faith</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>9th</td><td><i>magic missile barrage, midnight</i></td></tr>
                    </table>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GUIDING_BOLT" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="2" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGIC_MISSILE" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="2" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DARKNESS" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="3" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MOONBEAM" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="3" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CRUSADERS_MANTLE" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="5" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FLY" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="5" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DIVINATION" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="7" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GUARDIAN_OF_FAITH" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="7" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_SPELL_MAGIC_MISSILE_BARRAGE" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="9" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_SPELL_MIDNIGHT" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="9" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Powerful Fragments" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_CONSTELLATIONS_POWERFUL_FRAGMENTS">
                <description>
                    <p>At 2nd level, as you draw upon your power, you attract the power of the cosmos. Whenever you cast a druid spell of 1st level or higher, you gain a mote of starlight which drifts around you. You can have a maximum number of motes equal to your proficiency modifier at any one time. They last for 1 minute and the duration refreshes each time you gain one.</p>
                    <p class="indent">You can use an action to consume your motes, targeting a creature that you can see within 60 feet. For each mote consumed you can choose to either heal it for 1d4 + 1 or deal 1d4 + 1 radiant damage to it.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>Whenever you cast a druid spell of 1st level or higher, you gain a mote of starlight which drifts around you. You can have up to {{proficiency}} motes at one time, each lasting 1 minute. You can use an action to consume your motes, targeting a creature within 60 feet. For each mote you either heal 1d{{powerful-fragments:die-type}} + 1 or deal 1d{{powerful-fragments:die-type}} + 1 radiant damage.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="powerful-fragments:die-type" value="4" bonus="base" level="2"/>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Written in the Stars" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_CONSTELLATIONS_WRITTEN_IN_THE_STARS">
                <description>
                    <p>At 2nd level, your presence has become the focus of one of the legendary constellations. Choose one of the following:</p>
                    <ul class="unstyled">
                        <li><strong>The Anvil.</strong> Whenever you finish a short or long rest, you gain the benefits of mage armor.</li>
                        <li><strong>The Beast.</strong> You gain a natural weapon, such as a bite or claw attack, which you are proficient with. You use your Strength or Dexterity modifier for attack and damage rolls. It deals 1d8 bludgeoning, piercing, or slashing damage.</li>
                        <li><strong>The Chalice.</strong> You can cast bless once without expending a spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest. When you cast it, you gain 1 mote of starlight.</li>
                        <li><strong>The Crown.</strong> You can cast command once without expending a spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest. When you cast it, you gain 1 mote of starlight.</li>
                        <li><strong>The Galley.</strong> You gain a 30 feet swim speed.</li>
                        <li><strong>The Harp.</strong> You have advantage on saving throws made to avoid being frightened.</li>
                        <li><strong>The Jester.</strong> Opportunity attacks made against you have disadvantage.</li>
                        <li><strong>The Lover.</strong> You can cast blindness/deafness once without expending a spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest. When you cast it, you gain 1 mote of starlight.</li>
                        <li><strong>The Magus.</strong> You gain two cantrips from the Wizard spell list, they count as druid cantrips for you.</li>
                        <li><strong>The Serpent.</strong> Disguise self is added to your spell list.</li>
                        <li><strong>The Stranger.</strong> You can add your proficiency bonus to death saving throws.</li>
                        <li><strong>The Sword.</strong> You can consume your motes as part of making an attack roll.</li>
                        <li><strong>The Traveler.</strong> Your base walking speed increases by 10 feet.</li>
                        <li><strong>The Triplets.</strong> You can use a bonus action to gain a number of motes equal to your proficiency bonus. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</li>
                        <li><strong>The Watcher.</strong> You can see normally in darkness, both magical and nonmagical, to a distance of 60 feet.</li>
                    </ul>
                    <div class="sidebar">
                        <h5 class="caption"></h5>
                        <p></p>
                        <ul class="unstyled">
                            <li><strong>The Anvil</strong> - Baphomet’s Window, The Altar</li>
                            <li><strong>The Beast</strong> - The Companion, The Dog, The Jackal, The Leopard, The Lion</li>
                            <li><strong>The Chalice</strong> - The Amulet, The Horn, The Necklace</li>
                            <li><strong>The Crown</strong> - The Cage, The Court, The Empress, The King, The Throne</li>
                            <li><strong>The Galley</strong> - Lord of Storms, The Whale</li>
                            <li><strong>The Harp</strong> - The Archer, The Bow, The Lyre</li>
                            <li><strong>The Jester</strong> - Mask of Olidammara, The Fool, The Trickster</li>
                            <li><strong>The Lover</strong> - The Count, The Mistress, The Incubus</li>
                            <li><strong>The Magus</strong> - Boccob’s Shadow, The Archmage, The Robe, The Wizard</li>
                            <li><strong>The Serpent</strong> - The Kris, Traitor’s Tongue</li>
                            <li><strong>The Stranger</strong> - Cowl of the Unknown, Death, The Shadow, The Veil</li>
                            <li><strong>The Sword</strong> - Annam’s Belt, Corellon’s Tear, Kord’s Girdle, The Soldier, The Warrior</li>
                            <li><strong>The Traveler</strong> - Pipe Smoke, The Road</li>
                            <li><strong>The Triplets</strong> - Foundation of the World, The Children, The Crusade, The Mountains</li>
                            <li><strong>The Watcher</strong> - The Dual Daggers, The Eyes</li>
                        </ul>
                    </div>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Focus Constellation (Circle of the Constellations)" level="2" supports="Alpha Druid, Focus Constellation" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Cosmic Tales" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_CONSTELLATIONS_COSMIC_TALES">
                <description>
                    <p>At 6th level, you weave the motes you collect into to constellations of your own. You can consume your available motes to cast a druid spell of equal level to the number of motes consumed without expending a spell slot.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Once you’ve done this, you must finish a long rest before you can do so again.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Additionally, you can attune to a second constellation.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                    <description>You can consume your available motes to cast a druid spell of equal level to the number of motes consumed without expending a spell slot.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Focus Constellation (Circle of the Constellations)" level="6" supports="Alpha Druid, Focus Constellation" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Living Constellations" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_CONSTELLATIONS_LIVING_CONSTELLATIONS">
                <description>
                    <p>At 10th level, you power changes as the world turns to reveal new legends. After you finish a long rest, you can change which constellations you are attuned to.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Additionally, you can attune to a third constellation.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>After you finish a long rest, you can change which constellations you are attuned to.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Focus Constellation (Circle of the Constellations)" level="10" supports="Alpha Druid, Focus Constellation" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Hearth of Moon and Stars" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_CONSTELLATIONS_HEARTH_OF_MOON_AND_STARS">
                <description>
                    <p>Beginning at 14th level, the moon protects you wherever you are. During a short or long rest, you can invoke the power of the moon to guard your respite. At the start of the rest, you touch a point in space, and an invisible, 30-foot-radius sphere of magic appears, centered on that point. Total cover blocks the sphere.</p>
                    <p class="indent">While within the sphere, you and your allies gain a +5 bonus to Dexterity (Stealth) and Wisdom (Perception) checks, and any light from open flames or magic in the sphere (a campfire, dancing lights spell, torches, or the like) isn’t visible outside it. The upper part of the sphere shows a replica of the night sky, even if the sky is otherwise hidden.</p>
                    <p class="indent">The sphere vanishes at the end of the rest or when you leave the sphere.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Additionally, as long as you are under the night sky, you can ignore the material cost of the <em>divination</em> spell.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>At the start of the rest, you touch a point in space, and an invisible, 30-foot-radius sphere of magic appears, centered on that point. Total cover blocks the sphere. While within the sphere, you and your allies gain a +5 bonus to Dexterity (Stealth) and Wisdom (Perception) checks, and any light from open flames or magic in the sphere (a campfire, dancing lights spell, torches, or the like) isn’t visible outside it. The upper part of the sphere shows a replica of the night sky, even if the sky is otherwise hidden. Additionally, as long as you are under the night sky, you can ignore the material cost of the divination spell.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Celestial Body" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_CONSTELLATIONS_CELESTIAL_BODY">
                <description>
                    <p>Beginning at 18th level, you have become a legend of your own and the cosmos has seen fit to immortalize you among the stars. You gain the following benefits:</p>
                    <ul>
                        <li>Your motes use d8’s instead of d4’s, and whenever you use a mote on a target other than yourself, you are healed for half the amount of damage dealt or healing given.</li>
                        <li>When you consume the motes, you can divide the damage and healing as you see fit. For example, with 6 motes you can heal a friendly creature for 4d8 while dealing 2d8 to an enemy creature.</li>
                        <li>When you roll for initiative, you gain 6 motes.</li>
                    </ul>
                    <p class="indent">Additionally, you can change your attuned constellations when you finish a short rest.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>Whenever you use a mote on a target other than yourself, you are healed for half the amount of damage dealt or healing given. When you consume the motes, you can divide the damage and healing as you see fit. For example, with 6 motes you can heal a friendly creature for 4d8 while dealing 2d8 to an enemy creature. When you roll for initiative, you gain 6 motes. Additionally, you can change your attuned constellations when you finish a short rest.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="powerful-fragments:die-type" value="8" bonus="base" level="2"/>
                </rules>
            </element>


    <!-- focus constellations -->
        <element name="The Anvil" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FOCUS_CONSTELLATION_THE_ANVIL">
            <supports>Alpha Druid, Focus Constellation</supports>
            <description>
                <p>Whenever you finish a short or long rest, you gain the benefits of <em>mage armor</em>.</p>
                <div class="reference">
                    <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGE_ARMOR" />
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Whenever you finish a short or long rest, you gain the benefits of mage armor.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGE_ARMOR" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="The Beast" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FOCUS_CONSTELLATION_THE_BEAST">
            <supports>Alpha Druid, Focus Constellation</supports>
            <description>
                <p>You gain a natural weapon, such as a bite or claw attack, which you are proficient with. You use your Strength or Dexterity modifier for attack and damage rolls. It deals 1d8 bludgeoning, piercing, or slashing damage.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You gain a natural weapon, such as a bite or claw attack, which you are proficient with. You use your Strength or Dexterity modifier for attack and damage rolls. It deals 1d8 bludgeoning, piercing, or slashing damage.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="The Chalice" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FOCUS_CONSTELLATION_THE_CHALICE">
            <supports>Alpha Druid, Focus Constellation</supports>
            <description>
                <p>You can cast <em>bless</em> once without expending a spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest. When you cast it, you gain 1 mote of starlight.</p>
                <div class="reference">
                    <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLESS" />
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You can cast bless once without expending a spell slot. When you cast it, you gain 1 mote of starlight.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLESS" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="The Crown" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FOCUS_CONSTELLATION_THE_CROWN">
            <supports>Alpha Druid, Focus Constellation</supports>
            <description>
                <p>You can cast <em>command</em> once without expending a spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest. When you cast it, you gain 1 mote of starlight.</p>
                <div class="reference">
                    <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMMAND" />
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You can cast command once without expending a spell slot. When you cast it, you gain 1 mote of starlight.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMMAND" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="The Galley" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FOCUS_CONSTELLATION_THE_GALLEY">
            <supports>Alpha Druid, Focus Constellation</supports>
            <description>
                <p>You gain a 30 feet swim speed.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description>You gain a 30 feet swim speed.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="speed:swim" value="30" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="The Harp" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FOCUS_CONSTELLATION_THE_HARP">
            <supports>Alpha Druid, Focus Constellation</supports>
            <description>
                <p>You have advantage on saving throws made to avoid being frightened.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You have advantage on saving throws made to avoid being frightened.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="The Jester" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FOCUS_CONSTELLATION_THE_JESTER">
            <supports>Alpha Druid, Focus Constellation</supports>
            <description>
                <p>Opportunity attacks made against you have disadvantage.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Opportunity attacks made against you have disadvantage.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="The Lover" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FOCUS_CONSTELLATION_THE_LOVER">
            <supports>Alpha Druid, Focus Constellation</supports>
            <description>
                <p>You can cast <em>blindness/deafness</em> once without expending a spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest. When you cast it, you gain 1 mote of starlight.</p>
                <div class="reference">
                    <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLINDNESS_DEAFNESS" />
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You can cast blindness/deafness once without expending a spell slot. When you cast it, you gain 1 mote of starlight.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLINDNESS_DEAFNESS" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="The Magus" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FOCUS_CONSTELLATION_THE_MAGUS">
            <supports>Alpha Druid, Focus Constellation</supports>
            <description>
                <p>You gain two cantrips from the Wizard spell list, they count as druid cantrips for you.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description>You gain two cantrips from the Wizard spell list, they count as druid cantrips for you.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Circle of the Constellations)" number="2" supports="Wizard,0" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="The Serpent" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FOCUS_CONSTELLATION_THE_SERPENT">
            <supports>Alpha Druid, Focus Constellation</supports>
            <description>
                <p><em>Disguise self</em> is added to your spell list.</p>
                <div class="reference">
                    <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISGUISE_SELF" />
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description>Disguise self is added to your spell list.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISGUISE_SELF" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" known="true" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="The Stranger" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FOCUS_CONSTELLATION_THE_STRANGER">
            <supports>Alpha Druid, Focus Constellation</supports>
            <description>
                <p>You can add your proficiency bonus to death saving throws.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can add +{{proficiency}} to death saving throws.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="The Sword" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FOCUS_CONSTELLATION_THE_SWORD">
            <supports>Alpha Druid, Focus Constellation</supports>
            <description>
                <p>You can consume your motes as part of making an attack roll.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can consume your motes as part of making an attack roll.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="The Traveler" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FOCUS_CONSTELLATION_THE_TRAVELER">
            <supports>Alpha Druid, Focus Constellation</supports>
            <description>
                <p>Your base walking speed increases by 10 feet.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description>Your base walking speed increases by 10 feet.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="speed:misc" value="10" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="The Triplets" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FOCUS_CONSTELLATION_THE_TRIPLETS">
            <supports>Alpha Druid, Focus Constellation</supports>
            <description>
                <p>You can use a bonus action to gain a number of motes equal to your proficiency bonus. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You can gain up to {{proficiency}} motes.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="The Watcher" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FOCUS_CONSTELLATION_THE_WATCHER">
            <supports>Alpha Druid, Focus Constellation</supports>
            <description>
                <p>You can see normally in darkness, both magical and nonmagical, to a distance of 60 feet.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can see normally in darkness, both magical and nonmagical, to a distance of 60 feet.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
</elements>