<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Wake Strider Ranger Archetype</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="ranger-wake-strider.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/subclasses/ranger/ranger-wake-strider.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Wake Strider" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_HOMEBREWERY_SOURCE_Wake Strider">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation"></set>
            <set name="url">https://homebrewery.naturalcrit.com/share/xTWtDC2G</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" url=""></set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20200324</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Wake Strider" type="Archetype" source="Wake Strider" id="ID_HOMEBREWERY_ARCHETYPE_RANGER_WAKE_STRIDER">
        <supports>Ranger Archetype</supports>
        <description>
            <p>As a Wake Strider you seek to preserve the balance between sea and land, protecting the creatures and corals that call the seas their home. Meanwhile, a Wake Strider takes responsibility for the water itself to ensure that the balance between it and the land is not disrupted. This connection to water allows for a Wake Strider to harness its power to control the flow of water and later being able to morph their body into a liquid state.</p>
            <p class="indent">A Wake Strider will rarely go far from the bodies of water which they protect, however they will not hesitate to journey through land to stop a threat that seeks to harm the oceans, lakes, and rivers that they watch over.</p>
            <p class="indent">With the extensive time that they spend in or around water, Wake Strider’s tend to develop unique personalities based on their upbringing. You can pick from or roll on the Wake Strider Quirks table or create your own quirks.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">Wave Strider Quirk</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d6</td><td>Quirk</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>You feel unsafe sleeping on dry land, and will often seek out a body of water to rest in.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>You always smell like fish</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>You keep a seashell with you at all times and, when you feel uncertain, you listen to your seashell for guidance</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>Dry food disgusts you, and you always drench your food in water before eating it</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>You constantly cover yourself in seaweed and kelp to mask your scent</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>Your body is so used to being underwater that you sweat profusely when you are dry for an extended period of time</td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_HOMEBREWERY_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAKE_STRIDER_WAKE_STRIDER_MAGIC" />
            <div element="ID_HOMEBREWERY_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAKE_STRIDER_AQUATIC_AFFINITY" />
            <div element="ID_HOMEBREWERY_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAKE_STRIDER_WAKE_STRIKE" />
            <div element="ID_HOMEBREWERY_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAKE_STRIDER_WATERY_FORM" />
            <div element="ID_HOMEBREWERY_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAKE_STRIDER_MISTY_ESCAPE" />
            <div element="ID_HOMEBREWERY_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAKE_STRIDER_HIDDEN_MIST" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_HOMEBREWERY_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAKE_STRIDER_WAKE_STRIDER_MAGIC" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_HOMEBREWERY_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAKE_STRIDER_AQUATIC_AFFINITY" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_HOMEBREWERY_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAKE_STRIDER_WAKE_STRIKE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_HOMEBREWERY_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAKE_STRIDER_WATERY_FORM" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_HOMEBREWERY_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAKE_STRIDER_MISTY_ESCAPE" level="11" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_HOMEBREWERY_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAKE_STRIDER_HIDDEN_MIST" level="15" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Wake Strider Magic" type="Archetype Feature" source="Wake Strider" id="ID_HOMEBREWERY_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAKE_STRIDER_WAKE_STRIDER_MAGIC">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 3rd level, you learn an additional spell when you reach certain levels in this class, as shown in the Wake Strider Spells table. The spell counts as a ranger spell for you, but it doesn’t count against the number of ranger spells you know.</p>
                <h5 class="caption">Wake Strider Spells</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Ranger Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>create or destroy water</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>misty step</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><em>tidal wave</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>13th</td><td><em>control water</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>17th</td><td><em>maelstrom</em></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CREATE_OR_DESTROY_WATER" spellcasting="Ranger" known="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MISTY_STEP" spellcasting="Ranger" known="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_TIDAL_WAVE" spellcasting="Ranger" known="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONTROL_WATER" spellcasting="Ranger" known="true" level="13" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_MAELSTROM" spellcasting="Ranger" known="true" level="17" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Aquatic Affinity" type="Archetype Feature" source="Wake Strider" id="ID_HOMEBREWERY_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAKE_STRIDER_AQUATIC_AFFINITY">
            <description>
                <p>When you choose this archetype at 3rd, your connection to water gives you each of the following benefits:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>You can speak, read, and write Aquan</li>
                    <li>You learn the shape water cantrip, which counts as a Ranger cantrip for you</li>
                    <li>You gain a swimming speed of 30 feet. If you already have a swimming speed you can instead choose to increase your swimming speed by 10 feet.</li>
                    <li>You can breathe water as if it were air</li>
                    <li>You can walk on liquid water as if it were a solid surface</li>
                    <li>Attacking underwater does not impose disadvantage</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can breathe water as if it were air. You can walk on liquid water as if it were a solid surface. Attacking underwater does not impose disadvantage.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Language" id="ID_MM_LANGUAGE_AQUAN" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_SHAPE_WATER" spellcasting="Wizard" known="true" requirements="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_WIZARD" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_SHAPE_WATER" spellcasting="Archivist" known="true" requirements="ID_NCATS_VC_CLASS_ARCHIVIST" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_HOMEBREWERY_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAKE_STRIDER_AQUATIF_AFFINITY_SWIM30" requirements="[speed:swim:0]" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_HOMEBREWERY_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAKE_STRIDER_AQUATIF_AFFINITY_SWIM10" requirements="![speed:swim:0]" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Swim 30" type="Archetype Feature" source="Wake Strider" id="ID_HOMEBREWERY_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAKE_STRIDER_AQUATIF_AFFINITY_SWIM30">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description />
                <sheet display="false" />
                <rules>
                    <stat name="speed:swim" value="30" bonus="base" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Swim +10" type="Archetype Feature" source="Wake Strider" id="ID_HOMEBREWERY_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAKE_STRIDER_AQUATIF_AFFINITY_SWIM10">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description />
                <sheet display="false" />
                <rules>
                    <stat name="speed:swim" value="10" />
                </rules>
            </element>
        <element name="Wake Strike" type="Archetype Feature" source="Wake Strider" id="ID_HOMEBREWERY_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAKE_STRIDER_WAKE_STRIKE">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 3rd level, you can use your bonus action to sheathe your weapon in rushing water. The next time you hit a creature with that weapon, it deals an extra 1d8 cold damage and you can choose to push a creature who is large or smaller 5 feet away. This movement does not provoke opportunity attacks.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>You can sheathe your weapon in rushing water. The next time you hit a creature with that weapon, it deals an extra 1d8 cold damage and you can choose to push a creature who is large or smaller 5 feet away. This movement does not provoke opportunity attacks.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Watery Form" type="Archetype Feature" source="Wake Strider" id="ID_HOMEBREWERY_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAKE_STRIDER_WATERY_FORM">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 7th level, you can use your bonus action to turn your body into water. If you are in water you merge with the water surrounding you, while if you are on land you become a 5 foot puddle of water. While you are in this state you cannot be targeted, nor can you move or take actions, however you may move up to your swimming speed if you are in water. You can remain in your Watery Form for 10 minutes, or until you revert to your normal form, which you can do without requiring an action.</p>
                <p class="indent">When a creature within 30 feet of you moves, you may use your reaction to make an attack against that creature, exiting your Watery Form. That attack has the benefits of Wake Strike. You may use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier (minimum of once), and recover all uses when you complete a short or long rest</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="{{watery-form:uses}}/Short Rest">
                <description>You can use your bonus action to turn your body into water for up to 10 minutes. If you are in water you merge with the water surrounding you, while if you are on land you become a 5 foot puddle of water. While you are in this state you cannot be targeted, nor can you move or take actions, however you may move up to your swimming speed if you are in water. When a creature within 30 feet of you moves, you may use your reaction to make an attack against that creature, exiting your Watery Form. That attack has the benefits of Wake Strike.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="watery-form:uses" value="1" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="watery-form:uses" value="wisdom:modifier" bonus="base" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Misty Escape" type="Archetype Feature" source="Wake Strider" id="ID_HOMEBREWERY_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAKE_STRIDER_MISTY_ESCAPE">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 11th level, you can turn your body into mist to escape an attack. When a creature targets you with an attack you can use your reaction to turn your body into mist. The attack is made with disadvantage and you may then reapper in an unoccupied space within 30 feet of you and make an attack against the creature who made the triggering attack. This attack automatically has the benefits of Wake Strike.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Reaction">
                <description>When a creature targets you with an attack you can use your reaction to turn your body into mist. The attack is made with disadvantage and you may then reapper in an unoccupied space within 30 feet of you and make an attack against the creature who made the triggering attack. This attack automatically has the benefits of Wake Strike.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Hidden Mist" type="Archetype Feature" source="Wake Strider" id="ID_HOMEBREWERY_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAKE_STRIDER_HIDDEN_MIST">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 15th level, you can use your action to summon a cloud of thick mist. Choose a point within 60 feet of you. A cloud of mist appears with a 30 foot radius. The area which this cloud covers is considered heavily obscured.</p>
                <p class="indent">When you use this feature, select a number of creatures equal to your wisdom modifier. You and these creatures can see through the mist and, if they end their turn in the mist, they can go invisible at the end of their turn. This invisibility lasts until they use a reaction or until they take an action. If the creature reveals themself by making a weapon attack, that attack is made at advantage and has the benefits of Wake Strike.</p>
                <p class="indent">This cloud lasts for 1 minute, and once you use this feature you cannot use it again until you finish a short rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Short Rest">
                <description>You can summon a 30 foot radius cloud of thick mist at a point within 60 feet of you, which lasts for 1 minute. The area which this cloud covers is considered heavily obscured. Select up to {{wisdom:modifier}} creatures that can see through the mist and, if they end their turn in the mist, they can go invisible at the end of their turn. This invisibility lasts until they use a reaction or until they take an action. If the creature reveals themself by making a weapon attack, that attack is made at advantage and has the benefits of Wake Strike.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

</elements>