<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Corsair Ranger Conclave</name>
        <update version="0.0.2">
            <file name="ranger-corsair.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/subclasses/ranger/ranger-corsair.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Corsair Ranger Conclave" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_BLUEISHERP_GMBINDER_SOURCE_CORSAIR_RANGER_CONCLAVE">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation">CRC</set>
            <set name="url">https://www.gmbinder.com/share/-MC0ur72_oHswja0GQY7</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" abbreviation="BE" url="https://www.gmbinder.com/profile/blueisherp">blueisherp</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20200728</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Corsair" type="Archetype" source="Corsair Ranger Conclave" id="ID_BE_CRC_ARCHETYPE_RANGER_CORSAIR">
        <supports>Ranger Archetype</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Hardened by trials at sea, corsairs won’t bat an eye in the face of danger. Life for a corsair is full of adventure, sailing the open ocean with comrades in arms. They’ll stop at nothing to get their hands on treasure, except perhaps a duel with a worthy challenger.</p>
            <div element="ID_BE_CRC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CORSAIR_CORSAIR_MAGIC" />
            <div element="ID_BE_CRC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CORSAIR_TREASURE_HUNTER" />
            <div element="ID_BE_CRC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CORSAIR_SALTWATER_ROULETTE" />
            <div element="ID_BE_CRC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CORSAIR_CUTTING_RIPOSTE" />
            <div element="ID_BE_CRC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CORSAIR_BOARDING_PARTY" />
            <div element="ID_BE_CRC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CORSAIR_TOUGH_GRIT" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_BE_CRC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CORSAIR_CORSAIR_MAGIC" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_BE_CRC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CORSAIR_TREASURE_HUNTER" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_BE_CRC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CORSAIR_SALTWATER_ROULETTE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_BE_CRC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CORSAIR_CUTTING_RIPOSTE" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_BE_CRC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CORSAIR_BOARDING_PARTY" level="11" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_BE_CRC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CORSAIR_TOUGH_GRIT" level="15" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Corsair Magic" type="Archetype Feature" source="Corsair Ranger Conclave" id="ID_BE_CRC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CORSAIR_CORSAIR_MAGIC">
            <description>
                <p>You gain conclave spells at the ranger levels listed in the Corsair Spells table. These are always prepared and don’t count against your list of prepared spells.</p>
                <h5 class="caption">CORSAIR SPELLS</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Ranger Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>compelled duel</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>locate object</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><em>enemies abound</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>13th</td><td><em>Leomund’s secret chest</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>17th</td><td><em>legend lore</em></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMPELLED_DUEL" spellcasting="Ranger" known="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LOCATE_OBJECT" spellcasting="Ranger" known="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ENEMIES_ABOUND" spellcasting="Ranger" known="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LEOMUNDS_SECRET_CHEST" spellcasting="Ranger" known="true" level="13" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LEGEND_LORE" spellcasting="Ranger" known="true" level="17" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Treasure Hunter" type="Archetype Feature" source="Corsair Ranger Conclave" id="ID_BE_CRC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CORSAIR_TREASURE_HUNTER">
            <description>
                <p>At 3rd level, you have advantage on Perception checks to search for items worth at least 1 gp, and you can track them as you would a creature. You can do so by tracking individuals, investigating hearsay, or discerning physical evidence relevant to that item.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can also gain proficiency in Navigator’s Tools and waterborne vehicles.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You have advantage on Perception checks to search for items worth at least 1 gp, and you can track them as you would a creature. You can do so by tracking individuals, investigating hearsay, or discerning physical evidence relevant to that item.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_NAVIGATORS_TOOLS" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_VEHICLES_WATER" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Saltwater Roulette" type="Archetype Feature" source="Corsair Ranger Conclave" id="ID_BE_CRC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CORSAIR_SALTWATER_ROULETTE">
            <description>
                <p>At 3rd level, you can challenge a worthy opponent to a duel. As a bonus action, you can choose a creature you can see within 30 feet of you. For up to 1 minute or until either you or the target drops to 0 hit points, you both can deal 1d6 extra damage on attacks against each other once per turn.</p>
                <p class="indent">If a creature rolls a 1 on this d6, the attack will backfire, missing the target and hitting the attacker instead. This d6 can’t be rerolled, and critical hits can’t backfire. While you have half your maximum hit points or less, your d6 automatically rolls a 6.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can’t target a second creature with this feature until after the effect on the first creature ends. You can cast compelled duel with the same bonus action you use for this feature, targeting the same creature. You also don’t need to make Constitution saving throws to maintain concentration when damaged by creatures affected by this feature or your compelled duel.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>You can choose a creature you can see within 30 feet of you. For up to 1 minute or until either you or the target drops to 0 hit points, you both can deal 1d6 extra damage on attacks against each other once per turn. If a creature rolls a 1 on this d6, the attack will backfire, missing the target and hitting the attacker instead. This d6 can’t be rerolled, and critical hits can’t backfire. While you have half your maximum hit points or less, your d6 automatically rolls a 6.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Cutting Riposte" type="Archetype Feature" source="Corsair Ranger Conclave" id="ID_BE_CRC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CORSAIR_CUTTING_RIPOSTE">
            <description>
                <p>At 7th level, when a creature you can see makes a weapon attack against you, you can use your reaction to add your Wisdom modifier to your AC against that attack.</p>
                <p class="indent">If this causes a melee weapon attack to miss, the attacker must succeed on a Strength or Dexterity saving throw (the attacker’s choice) or drop the weapon used to make the attack if they’re holding it.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Reaction">
                <description>When a creature you can see makes a weapon attack against you, you can add +{{wisdom:modifier}} to your AC against that attack. If this causes a melee weapon attack to miss, the attacker must succeed on a Strength or Dexterity saving throw (the attacker’s choice) or drop the weapon used to make the attack if they’re holding it.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Boarding Party" type="Archetype Feature" source="Corsair Ranger Conclave" id="ID_BE_CRC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CORSAIR_BOARDING_PARTY">
            <description>
                <p>At 11th level, you can use your action to yell a rallying battle cry. Each hostile creature within 30 feet of you that can hear you must succeed a Wisdom saving throw or be affected by Saltwater Roulette for 1 minute. You and any willing creature within 30 feet of you that can hear you are also affected.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once per turn, an affected creature can add the Saltwater Roulette’s d6 to the damage roll of their attack against another affected creature. After you use this feature, you can’t do so again until you complete a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Short Rest">
                <description>You yell a rallying battle cry. Each hostile creature within 30 feet of you that can hear you must succeed a Wisdom saving throw or be affected by Saltwater Roulette for 1 minute. You and any willing creature within 30 feet of you that can hear you are also affected. Once per turn, an affected creature can add the Saltwater Roulette’s d6 to the damage roll of their attack against another affected creature.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Tough Grit" type="Archetype Feature" source="Corsair Ranger Conclave" id="ID_BE_CRC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CORSAIR_TOUGH_GRIT">
            <description>
                <p>By 15th level, the carnage of battle no longer fazes you. You gain resistance against bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage from creatures affected by your Saltwater Roulette.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You have resistance against bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage from creatures affected by your Saltwater Roulette.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

</elements>