<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Peace Divine Domain</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="cleric-peace-domain.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/compendium-of-sacred-mysteries-resurrection/cleric-peace-domain.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Peace Domain" type="Archetype" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_CLERIC_PEACE_DOMAIN">
        <supports>Divine Domain</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The world is filled with violence, unceasing and unending. The beasts feast upon one another as is their purpose, but mortal races can live in harmony with one another, bringing joy and life rather than pain and death. You believe this, firmly and with conviction, as your deity is one of peace and prosperity, love and harmony. You are tasked with providing protection and solace to those who join your cause, fostering friendship and unity among the members of your party as you work to end wars and conflicts. Clerics of this domain are missionaries and speakers for the divine, calling others to lay down their weapons and bow their heads in prayer. Lead the march for peace, and let benevolence guide your hand.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">PEACE DOMAIN SPELLS</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Cleric Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1st</td><td><em>animal friendship, sanctuary</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>calm emotions, hold person</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>beacon of hope, create food and water</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>7th</td><td><em>aura of life, resilient sphere</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>9th</td><td><em>commune, wall of force</em></td></tr>
            </table>
            <div class="reference">
                <p class="flavor">Peace does not mean suicidal pacifism. The Divine Cords of Fate dictate the time and place that each person will die. It is heretical to contemplate death before that appointed time, so to lay down arms and be slaughtered like sheep is not Peace.</p>
                <p class="indent flavor">Peace is something to be pursued, but it can not be secured without conflict. Fate dictates that violence is inevitable, for it is the nature of evil to reject the purity of Peace. Cruelty and wickeness must not be allowed to fester and rot within our world. It must be cleansed, either with education and enlightenment or with the blazing sword of truth. Even the most wicked will have a chance at redemption, but that chance may come after death. It is our duty to deliver them to that chance at the appointed time, in accordance with Fate.</p>
                <p class="indent flavor">Do not spare the villain and the murderer. Do not spare the wicked merely because they lie, speaking of Peace. Spare them because you know they are Fated to atone. Help them find redemption, either in life or in death.</p>
                <p class="indent flavor">That is the way of Peace.</p>
                <p style="text-align: right;" class="flavor">-Auren Garavial, Cleanser of House Gavarial</p>
            </div>
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PEACE_DOMAIN_PURSUIT_OF_PEACE" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PEACE_DOMAIN_MOMENT_OF_CALM" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PEACE_DOMAIN_CD_HEART_STRING" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PEACE_DOMAIN_PROTECTIVE_GRACE" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PEACE_DOMAIN_POTENT_SPELLCASTING" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PEACE_DOMAIN_LIVING_MARTYR" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANIMAL_FRIENDSHIP" spellcasting="Cleric" known="true" level="1" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SANCTUARY" spellcasting="Cleric" known="true" level="1" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CALM_EMOTIONS" spellcasting="Cleric" known="true" level="3" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HOLD_PERSON" spellcasting="Cleric" known="true" level="3" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BEACON_OF_HOPE" spellcasting="Cleric" known="true" level="5" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CREATE_FOOD_AND_WATER" spellcasting="Cleric" known="true" level="5" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AURA_OF_LIFE" spellcasting="Cleric" known="true" level="7" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_OTILUKES_RESILIENT_SPHERE" spellcasting="Cleric" known="true" level="7" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMMUNE" spellcasting="Cleric" known="true" level="9" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WALL_OF_FORCE" spellcasting="Cleric" known="true" level="9" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PEACE_DOMAIN_PURSUIT_OF_PEACE" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PEACE_DOMAIN_MOMENT_OF_CALM" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PEACE_DOMAIN_CD_HEART_STRING" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PEACE_DOMAIN_PROTECTIVE_GRACE" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PEACE_DOMAIN_POTENT_SPELLCASTING" level="8" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PEACE_DOMAIN_LIVING_MARTYR" level="17" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Pursuit of Peace" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PEACE_DOMAIN_PURSUIT_OF_PEACE">
            <description>
                <p>When you select this domain at 1st level, you gain proficiency in the Persuasion and Religion skills.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERSUASION" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_RELIGION" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Moment of Calm" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PEACE_DOMAIN_MOMENT_OF_CALM">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 1st level, your quiet prayer gives others a sensation of warmth and fairness. When you roll initiative, you can choose to cause all creatures that are also rolling initiative to hesitate. When you do, those creatures can’t take actions until the end of your second turn. When you do this, you can’t attack or cast spells that deal damage or target hostile creatures until after the end of your second turn. During this time, you gain advantage on rolls made to convince other creatures to stop fighting.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you roll initiative, you can choose to cause all creatures that are also rolling initiative to hesitate. When you do, those creatures can’t take actions until the end of your second turn. When you do this, you can’t attack or cast spells that deal damage or target hostile creatures until after the end of your second turn. During this time, you gain advantage on rolls made to convince other creatures to stop fighting.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Channel Divinity: Heart String" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PEACE_DOMAIN_CD_HEART_STRING">
            <description>
                <p>At 2nd level, you can use your action and your Channel Divinity to bind the life force of two creatures together for 1 minute. Choose two creatures you can see. When one of these creatures regains hit points or gains temporary hit points, the other creature regains or gains an equal amount.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet alt="Heart String" usage="Channel Divinity" action="Action">
                <description>You can bind the life force of 2 creatures together for 1 minute. Choose two creatures you can see. When one of these creatures regains hit points or gains temporary hit points, the other creature regains or gains an equal amount.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Protective Grace" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PEACE_DOMAIN_PROTECTIVE_GRACE">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, your blessed presence alone is enough to deter disaster. When a creature finishes a short or long rest while within 60 feet of you, it gains resistance to all damage until it attacks or casts a spell targeting a creature hostile to it. It also loses this resistance if it finishes another short or long rest while you are not present.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When a creature finishes a short or long rest while within 60 feet of you, it gains resistance to all damage until it attacks or casts a spell targeting a creature hostile to it. It also loses this resistance if it finishes another short or long rest while you are not present.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Potent Spellcasting" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PEACE_DOMAIN_POTENT_SPELLCASTING">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 8th level, you add your Wisdom modifier to the damage you deal with any cleric cantrip.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You add {{wisdom:modifier}} to the damage you deal with any cleric cantrip.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Living Martyr" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PEACE_DOMAIN_LIVING_MARTYR">
            <description>
                <p>At 17th level, your devotion to your ideals presses against the souls of those who would use violence. While you are gaining the benefits of your Protective Grace feature, any hostile creature that damages you must make a Wisdom saving throw against your cleric spell save DC. If a creature fails, it is stunned until the start of its next turn.</p>
                <div class="sidebar">
                    <h5 class="caption">PACIFISM AND VIOLENCE</h5>
                    <p>Worlds of fantasy and wonder are filled with all sorts of horrible and nightmarish creatures that stalk the realms without any remorse, or even the capacity for it. Just because something appears humanoid does not necessarily mean that it is capable of peaceful coexistence. At the same time, many things that often are reviled may simply be misunderstood. In any case, there are times where violent conflict can’t be avoided with the tools available. Total pacifism, to the degree that all violent acts are shunned, is very rarely an attitude adopted by adventurers, and for good reason: those that do so tend to get eaten by something less morally-upright.</p>
                    <p class="indent">If you’re considering using this option, speak with your party about how you intend to work towards peace in a world of violence and war, with the understanding that it may not be appropriate for all groups.</p>
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>While you are gaining the benefits of your Protective Grace feature, any hostile creature that damages you must make a Wisdom saving throw (DC {{spellcasting:dc:wis}}). If a creature fails, it is stunned until the start of its next turn.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
    
</elements>