<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Metal Divine Domain</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="cleric-metal-domain.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/compendium-of-sacred-mysteries-resurrection/cleric-metal-domain.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Metal Domain" type="Archetype" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_CLERIC_METAL_DOMAIN">
        <supports>Divine Domain</supports>
        <description>
            <p>In the beginning, many believe that the universe was created by the gods in a singular display of incredible sound, and that the echoes of this event have crystalized and transformed within the earth, becoming the mystical metals of adamant, mithril, and starsteel. Deities of thunder, flame, creation, and destruction, such as Odin, Thor, Zeus, Jupiter, Creidhne, Gibli, Gofannon, Hephaestus, Iimarinen, Fulgora, Ogun, Ptah, and Svarog are commonly revered by clerics of this domain, who call upon their faith to wield the awesome power of creation itself. Wield weapons forged from these mystical metals and let loose the roar of the wrath of the gods and goddesses of metal.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">METAL DOMAIN SPELLS</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Cleric Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1st</td><td><em>mercurial weapon*, thunderwave</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>heat metal, shatter</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>call lightning, conductive spike*</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>7th</td><td><em>hand of hell*, wall of fire</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>9th</td><td><em>flame strike, legend lore</em></td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INSTRUMENT_OF_DESTRUCTION" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CD_OVERKILL" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARMOR_OF_THE_GODS" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DIVINE_STRIKE" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AVATAR_OF_METAL" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_SPELL_MERCURIAL_WEAPON" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="1" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_THUNDERWAVE" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="1" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HEAT_METAL" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="3" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHATTER" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="3" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CALL_LIGHTNING" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="5" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_SPELL_CONDUCTIVE_SPIKE" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="5" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_SPELL_HAND_OF_HELL" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="7" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WALL_OF_FIRE" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="7" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FLAME_STRIKE" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="9" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LEGEND_LORE" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="9" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INSTRUMENT_OF_DESTRUCTION" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CD_OVERKILL" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARMOR_OF_THE_GODS" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DIVINE_STRIKE" level="8" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AVATAR_OF_METAL" level="17" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Bonus Proficiencies" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES">
            <description>
                <p>When you select this domain at 1st level, you gain proficiency in the Performance skill, martial weapons, and heavy armor.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERFORMANCE" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_MARTIAL_WEAPONS" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_HEAVY_ARMOR" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Instrument of Destruction" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_INSTRUMENT_OF_DESTRUCTION">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 1st level, you learn to call forth a mystical weapon from the depths of the earth over the course of a long rest. This weapon takes the form of a magical martial weapon crafted from adamantine, and it deals damage of its normal type or thunder damage (your choice). This weapon is considered a holy symbol and an instrument of your choosing, you are proficient with this instrument, and if it is Heavy, Small creatures can wield it without penalty. When you critically hit with a spell attack during your turn, or cause more than one creature to fail a saving throw when you cast a spell that deals damage, you can use your bonus action to make an attack with this weapon.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can only have one of these weapons at a time. If you create a second one, the first one vanishes.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Over the course of a long rest, you can summon a magical martial weapon made of adamantium. It deals its normal damage type or thunder damage (your choice). It is considered a holy symbol. When you critically hit with a spell attack during your turn, or cause more than one creature to fail a saving throw when you cast a spell that deals damage, you can use your bonus action to make an attack with this weapon.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Channel Divinity: Overkill" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CD_OVERKILL">
            <description>
                <p>At 2nd level, when you or a creature you can see deals damage to a creature with a weapon attack, you can use your reaction and your Channel Divinity to transmute the victim’s essence into blades of starsteel that lance outward before vanishing. The target immediately takes additional magical piercing damage equal to 1d8 + your cleric level. If this causes the creature to die, its corpse detonates in a thunderous spray of blood and steel. Hostile creatures within 15 feet of the corpse must make a Dexterity saving throw against your cleric spell save DC. If a creature fails, it takes magical piercing damage equal to 1d8 + twice your cleric level, or half as much damage on a success. If this damage kills another creature that is Small or larger, that creature also explodes, repeating the effect until no more creatures die.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Channel Divinity" alt="Overkill" action="Reaction">
                <description>When you or a creature you can see deals damage to a creature with a weapon attack, you can use your reaction to transmute the victim’s essence into blades of starsteel that lance outward before vanishing. The target immediately takes additional magical 1d8 + {{level:cleric}} piercing damage.  If this causes the creature to die, hostile creatures within 15 feet of the corpse must make a Dexterity saving throw against your cleric spell save DC. If a creature fails, it takes 1d8 + {{cd-overkill:damage-bonus}} magical piercing damage, or half as much damage on a success. If this damage kills another creature that is Small or larger, that creature also explodes, repeating the effect until no more creatures die.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="cd-overkill:damage-bonus" value="level:cleric" />
                <stat name="cd-overkill:damage-bonus" value="level:cleric" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Armor of the Gods" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARMOR_OF_THE_GODS">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, your flesh is as unyelding as that which adorns it. While you are wearing heavy armor, you gain advantage on saving throws and ability checks made to avoid being forcibly moved or knocked prone. When a creature critically hits you with a melee attack, that creature is knocked prone.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>While you are wearing heavy armor, you gain advantage on saving throws and ability checks made to avoid being forcibly moved or knocked prone. When a creature critically hits you with a melee attack, that creature is knocked prone.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Divine Strike" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DIVINE_STRIKE">
            <description>
                <p>At 8th level, your attacks are infused with the booming voices of the divine pantheon. Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can cause the attack to deal an extra 1d8 thunder or lightning damage (your choice) to the target. When you reach 14th level, the extra damage increases to 2d8.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can cause the attack to deal an extra {{divine-strike:damage-dice}}d8 thunder or lightning damage (your choice) to the target.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="divine-strike:damage-dice" value="1" level="8" />
                <stat name="divine-strike:damage-dice" value="1" level="14" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Avatar of Metal" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AVATAR_OF_METAL">
            <description>
                <p>At 17th level, you can use your action to invoke the wrath of your deity, transforming one willing creature you can see into a massive and terrifying Avatar of Metal until the end of your next turn. You can repeatedly use your bonus action during each of your turns to play an insturment you are holding or to sing, causing the Avatar transformation to persist for an additional round.</p>
                <p class="indent">The Avatar transformation ends if the target is reduced to 0 hit points or when you end your turn without having used your action to sustain it.</p>
                <p class="indent">The creature gains the following benefits so long as it is transformed:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>The creature grows in size, becoming Large, Huge, or Gargantuan, chosen by you when this effect begins.</li>
                    <li>The creature ignores difficult terrain.</li>
                    <li>The creature can’t be charmed, frightened, stunned, paralyzed, petrified, or restrained.</li>
                    <li>Burning, spiked armor covers the creature, increasing its AC to 25 and granting it immunity to fire, lightning, and thunder damage.</li>
                    <li>The creature has advantage on all attack rolls, ability checks, and saving throws.</li>
                    <li>Once per turn when the creature hits with a weapon attack, it deals additional damage equal to your cleric level.</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You can transform one willing creature into an Avatar of Metal. You can repeatedly use your bonus action to maintain the Avatar form until the target reaches 0 hit points. The target grows to Large, Huge or Gargantuan and ignores difficult terrain. It can’t be charmed, frightened, stunned, paralyzed, petrified, or restrained. Its AC increases to 25 and it is immune to fire, lightning, and thunder damage. The creature has advantage on all attack rolls, ability checks, and saving throws. Once per turn when the creature hits with a weapon attack, it deals {{level:cleric}} additional damage.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    
</elements>