<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Agony Divine Domain</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="cleric-agony-domain.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/compendium-of-sacred-mysteries-resurrection/cleric-agony-domain.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Agony" type="Archetype" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_CLERIC_AGONY_DOMAIN">
        <supports>Divine Domain</supports>
        <description>
            <p>To live is to suffer. Pain and misery are an inescapable part of life, kept at bay by caution and prudent action. Agony is a blessing to the living, for the existence of suffering makes pleasure all the sweeter, and those too long deprived of it are often cruel, callous, and entirely lacking in empathy. Deities of murder, war, death, poison, sickness, and bloodshed of any kind lay claim to this domain, but they are not alone in that regard. While some clerics of this domain serve cruel and torturous gods, others worship at the altars of martyred deities who have taken pain upon themselves to spare others from the full weight of the world. Show the enemies of your faith what agony truly means, and take that pain into your heart, armored by penitent virtue.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">AGONY DOMAIN SPELLS</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Cleric Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1st</td><td><em>bane, inflict wounds</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>acid arrow, protection from poison</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>bestow curse, fear</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>7th</td><td><em>confusion, phantasmal killer</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>9th</td><td><em>contagion, hold monster</em></td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AGONY_INSTRUMENTS_OF_ANGUISH" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AGONY_MARK_OF_PAIN" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AGONY_CD_TORMENT" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AGONY_MARTYRS_BLESSING" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AGONY_POTENT_SPELLCASTING" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AGONY_UNSPEAKABLE_AGONY" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BANE" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="1" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INFLICT_WOUNDS" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="1" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ACID_ARROW" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="3" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PROTECTION_FROM_POISON" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="3" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BESTOW_CURSE" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="5" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FEAR" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="5" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONFUSION" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="7" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PHANTASMAL_KILLER" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="7" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONTAGION" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="9" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HOLD_MONSTER" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="9" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AGONY_INSTRUMENTS_OF_ANGUISH" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AGONY_MARK_OF_PAIN" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AGONY_CD_TORMENT" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AGONY_MARTYRS_BLESSING" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AGONY_POTENT_SPELLCASTING" level="8" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AGONY_UNSPEAKABLE_AGONY" level="17" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Instruments of Anguish" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AGONY_INSTRUMENTS_OF_ANGUISH">
            <description>
                <p>When you select this domain at 1st level, your deity’s attention amplifies the pain of those you fight. When a friendly creature you can see or hear hits with a attack, you can choose to have that attack deal acid, necrotic, or poison damage (your choice) instead of the normal damage type.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When a friendly creature you can see or hear hits with a attack, you can choose to have that attack deal acid, necrotic, or poison damage (your choice) instead of the normal damage type.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Mark of Pain" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AGONY_MARK_OF_PAIN">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 1st level, you gain the ability to scar the unrighteous with a terrible curse. When you cast a spell that deals damage, you can use your bonus action to apply this cursed mark to one creature damaged by the spell. This mark is visibly magical and lasts for 1 minute. For the duration, when the marked creature takes damage, you can use your reaction to cause the creature to take additional damage equal to your Wisdom modifier (minimum 1).</p>
                <p class="indent">If you mark a second creature, the first mark vanishes.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>When you cast a spell that deals damage, you can use your bonus action to apply this cursed mark to one creature damaged by the spell. This mark is visibly magical and lasts for 1 minute. For the duration, when the marked creature takes damage, you can use your reaction to cause the creature to take {{mark-of-pain:damage}} additional damage. If you mark a second creature, the first mark vanishes.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="mark-of-pain:damage" value="1" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="mark-of-pain:damage" value="wisdom:modifier" bonus="base" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Channel Divinity: Torment" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AGONY_CD_TORMENT">
            <description>
                <p>At 2nd level, wounds upon your flesh become poison to your enemies. When you take damage, you can use your reaction and your Channel Divinity to cause vile ichor to pour from your wounds, causing each hostile creature within 15 feet of you to take acid, necrotic, or poison damage (your choice) equal to 1d8 + your cleric level.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Channel Divinity" alt="Torment" action="Reaction">
                <description>When you take damage, you can cause each hostile creature within 15 feet of you to take 1d8 + {{level:cleric}} acid, necrotic, or poison damage (your choice).</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Martyr’s Blessing" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AGONY_MARTYRS_BLESSING">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, you can take the suffering of others from them, embracing it yourself. When a friendly creature within 15 feet of you takes damage, you can choose to halve the amount of damage it takes. You lose hit points equal to the amount of damage reduced in this way.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When a friendly creature within 15 feet of you takes damage, you can choose to halve the amount of damage it takes. You lose hit points equal to the amount of damage reduced in this way.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Potent Spellcasting" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AGONY_POTENT_SPELLCASTING">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 8th level, you add your Wisdom modifier to the damage you deal with any cleric cantrip.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You add {{wisdom:modifier}} to the damage you deal with any cleric cantrip.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Unspeakable Agony" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AGONY_UNSPEAKABLE_AGONY">
            <description>
                <p>At 17th level, the suffering sacred to your deity pours forth into the world like a venom into veins. As an action, you can cause all creatures within 60 feet of you to become poisoned for 1 minute as they are wracked by horrible agony. Creatures that are immune to the poisoned condition are not immune to this effect unless they are also immune to psychic damage.</p>
                <p class="indent">While a creature is poisoned in this way, you can use your bonus action to take the suffering from a creature, causing it to no longer be poisoned. When you do this, the creature gains temporary hit points equal to your cleric level.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t do so again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Short Rest">
                <description>You can cause all creatures within 60 feet of you to become poisoned for 1 minute as they are wracked by horrible agony. Creatures that are immune to the poisoned condition are not immune to this effect unless they are also immune to psychic damage. While a creature is poisoned in this way, you can use your bonus action to take the suffering from a creature, causing it to no longer be poisoned. When you do this, the creature gains {{level:cleric}} temporary hit points.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
    
    
</elements>