<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Moonlight Divine Domain</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="cleric-moonlight-domain.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/compendium-of-sacred-mysteries-resurrection/cleric-moonlight-domain.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Moonlight Domain" type="Archetype" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_CLERIC_MOONLIGHT_DOMAIN">
        <supports>Divine Domain</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The moonlight whispers in the darkness of night, sending dreams and shadows dancing in the cold wind. It is both a keeper of secrets and a revealer of truths, a shifter of shapes and an eternal watcher over the world. Deities such as Ta’lab, Thoth, Isis, Artemis, Selene, Luna, Arianhod, Kuhu, Han Ying, Awilix, and gods and goddesses of the moon, stars, night, cold, or darkness may lay claim to this domain. As a cleric serving a deity of this enigmatic sphere, you embody the same mysteries, cleaving apart the darkness that lurks beyond the candlelight with radiant power and silent purpose. Those like you are guardians and seekers, fearless in the face of the unknown and in your pursuit of the madness that lurks beyond.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">MOONLIGHT DOMAIN SPELLS</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Cleric Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1st</td><td><em>guiding bolt, sanctuary</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>levitate, moonbeam</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>slow, water walk</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>7th</td><td><em>greater invisibility, Otiluke's resilient sphere</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>9th</td><td><em>dream, telekinesis</em></td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOONLIGHT_MIDNIGHT_ARMAMENT" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOONLIGHT_NIGHTSLAYER" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOONLIGHT_CD_LUNAR_CYCLE" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOONLIGHT_CELESTIAL_WITNESS" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOONLIGHT_DIVINE_STRIKE" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOONLIGHT_MOONWALKER" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GUIDING_BOLT" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="1" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SANCTUARY" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="1" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LEVITATE" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="3" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MOONBEAM" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="3" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SLOW" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="5" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WATER_WALK" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="5" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GREATER_INVISIBILITY" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="7" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_OTILUKES_RESILIENT_SPHERE" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="7" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DREAM" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="9" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TELEKINESIS" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="9" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOONLIGHT_MIDNIGHT_ARMAMENT" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOONLIGHT_NIGHTSLAYER" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOONLIGHT_CD_LUNAR_CYCLE" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOONLIGHT_CELESTIAL_WITNESS" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOONLIGHT_DIVINE_STRIKE" level="8" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOONLIGHT_MOONWALKER" level="17" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Midnight Armament" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOONLIGHT_MIDNIGHT_ARMAMENT">
            <description>
                <p>When you select this domain at 1st level, your faith allows you to imbue your weapons with sacred light and weightlessness. As an action, you can touch a melee or ranged weapon you possess, infusing it with moonlight. While it is infused, you are proficient with it, it gains the finesse property, it deals 1d8 damage instead of its normal amount, and the weapon and any ammunition it uses are considered silvered for the purposes of overcoming damage resistances and immunities. This infusion fades if you do not possess the weapon at the start of your turn or if you infuse another weapon.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>You can touch a melee or ranged weapon you possess. You become proficient with it, it gains the finesse property, it deals 1d8 damage instead of its normal amount, and the weapon and any ammunition it uses are considered silvered for the purposes of overcoming damage resistances and immunities. This infusion fades if you do not possess the weapon at the start of your turn or if you infuse another weapon.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Nightslayer" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOONLIGHT_NIGHTSLAYER">
            <description>
                <p>At 1st level, you assault your foes with mysterious intent. When you cast a cleric cantrip that deals damage and targets one creature, you can use your bonus action to make a melee weapon attack with your infused weapon targeting that creature, instead of making a spell attack or causing the creature to make a saving throw. If your attack hits, the creature takes damage equal to your weapon attack’s damage plus your cantrip’s damage.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>When you cast a cleric cantrip that deals damage and targets one creature, you can make a melee weapon attack with your infused weapon targeting that creature, instead of making a spell attack or causing the creature to make a saving throw. If your attack hits, the creature takes damage equal to your weapon attack’s damage plus your cantrip’s damage.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Channel Divinity: Lunar Cycle" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOONLIGHT_CD_LUNAR_CYCLE">
            <description>
                <p>At 2nd level, you learn to unleash the cleansing light of your deity in a series of furious, radiant strikes, by using your action and your Channel Divinity. When you do, you perform the Wax phase listed below. After performing a phase, you can perform the next phase in the series on your subsequent turn by using your action. If you do not, or if you’ve performed all four phases, the cycle ends.</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Wax. You unleash a cleaving crescent blast of radiant energy in a line up to 30 feet long and 5 feet wide, ending with a burst in a 10-foot radius sphere at the end of the line. Creatures within the area must make a Dexterity saving throw. If a creature fails, it takes radiant damage equal to 1d10 + your cleric level, or half as much damage on a success.</li>
                    <li>Full. You shield yourself with moonlight, gaining temporary hit points equal to your cleric level that last for one minute. If damage from a creature causes you to lose any of these temporary hit points, that creature takes radiant damage equal to the temporary hit points lost.</li>
                    <li>Wane. You teleport up to 30 feet in a burst of moonlight to a location you can see within 5 feet of another creature, and can immediately cast a cleric cantrip targeting that creature as part of the same action.</li>
                    <li>Eclipse. You call down a scorching blast of radiant energy. Each hostile creature within 15 feet of you must make a Charisma saving throw. If a creature fails, it takes radiant damage equal to 1d10 + twice your cleric level, or half as much damage on a success.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="Channel Divinity" alt="Lunar Cycle">
                <description>You perform the Wax phase of Lunar Cycle listed. After performing a phase, you can perform the next phase (Wax -> Full -> Wane -> Eclipse) on your subsequent turn using your action.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFR_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CD_LUNAR_CYCLE_WAX" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFR_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CD_LUNAR_CYCLE_FULL" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFR_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CD_LUNAR_CYCLE_WANE" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFR_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CD_LUNAR_CYCLE_ECLIPSE" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Wax" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFR_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CD_LUNAR_CYCLE_WAX">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>You unleash a cleaving crescent blast of radiant energy in a line up to 30 feet long and 5 feet wide, ending with a burst in a 10-foot radius sphere at the end of the line. Creatures within the area must make a Dexterity saving throw. If a creature fails, it takes radiant damage equal to 1d10 + your cleric level, or half as much damage on a success.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Lunar Cycle">
                    <description>30 feet long and 5 feet wide, ending with a burst in a 10-foot radius sphere at the end of the line. Creatures within the area must make a Dexterity saving throw. If a creature fails, it takes radiant damage equal to 1d10 + {{level:cleric}}, or half as much damage on a success.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Full" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFR_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CD_LUNAR_CYCLE_FULL">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>You shield yourself with moonlight, gaining temporary hit points equal to your cleric level that last for one minute. If damage from a creature causes you to lose any of these temporary hit points, that creature takes radiant damage equal to the temporary hit points lost.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Lunar Cycle">
                    <description>You gain {{level:cleric}} temporary hit points that last for one minute. If damage from a creature causes you to lose any of these temporary hit points, that creature takes radiant damage equal to the temporary hit points lost.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Wane" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFR_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CD_LUNAR_CYCLE_WANE">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>You teleport up to 30 feet in a burst of moonlight to a location you can see within 5 feet of another creature, and can immediately cast a cleric cantrip targeting that creature as part of the same action.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Lunar Cycle">
                    <description>You teleport up to 30 feet in a burst of moonlight to a location you can see within 5 feet of another creature, and can immediately cast a cleric cantrip targeting that creature as part of the same action.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Eclipse" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFR_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CD_LUNAR_CYCLE_ECLIPSE">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>You call down a scorching blast of radiant energy. Each hostile creature within 15 feet of you must make a Charisma saving throw. If a creature fails, it takes radiant damage equal to 1d10 + twice your cleric level, or half as much damage on a success.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Lunar Cycle">
                    <description>Each hostile creature within 15 feet of you must make a Charisma saving throw. If a creature fails, it takes radiant damage equal to 1d10 + {{eclipse:damage}}, or half as much damage on a success.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="eclipse:damage" value="level:cleric" />
                    <stat name="eclipse:damage" value="level:cleric" />
                </rules>
            </element>
        <element name="Celestial Witness" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOONLIGHT_CELESTIAL_WITNESS">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, your sight becomes akin to that of the moon. You can treat dim light or darkness as bright light, and while you can see the moon, you can see invisible creatures and objects.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can treat dim light or darkness as bright light, and while you can see the moon, you can see invisible creatures and objects.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Divine Strike" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOONLIGHT_DIVINE_STRIKE">
            <description>
                <p>At 8th level, your attacks are empowered with the cold envy of the moon. Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can cause the attack to deal an extra 1d8 radiant or cold damage (your choice) to the target. When you reach 14th level, the extra damage increases to 2d8.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can cause the attack to deal an extra {{divine-strike:damage-dice}}d8 radiant or cold damage (your choice) to the target.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="divine-strike:damage-dice" value="1" level="8" />
                <stat name="divine-strike:damage-dice" value="1" level="14" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Moonwalker" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOONLIGHT_MOONWALKER">
            <description>
                <p>At 17th level, you are blessed in full by the soaring sphere above. You are immune to falling damage. Once during each of your turns, you can choose to influence your personal gravity, causing you to fall in a direction of your choosing. When falling in this way, you travel 300 feet in that direction during each of your turns until you land upon a surface. If your fall would cause you to enter a creature’s space, you travel through that creature’s space. Your altered gravity persists until you choose a new direction to fall, allowing you to walk on walls or ceilings.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You are immune to falling damage. Once during each of your turns, you can choose to influence your personal gravity, causing you to fall in a direction of your choosing. When falling in this way, you travel 300 feet in that direction during each of your turns until you land upon a surface. If your fall would cause you to enter a creature’s space, you travel through that creature’s space. Your altered gravity persists until you choose a new direction to fall, allowing you to walk on walls or ceilings.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

</elements>