<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Witchcraft Divine Domain</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="cleric-witchcraft-domain.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/subclasses/cleric/cleric-witchcraft-domain.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Witchcraft Domain" type="Archetype" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_CLERIC_WITCHCRAFT_DOMAIN">
        <supports>Divine Domain</supports>
        <description>
            <p>At the midnight hour, when the sky is shrouded in shadow and the full moon’s light shines down upon the world, the arts sacred to the deities of witchcraft are practiced. Hecate, Hel, Circe, Abonde, Aradia, Nicneven, Leonard, Cerrunos, Oya, Cerridwen, Diana, and other gods and goddesses of darkness, magic, fear, death, nature, and eldritch forces lay claim to the domain of witchcraft. Servants of these deities learn of the wishes of their gods through the voice of a familiar, which instructs them in the esoteric rites of the faith. Call upon the arcana you have learned, cleric, and offer praise to the oldest and truest ways.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">Witchcraft Domain Spells</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Cleric Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1st</td><td><em>speak with animals, hideous laughter</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>augury, suggestion</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>conjure animals, fly</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>7th</td><td><em>hallucinatory terrain, polymorph</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>9th</td><td><em>dream, geas</em></td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WITCHCRAFT_WITCHS_FAMILIAR" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WITCHCRAFT_WICKED_CURSE" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WITCHCRAFT_CD_VILE_BREW" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WITCHCRAFT_DARK_WITNESS" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WITCHCRAFT_POTENT_SPELLCASTING" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WITCHCRAFT_RAVENS_ECLIPSE" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_ANIMALS" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="1" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TASHAS_HIDEOUS_LAUGHTER" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="1" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AUGURY" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="3" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SUGGESTION" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="3" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONJURE_ANIMALS" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="5" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FLY" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="5" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HALLUCINATORY_TERRAIN" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="7" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_POLYMORPH" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="7" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DREAM" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="9" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GEAS" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="9" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WITCHCRAFT_WITCHS_FAMILIAR" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WITCHCRAFT_WICKED_CURSE" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WITCHCRAFT_CD_VILE_BREW" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WITCHCRAFT_DARK_WITNESS" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WITCHCRAFT_POTENT_SPELLCASTING" level="8" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WITCHCRAFT_RAVENS_ECLIPSE" level="17" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Witch’s Familiar" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WITCHCRAFT_WITCHS_FAMILIAR">
            <description>
                <p>When you select this domain at 1st level, you learn the find familiar spell, which is treated as a domain spell for you. When you cast find familiar, the creature you summon has its Intelligence, Wisdom, and Charisma scores increased to 14, and it can speak any language you can. When your familiar would take damage or be targeted by an effect or spell, you can use your reaction to dismiss your familiar instead, preventing it from taking damage or being targeted.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you cast find familiar, the creature you summon has its Intelligence, Wisdom, and Charisma scores increased to 14, and it can speak any language you can. When your familiar would take damage or be targeted by an effect or spell, you can use your reaction to dismiss your familiar instead, preventing it from taking damage or being targeted.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIND_FAMILIAR" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="1" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Wicked Curse" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WITCHCRAFT_WICKED_CURSE">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 1st level, you learn to call upon the strange arcane rites of your faith to inflict a malignant curse upon those who vex you. As an action, you can force a creature you can see to lock eyes with you. The target must make a Charisma saving throw. If it fails, it is cursed by you for 1 week. If it succeeds, it is not cursed and is immune to this curse for 1 day. If you successfully use this feature to curse a second creature, the first curse ends.</p>
                <p class="indent">The first time you cast a cantrip that requires the cursed target to make a saving throw, it automatically fails. When you do this, the curse ends.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can use your action to see and hear from the eyes and ears of any creature you have cursed using either this feature or another feature or spell that curses a creature, during which time you are deaf and blind to your own senses. This effect lasts until you choose to end it (no action required).</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>You can force a creature you can see to make a Charisma saving throw. If it fails, it is cursed by you for 1 week. If it succeeds, it is not cursed and is immune to this curse for 1 day. If you successfully use this feature to curse a second creature, the first curse ends. The first time you cast a cantrip that requires the cursed target to make a saving throw, it automatically fails. When you do this, the curse ends. You can use your action to see and hear from the eyes and ears of any creature you have cursed using either this feature or another feature or spell that curses a creature, during which time you are deaf and blind to your own senses. This effect lasts until you choose to end it (no action required).</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Channel Divinity: Vile Brew" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WITCHCRAFT_CD_VILE_BREW">
            <description>
                <p>At 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity as an action to conjure a potion of strange power. As part of this action, you cast a cleric spell of your choice that you have prepared that has a casting time of 1 action and doesn’t have a range of Self, which has no effect and is stored within the potion. A creature can use its action to consume the potion. When it does, the spell takes effect with the creature as the target, or as the point of origin if the spell targets an area. The potion retains potency until you finish a short or long rest, after which it has no effect.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet alt="Vile Brew" usage="Channel Divinity" action="Action">
                <description>You can conjure a potion of strange power. As part of this action, you cast a cleric spell of your choice that you have prepared that has a casting time of 1 action and doesn’t have a range of Self, which has no effect and is stored within the potion. A creature can use its action to consume the potion. When it does, the spell takes effect with the creature as the target, or as the point of origin if the spell targets an area. The potion retains potency until you finish a short or long rest, after which it has no effect.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Dark Witness" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WITCHCRAFT_DARK_WITNESS">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, when you use your Wicked Curse feature to see through the eyes of another creature, you can use your action to force a creature that you can see to lock eyes with the eyes you are seeing through, using your Wicked Curse feature to attempt to curse a new target.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you use your Wicked Curse feature to see through the eyes of another creature, you can use your action to force a creature that you can see to lock eyes with the eyes you are seeing through, using your Wicked Curse feature to attempt to curse a new target.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Potent Spellcasting" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WITCHCRAFT_POTENT_SPELLCASTING">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 8th level, you add your Wisdom modifier to the damage you deal with any cleric cantrip.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You add {{wisdom:modifier}} to the damage you deal with any cleric cantrip.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Raven’s Eclipse" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WITCHCRAFT_RAVENS_ECLIPSE">
            <description>
                <p>At 17th level, the otherworldly blessings bestowed upon you allow you to cloak the world in shadowed eyes and dark feathers. As an action, you can cause magical darkness to pour forth from yourself or from a cursed creature you can see, filling a 30-foot radius sphere around source and following it as it moves. Creatures friendly to you within the area can see clearly through the magical darkness. If a creature within the radius is hostile to you, it must make a Wisdom saving throw. If it fails, it is frightened of the creature of origin until the end of your next turn, and can see the creature of origin despite the darkness. If it succeeds, it can’t be frightened by this feature for 1 minute. The darkness lasts until the start of your next turn unless you use your action to maintain the effect, extending the duration until the start of your following turn with each consecutive use.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>You can cause magical darkness to pour forth from yourself or from a cursed creature you can see, filling a 30-foot radius sphere around source and following it as it moves. Creatures friendly to you within the area can see clearly through the magical darkness. If a creature within the radius is hostile to you, it must make a Wisdom saving throw. If it fails, it is frightened of the creature of origin until the end of your next turn, and can see the creature of origin despite the darkness. If it succeeds, it can’t be frightened by this feature for 1 minute. The darkness lasts until the start of your next turn unless you use your action to maintain the effect, extending the duration until the start of your following turn with each consecutive use.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

</elements>