<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Druid Circle of the Abattoir</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="druid-circle-of-the-abattoir.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/compendium-of-sacred-mysteries-resurrection/druid-circle-of-the-abattoir.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Circle of the Abattoir" type="Archetype" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_DRUID_CIRCLE_OF_THE_ABATTOIR">
        <supports>Druid Circle</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Hunting and predation are a natural part of the cycle of life, but spiders and shrikes and beasts unspoken capture their prey and bind them with webs or thorns or things darker still, devouring them only after the proper time has arrived. It requires foresight not often held by these lowly beasts to keep prey alive even longer, using those so kept to sustain a population of hapless victims from which their captor might select the most delicious morsel. Such cruel intellect is honored by this: the Circle of the Abattoir. Known often as scions of the slaughterhouse, druids such as yourself reap a grim harvest of flesh and bone, turning your unique perspective on vivisection into a tool for both defense and dismemberment. This task is a sacred one, blessed by the divines and ancient spirits, for your objective is to keep sated and content the endless appetite of the soil and sand, allowing new life to emerge from the carrion left behind. Servant of an order bound by bloodshed, wield these primal magics in defense of your kin and harness the ancient secrets of the lurking darkness.</p>
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COTA_BOUND_FOR_BUTCHERY" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COTA_RITE_OF_EXSANGUINATION" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COTA_VENGEFUL_VIVISECTION" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COTA_CRIMSON_CAGE" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COTA_FLESH_OF_MANY" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COTA_BOUND_FOR_BUTCHERY" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COTA_RITE_OF_EXSANGUINATION" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COTA_VENGEFUL_VIVISECTION" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COTA_CRIMSON_CAGE" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COTA_FLESH_OF_MANY" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Bound for Butchery" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COTA_BOUND_FOR_BUTCHERY">
            <description>
                <p>At 2nd level, you invoke shadow to bind and prepare your subjects for what is to come. As an action, you can expend a use of your Wild Shape feature to envelop a creature within your reach with twisting cords of darkness. An unwilling target must make a Charisma saving throw against your druid spell save DC. If the target fails or is willing, it is knocked prone and restrained. These eldritch bonds drink away the creature’s pain while it is bound, preventing it from dying unless it is damaged by a creature intending to kill it.</p>
                <p class="indent">If the creature is not grappled by you, it can use its bonus action to make a Strength saving throw, freeing itself and ending this effect if it succeeds.</p>
                <p class="indent">If the bound creature dies while it is within your reach, you can use your reaction to harvest a trophy from it, such as a claw, fang, horn, heart, or eye, and magically preserve that trophy.</p>
                <p class="indent">While holding such a trophy, you can surgically integrate it into the body of another creature bound using this feature over the course of one minute. After the process is complete, the subject’s flesh mends and the trophy becomes a permanent feature of their anatomy. The integrated part is vestigial and serves no functional purpose unless it replaces an existing or previously lost anatomical feature of the subject, at which point it restores that organ to functional order.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="Wild Shape">
                <description>You can envelop a creature within your reach with twisting cords of darkness. An unwilling target must make a Charisma saving throw against your druid spell save DC. If the target fails or is willing, it is knocked prone and restrained. These eldritch bonds drink away the creature’s pain while it is bound, preventing it from dying unless it is damaged by a creature intending to kill it.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Rite of Exsanguination" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COTA_RITE_OF_EXSANGUINATION">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 2nd level, blood heralds your arrival and follows in your wake. While casting a spell as a ritual, you can siphon an unnatural amount of blood from a dead, captive, or willing creature within your reach. If the creature is alive, it takes necrotic damage equal to five times the spell level of the ritual. When the ritual is complete, the siphoned blood forms a shallow pool covering a 15-foot radius area centered on you, and will follow you so long as it is fresh or until you command it to remain still. The blood remains fresh for up to one week, spoiling if you perform this ritual again. During this time, you can use your action to command the blood to seek its origin, causing it to slither with a life of its own at a rate of 30 feet per round, or about 3.5 miles each hour. When the blood reaches the creature it came from, you can choose to either have the blood heal the creature, causing it to regain hit points equal to the original necrotic damage taken, or damage the creature, causing it to take necrotic damage equal to five times the original necrotic damage taken. If the creature or corpse is on another plane of existence, the blood will become inert.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>While casting a spell as a ritual, you can siphon an unnatural amount of blood from a dead, captive, or willing creature within your reach. If the creature is alive, it takes necrotic damage equal to five times the spell level of the ritual. When the ritual is complete, the siphoned blood forms a shallow pool covering a 15-foot radius area centered on you, and will follow you so long as it is fresh or until you command it to remain still.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Vengeful Vivisection" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COTA_VENGEFUL_VIVISECTION">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, your set to your work with terrible purpose, and refuse to let interruption go unpunished. When you lose concentration on a spell due to taking damage from a hostile creature, you can use your reaction to cause a scything arc of shadow to cripple that creature. The target must make a Dexterity saving throw against your druid spell save DC. If the creature fails, it takes necrotic damage equal to three times the level of the spell you were concentrating on (minimum 3) and has its movement speed halved until it takes the Dodge action.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Reaction">
                <description>When you lose concentration on a spell due to taking damage from a hostile creature, you can cause a scything arc of shadow to cripple that creature. The target must make a Dexterity saving throw against your druid spell save DC. If the creature fails, it takes necrotic damage equal to three times the level of the spell you were concentrating on (minimum 3) and has its movement speed halved until it takes the Dodge action.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Crimson Cage" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COTA_CRIMSON_CAGE">
            <description>
                <p>At 10th level, the blood at your feet is both prison and protection. You can use your bonus action to cause the pool of blood from your Rite of Exsanguination to form a dome-shaped cage and become immobile. The cage has 1-inch gaps between the curved bars, fills a 15-foot radius sphere centered on you, has AC 15, and has hit points equal to five times the amount of hit points lost to create the pool. The cage lasts until you dismiss it using your bonus action, or until destroyed. When the cage is dismissed or destroyed, the pool of blood evaporates.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>You can use your bonus action to cause the pool of blood from your Rite of Exsanguination to form a dome-shaped cage and become immobile. The cage has 1-inch gaps between the curved bars, fills a 15-foot radius sphere centered on you, has AC 15, and has hit points equal to five times the amount of hit points lost to create the pool.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Flesh of Many" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COTA_FLESH_OF_MANY">
            <description>
                <p>At 14th level, your dedication to your art has reached the stage of true mastery. When you integrate a trophy into the anatomy of a creature using your Bound for Butchery feature, you can empower that addition. The creature gains one of the following features of your choosing until you use this feature on it again.</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>The creature gains darkvision out to 120 feet.</li>
                    <li>The creature gains advantage on Athletics checks.</li>
                    <li>The creature gains resistance to one damage type of your choosing.</li>
                    <li>The creature gains a natural melee weapon with which it is proficient that deals 1d12 bludgeoning, piercing, or slashing damage (your choice), or improves an existing natural weapon to deal that much damage.</li>
                    <li>The creature gains a swim speed equal to its walking speed and the ability to breathe air or water.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you integrate a trophy into the anatomy of a creature using your Bound for Butchery feature, you can empower that addition. The creature gains one of the following features of your choosing until you use this feature on it again: 120-foot darkvision; advantage on Athletics checks; resistance to one damage type you choose; a natural melee weapon that does 1d12 damage; or a swim speed equal to its walking speed and the ability to breathe air or water.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    
</elements>