<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Heavensent Hellion Martial Archetype</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="fighter-heavensent-hellion.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/compendium-of-sacred-mysteries-resurrection/fighter-heavensent-hellion.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Heavensent Hellion" type="Archetype" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FIGHTER_HEAVENSENT_HELLION">
        <supports>Martial Archetype</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Time is a fickle thing, especially to the heavens and hells beyond the corporeal world. For those who believe in reincarnation after death and ascenscion into an afterlife of unceasing warfare, it is possible to align with these eternal battlegrounds to summon fragments of past and future selves from the swirling chaos beyond time. You are among these warriors blessed with the ability to summon endless legions of your own incarnations. However, you are cursed to exist as a living paradox, for you are both commander and commanded, slayer and slain. You have been and will be a living weapon in an eternal war, and when you die, you will return to call upon yourself once again, sent by heaven to fight like hell.</p>
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HEAVENSENT_HELLION_KNIGHTS_OF_DISCORD" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HEAVENSENT_HELLION_WEAPON_OF_CHAOTIC_ORDER" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HEAVENSENT_HELLION_SELFISH_UNITY" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HEAVENSENT_HELLION_PERFECT_PARADOX" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HEAVENSENT_HELLION_LIMITED_INFINITY" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HEAVENSENT_HELLION_ARMAGEDDONS_ARBITER" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HEAVENSENT_HELLION_KNIGHTS_OF_DISCORD" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HEAVENSENT_HELLION_WEAPON_OF_CHAOTIC_ORDER" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HEAVENSENT_HELLION_SELFISH_UNITY" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HEAVENSENT_HELLION_PERFECT_PARADOX" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HEAVENSENT_HELLION_LIMITED_INFINITY" level="15" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HEAVENSENT_HELLION_ARMAGEDDONS_ARBITER" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Knights of Discord" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HEAVENSENT_HELLION_KNIGHTS_OF_DISCORD">
            <description>
                <p>When you choose this archetype at 3rd level, you learn to call forth a disciplined legion of alternate selves from the timeless afterlife. Once during each of your turns, you can cause a copy of yourself to appear in an open space within 5 feet of you. If you are mounted, your mount is also copied.</p>
                <p class="indent">When you use your Action Surge feature, you can immediately create a number of additional copies within 30 feet of you up to your character level.</p>
                <p class="indent">Your copies are semi-corporeal, quasi-real illusions that are visibly magical and can immediately move up to your speed when you summon them. They do not provide cover, and creatures and objects can pass through them, but they can’t pass through creatures or objects. You can take actions as though you were located in the spaces of your illusory copies. Copies created using this feature immediately vanish when your turn ends.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Once during each of your turns, you can cause a copy of yourself to appear in an open space within 5 feet of you. If you are mounted, your mount is also copied. When you use your Action Surge feature, you can immediately create up to {{level}} additional copies within 30 feet of you.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Weapon of Chaotic Order" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HEAVENSENT_HELLION_WEAPON_OF_CHAOTIC_ORDER">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 3rd level, your weapons momentarily duplicate and ripple through time when swung in dire moments, striking with unpredictable force. When you make a weapon attack with disadvantage and the attack hits, you can choose to have the weapon’s damage die result equal the lower d20 result, instead of rolling damage. If the attack was a critical hit, double the total amount of damage dealt.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you make a weapon attack with disadvantage and the attack hits, you can choose to have the weapon’s damage die result equal the lower d20 result, instead of rolling damage. If the attack was a critical hit, double the total amount of damage dealt.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Selfish Unity" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HEAVENSENT_HELLION_SELFISH_UNITY">
            <description>
                <p>At 7th level, your eternal war tears holes in reality, tying you more deeply to the endless selves you bring forth. When you take the Attack action during your turn, you can choose to sacrifice one of your attacks to teleport, switching places with one of your copies that you can see within 30 feet of your real location.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you take the Attack action during your turn, you can choose to sacrifice one of your attacks to teleport, switching places with one of your copies that you can see within 30 feet of your real location.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Perfect Paradox" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HEAVENSENT_HELLION_PERFECT_PARADOX">
            <description>
                <p>At 10th level, the force of your attacks is strange and furious, opening countless doors to places beyond time. Each time you attack a creature and miss, you can summon one of your copies to a location of your choosing within 5 feet of the target of your attack. Copies summoned in this way can’t move and vanish at the start of your next turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Each time you attack a creature and miss, you can summon one of your copies to a location of your choosing within 5 feet of the target of your attack. Copies summoned in this way can’t move and vanish at the start of your next turn.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Limited Infinity" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HEAVENSENT_HELLION_LIMITED_INFINITY">
            <description>
                <p>At 15th level, your endless soul begins to fray apart. Once per turn when you make an attack as though you were in the space of one of your copies, you can cause that copy to dupilcate. The copy creates a dupilcate within 5 feet of it, which immediately moves up to 30 feet. You can then immediately make one weapon attack with disadvantage from the duplicate’s location. The duplicate vanishes after you make the attack, or at the end of the current turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Once per turn when you make an attack as though you were in the space of one of your copies, you can cause that copy to dupilcate. The copy creates a dupilcate within 5 feet of it, which immediately moves up to 30 feet. You can then immediately make one weapon attack with disadvantage from the duplicate’s location. The duplicate vanishes after you make the attack, or at the end of the current turn.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Armageddon’s Arbiter" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HEAVENSENT_HELLION_ARMAGEDDONS_ARBITER">
            <description>
                <p>At 18th level, you are everywhere and nowhere at once. When a creature damages you, you can use your reaction to create a copy in an open space within 5 feet of that creature, and you immediately make one melee weapon attack from that copy’s space. The copy can’t move and vanishes at the end of the current turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Reaction">
                <description>When a creature damages you, you can use your reaction to create a copy in an open space within 5 feet of that creature, and you immediately make one melee weapon attack from that copy’s space. The copy can’t move and vanishes at the end of the current turn.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
    
</elements>