<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Steelbreaker Martial Archetype</name>
        <update version="0.0.2">
            <file name="fighter-steelbreaker.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/compendium-of-sacred-mysteries-resurrection/fighter-steelbreaker.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Steelbreaker" type="Archetype" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FIGHTER_STEELBREAKER">
        <supports>Martial Archetype</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Metal is not merely the bones of the earth; it is the foundation of war, the weapon of choice for every army in every age. You have learned the secrets of a particular sect of warriors who see this truth far better than any other, learning to wield metal itself without regard to what becomes of it. Brittle blades crack and break apart into shards of stabbing, slicing death. Armor, pierced through, becomes a prison for your enemies. Steelbreakers like you possess an almost supernatural control over metal, and destroy it to destroy your foes.</p>
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STEELBREAKER_SHATTERING_STEEL" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STEELBREAKER_REFORGE" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STEELBREAKER_IRON_IMPALER" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STEELBREAKER_SACRED_METAL" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STEELBREAKER_UNBREAKABLE" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STEELBREAKER_PRISON_OF_PAIN" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STEELBREAKER_PLATINUM_WRATH" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STEELBREAKER_SHATTERING_STEEL" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STEELBREAKER_REFORGE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STEELBREAKER_IRON_IMPALER" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STEELBREAKER_SACRED_METAL" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STEELBREAKER_UNBREAKABLE" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STEELBREAKER_PRISON_OF_PAIN" level="15" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STEELBREAKER_PLATINUM_WRATH" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Shattering Steel" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STEELBREAKER_SHATTERING_STEEL">
            <description>
                <p>At 3rd level, you learn to turn broken weapons into a potent arsenal. When you use your Action Surge feature, you can choose to break and twist loose, unattended nonmagical metal of your choosing, such as discarded weapons or coins, within a 15-foot radius around you, pulling and warping it into four broken blades that hover around you for 1 minute. When you attack while you possess at least one broken blade, you can expend that blade, causing it to fly forward and shatter, producing one of the following effects:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Shard Wave: Your attack targets each creature within a 15-foot cone originating from you. Roll one attack for all targets.</li>
                    <li>Splitting Spike: You launch the broken blade to a point you can see within 30 feet of you and cause it to explode, dealing 1d8 piercing damage to each creature within 10 feet of the point.</li>
                    <li>Lethal Lance: You hurl shards of the broken blade in a 5-foot wide, 30-foot long line. Each creature within the area must choose to either fall prone or take 1d12 piercing damage.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you use your Action Surge feature, you can create four broken blades that hover around you for 1 minute. When you attack while you possess at least one broken blade, you can expend that blade, causing it to fly forward and shatter, producing one of the following effects:</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STEELBREAKER_SHATTERING_STEEL_SHARD_WAVE" level="3" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STEELBREAKER_SHATTERING_STEEL_SPLITTING_SPIKE" level="3" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STEELBREAKER_SHATTERING_STEEL_LETHAL_LANCE" level="3" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Shard Wave" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STEELBREAKER_SHATTERING_STEEL_SHARD_WAVE">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>Your attack targets each creature within a 15-foot cone originating from you. Roll one attack for all targets.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Shattering Steel">
                    <description>Your attack targets each creature within a 15-foot cone originating from you. Roll one attack for all targets.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Splitting Spike" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STEELBREAKER_SHATTERING_STEEL_SPLITTING_SPIKE">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>You launch the broken blade to a point you can see within 30 feet of you and cause it to explode, dealing 1d8 piercing damage to each creature within 10 feet of the point.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Shattering Steel">
                    <description>You launch the broken blade to a point you can see within 30 feet of you and cause it to explode, dealing 1d8 piercing damage to each creature within 10 feet of the point.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Lethal Lance" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STEELBREAKER_SHATTERING_STEEL_LETHAL_LANCE">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>You hurl shards of the broken blade in a 5-foot wide, 30-foot long line. Each creature within the area must choose to either fall prone or take 1d12 piercing damage.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Shattering Steel">
                    <description>You hurl shards of the broken blade in a 5-foot wide, 30-foot long line. Each creature within the area must choose to either fall prone or take 1d12 piercing damage.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
        <element name="Reforge" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STEELBREAKER_REFORGE">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 3rd level, you gain the ability to cast the <i>mending</i> cantrip. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for this cantrip. While you are holding a piece of metal that was once part of a completed object, such as the hilt of a sword or the head of a nail, you know the direction, but not the distance, of all other components of the completed object that are on the same plane as you.</p>
                <div class="reference">
                    <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_MENDING" />
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can cast mending. (Wisdom) While you are holding a piece of metal that was once part of a completed object, you know the direction, but not the distance, of all other components of the completed object that are on the same plane as you.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MENDING" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Iron Impaler" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STEELBREAKER_IRON_IMPALER">
            <description>
                <p>At 7th level, your strikes leave shattered shards of metal in your enemies. When you use your Second Wind feature, each creature within 30 feet of you that you have damaged with a weapon attack or your Shattering Steel feature takes piercing damage equal to the amount of hit points you regain, and you immediately call forth one broken blade to hover around you for each creature damaged in this way.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you use your Second Wind feature, each creature within 30 feet of you that you have damaged with a weapon attack or your Shattering Steel feature takes piercing damage equal to the amount of hit points you regain, and you immediately call forth one broken blade to hover around you for each creature damaged in this way.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Sacred Metal" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STEELBREAKER_SACRED_METAL">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 7th level, your weapon attacks and damage from your Steelbreaker features are considered magical for the purposes of overcoming resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Your weapon attacks and damage from your Steelbreaker features are considered magical for the purposes of overcoming resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Unbreakable" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STEELBREAKER_UNBREAKABLE">
            <description>
                <p>At 10th level, you reject any attempt to stop your advance. When you use your Indomitable feature and succeed on the saving throw, you can immediately move up to 30 feet without provoking opportunity attacks and make a single weapon attack. If you fail the saving throw, you instead gain temporary hit points equal to your fighter level.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you use your Indomitable feature and succeed on the saving throw, you can immediately move up to 30 feet without provoking opportunity attacks and make a single weapon attack. If you fail the saving throw, you instead gain {{level:fighter}} temporary hit points.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Prison of Pain" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STEELBREAKER_PRISON_OF_PAIN">
            <description>
                <p>At 15th level, you control the shards you leave stabbed in your foes. When you deal damage to a creature using your Shattering Steel feature, that creature’s movement speed is reduced to 0 until the start of your next turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you deal damage to a creature using your Shattering Steel feature, that creature’s movement speed is reduced to 0 until the start of your next turn.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Platinum Wrath" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STEELBREAKER_PLATINUM_WRATH">
            <description>
                <p>At 18th level, the blades swirling around you are extensions of your will. When you use your Action Surge feature, you can now choose to break and shatter any nonmagical metals of your choosing, including wielded weapons or worn armor, in a 30-foot radius of you. If you destroy a creature’s weapon or armor, it takes piercing damage equal to your fighter level and is restrained until the start of your next turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you use your Action Surge feature, you can now choose to break and shatter any nonmagical metals of your choosing, including wielded weapons or worn armor, in a 30-foot radius of you. If you destroy a creature’s weapon or armor, it takes piercing damage equal to your fighter level and is restrained until the start of your next turn.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
    
</elements>