<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Way of Fiend’s Fury Monastic Tradition</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="monk-way-of-fiends-fury.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/compendium-of-sacred-mysteries-resurrection/monk-way-of-fiends-fury.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Way of Fiend’s Fury" type="Archetype" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_MONK_WAY_OF_FIENDS_FURY">
        <supports>Monastic Tradition</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Fate is a terrible and fickle thing, casting down those who have risen to greatness and allowing others to fall to terrible ruin. Yet, those damned souls can still rise to glory once more, finding redemption in the service of a greater cause. The Way of Fiend’s Fury is a sacred art, practiced by those pursuing glory through the salvation of fiends by binding these nightmares into weapons of immense power, and wielding these mysterious artifacts towards proper ends. To bear the fury of a fiend is a task requiring immense courage and personal sacrifice, as the temptations of power are often too great for some to resist. By taking the first step down this dark path, you’ve stepped into a valley of shadow and horror. What will emerge at the end is for you to decide.</p>
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WOFF_ANGUISHED_GLORY" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WOFF_REDEMPTION_THROUGH_BATTLE" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WOFF_DARK_ADVERSARY" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WOFF_DEVIL_MAY_DIE" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WOFF_ANGUISHED_GLORY" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WOFF_REDEMPTION_THROUGH_BATTLE" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WOFF_DARK_ADVERSARY" level="11" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WOFF_DEVIL_MAY_DIE" level="17" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Anguished Glory" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WOFF_ANGUISHED_GLORY">
            <description>
                <p>When you choose this tradition at 3rd level, you discover the secrets of summoning and binding a soul from the lower planes, shaping it into a weapon of incredible power called a mastix. During your turn, you can use your bonus action to call this weapon to your hand, where it remains until the start of your next turn. This monk weapon has an appearance of your choosing, requires two hands to wield, has the reach property, and deals 2d8 necrotic damage on a hit.</p>
                <p class="indent">While you are holding this weapon, you are afflicted with a terrible bloodlust. Your movement speed and jump height and distance are doubled, but you can only move directly towards the nearest hostile creature that you can sense. If you move at least 15 feet during your turn while in this state before making an attack, and your attack hits, you can force the target to make a Strength saving throw against your ki save DC, knocking the creature prone if it fails.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>You can summon your mastix, which is a monk weapon for you, requires two hands to wield, has the reach property and deals 2d8 necrotic damage. While you are holding this weapon, your movement speed and jump height and distance are doubled, but you can only move directly towards the nearest hostile creature that you can sense. If you move at least 15 feet during your turn while in this state before making an attack, and your attack hits, you can force the target to make a Strength saving throw against your ki save DC, knocking the creature prone if it fails.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Redemption Through Battle" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WOFF_REDEMPTION_THROUGH_BATTLE">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, your fulfillment of fate’s grandest design turns aside the weapons of your adversaries. When you hit a creature with your mastix, you can spend 1 ki point to cause attacks targeting you to be made with disadvantage until the start of your next turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you hit a creature with your mastix, you can spend 1 ki point to cause attacks targeting you to be made with disadvantage until the start of your next turn.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Dark Adversary" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WOFF_DARK_ADVERSARY">
            <description>
                <p>At 11th level, you’ve attuned yourself fully to your mastix, allowing you to maintain greater control or sink deeper into its madness. Your movement direction is no longer restricted when you are holding your mastix.</p>
                <p class="indent">When you summon your mastix, you can designate one creature that you can sense as your adversary. Until the start of your next turn, you can only move closer to your adversary, and your weapon attacks made with your mastix targeting your adversary deal additional damage equal to half your monk level, rounded down.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Your movement direction is no longer restricted when you are holding your mastix. When you summon your mastix, you can designate one creature that you can sense as your adversary. Until the start of your next turn, you can only move closer to your adversary, and your weapon attacks made with your mastix targeting your adversary deal additional {{level:monk:half}} damage.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Devil May Die" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WOFF_DEVIL_MAY_DIE">
            <description>
                <p>At 17th level, you can fully embrace and purify the fiendish power burning within your weapon, transforming into a sacred warrior of breathtaking strength. While you are holding your mastix, you can spend 3 ki points to assume your redeemer form until the start of your next turn. While in this form, your size grows to become Large, you gain a flying speed equal to your walking speed, you can use your Wisdom score in place of your Strength score, and weapon attacks you make with your mastix can target any number of creatures within your reach. Make a single attack roll for all creatures targeted.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once per turn when you hit your adversary with your mastix while in your redeemer form, you can choose to deliver a brutal unarmed strike, which automatically hits, deals an extra 2d10 necrotic damage, and pushes the creature 10 feet directly away from you.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>While you are holding your mastix, you can spend 3 ki points to assume your redeemer form until the start of your next turn. While in this form, your size grows to become Large, you gain a flying speed equal to your walking speed, you can use your Wisdom score in place of your Strength score, and weapon attacks you make with your mastix can target any number of creatures within your reach. Make a single attack roll for all creatures targeted. Once per turn when you hit your adversary with your mastix while in your redeemer form, you can choose to deliver a brutal unarmed strike, which automatically hits, deals an extra 2d10 necrotic damage, and pushes the creature 10 feet directly away from you.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
    
</elements>