<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Oath of Sorrow Sacred Oath</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="paladin-oath-of-sorrow.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/compendium-of-sacred-mysteries-resurrection/paladin-oath-of-sorrow.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
        <element name="Oath of Sorrow" type="Archetype" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_PALADIN_OATH_OF_SORROW">
            <supports>Sacred Oath</supports>
            <description>
                <p></p>
                <p class="indent">Misery and loss leave one cold, empty, grasping for life and light like a flower smothered by the icy dark of winter. You have felt this loss and bear it upon your soul as one who survived when others fell, or one who failed when it mattered most. The pale midnight moon and the endless snow are your heart’s companions now, calm and watchful, timeless and eternal in their vigil. Your oath is one of sorrow, but sorrow exists to be defied, to be overcome, to be wielded and forged into determination and undeniable purpose. The ice that covers your heart will be your weapon against the cruelties of this world, and the sharp bite of your tongue shall remind those who have forgotten what it means to live. Each day you draw breath shall be a testament to your faith, for the divines reward those who refuse to break. Stand tall, despite the tears, and search for winter’s end.</p>
                <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OOSORROW_TENETS_OF_SORROW" />
                <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OOSORROW_OATH_SPELLS" />
                <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OOSORROW_CHANNEL_DIVINITY" />
                <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OOSORROW_AURA_OF_REGRET" />
                <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OOSORROW_MOONLIT_LAMENTATION" />
                <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OOSORROW_MEMENTO_MORI" />
            </description>
            <sheet display="false" />
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OOSORROW_TENETS_OF_SORROW" level="3" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OOSORROW_OATH_SPELLS" level="3" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OOSORROW_CHANNEL_DIVINITY" level="3" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OOSORROW_AURA_OF_REGRET" level="7" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OOSORROW_MOONLIT_LAMENTATION" level="15" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OOSORROW_MEMENTO_MORI" level="20" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Tenets of Sorrow" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OOSORROW_TENETS_OF_SORROW">
            <description>
                <p>The tenets of the Oath of Sorrow are often difficult to uphold. Its principles present this path:</p>
                <p class="indent"><b><i>Remember the Reason:</i></b> Hold fast to the memories of what you have lost, and what has been taken from you.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b><i>Grow Cold:</i></b> Smother the fires of passionate fury, and instead act with grim determination and purpose.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b><i>Seek the End:</i></b> The source of your sorrow must be overcome, and the wrongs that have been done must be righted.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Oath Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OOSORROW_OATH_SPELLS">
            <description>
                <p>You gain oath spells at the paladin levels listed.</p>
                <h5 class="caption">OATH OF SORROW SPELLS</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Paladin Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>bane, shield</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>calm emotions, moonbeam</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><em>sleet storm, speak with dead</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>13th</td><td><em>hallucinatory terrain, ice storm</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>17th</td><td><em>antilife shell, cone of cold</em></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BANE" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHIELD" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CALM_EMOTIONS" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MOONBEAM" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SLEET_STORM" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_DEAD" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HALLUCINATORY_TERRAIN" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="13" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ICE_STORM" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="13" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANTILIFE_SHELL" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="17" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONE_OF_COLD" spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" level="17" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Channel Divinity" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OOSORROW_CHANNEL_DIVINITY">
            <description>
                <p>When you take this oath at 3rd level, you gain the following two Channel Divinity options.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b><i>Cold Comfort.</i></b> As an action, you can use your Channel Divinity to embrace suffering for 1 hour. During this time, you can choose to automatically fail saving throws you make. When you fail a saving throw during this time against a spell or effect that targets multiple creatures, you can cause all other creatures making the same saving throw to succeed automatically.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b><i>Quiet Misery.</i></b> When you see or hear a creature speak within 60 feet of you, you can use your Channel Divinity as a reaction to cause that creature to become incapable of speaking or casting spells requiring verbal components until the start of your next turn, potentially causing a spell it is casting to fail. The target must then make a Wisdom saving throw. If it fails, it loses concentration on any spell it is currently concentrating on.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OOSORROW_CD_COLD_COMFORT" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OOSORROW_CD_QUIET_MISERY" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Channel Divinity: Cold Comfort" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OOSORROW_CD_COLD_COMFORT">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>As an action, you can use your Channel Divinity to embrace suffering for 1 hour. During this time, you can choose to automatically fail saving throws you make. When you fail a saving throw during this time against a spell or effect that targets multiple creatures, you can cause all other creatures making the same saving throw to succeed automatically.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet alt="Cold Comfort" usage="Channel Divinity" action="Action">
                    <description>For 1 hour, you can choose to automatically fail saving throws you make. When you fail a saving throw during this time against a spell or effect that targets multiple creatures, you can cause all other creatures making the same saving throw to succeed automatically.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Channel Divinity: Quiet Misery" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OOSORROW_CD_QUIET_MISERY">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>When you see or hear a creature speak within 60 feet of you, you can use your Channel Divinity as a reaction to cause that creature to become incapable of speaking or casting spells requiring verbal components until the start of your next turn, potentially causing a spell it is casting to fail. The target must then make a Wisdom saving throw. If it fails, it loses concentration on any spell it is currently concentrating on.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet alt="Quiet Misery" usage="Channel Divinity" action="Reaction">
                    <description>When you see or hear a creature speak within 60 feet of you, you can cause that creature to become incapable of speaking or casting spells requiring verbal components until the start of your next turn, potentially causing a spell it is casting to fail. The target must then make a Wisdom saving throw. If it fails, it loses concentration on any spell it is currently concentrating on.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
        <element name="Aura of Regret" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OOSORROW_AURA_OF_REGRET">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 7th level, you can surround yourself with a 10-foot aura of chilling remorse while you are conscious. Once per turn when a hostile creature within the aura deals damage, it must choose to either reduce the amount of damage it deals by an amount equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum 1), or to take cold or psychic damage (your choice) equal to half your paladin level.</p>
                <p class="indent">At 18th level, the range of this aura increases to 30 feet.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Moonlit Lamentation" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OOSORROW_MOONLIT_LAMENTATION">
            <description>
                <p>At 15th level, your connection to the pale midnight light allows you to bring forth past memories. When you cast a spell of 1st level or higher, you can create a phantasmal memory in a space you can see within 30 feet of you, which occupies a 15-foot cube. When you do, choose either a joyful memory or a sorrowful memory to recreate.</p>
                <p class="indent">If you choose a joyful memory, you invoke an illusion of a better time now gone, which appears in a manner of your choosing, with visual effects and sounds. The illusion can be of something you remember or something you’ve heard described, and can move as it replays events as you believe they took place.</p>
                <p class="indent">If you choose a sorrowful memory, you invoke a shadowy illusion that appears different to each observer, but is painful to hear and witness. Hostile creatures that can see or hear the sorrowful memory must make a Charisma saving throw against your paladin spell save DC at the start of each of their turns. If a creature fails, it can’t voluntarily move closer to the memory during that turn.</p>
                <p class="indent">Each memory lasts up to 1 minute, or until you dismiss it (no action required). If you summon a memory in moonlight, it can last until touched by sunlight.</p>
                <p class="indent">If you create a second memory, the first vanishes.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Memento Mori" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OOSORROW_MEMENTO_MORI">
            <description>
                <p>At 20th level, you can use your action to invoke the true nature of your oath, surrounding yourself with the cold of winter and the memories of what has been lost. For 10 minutes, you gain the following benefits.</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>When you deal damage to a creature, you can choose to halve that creature’s speed for 1 minute.</li>
                    <li>Your Aura of Regret, Aura of Protection, and Aura of Courage expand to 120 feet.</li>
                    <li>Hostile creatures within your Aura of Regret make saving throws to maintain concentration with disadvantage.</li>
                    <li>You can have any number of memories summoned at the same time using your Moonlit Lamentation feature.</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>

</elements>