<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Wind Runner Ranger Archetype</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="ranger-wind-runner.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/compendium-of-sacred-mysteries-resurrection/ranger-wind-runner.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Wind Runner" type="Archetype" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_">
        <supports>Ranger Archetype</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The sky calls to the earth below, beckoning to the land. The wind whispers, screaming in the highest peaks and whispering in the quiet valleys below. You hear the voice hidden within the breeze, and it has become your constant companion. The soft caress of the air can be pleasant, but the furious tempest also carries the maddening sounds of the darkest places and the cries of the nightmares that dwell within. Rangers who follow your path reject the cruel grasp of the world beneath them, fighting against the wicked beasts and hellish things that lurk below. Your voice carries like the shout of a hurricane and your blades and arrows hiss as they cut the sky itself. You’ve chosen to embrace the breeze, calling upon it in your quest to venture beyond the earth. You’ve chosen to ascend, triumphant, as a wind runner.</p>
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WIND_RUNNERS_GIFT" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WHISPER_OF_THE_BREEZE" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MISTY_MOUNTAIN" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_EYE_OF_THE_TEMPEST" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VOICE_OF_THE_WHIRLWIND" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SKYWARD_ASCENSION" />
            <div class="sidebar">
                <h5>RANGER VARIANTS</h5>
                <p>If you don’t gain a feature at 5th level, use this one.</p>
                <h4>EXTRA ATTACK</h4>
                <p>Beginning at 5th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</p>
            </div>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WIND_RUNNERS_GIFT" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WHISPER_OF_THE_BREEZE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MISTY_MOUNTAIN" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_EYE_OF_THE_TEMPEST" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VOICE_OF_THE_WHIRLWIND" level="11" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SKYWARD_ASCENSION" level="15" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Wind Runner’s Gift" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WIND_RUNNERS_GIFT">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 3rd level, you learn additional spells when you reach certain levels in this class, as shown in the table below. The spells count as ranger spells for you, but don’t count against the number of ranger spells you know.</p>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Ranger Level</td><td>Spell</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>fog cloud</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>gust of wind</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><em>wind wall</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>13th</td><td><em>greater invisibility</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>17th</td><td><em>conjure elemental</em></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FOG_CLOUD" spellcasting="Ranger" known="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GUST_OF_WIND" spellcasting="Ranger" known="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WIND_WALL" spellcasting="Ranger" known="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GREATER_INVISIBILITY" spellcasting="Ranger" known="true" level="13" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONJURE_ELEMENTAL" spellcasting="Ranger" known="true" level="17" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Whisper of the Breeze" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WHISPER_OF_THE_BREEZE">
            <description>
                <p>At 3rd level, your affinity to the primal element of air allows you to speak to the wind, calling it to serve your purpose. Whenever you take the Attack action, before making your first attack, you can choose to guide the wind in one of the following ways for the described duration:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li><b>Arcing Gust:</b> This turn, when you see a ranged attack miss a target, you can use your reaction to whistle, guiding the projectile towards a new target you can see. Reroll the attack roll against a different target within 30 feet of the original target.</li>
                    <li><b>Hurricane Shout:</b> You take a deep breath, preparing to unleash the tempest. This turn, when a creature within 15 feet of you takes damage from a melee attack, you can use your reaction to let loose a buffeting yell. The creature or the attacker (your choice) must make a Strength saving throw against your ranger spell save DC. If it fails, it takes 1d6 force damage and is pushed back 10 feet or knocked prone (it’s choice).</li>
                    <li><b>Sky Dance:</b> You enter a defensive stance until the start of your next turn, exhaling to call the wind to your back. While you are in this stance, once per turn when a creature misses you with an attack or you succeed on a Dexterity saving throw, you can move up to 10 feet without provoking opportunity attacks.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Whenever you take the Attack action, before making your first attack, you can choose to guide the wind in one of the following ways for the described duration:</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WHISPER_OF_THE_BREEZE_ARCING_GUST" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WHISPER_OF_THE_BREEZE_HURRICANE_SHOUT" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WHISPER_OF_THE_BREEZE_SKY_DANCE" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Arcing Gust" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WHISPER_OF_THE_BREEZE_ARCING_GUST">
                <description>
                    <p>This turn, when you see a ranged attack miss a target, you can use your reaction to whistle, guiding the projectile towards a new target you can see. Reroll the attack roll against a different target within 30 feet of the original target.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet action="Reaction">
                    <description>When you see a ranged attack miss a target, you can guide the projectile towards a new target you can see. Reroll the attack roll against a different target within 30 feet of the original target.</description>
                    <description level="11">When you see a ranged attack miss a target, you can guide the projectile towards a new target you can see. Reroll the attack roll against a different target within 30 feet of the original target. If the attack misses the secondary target, you can choose to reroll the attack against the original target.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Hurricane Shout" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WHISPER_OF_THE_BREEZE_HURRICANE_SHOUT">
                <description>
                    <p>You take a deep breath, preparing to unleash the tempest. This turn, when a creature within 15 feet of you takes damage from a melee attack, you can use your reaction to let loose a buffeting yell. The creature or the attacker (your choice) must make a Strength saving throw against your ranger spell save DC. If it fails, it takes 1d6 force damage and is pushed back 10 feet or knocked prone (it’s choice).</p>
                </description>
                <sheet action="Reaction">
                    <description>When a creature within 15 feet of you takes damage from a melee attack, you can let loose a buffeting yell. The creature or the attacker (your choice) must make a Strength saving throw against your ranger spell save DC. If it fails, it takes 1d6 force damage and is pushed back 10 feet or knocked prone (it’s choice).</description>
                    <description level="11">When a creature within 15 feet of you takes damage from a melee attack, you can let loose a buffeting yell. The creature or the attacker (your choice) must make a Strength saving throw against your ranger spell save DC. If it fails, it takes 1d6 force damage and is pushed back 10 feet or knocked prone (it’s choice). If the target fails the saving throw, it is pushed back 20 feet or is knocked prone (it’s choice). If the target is knocked prone or impacts a surface due to this movement, it takes an additional 2d6 force damage.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Sky Dance" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WHISPER_OF_THE_BREEZE_SKY_DANCE">
                <description>
                    <p>You enter a defensive stance until the start of your next turn, exhaling to call the wind to your back. While you are in this stance, once per turn when a creature misses you with an attack or you succeed on a Dexterity saving throw, you can move up to 10 feet without provoking opportunity attacks.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>You enter a defensive stance until the start of your next turn. While you are in this stance, once per turn when a creature misses you with an attack or you succeed on a Dexterity saving throw, you can move up to 10 feet without provoking opportunity attacks.</description>
                    <description level="11">You enter a defensive stance until the start of your next turn. While you are in this stance, once per turn when a creature misses you with an attack or you succeed on a Dexterity saving throw, you can move up to 10 feet without provoking opportunity attacks. The first time you move due to this stance’s effect, your spirit charges with power, causing your next attack to deal an extra 2d8 lightning damage.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
        <element name="Misty Mountain" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MISTY_MOUNTAIN">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 3rd level, your dedication to this path has taken you to the highest places, sharpening your senses and training you to survive. You ignore disadvantage on Perception checks and are always acclimated to high altitudes. Falling damage you take is reduced by an amount equal to four times your ranger level, to a minimum of 0.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You ignore disadvantage on Perception checks and are always acclimated to high altitudes. Falling damage you take is reduced {{misty-mountain:damage-reduction}}, to a minimum of 0.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="misty-mountain:damage-reduction" value="level:ranger" />
                <stat name="misty-mountain:damage-reduction" value="level:ranger" />
                <stat name="misty-mountain:damage-reduction" value="level:ranger" />
                <stat name="misty-mountain:damage-reduction" value="level:ranger" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Eye of the Tempest" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_EYE_OF_THE_TEMPEST">
            <description>
                <p>At 7th level, your grace is supplemented by the whims of the breeze as you turn against your earthly origins. When you make a Dexterity saving throw, you can use your reaction to immediately fly a number of feet up to your walking speed without provoking opportunity attacks. If this movement would take you out of the range or area of the effect that forced you to make the saving throw, you gain advantage on the saving throw.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Reaction">
                <description>When you make a Dexterity saving throw, you can immediately fly up to {{speed}} feet without provoking opportunity attacks. If this movement would take you out of the range or area of the effect that forced you to make the saving throw, you gain advantage on the saving throw.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Voice of the Whirlwind" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VOICE_OF_THE_WHIRLWIND">
            <description>
                <p>At 11th level, you speak plainly with the wind itself, and it answers in earnest. The options granted to you by your Whisper of the Breeze feature improve in the following ways:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li><b>Arcing Gust:</b> If the attack misses the secondary target, you can choose to reroll the attack against the original target.</li>
                    <li><b>Hurricane Shout:</b> If the target fails the saving throw, it is pushed back 20 feet or is knocked prone (it’s choice). If the target is knocked prone or impacts a surface due to this movement, it takes an additional 2d6 force damage.</li>
                    <li><b>Sky Dance:</b> The first time you move due to this stance’s effect, your spirit charges with power, causing your next attack to deal an extra 2d8 lightning damage.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Skyward Ascension" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SKYWARD_ASCENSION">
            <description>
                <p>At 15th level, you are no longer bound to the earth that once hindered you. You can take the Dash action as a bonus action. When you take the Dash action, you gain a flying speed equal to your walking speed until the start of your next turn. If you do not Dash again at that time, you will fall. Whenever you voluntarily move while it is not your turn, you can choose to fly an equal distance instead.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>You can take the Dash action. When you take the Dash action, you gain a {{speed}}-foot flying speed until the start of your next turn. If you do not Dash again at that time, you will fall. Whenever you voluntarily move while it is not your turn, you can choose to fly an equal distance instead.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>    
</elements>