<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Seven-Sealed Savior Sorcerous Origin</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="sorcerer-seven-sealed-savior.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/compendium-of-sacred-mysteries-resurrection/sorcerer-seven-sealed-savior.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Seven-Sealed Savior" type="Archetype" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_SORCERER_SEVEN_SEALED_SAVIOR">
        <supports>Sorcerous Origin</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You are not alone. Inside your soul, there is a being of pure light, wild joy, and benevolent harmony. It saved you from death, and claims that you saved it as well. To protect you from its overwhelming power, it sealed itself inside your heart. As you act in accordance with the virtues of your guest, your power grows and wells forth from within you. Act with pure intent, and fight against darkness wherever you find it. You are not alone.</p>
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SEVEN_SEALED_SAVIOR_ORIGIN_SPELLS" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SEVEN_SEALED_SAVIOR_THE_SEVEN_SACRED_SEALS" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SEVEN_SEALED_SAVIOR_HARMONIOUS_ACTION" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SEVEN_SEALED_SAVIOR_HEAVENLY_GRACE" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SEVEN_SEALED_SAVIOR_CLEANSING_LIGHT" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SEVEN_SEALED_SAVIOR_ORIGIN_SPELLS" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SEVEN_SEALED_SAVIOR_THE_SEVEN_SACRED_SEALS" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SEVEN_SEALED_SAVIOR_HARMONIOUS_ACTION" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SEVEN_SEALED_SAVIOR_HEAVENLY_GRACE" level="14" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SEVEN_SEALED_SAVIOR_CLEANSING_LIGHT" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Origin Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SEVEN_SEALED_SAVIOR_ORIGIN_SPELLS">
            <description>
                <p>When you choose this sorcerous origin, you gain access to the following spells, which do not count against your spells known but can only be cast once you reach the required sorcerer level.</p>
                <h5 class="caption">SEVEN-SEALED SAVIOR ORIGIN SPELLS</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Sorcerer Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1st</td><td><em>cure wounds</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>calm emotions</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>revivify</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>7th</td><td><em>banishment</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><em>flame strike</em></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CURE_WOUNDS" level="1" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CALM_EMOTIONS" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_REVIVIFY" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BANISHMENT" level="7" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FLAME_STRIKE" level="9" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="The Seven Sacred Seals" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SEVEN_SEALED_SAVIOR_THE_SEVEN_SACRED_SEALS">
            <description>
                <p>At 1st level, the heavenly being within you begins to gradually loosen the seals containing it, allowing you to open the seals listed in the adjacent table by casting spells. Once you have expended all spell slots you possess of the listed spell level, you temporarily gain the feature described, losing access again when you regain one or more spell slots of that level. You must possess the minimum sorcerer level listed to unlock that seal’s feature.</p>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Spell Slot Level (Sorcerer Level)</td><td>Temporary Feature</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1st (1st)</td><td><strong>The First Seal of Purity.</strong> Your heart is open to the world. Whenever you use your action to cast a spell that targets one or more friendly creatures, you gain temporary hit points equal to twice your Charisma modifier (minimum 2).</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>2nd (3rd)</td><td><strong>The Second Seal of Temperance.</strong> You take no more than is needed. When you regain hit points that would exceed your hit point maximum, you can choose to distribute the excess hit points among creatures you can see within 30 feet of you.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3rd (5th)</td><td><strong>The Third Seal of Charity.</strong> You give freely to others. When you lose hit points, you can use your reaction to gift a creature you can see within 30 feet of you temporary hit points equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum 1). You can expend a number of sorcery points up to your sorcerer level to increase the amount of temporary hit points granted by 3 per sorcery point spent.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>4th (7th)</td><td><strong>The Fourth Seal of Diligence.</strong> You will not be turned aside from your purpose. When you are frightened or charmed, you can choose to end the condition on yourself using your bonus action by expending 2 sorcery points.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th (9th)</td><td><strong>The Fifth Seal of Patience.</strong> You understand that there is a time for everything. When you Ready an Action and do not perform it before the start of your next turn, you can take that action using your bonus action during your next turn, preventing spells cast for the readied action from being lost if they were not used.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>6th (11th)</td><td><strong>The Sixth Seal of Kindness.</strong> You are joyful when others succeed, and comfort them when they fail. When a creature you can see within 30 feet of you makes an attack roll, you can use your reaction to expend a number of sorcery points up to your sorcerer level to cause the creature to regain 4 hit points per sorcery point spent.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>7th (13th)</td><td><strong>The Seventh Seal of Humility.</strong> Despite your incredible power, you do not boast. When you would cause a creature to take damage, you can choose to instead mark it with a visible celestial inscription. When that creature would take damage from another creature, you can choose to trigger the inscription, dealing the original damage from your spell plus additional damage of the same type equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum 1). A creature can only have one inscription upon it at a time; applying a second inscription removes the first one.</td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Once you have expended all spell slots you possess of the listed spell level, you temporarily gain the feature described, losing access again when you regain one or more spell slots of that level. You must possess the minimum sorcerer level listed to unlock that seal’s feature.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SSS_FIRST_SACRED_SEAL" level="1" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SSS_SECOND_SACRED_SEAL" level="3" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SSS_THIRD_SACRED_SEAL" level="5" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SSS_FOURTH_SACRED_SEAL" level="7" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SSS_FIFTH_SACRED_SEAL" level="9" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SSS_SIXTH_SACRED_SEAL" level="11" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SSS_SEVENTH_SACRED_SEAL" level="13" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="The First Seal of Purity" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SSS_FIRST_SACRED_SEAL">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>Your heart is open to the world. Whenever you use your action to cast a spell that targets one or more friendly creatures, you gain temporary hit points equal to twice your Charisma modifier (minimum 2).</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Sacred Seal">
                    <description>Whenever you use your action to cast a spell that targets one or more friendly creatures, you gain {{first-seal:temp-hp}} temporary hit points</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="first-seal:temp-hp:base" value="1" bonus="base" />
                    <stat name="first-seal:temp-hp:base" value="charisma:modifier" bonus="base" />
                    <stat name="first-seal:temp-hp" value="first-seal:temp-hp:base" />
                    <stat name="first-seal:temp-hp" value="first-seal:temp-hp:base" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="The Second Seal of Temperance" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SSS_SECOND_SACRED_SEAL">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>You take no more than is needed. When you regain hit points that would exceed your hit point maximum, you can choose to distribute the excess hit points among creatures you can see within 30 feet of you.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Sacred Seal">
                    <description>When you regain hit points that would exceed your hit point maximum, you can choose to distribute the excess hit points among creatures you can see within 30 feet of you.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="The Third Seal of Charity" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SSS_THIRD_SACRED_SEAL">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>You give freely to others. When you lose hit points, you can use your reaction to gift a creature you can see within 30 feet of you temporary hit points equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum 1). You can expend a number of sorcery points up to your sorcerer level to increase the amount of temporary hit points granted by 3 per sorcery point spent.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Sacred Seal" action="Reaction">
                    <description>When you lose hit points, you can gift a creature you can see within 30 feet of you {{third-seal:temp-hp}} temporary hit points. You can expend up to {{level:sorcerer}} sorcery points to increase the amount of temporary hit points granted by 3 per sorcery point spent.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="third-seal:temp-hp" value="1" bonus="base" />
                    <stat name="third-seal:temp-hp" value="charisma:modifier" bonus="base" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="The Fourth Seal of Diligence" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SSS_FOURTH_SACRED_SEAL">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>You will not be turned aside from your purpose. When you are frightened or charmed, you can choose to end the condition on yourself using your bonus action by expending 2 sorcery points.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Sacred Seal" action="Bonus Action">
                    <description>When you are frightened or charmed, you can choose to end the condition on yourself by expending 2 sorcery points.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="The Fifth Seal of Patience" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SSS_FIFTH_SACRED_SEAL">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>You understand that there is a time for everything. When you Ready an Action and do not perform it before the start of your next turn, you can take that action using your bonus action during your next turn, preventing spells cast for the readied action from being lost if they were not used.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Sacred Seal">
                    <description>When you Ready an Action and do not perform it before the start of your next turn, you can take that action using your bonus action during your next turn, preventing spells cast for the readied action from being lost if they were not used</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="The Sixth Seal of Kindness" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SSS_SIXTH_SACRED_SEAL">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>You are joyful when others succeed, and comfort them when they fail. When a creature you can see within 30 feet of you makes an attack roll, you can use your reaction to expend a number of sorcery points up to your sorcerer level to cause the creature to regain 4 hit points per sorcery point spent.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Sacred Seal" action="Reaction">
                    <description>When a creature you can see within 30 feet of you makes an attack roll, you can expend up to {{level:sorcerer}} sorcery points to cause the creature to regain 4 hit points per sorcery point spent.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="The Seventh Seal of Humility" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SSS_SEVENTH_SACRED_SEAL">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>Despite your incredible power, you do not boast. When you would cause a creature to take damage, you can choose to instead mark it with a visible celestial inscription. When that creature would take damage from another creature, you can choose to trigger the inscription, dealing the original damage from your spell plus additional damage of the same type equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum 1). A creature can only have one inscription upon it at a time; applying a second inscription removes the first one.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Sacred Seal">
                    <description>When you would cause a creature to take damage, you can choose to instead mark it with a visible celestial inscription. When that creature would take damage from another creature, you can choose to trigger the inscription, dealing the original damage from your spell plus {{seventh-seal:damage}} additional damage of the same type. A creature can only have one inscription upon it at a time; applying a second inscription removes the first one.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="seventh-seal:damage" value="1" bonus="base" />
                    <stat name="seventh-seal:damage" value="charisma:modifier" bonus="base" />
                </rules>
            </element>
        <element name="Harmonious Action" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SEVEN_SEALED_SAVIOR_HARMONIOUS_ACTION">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 6th level, you work in unison with your guest to aid those in need. When you take the Help action to assist a creature with an ability check, that creature gains a bonus to the roll equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum 1).</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you take the Help action to assist a creature with an ability check, that creature gains a +{{harmonious-action:bonus}} bonus to the roll.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="harmonious-action:bonus" value="1" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="harmonious-action:bonus" value="charisma:modifier" bonus="base" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Heavenly Grace" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SEVEN_SEALED_SAVIOR_HEAVENLY_GRACE">
            <description>
                <p>At 14th level, the power of your savior frees you from the constraints of cruelty and harm. You are permanently under the effects of the <em>freedom of movement</em> spell.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You are permanently under the effects of the freedom of movement spell.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FREEDOM_OF_MOVEMENT" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Cleansing Light" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SEVEN_SEALED_SAVIOR_CLEANSING_LIGHT">
            <description>
                <p>At 18th level, once per turn when a hostile creature targets you with a melee attack, it must make a Wisdom saving throw. If it fails, it is blinded, prior to rolling to hit, until the start of its next turn. Additionally, when you cast a spell that causes a creature to regain hit points, you can cause that creature to no longer be charmed, frightened, or stunned.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Once per turn when a hostile creature targets you with a melee attack, it must make a Wisdom saving throw. If it fails, it is blinded, prior to rolling to hit, until the start of its next turn. Additionally, when you cast a spell that causes a creature to regain hit points, you can cause that creature to no longer be charmed, frightened, or stunned.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

</elements>