<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Compendium of Sacred Mysteries Spells</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="spells.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/compendium-of-sacred-mysteries-resurrection/spells.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Mercurial Weapon" type="Spell" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_SPELL_MERCURIAL_WEAPON">
        <supports>Druid, Ranger, Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Liquid and elusive, puncturingflesh and drinking blood, a gluttonous eel with a taste for the macabre.</p>
            <p>You pour energy into a melee weapon you are holding, your magic making it flex and twist in harmony with its wielder. For the duration, the weapon’s reach increases by 5 feet, and it ignores half and three-quarters cover. If the weapon leaves your possession, the spell ends.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">transmutation</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">1 minute</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Conductive Spike" type="Spell" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_SPELL_CONDUCTIVE_SPIKE">
        <supports>Druid, Ranger, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">The earth and sky are united in more ways than most expect, for each desires to make its mark upon the other.</p>
            <p>You raise a hand, calling a spike of metal from the earth at a point you can see within range. If the point is below a creature, the creature must make a Dexterity saving throw. If the creature fails, it takes 4d8 magical piercing damage, or half as much damage if it succeeds.</p>
            <p class="indent">The spike remains for the duration of the spell. If the spike is within the area of a spell or effect that deals lightning damage, the spike absorbs and amplifies some of that power, becoming charged. You can use your bonus action during your turn to release the charge, causing an explosion of lightning in a 10-foot radius around the spike. All creatures within the radius must make a Dexterity saving throw. If a creature fails, it takes 6d6 lightning damage, or half as much damage if it succeeds.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the piercing and lightning damage each increase by 1d6 per slot level above 3rd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">conjuration</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a small metal spike</set>
            <set name="duration">1 minute</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Arclight Trinity" type="Spell" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_SPELL_ARCLIGHT_TRINITY">
        <supports>Cleric, Paladin, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">True purification requires a willingness to cleanse and excise that which is corrupt and wretched without regard to what will be lost.</p>
            <p>You unleash a deadly arc of light, flame, and shocking energy between three points of your choosing that you can see within range, creating a triangular slice of destruction in the space between the points. Each creature within the area must make a Dexterity saving throw. If a creature fails, it takes 2d6 fire, 2d6 lightning, and 2d6 radiant damage, or half as much damage if it succeeds. Unattended objects within the area take twice as much damage.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, either the fire, lightining, or radiant damage (your choice) increases by 1d6 per slot level above 4th.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">4</set>
            <set name="school">evocation</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a shard of glass</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Hand of Hell" type="Spell" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_SPELL_HAND_OF_HELL">
        <supports>Cleric, Paladin, Warlock</supports>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">In a place of fire and punishment, the only fuel left to burn is the flesh of the sinful and wicked.</p>
            <p>With a gesture, you call forth a massive burning gauntlet from the ground at an unoccupied point you can see within range, filling a 5-foot cube. Fire constantly pours from the gauntlet’s palm in a linear blast that is 5 feet wide and 30 feet long, pointed in a direction of your choosing. When a creature enters the area or starts its turn within, it must make a Dexterity saving throw. If a creature fails, it takes 5d6 fire damage, or half as much damage if it succeeds.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can use your action to cause the gauntlet to close and reopen, blasting fire in a new direction of your choosing. When the spell ends, the gauntlet and fire vanish.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 6th level or higher, the fire damage increases by 2d6 per two slot levels above 4th.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">4</set>
            <set name="school">conjuration</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">an iron gauntlet</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute.</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
</elements>