<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Demi-Dragon 4.0.2 Backgrounds</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="backgrounds-demi-dragon.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/aron/backgrounds-demi-dragon.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Chosen of the Community" type="Background" source="Demi-Dragon" id="ID_ARON_DD_BACKGROUND_CHOSEN_OF_THE_COMMUNITY">
        <description>
            <p>You were chosen by a small community of individuals to undergo transformation. Perhaps you were a promising young warrior who was deemed ready to take part in an ancient ritual, or perhaps you were part of a group of zealous dragon worshippers, honored to be selected as a vessel for their devotion. Regardless of how the rest of the world may view you now, you can always count on the small group of people that stand at your back, perceiving you as an exalted idol.</p>
            <p><b>Skill Proficiencies:</b> Persuasion, Religion</p>
            <p><b>Tool Proficiencies:</b> One type of artisan's tools</p>
            <p><b>Languages:</b> One of your choice</p>
            <p><b>Equipment:</b> A set of artisan's tools (one of your choice), the symbol of your community (a signet ring, a religious emblem, a brand or scale-wrought tattoo), and a pouch containing 10 gp</p>
            <h5>Shared Society</h5>
            <p>You previously pursued a simple profession among your community before you were chosen. Your community and your role within it have played a defining part in your life. Choose or randomly determine the nature of your community from the table below.</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d6</td><td>Community</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>You are part of a clan of barbarians far from here. Each century, a warrior is selected to take on the role of guardian and keep the elements at bay.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>You are a member of a secret society that is searching for a way to prolong life. You are the latest experiment.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>A small group of demi-dragons travels the country-side, offering transformation to those who are willing. You accepted, and found a start to a new life.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>Selected by your village to confront an ancient dragon, you had expected to meet death. Instead, the dragon agreed to your terms, but bound you in a magical pact.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>As an acolyte of a dragon god, your prayers for strength were one day answered. The priesthood has since recognized you as a minor saint.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>You were part of an adventurers guild for years before an unfortunate accident caused your transformation.</td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_ARON_DD_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_CHOSEN_OF_THE_COMMUNITY_COMMUNITY_SUPPORT" />
            <h5>SUGGESTED CHARACTERISTICS</h5>
            <p>Though different from those around you, you've been accepted as part of the community, and have shared in local values, customs, and daily practices.</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d8</td><td>Personality Trait</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>I always put others ahead of myself.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>I prefer to listen to the opinions of those around me before speaking my mind.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>I like to hear myself talk.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>I am loyal and dependable to the end.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>My life is built on secrets, as is my community.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>I always act with great solemnity and ceremony.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>7</td><td>I have adopted the persona that my community believes me to be, but that's not the real me.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>8</td><td>I feel like an outsider and a fraud, unable to really connect with those around me.</td></tr>
            </table>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d6</td><td>Ideal</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td><b>For the Cause.</b> I have an important mission to carry out that will benefit all. (Good)</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td><b>Tradition.</b> I uphold the traditions of my community and bring honor to us all. (Lawful)</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td><b>Peace.</b> We can only be truly happy in those rare moments of quiet. (Neutral)</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td><b>Adventure.</b> Home is well and good, but I only truly live when I break away from daily life. (Chaotic)</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td><b>Prestige.</b> I will spread my influence far and wide, and use it for my own ends. (Evil)</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td><b>Bravery.</b> To act when others quake in fear—this is the essence of the warrior. (Any)</td></tr>
            </table>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d6</td><td>Bond</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>I used to work as a craftsman, and I still have a close relationship with the artisan who taught me.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>I am a natural-born leader, and have worked for years to coordinate with my community.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>My family has taken my transformation poorly.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>My community is split into opposed factions, with me at the center of the conflict.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>My community has entrusted me with a mission. I must live up what is expected of me.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>I have grown distant from those around me since my transformation. Things can't ever be the same again.</td></tr>
            </table>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d6</td><td>Flaw</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>I desperately crave acceptance from those around me. I am terrified of being rejected.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>I worry that others now think of me as strange, and obsess over the smallest comment or glance.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>I have certain traditions and rituals that I follow routinely. I must never fail to uphold them.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>I secretly believe that I am more important than others.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>I believe in complicated conspiracy movements that explain the real truth of this world.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>I believe myself a leader, but I'm not actually good at it. I get very defensive about it when others bring it up.</td></tr>
            </table>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_ARON_DD_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_CHOSEN_OF_THE_COMMUNITY_COMMUNITY_SUPPORT" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_OPTIONAL_BACKGROUND_FEATURE"/>
            <select type="List" name="Personality Trait" number="2">
                <item id="1">I always put others ahead of myself.</item>
                <item id="2">I prefer to listen to the opinions of those around me before speaking my mind.</item>
                <item id="3">I like to hear myself talk.</item>
                <item id="4">I am loyal and dependable to the end.</item>
                <item id="5">My life is built on secrets, as is my community.</item>
                <item id="6">I always act with great solemnity and ceremony.</item>
                <item id="7">I have adopted the persona that my community believes me to be, but that's not the real me.</item>
                <item id="8">I feel like an outsider and a fraud, unable to really connect with those around me.</item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="Ideal">
                <item id="1">For the Cause. I have an important mission to carry out that will benefit all. (Good)</item>
                <item id="2">Tradition. I uphold the traditions of my community and bring honor to us all. (Lawful)</item>
                <item id="3">Peace. We can only be truly happy in those rare moments of quiet. (Neutral)</item>
                <item id="4">Adventure. Home is well and good, but I only truly live when I break away from daily life. (Chaotic)</item>
                <item id="5">Prestige. I will spread my influence far and wide, and use it for my own ends. (Evil)</item>
                <item id="6">Bravery. To act when others quake in fear—this is the essence of the warrior. (Any)</item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="Bond">
                <item id="1">I used to work as a craftsman, and I still have a close relationship with the artisan who taught me.</item>
                <item id="2">I am a natural-born leader, and have worked for years to coordinate with my community.</item>
                <item id="3">My family has taken my transformation poorly.</item>
                <item id="4">My community is split into opposed factions, with me at the center of the conflict.</item>
                <item id="5">My community has entrusted me with a mission. I must live up what is expected of me.</item>
                <item id="6">I have grown distant from those around me since my transformation. Things can't ever be the same again.</item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="Flaw">
                <item id="1">I desperately crave acceptance from those around me. I am terrified of being rejected.</item>
                <item id="2">I worry that others now think of me as strange, and obsess over the smallest comment or glance.</item>
                <item id="3">I have certain traditions and rituals that I follow routinely. I must never fail to uphold them.</item>
                <item id="4">I secretly believe that I am more important than others.</item>
                <item id="5">I believe in complicated conspiracy movements that explain the real truth of this world.</item>
                <item id="6">I believe myself a leader, but I'm not actually good at it. I get very defensive about it when others bring it up.</item>
            </select>
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Feature: Community Support" type="Background Feature" source="Demi-Dragon" id="ID_ARON_DD_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_CHOSEN_OF_THE_COMMUNITY_COMMUNITY_SUPPORT">
            <description>
                <p>You are accepted as part of a community that will care for you and provide you with shelter, food, and any information that they can. Your community will shield you from the law or anyone else searching for you, though they will not risk their lives for you.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>

    <element name="Curse of Greed" type="Background" source="Demi-Dragon" id="ID_ARON_DD_BACKGROUND_CURSE_OF_GREED">
        <description>
            <p>In a moment of weakness, you gave in to your own avaricious nature—an action that resulted in a curse of transformation being placed upon you. Perhaps a god, a fey, or some other entity took umbrage with your act of selfishness and condemned you to spend your days in the guise of a creature that is defined by greed, or perhaps your own act simply brought out the worst in you. Either way, your curse is a life-changing experience that leads you to answer the call to adventure. Will you seek to break the curse, or embrace it?</p>
            <p><b>Skill Proficiencies:</b> Deception, Sleight of Hand</p>
            <p><b>Tool Proficiencies:</b> Jeweler's tools</p>
            <p><b>Languages:</b> One of your choice</p>
            <p><b>Equipment:</b> A set of jeweler's tools, a token from the event that cursed you, a pouch containing 20 gp</p>
            <div element="ID_ARON_DD_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_CURSE_OF_GREED_EYE_FOR_VALUE" />
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d6</td><td>Cause of Curse</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>I came across a hoard of wealth and claimed it as my own, an action that later brought its true owner's spite down upon me.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>I entered into a wager with a hag, hoping to win a large sum of money. I lost, and paid the price.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>I betrayed someone who was near to me, hoping to take their wealth for my own.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>I used my wealth to purchase prolonged life, not realizing that what I had bought was dragon's blood.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>I had been stealing from powerful people. When I was found out, I was punished and exiled.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>The magic of a cursed item changed me.</td></tr>
            </table>
            <p class="indent">If the source of your curse is an item, choose from the table below, or decide on an appropriate item yourself.</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d6</td><td>Cursed Item</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>A golden armring</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>An inscribed golden coin</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>A book of indecipherable lore</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>A pendant carved from dragon scale</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>A gem shining with a radiant light only I see</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>A polished chunk of amber with a tiny dragon within</td></tr>
            </table>
            <h5>SUGGESTED CHARACTERISTICS</h5>
            <p>Though anyone can fall victim to greed, you are more familiar with it than most, having paid with your own humanity for your folly. However, what defines you isn't the price you paid, but your attitude going forwards.</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d8</td><td>Personality Trait</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>I am easily distracted by shiny objects.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>Sometimes, I dream of sleeping on a bed of gold.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>I studiously avoid reacting to objects of wealth when others are near, even though I secretly want them.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>I now want nothing at all to do with gold and wealth.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>I am deeply annoyed that my curse is preventing me from fully living out my dreams of opulence.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>I want to own only the finest and most prestigious of the many rare and exotic objects that come before me.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>7</td><td>I think of myself as a connoisseur of the pleasures of life—fine food and drink especially.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>8</td><td>I am generous. Once every month.</td></tr>
            </table>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d6</td><td>Ideal</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td><b>Selflessness.</b> I've learned my lesson, and now want to give instead of receive. (Good)</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td><b>Efficiency.</b> I always drive those around me to be better—after all, that just might benefit me. (Lawful)</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td><b>Acceptance.</b> The mistakes of the past are better left forgotten. I lead a new life now. (Neutral)</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td><b>Results.</b> I care nothing for the price, all that matters is that I get what I want. (Chaotic)</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td><b>Greed.</b> I regret nothing, and want more. (Evil)</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td><b>Pride.</b> I deserve my own success, and will fight fang and claw for every victory. (Any)</td></tr>
            </table>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d6</td><td>Bond</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>I have a close friend, the only person I think I can really trust with the whole truth.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>I still keep in loose contact with my family. They don't know about my curse.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>I've found it difficult to relate to the people I used to, and instead prefer the company of a beloved pet.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>My act of greed was actually done in the name of the love of my life, so that we could be together.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>I will do anything to prove myself superior to my hated rival.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>The only thing I really love is the luster of gold and the glint of metal.</td></tr>
            </table>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d6</td><td>Flaw</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>I am beset by greedy impulses, collecting every bit of wealth that I can.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>I get angry when reminded of my mistakes.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>When people fail to live up to my expectations, I don't hesitate to let them know.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>I can't help but let everyone know that I am wealthier than they.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>I judge people based on what they own.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>I can't trust those around me.</td></tr>
            </table>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_ARON_DD_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_CURSE_OF_GREED_EYE_FOR_VALUE" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_OPTIONAL_BACKGROUND_FEATURE"/>
            <select type="List" name="Personality Trait" number="2">
                <item id="1">I am easily distracted by shiny objects.</item>
                <item id="2">Sometimes, I dream of sleeping on a bed of gold.</item>
                <item id="3">I studiously avoid reacting to objects of wealth when others are near, even though I secretly want them.</item>
                <item id="4">I now want nothing at all to do with gold and wealth.</item>
                <item id="5">I am deeply annoyed that my curse is preventing me from fully living out my dreams of opulence.</item>
                <item id="6">I want to own only the finest and most prestigious of the many rare and exotic objects that come before me.</item>
                <item id="7">I think of myself as a connoisseur of the pleasures of life—fine food and drink especially.</item>
                <item id="8">I am generous. Once every month.</item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="Ideal">
                <item id="1">Selflessness. I've learned my lesson, and now want to give instead of receive. (Good)</item>
                <item id="2">Efficiency. I always drive those around me to be better—after all, that just might benefit me. (Lawful)</item>
                <item id="3">Acceptance. The mistakes of the past are better left forgotten. I lead a new life now. (Neutral)</item>
                <item id="4">Results. I care nothing for the price, all that matters is that I get what I want. (Chaotic)</item>
                <item id="5">Greed. I regret nothing, and want more. (Evil)</item>
                <item id="6">Pride. I deserve my own success, and will fight fang and claw for every victory. (Any)</item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="Bond">
                <item id="1">I have a close friend, the only person I think I can really trust with the whole truth.</item>
                <item id="2">I still keep in loose contact with my family. They don't know about my curse.</item>
                <item id="3">I've found it difficult to relate to the people I used to, and instead prefer the company of a beloved pet.</item>
                <item id="4">My act of greed was actually done in the name of the love of my life, so that we could be together.</item>
                <item id="5">I will do anything to prove myself superior to my hated rival.</item>
                <item id="6">The only thing I really love is the luster of gold and the glint of metal.</item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="Flaw">
                <item id="1">I am beset by greedy impulses, collecting every bit of wealth that I can.</item>
                <item id="2">I get angry when reminded of my mistakes.</item>
                <item id="3">When people fail to live up to my expectations, I don't hesitate to let them know.</item>
                <item id="4">I can't help but let everyone know that I am wealthier than they.</item>
                <item id="5">I judge people based on what they own.</item>
                <item id="6">I can't trust those around me.</item>
            </select>
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Feature: Eye for Value" type="Background Feature" source="Demi-Dragon" id="ID_ARON_DD_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_CURSE_OF_GREED_EYE_FOR_VALUE">
            <description>
                <p>Whether or not you've chosen to embrace your curse and its source, you've taken a keen interest in the worth of a multitude of objects, learning the prices of everything around you. When appraising a mundane item, you know its exact value measured in copper, silver, and gold.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>

    <element name="True-Born Dragon" type="Background" source="Demi-Dragon" id="ID_ARON_DD_BACKGROUND_TRUE_BORN_DRAGON">
        <description>
            <p>Born a true dragon, you are legend embodied and heir to countless myths and stories. Though true dragons don't usually lead lives of adventure—often preferring to safely amass power by growing old—something has pushed you to seek out such a life. Still young, you must navigate both the trials of adventure and the prejudice of a world that fears you.</p>
            <p><b>Skill Proficiencies:</b> Perception, Stealth</p>
            <p><b>Languages:</b> Two of your choice</p>
            <p><b>Equipment:</b> A meager hoard, containing cheap gemstones and a mix of various coins totaling a value of 30 gp</p>
            <p><b>Class Feature Variants:</b> Use the rules for Resolution, replacing Devour Magic</p>
            <div element="ID_ARON_DD_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_TRUE_BORN_DRAGON_DRAGONS_LAIR" />
            <h5>Inherent Nature</h5>
            <p>Dragonkind is split into ten bloodlines, each of which is ruled by different traits. The traits shared by these bloodlines run strong in all dragons of that type, like a powerful natural-born inclination towards a certain way of acting, and although it is possible for an individual to defy their nature, they can never get rid of it. A chromatic dragon may be raised with great difficulty to act with good intentions, but the temptation to give in to their darker side will always remain—likewise, a metallic dragon may fall prey to evil influence, but will tend to retain a benevolent predisposition.</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Type</td><td>Inherent Nature</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>Black</td><td>You have a predisposition towards cruelty, and find great satisfaction in bringing ruination to everything around you. You are best at home when you are unseen, hidden by darkness or beneath fetid swamp waters.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Blue</td><td>To your ordered mind, everything has its place in the world—it's just that most of it exists purely for your benefit. Other creatures are merely a means to an end, and those who don't understand their place deserve to be made an example of.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Brass</td><td>You can't help but enjoy the sound of your own voice, and can talk ceaselessly for hours on end about practically anything. You find gossip and the motivations of lesser creatures to be fascinating.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Bronze</td><td>You have an inquisitive mind, and can't help but want to right wrongs and bring evildoers to justice. You tend to prefer anonymity, and only open up to a few people that are close to you.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Copper</td><td>You have an appreciation for wit, wordplay, and humor. Dazzling others with your cleverness—whether by pranking them, sharing an insightful story, or causing them to laugh—has a certain intrinsic appeal to it.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Gold</td><td>Reserved and insightful, you tend to consider before speaking, and can't help but hold others to the same high standards of order, piety, and morality that you tend to gravitate towards.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Green</td><td>You see other creatures as tools that can be manipulated with subtlety and cunning to get you what you want. Your long-lasting plots and schemes are often strongly motivated by short bursts of emotion—whether anger, fear, or greed.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Red</td><td>You are better than everyone and everything, and all should learn to grovel before you or face your wrath. You can't help but revel in destruction, brutality, and conquest. You feel compelled to invent complex strategies to improve your odds of victory and squash out the possibility of defeat.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Silver</td><td>You tend to be open, honest, and tolerant, and you can't help but sympathize with those in need—especially lesser creatures who are down on their luck. The history and actions of the mortal races is a subject of your endless fascination.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>White</td><td>You delight in your physicality, living in the moment and expressing yourself through movement and action, viewing all others as prey to be chased. You disdain speech, and have trouble grasping abstract concepts or promises.</td></tr>
            </table>
            <h5>SUGGESTED CHARACTERISTICS</h5>
            <p>Dragons tend to view the world differently than the mortal races, and their worldview is shaped chiefly by their inherent nature, and secondarily by their surroundings and experiences. Most dragons are lonesome outsiders that never truly belong around others, and only a few ever find genuine companionship.</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d8</td><td>Personality Trait</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>I want to be remembered as a mythical dragon of which tales are told and songs are made.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>I consider myself a knowledgeable scholar of a particular subject, which holds my eternal fascination.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>I love exploring the land and trying new experiences.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>I want to change how mortals view dragonkind.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>I want to defy my inherent nature through great effort, but it is a constant, daily struggle.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>I am faithful to a god, whose decree I seek to carry out.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>7</td><td>I idolize a particular ancient dragon, whose stories and legends I model myself after.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>8</td><td>I try to rebel against the expectations that people often have of dragons, and go out of my way to be different.</td></tr>
            </table>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d6</td><td>Ideal</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td><b>Justice.</b> I will use my strength to protect others from those that would cause harm. (Good)</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td><b>Authority.</b> The mortal races must be led by those who know better. (Lawful)</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td><b>Freedom.</b> I will not be beholden to anything or anyone. My path is mine alone. (Chaotic)</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td><b>Might.</b> The power to do as I please is all that matters. (Evil)</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td><b>Treasure.</b> Through wealth, I shall live beyond death. I must amass treasure to transcend mortality. (Any)</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td><b>Arrogance.</b> In fact, I am better than everyone else. (Any)</td></tr>
            </table>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d6</td><td>Bond</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>My relationship with my siblings or parents drives me to continually seek to always meet expectations.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>I was left abandoned when I hatched, and soon after learned not to trust strangers.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>I was raised by a mortal, and though I love my foster parent, I never really fit in.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>I haven't had many to speak with, and have filled the void with an imaginary friend that I talk to.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>One day, I met and befriended an explorer. We still regularly speak or exchange letters.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>My only companions are the weak mortals that I subjugate to do my bidding.</td></tr>
            </table>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d6</td><td>Flaw</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>I am flawless. Those who say otherwise earn my ire.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>I like to be worshiped or praised, and will aggressively encourage others to do so.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>I am full of boasts and clever jests that drive home how much better than the mortal races I am.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>I hate being questioned or second-guessed.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>I am often unpleasantly surprised when others don't give me the attention that I clearly deserve.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>As I view it, in this world, there are only predators and prey, and I will be a predator.</td></tr>
            </table>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_ARON_DD_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_TRUE_BORN_DRAGON_DRAGONS_LAIR" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_OPTIONAL_BACKGROUND_FEATURE"/>
            <select type="List" name="Personality Trait" number="2">
                <item id="1">I want to be remembered as a mythical dragon of which tales are told and songs are made.</item>
                <item id="2">I consider myself a knowledgeable scholar of a particular subject, which holds my eternal fascination.</item>
                <item id="3">I love exploring the land and trying new experiences.</item>
                <item id="4">I want to change how mortals view dragonkind.</item>
                <item id="5">I want to defy my inherent nature through great effort, but it is a constant, daily struggle.</item>
                <item id="6">I am faithful to a god, whose decree I seek to carry out.</item>
                <item id="7">I idolize a particular ancient dragon, whose stories and legends I model myself after.</item>
                <item id="8">I try to rebel against the expectations that people often have of dragons, and go out of my way to be different.</item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="Ideal">
                <item id="1">Justice. I will use my strength to protect others from those that would cause harm. (Good)</item>
                <item id="2">Authority. The mortal races must be led by those who know better. (Lawful)</item>
                <item id="3">Freedom. I will not be beholden to anything or anyone. My path is mine alone. (Chaotic)</item>
                <item id="4">Might. The power to do as I please is all that matters. (Evil)</item>
                <item id="5">Treasure. Through wealth, I shall live beyond death. I must amass treasure to transcend mortality. (Any)</item>
                <item id="6">Arrogance. In fact, I am better than everyone else. (Any)</item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="Bond">
                <item id="1">My relationship with my siblings or parents drives me to continually seek to always meet expectations.</item>
                <item id="2">I was left abandoned when I hatched, and soon after learned not to trust strangers.</item>
                <item id="3">I was raised by a mortal, and though I love my foster parent, I never really fit in.</item>
                <item id="4">I haven't had many to speak with, and have filled the void with an imaginary friend that I talk to.</item>
                <item id="5">One day, I met and befriended an explorer. We still regularly speak or exchange letters.</item>
                <item id="6">My only companions are the weak mortals that I subjugate to do my bidding.</item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="Flaw">
                <item id="1">I am flawless. Those who say otherwise earn my ire.</item>
                <item id="2">I like to be worshiped or praised, and will aggressively encourage others to do so.</item>
                <item id="3">I am full of boasts and clever jests that drive home how much better than the mortal races I am.</item>
                <item id="4">I hate being questioned or second-guessed.</item>
                <item id="5">I am often unpleasantly surprised when others don't give me the attention that I clearly deserve.</item>
                <item id="6">As I view it, in this world, there are only predators and prey, and I will be a predator.</item>
            </select>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Feature: Dragon's Lair" type="Background Feature" source="Demi-Dragon" id="ID_ARON_DD_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_TRUE_BORN_DRAGON_DRAGONS_LAIR">
            <description>
                <p>Your natural lifespan is counted in the thousands of years, and you never suffer any ill effects from old age.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, you have a knack for locating a suitable lair for your own use. This lair can be anything from an abandoned cave to an underwater cove, an old fort, a forest glade, a hollow glacier, or a forgotten house. Any lair that you make use of gains no special benefits, but readily provides you with a safe haven away from prying eyes.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>

    <element name="Victim Of Thaumaturgy" type="Background" source="Demi-Dragon" id="ID_ARON_DD_BACKGROUND_VICTIM_OF_THAUMATURGY">
        <description>
            <p><p>You've met an unfortunate fate. Against your own will, you were plucked from your old life and forced to give up your humanity at the behest of your captor. Held against your will, you had plenty of time to observe your captor, and eventually formulated an escape plan or reached an agreement with your captor or another entity. Regardless of how you've won your freedom, your life can never be the same again.</p></p>
            <p><b>Skill Proficiencies:</b> Arcana, Insight</p>
            <p><b>Tool Proficiencies:</b> Choose between alchemist's supplies, tinker's tools, poisoner's kit, and thieves' tools</p>
            <p><b>Languages:</b> One of your choice</p>
            <p><b>Equipment:</b> A set of tools (one of your choice), a token belonging to your captor, a sack of stolen or gifted valuables totaling 15 gp</p>
            <div element="ID_ARON_DD_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_VICTIM_OF_THAUMATURGY_THAUMATURGIC_RITES" />
            <h5>OPPRESSIVE CAPTOR</h5>
            <p>Your captor has been a brief but influental figure in your life. Depending on the nature of your captor, perhaps you've had time to watch them perform their thaumaturgic work, or perhaps even gotten to know them. While a captor may be a cruel and selfish lunatic from whom you must escape, they may just as easily be eccentric or misguided, and may have offered you your freedom of their own free will. Work with your DM to determine who your captor is, what your relationship to them is like, or use the table below.</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d6</td><td>Captor</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>A crazed wizard abducted you and used you as a test subject in their mad pursuit for immortality.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>An ancient dragon destroyed your home and offered you a choice: die, or serve and be transformed.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>The Cult of the Dragon chose you to trial their blood magics, as the first of many more to come.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>You were ritually sacrificed to a god. Though you died, the god offered you rebirth in exchange for servitude.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>An abishai used you as part of an experiment to break free from Tiamat's control, and now roams the Material Plane, leaving you to escape on your own.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>A powerful entity punished a wyrmling dragon with mortality, and swapped your form for the dragon's. Now the dragon roams the world with your old body.</td></tr>
            </table>
            <h5>LINGERING QUIRK</h5>
            <p>Your unique experiences have left their mark on you, manifesting as a peculiar quirk. Choose what this means for you, or roll on the table below.</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d6</td><td>Quirk</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>Your form is a mishmash of different dragon types.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>You are haunted by the voice of your captor or another captive, and sometimes hear that voice speak to you.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>Your body is artificial and is made of stone, wood, or metal, like a draconic version of a warforged.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>When you look at your reflection, it's the old you staring back.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>You bear the memories of a wyrmling dragon which you've learned was slain by your captor.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>You are scaleless—flawed and incomplete.</td></tr>
            </table>
            <h5>SUGGESTED CHARACTERISTICS</h5>
            <p>You've gone through the trauma of having your body changed against your will. Your attitude towards this event is crucial—will you embrace this change, or rage against it?</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d8</td><td>Personality Trait</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>I am cautious in my dealings with others.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>I am always fiddling with tools, vials, and other components relevant to my new dragon studies.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>The life I left behind was dull, and I don't regret trading it for one of adventure.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>I judge people by how they treat others, rather than by what they say or how they appear.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>I joke about my condition as if it doesn't matter to me.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>It's not all bad. I love flying and exploring new places!</td></tr>
                <tr><td>7</td><td>I get angry easily, and afterwards, I can't help but be a little afraid of myself.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>8</td><td>I must battle this monster I've become, lest I slip and hurt someone I care for.</td></tr>
            </table>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d6</td><td>Ideal</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td><b>Confrontation.</b> I adventure to make the world a safer place, and to exorcise my own demons. (Good)</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td><b>Progress.</b> We must advance our knowledge for the good of the world, even of darker subjects. (Lawful)</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td><b>Self-Determination.</b> Everyone should be free to make their own choices, be they good or bad. (Chaotic)</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td><b>Depravity.</b> I've seen what one dark ritual can do, and I harbor an unshakable hunger to know more. (Evil)</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td><b>Change.</b> Life is constant change, and I will learn to adapt to any circumstance. (Neutral)</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td><b>Destiny.</b> I believe that my circumstances are a road to be traveled, and that my journey has just started. (Any)</td></tr>
            </table>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d6</td><td>Bond</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>I seek to undo what's been done to me, and will pursue a way to do so by any means necessary.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>I got to know one of my captor's other captives. They didn't survive, and I now seek to carry on their legacy.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>Though I didn't have a choice, my captor wasn't so bad after all, and I now work for them.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>I miss my family, but I can't face them like this.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>The few people who are nice to me are like a beacon of hope. They matter more than anything else.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>I stick up for anyone that is treated poorly.</td></tr>
            </table>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d6</td><td>Flaw</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>I don't trust people easily.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>I feel like I didn't deserve to survive when there were others who didn't make it.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>I will shout loudly at anyone who makes mean comments about my form until they shut up.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>Others are afraid of me now. I like that.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>I've never felt more distanced from others, and sometimes I will cry myself to sleep in loneliness.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>I always expect the worst from others. I am genuinely surprised when they occasionally prove me wrong.</td></tr>
            </table>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_ARON_DD_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_VICTIM_OF_THAUMATURGY_THAUMATURGIC_RITES" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_OPTIONAL_BACKGROUND_FEATURE"/>
            <select type="List" name="Personality Trait" number="2">
                <item id="1">I am cautious in my dealings with others.</item>
                <item id="2">I am always fiddling with tools, vials, and other components relevant to my new dragon studies.</item>
                <item id="3">The life I left behind was dull, and I don't regret trading it for one of adventure.</item>
                <item id="4">I judge people by how they treat others, rather than by what they say or how they appear.</item>
                <item id="5">I joke about my condition as if it doesn't matter to me.</item>
                <item id="6">It's not all bad. I love flying and exploring new places!</item>
                <item id="7">I get angry easily, and afterwards, I can't help but be a little afraid of myself.</item>
                <item id="8">I must battle this monster I've become, lest I slip and hurt someone I care for.</item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="Ideal">
                <item id="1">Confrontation. I adventure to make the world a safer place, and to exorcise my own demons. (Good)</item>
                <item id="2">Progress. We must advance our knowledge for the good of the world, even of darker subjects. (Lawful)</item>
                <item id="3">Self-Determination. Everyone should be free to make their own choices, be they good or bad. (Chaotic)</item>
                <item id="4">Depravity. I've seen what one dark ritual can do, and I harbor an unshakable hunger to know more. (Evil)</item>
                <item id="5">Change. Life is constant change, and I will learn to adapt to any circumstance. (Neutral)</item>
                <item id="6">Destiny. I believe that my circumstances are a road to be traveled, and that my journey has just started. (Any)</item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="Bond">
                <item id="1">I seek to undo what's been done to me, and will pursue a way to do so by any means necessary.</item>
                <item id="2">I got to know one of my captor's other captives. They didn't survive, and I now seek to carry on their legacy.</item>
                <item id="3">Though I didn't have a choice, my captor wasn't so bad after all, and I now work for them.</item>
                <item id="4">I miss my family, but I can't face them like this.</item>
                <item id="5">The few people who are nice to me are like a beacon of hope. They matter more than anything else.</item>
                <item id="6">I stick up for anyone that is treated poorly.</item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="Flaw">
                <item id="1">I don't trust people easily.</item>
                <item id="2">I feel like I didn't deserve to survive when there were others who didn't make it.</item>
                <item id="3">I will shout loudly at anyone who makes mean comments about my form until they shut up.</item>
                <item id="4">Others are afraid of me now. I like that.</item>
                <item id="5">I've never felt more distanced from others, and sometimes I will cry myself to sleep in loneliness.</item>
                <item id="6">I always expect the worst from others. I am genuinely surprised when they occasionally prove me wrong.</item>
            </select>
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Feature: Thaumaturgic Rites" type="Background Feature" source="Demi-Dragon" id="ID_ARON_DD_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_VICTIM_OF_THAUMATURGY_THAUMATURGIC_RITES">
            <description>
                <p>You've witnessed firsthand the application of blood magic or some other form of metamorphic power. With the right preparation, research, and access to materials, you believe that you could duplicate the same rites that were inflicted upon you, creating another demi-dragon.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
    
    
</elements>