<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Embodiment of the Voidmaw Draconic Embodiment</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="demi-dragon-voidmaw.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/aron/demi-dragon-voidmaw.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Embodiment of the Voidmaw" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_CHIMERICWILDER_RDDTUA_SOURCE_EMBODIMENT_OF_THE_VOIDMAW">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation">EOTV</set>
            <set name="url">https://drive.google.com/file/d/1bJ1-V8vEzBuTXo9-EvlR8tSDt0TwNPSx/view</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" abbreviation="ARON" url="https://www.gmbinder.com/profile/aron">Aron</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20210225</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Embodiment of the Voidmaw" type="Archetype" source="Embodiment of the Voidmaw" id="ID_ARON_EOTV_ARCHETYPE_DEMI_DRAGON_EMBODIMENT_OF_THE_VOIDMAW">
        <supports>Draconic Embodiment</supports>
        <requirements>!ID_ARON_EOTV_CLASS_FEATURE_DEMI_DRAGON_OPTIONAL_BREATH_RECHARGE</requirements>
        <description>
            <p></p>
            <p class="indent">The Great Maw is a cosmic draconic entity of alien nature and immense power, capable of altering the fabric of space itself in order to consume all that it desires. Cults of dragons over the millennia have referred to it as the Dragon God of Consumption, while others believe it to be a corrupting influence that ensures the downfall of all that is dragonkind.</p>
            <p class="indent">Demi-dragons gifted with the powers of the Great Maw are exceedingly rare and powerful, able to tear holes in space for countless teeth to grab and consume any who oppose them. Once a voidmaw has set its sight on something it desires, it is near impossible to sway it towards any other goal. At their best, a voidmaw is a force that will ensure a goal is met no matter the cost. At their worst, a voidmaw is an engine of destruction devouring all in their path.</p>
            <div element="ID_ARON_EOTV_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VOIDMAW_RAVENOUS_WALTZ" />
            <div element="ID_ARON_EOTV_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VOIDMAW_COVETOUS_NATURE" />
            <div element="ID_ARON_EOTV_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VOIDMAW_HUNGERING_JAWS" />
            <div element="ID_ARON_EOTV_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VOIDMAW_RAVENOUS_BLOOM" />
            <div element="ID_ARON_EOTV_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VOIDMAW_VORACIOUS_APPETITE" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ARON_EOTV_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VOIDMAW_RAVENOUS_WALTZ" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ARON_EOTV_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VOIDMAW_COVETOUS_NATURE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ARON_EOTV_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VOIDMAW_HUNGERING_JAWS" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ARON_EOTV_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VOIDMAW_RAVENOUS_BLOOM" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ARON_EOTV_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VOIDMAW_VORACIOUS_APPETITE" level="17" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Ravenous Waltz" type="Archetype Feature" source="Embodiment of the Voidmaw" id="ID_ARON_EOTV_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VOIDMAW_RAVENOUS_WALTZ">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 3rd level when you take this archetype, you can use your draconic power to tear a hole in the veil and allow the a portion of the Great Maw's power to spill forth.</p>
                <p class="indent">When you use your Dragon's Breath feature, you can instead create a line originating from yourself along a surface where numerous teeth erupt forth. The line is 5 feet wide and its length is equal to your Dragon Breath's line range. Each creature in the line must make a Dexterity saving throw equal to your Dragon Spark Spell save DC, taking magical piercing damage equal to your Dragon's Breath Damage dice on a failed save, or half as much on a successful save.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can choose to end the line at any point past 5 feet up to the line's maximum range. When you do, a 10-foot diameter sphere of teeth erupt from the surface at a point adjacent to where the line ends. Creatures within the sphere must make the Dexterity saving throw as if they had been hit by the Ravenous Waltz.</p>
                <p class="indent">The sphere's diameter increases to 15 feet at 6th level, and to 20 feet at 10th level.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you use your Dragon's Breath feature, you can instead create a line originating from yourself along a surface {{dragons-breath:length}} feet long and {{dragons-breath:width}} feet wide. Each creature in the line must make a DC {{dragon-spark:save-dc}} Dexterity saving throw, taking {{dragons-breath:damage-dice}}d{{dragons-breath:die-type}} magical piercing damage on a failed save, or half as much on a successful save. You can choose to end the line at any point past 5 feet up to the line's maximum range. When you do, a {{ravenous-waltz:radius}}-foot diameter sphere appears. Creatures within the sphere must make the Dexterity saving throw as if they had been hit by the Ravenous Waltz.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="ravenous-waltz:radius" value="10" level="3" />
                <stat name="ravenous-waltz:radius" value="5" level="6" />
                <stat name="ravenous-waltz:radius" value="5" level="10" />
                <stat name="ravenous-waltz:radius" value="10" level="17" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Covetous Nature" type="Archetype Feature" source="Embodiment of the Voidmaw" id="ID_ARON_EOTV_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VOIDMAW_COVETOUS_NATURE">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 3rd level, the power of the Great Maw greedily hoards your life force.</p>
                <p class="indent">You are immune to having your hit points drained in order to restore those of hostile creatures, such as with the vampiric touch spell or a vampire's bite attack.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, whenever you deal damage with your Dragon's Breath or any of your Embodiment features to a creature for the first time on your turn, you gain temporary hit points equal to your Charisma modifier + your demi-dragon level (minimum 1). If multiple creatures take damage from the same source, you choose which creature you gain the temporary hit points from.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You are immune to having your hit points drained in order to restore those of hostile creatures, such as with the vampiric touch spell or a vampire's bite attack. Additionally, whenever you deal damage with your Dragon's Breath or any of your Embodiment features to a creature for the first time on your turn, you gain {{covetous-nature:temp-hp}} temporary hit points equal. If multiple creatures take damage from the same source, you choose which creature you gain the temporary hit points from.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="covetous-nature:temp-hp" value="dragon-spark:modifier" />
                <stat name="covetous-nature:temp-hp" value="level:demi-dragon" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Hungering Jaws" type="Archetype Feature" source="Embodiment of the Voidmaw" id="ID_ARON_EOTV_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VOIDMAW_HUNGERING_JAWS">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level you can tear the fabric of space to summon the jaws of the Great Maw.</p>
                <p class="indent">As an action, you can have the jaws clamp down on a creature of your choice. Choose a creature within 30 feet of you, that creature makes a Strength saving throw equal to your Dragon Spark Spell save DC, taking magical piercing damage equal to your Dragon's Breath Damage dice on a failed save, or half as much on a successful one. If the target fails the save, it is restrained by the jaws until the end of your next turn.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you've used this feature you can't do so again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Short Rest">
                <description>Choose a creature within 30 feet of you, that creature makes a DC {{dragon-spark:save-dc}} Strength saving throw, taking {{dragons-breath:damage-dice}}d{{dragons-breath:die-type}} magical piercing damage equal on a failed save, or half as much on a successful one. If the target fails the save, it is restrained by the jaws until the end of your next turn.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Ravenous Bloom" type="Archetype Feature" source="Embodiment of the Voidmaw" id="ID_ARON_EOTV_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VOIDMAW_RAVENOUS_BLOOM">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 10th level, the Great Maw's power within you expands, empowering your ability to use its gifts. The line created by your Ravenous Waltz increases to 10 feet wide. When you use your Ravenous Waltz feature, the teeth it creates persist until the beginning of your next turn, creating an area of difficult terrain for creatures other than you.</p>
                <p class="indent">When a creature enters the area for the first time on a turn or starts its turn there, it takes magical piercing damage equal to your Charisma modifier.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you use your Ravenous Waltz feature, the teeth it creates persist until the beginning of your next turn, creating an area of difficult terrain for creatures other than you. When a creature enters the area for the first time on a turn or starts its turn there, it takes {{ravenous-bloom:damage}} magical piercing damage.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="dragons-breath:width" value="5" level="10" />
                <stat name="ravenous-bloom:damage" value="ds-mod:min-one" level="10" />
                <stat name="ravenous-bloom:damage" value="ds-mod:min-one" level="17" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Voracious Appetite" type="Archetype Feature" source="Embodiment of the Voidmaw" id="ID_ARON_EOTV_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VOIDMAW_VORACIOUS_APPETITE">
            <description>
                <p>At 17th level, you learn to channel the full power of the Great Maw for a short amount of time.</p>
                <p class="indent">You focus your energy on empowering your abilities. You gain the following benefits:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Whenever you drop a creature to 0 hit points for the first time on your turn, you gain hit points equal to the damage dealt. If multiple creatures take damage from the same source, you choose which creature you gain the hit points from.</li>
                    <li>The diameter of the sphere created by your Ravenous Waltz increase to 30 feet.</li>
                    <li>Damage dealt to creatures within the area of difficult terrain created by your Ravenous Bloom feature increases to double your Charisma modifier.</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">Your voracious appetite lasts for 1 minute. Once you've used this feature, you can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Whenever you drop a creature to 0 hit points for the first time on your turn, you gain hit points equal to the damage dealt. If multiple creatures take damage from the same source, you choose which creature you gain the hit points from.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>

            </rules>
        </element>


</elements>