<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Demi-Dragon 4.0.2 Items</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="items-demi-dragon.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/aron/items-demi-dragon.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <!-- Mundane items -->
        <element name="Clawguards" type="Item" source="Demi-Dragon" id="ID_ARON_DD_ITEM_CLAWGUARDS">
            <description>
                <p>These sturdy kite-shaped steel spades are made to fit over a creature's claws, serving as gauntlets. They are intended to reduce the strain of manual labor, and you can use them to perform the functions of a shovel, crowbar, or hammer. While wearing them, your claw attacks deal piercing damage.</p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="category">Adventuring Gear</set>
                <set name="cost" currency="gp">20</set>
                <set name="weight" lb="10">10 lb.</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
        <element name="Dragonrider's Saddle" type="Item" source="Demi-Dragon" id="ID_ARON_DD_ITEM_DRAGONRIDERS_SADDLE">
            <description>
                <p>Each of these heavily-cushioned saddles are constructed to individual specifications. A dragonrider's saddle braces the rider, helping them keep their seat during battle, and comes with straps and handholds to hold the rider in place during flight, providing advantage on any check to remain mounted.</p>
                <p class="indent">It also comes with space for pouches and saddlebags, positioned within the reach of the dragon wearing it.</p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="category">Adventuring Gear</set>
                <set name="cost" currency="gp">75</set>
                <set name="weight" lb="30">30 lb.</set>
            </setters>
        </element>

    <!-- Magic Items -->
        <element name="Green Dragon Gizzard Stone" type="Magic Item" source="Demi-Dragon" id="ID_ARON_DD_MAGIC_ITEM_GREEN_DRAGON_GIZZARD_STONE">
            <description>
                <p>This noxious green jewel writhes with vile smoke. Exposed to centuries of magical corruption, the hazardous vapor it emits would kill a lesser creature. As part of attuning to it, you must swallow it in order to gain its benefits.</p>
                <p class="indent">While attuned to the gizzard stone, you are immune to the poisoned condition. Additionally, any creature that fails their saving throw against your breath weapon is poisoned for 1 minute. A creature can repeat the same saving throw they made against your breath weapon at the end of each of their turns, ending the effect on themselves on a success.</p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="category">Wondrous item</set>
                <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
                <set name="type">Wondrous item</set>
                <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
                <set name="attunement" addition=" by a poison demi-dragon, dragonborn, or half-dragon">true</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
        <element name="Dragongilded Armring" type="Magic Item" source="Demi-Dragon" id="ID_ARON_DD_MAGIC_ITEM_DRAGONGILDED_ARMRING">
            <description>
                <p>This ornate armring was forged from gold mixed with dragon's blood. It is made up of looping segments that can be adjusted to fit onto practically any limb, and bears a subtle magical enchantment that protects its wearer. While wearing the armring, you can choose to calculate your Armor Class as 13 + your Constitution modifier.</p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="category">Wondrous item</set>
                <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
                <set name="type">Wondrous item</set>
                <set name="rarity">uncommon</set>
                <set name="attunement" addition="">true</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
        <element name="Formshifter's Armring" type="Magic Item" source="Demi-Dragon" id="ID_ARON_DD_MAGIC_ITEM_FORMSHIFTERS_ARMRING">
            <description>
                <p>This gleaming gold armring appears to be a dragongilded armring to anyone who tries to identify it, and it confers that item's property when attuned to.</p>
                <p class="indent">Curse. This item is cursed. When attuned to, you fall unconscious for 2d4 hours, during which you are transformed into a demi-dragon as if you had used Transformed Power, using your highest mental ability score for Dragon Spark and all class effects. The DM determines the shape and damage type of your Dragon's Breath, but you otherwise make your own class choices. The armring can be removed with the remove curse spell or similar magic, but doing so doesn't return you to your old form. Only a remove curse spell cast at 6th level or higher, the wish spell, or obtaining the blessing of a true dragon can restore you to your old form. This curse has no effect on a character that is already a demi-dragon, and it can't curse more than one target at a time.</p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="category">Wondrous item</set>
                <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
                <set name="type">Wondrous item</set>
                <set name="rarity">very rare</set>
                <set name="attunement" addition="">true</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
        <element name="Inkbound Jewel" type="Magic Item" source="Demi-Dragon" id="ID_ARON_DD_MAGIC_ITEM_INKBOUND_JEWEL">
            <description>
                <p>This small gem bears a simple enchantment. By focusing on the jewel and passing it across a surface, you can sketch a simple picture or write a short message in a language you know as an action. The image or message appears on a suitable surface that is within 5 feet of you, and is written in ink.</p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="category">Wondrous item</set>
                <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
                <set name="type">Wondrous item</set>
                <set name="rarity">common</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
        <element name="Medallion of Change Shape" type="Magic Item" source="Demi-Dragon" id="ID_ARON_DD_MAGIC_ITEM_MEDALLION_OF_CHANGE_SHAPE">
            <description>
                <p>This rune-inscribed medallion, with a core of willow wood inset in a steel frame, grants the ability to change one's physical shape. As an action while wearing the medallion, you magically polymorph into a humanoid that has a challenge rating no higher than 1. You revert to your true form if you die, if you lose the medallion, or if you use a bonus action to do so. Any equipment you are wearing or carrying is absorbed or borne by the new form (your choice).</p>
                <p class="indent">In a new form, you retain your personality, alignment, hit points, Hit Dice, ability to speak, proficiencies, and Intelligence, Wisdom, and Charisma scores. Your statistics and capabilities are otherwise replaced by those of the new form, except any class features or legendary actions of that form, and you additionally gain proficiency with simple weapons, light armor, as well as medium armor if that humanoid would have those armor proficiencies.</p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="category">Wondrous item</set>
                <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
                <set name="slot">neck</set>
                <set name="type">Wondrous item</set>
                <set name="rarity">rare</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
        <element name="Potion of Change Shape" type="Magic Item" source="Demi-Dragon" id="ID_ARON_DD_MAGIC_ITEM_POTION_OF_CHANGE_SHAPE">
            <description>
                <p>This grayish, murky potion swirls and shifts when shaken. When you drink it, you magically polymorph into a humanoid that has a challenge rating no higher than 1 for 2d4 hours. This form is determined when the potion is initially created. You revert to your true form if you die or at the end of the duration. Any equipment you are wearing or carrying is absorbed or borne by the new form (your choice).</p>
                <p class="indent">In a new form, you retain your personality, alignment, hit points, Hit Dice, ability to speak, proficiencies, and Intelligence, Wisdom, and Charisma scores. Your statistics and capabilities are otherwise replaced by those of the new form, except any class features or legendary actions of that form, and you additionally gain proficiency with simple weapons, light armor, as well as medium armor if that humanoid would have those armor proficiencies.</p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="category">Wondrous item</set>
                <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
                <set name="type">Wondrous item</set>
                <set name="rarity">uncommon</set>
                <set name="stackable">true</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
        <element name="Obsidian Blast-Sphere" type="Magic Item" source="Demi-Dragon" id="ID_ARON_DD_MAGIC_ITEM_OBSIDIAN_BLAST_SPHERE">
            <description>
                <p>This spherical chunk of shaped obsidian is hollow on the inside, and its dark surface is inscribed with runes of protection. A gilded lid on one side gives access to the interior. If you have a breath weapon, you can breathe into the inert Blast-Sphere, sealing one use of your breath weapon within the sphere for up to 1 hour.</p>
                <p class="indent">As an action, you can unseal a charged Blast-Sphere, causing the stored breath to burst forth in a direction of your choosing. Alternatively, the Blast-Sphere can be thrown up to 30 feet as an action. When thrown, roll a d8 to determine which direction the breath bursts forth in.</p>
                <p class="indent">After being used, a charged Blast-Sphere becomes inert.</p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="category">Wondrous item</set>
                <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
                <set name="type">Wondrous item</set>
                <set name="rarity">uncommon</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
        <element name="Skybreaker's Wing Spurs" type="Magic Item" source="Demi-Dragon" id="ID_ARON_DD_MAGIC_ITEM_SKYBREAKERS_WING_SPURS">
            <description>
                <p>This set of elaborate mithral plates are of a distinctly elven design, and end in talon-like spurs inset with sapphires. They are worn on a creature's wings, protecting the main limb. While wearing them during flight, you have advantage on saving throws made to resist being knocked prone.</p>
                <p class="indent">The spurs have 5 charges, which are used to fuel the spells within them. While wearing the spurs, you can use your action and expend 1 charge to cast one of the following spells (save DC 15) from the spurs: gust of wind, thunderwave (2nd level), or warding wind.</p>
                <p class="indent">The spurs regain 1d4 + 1 expended charges each day at dawn. If you expend the spurs' last charge, roll a d20. On a 1, the sapphires set into the spurs crack, and they can no longer be used to cast spells.</p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="category">Wondrous item</set>
                <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
                <set name="type">Wondrous item</set>
                <set name="rarity">rare</set>
                <set name="attunement" addition=" by a winged creature">true</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
        <element name="Spell Slinger's Chains" type="Magic Item" source="Demi-Dragon" id="ID_ARON_DD_MAGIC_ITEM_SPELL_SLINGERS_CHAINS">
            <description>
                <p>This set of thick iron chains connects to a ruby pendant, intended to be worn on the limbs and chest, respectively. The set was created by a gallant wizard spell duelist who preferred to defeat his adversaries by turning the power of their own magic against them.</p>
                <p class="indent">As a reaction when you see a creature within 60 feet of you casting a spell, you can attempt to interrupt the creature's spellcasting. Make an ability check using your highest mental ability score. The DC equals 10 + the spell’s level. On a success, the creature’s spell fails and has no effect, and you store the spell that was being cast for up to 8 hours. You can cast the spell stored in the chains, even if you can't usually cast spells. The spell uses the slot level, spell save DC, spell attack bonus, and spellcasting ability of the original caster, but is otherwise treated as if you cast the spell. Once the spell has been cast from the chains, it is no longer stored in them.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this property, it can't be used again until the next dawn.</p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="category">Wondrous item</set>
                <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
                <set name="type">Wondrous item</set>
                <set name="rarity">very rare</set>
                <set name="attunement" addition="">true</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
        <element name="Stone of Avarice" type="Magic Item" source="Demi-Dragon" id="ID_ARON_DD_MAGIC_ITEM_STONE_OF_AVARICE">
            <description>
                <p>This lustrous gemstone appears to be a stone of good luck to anyone who tries to identify it, and it confers that item's property while on your person.</p>
                <p class="indent">Curse. This item is cursed. While it is on your person, you are seized by boundless greed. Whenever you are presented with a clear chance to add to your fortune, you must make a DC 10 Wisdom saving throw. On a failure, you must act on your desire, even if doing so would put you in danger. You are unwilling to part with the stone until the curse is broken with remove curse or similar magic.</p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="category">Wondrous item</set>
                <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
                <set name="type">Wondrous item</set>
                <set name="rarity">uncommon</set>
                <set name="attunement" addition="">true</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
        <element name="Warmask of the Brass Dragon" type="Magic Item" source="Demi-Dragon" id="ID_ARON_DD_MAGIC_ITEM_WARMASK_OF_THE_BRASS_DRAGON">
            <description>
                <p>This ornamental mask of burnished brass is stylized with the back-swept crest of a brass dragon. While you are wearing the mask and attuned to it, you can access the following properties.</p>
                <p class="indent">Damage Protection. You have resistance against fire damage. If you already have resistance to fire damage from another source, you instead have immunity to fire damage.</p>
                <p class="indent">Dragon Tongue. You can speak and understand Draconic. You also have advantage on any Charisma check you make against Brass Dragons.</p>
                <p class="indent">Sleep Breath. As an action, you can use a charge of your breath weapon to exhale sleep gas in an area. The affected area is determined by your breath weapon. Each creature in that area must succeed on a Constitution saving throw with a DC equal to your breath weapon or fall unconscious for 10 minutes. This effect ends for a creature if the creature takes damage or someone uses an action to wake it.</p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="category">Wondrous item</set>
                <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
                <set name="type">Wondrous item</set>
                <set name="rarity">very rare</set>
                <set name="attunement" addition=" by a demi-Dragon, dragonborn, or half-dragon">true</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
        <element name="Warmask of the Bronze Dragon" type="Magic Item" source="Demi-Dragon" id="ID_ARON_DD_MAGIC_ITEM_WARMASK_OF_THE_BRONZE_DRAGON">
            <description>
                <p>This ornamental mask of polished bronze is stylized with the ribbed crest of a bronze dragon. While you are wearing the mask and attuned to it, you can access the following properties.</p>
                <p class="indent">Damage Protection. You have resistance against lightning damage. If you already have resistance to lightning damage from another source, you instead have immunity to lightning damage.</p>
                <p class="indent">Dragon Tongue. You can speak and understand Draconic. You also have advantage on any Charisma check you make against Bronze Dragons.</p>
                <p class="indent">Repulsion Breath. As an action, you can use a charge of your breath weapon to exhale repulsion energy in an area. The affected area is determined by your breath weapon. Each creature in that area must succeed on a Strength saving throw with a DC equal to your breath weapon or be pushed 60 feet away from you.</p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="category">Wondrous item</set>
                <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
                <set name="type">Wondrous item</set>
                <set name="rarity">very rare</set>
                <set name="attunement" addition=" by a demi-dragon, dragonborn, or half-dragon">true</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
        <element name="Warmask of the Copper Dragon" type="Magic Item" source="Demi-Dragon" id="ID_ARON_DD_MAGIC_ITEM_WARMASK_OF_THE_COPPER_DRAGON">
            <description>
                <p>This ornamental mask of ruddy copper is stylized with the prominent brow plates of a copper dragon. While you are wearing the mask and attuned to it, you can access the following properties.</p>
                <p class="indent">Damage Protection. You have resistance against acid damage. If you already have resistance to acid damage from another source, you instead have immunity to acid damage.</p>
                <p class="indent">Dragon Tongue. You can speak and understand Draconic. You also have advantage on any Charisma check you make against Copper Dragons.</p>
                <p class="indent">Slowing Breath. As an action, you can use a charge of your breath weapon to exhale slowing gas in an area. The affected area is determined by your breath weapon. Each creature in that area must succeed on a Constitution saving throw with a DC equal to your breath weapon. On a failed save, the creature can't use reactions, its speed is halved, and it can't make more than one attack on its turn. In addition, the creature can use either an action or a bonus action on its turn, but not both. These effects last for 1 minute. The creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself with a successful save.</p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="category">Wondrous item</set>
                <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
                <set name="type">Wondrous item</set>
                <set name="rarity">very rare</set>
                <set name="attunement" addition=" by a demi-dragon, dragonborn, or half-dragon">true</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
        <element name="Warmask of the Gold Dragon" type="Magic Item" source="Demi-Dragon" id="ID_ARON_DD_MAGIC_ITEM_WARMASK_OF_THE_GOLD_DRAGON">
            <description>
                <p>This ornamental mask of gleaming gold is stylized with the sagely whiskers of a gold dragon. While you are wearing the mask and attuned to it, you can access the following properties.</p>
                <p class="indent">Damage Protection. You have resistance against fire damage. If you already have resistance to fire damage from another source, you instead have immunity to fire damage.</p>
                <p class="indent">Dragon Tongue. You can speak and understand Draconic. You also have advantage on any Charisma check you make against Gold Dragons.</p>
                <p class="indent">Weakening Breath. As an action, you can use a charge of your breath weapon to exhale weakening gas in an area. The affected area is determined by your breath weapon. Each creature in that area must succeed on a Strength saving throw with a DC equal to your breath weapon or have disadvantage on Strength-based attack rolls, Strength checks, and Strength saving throws for 1 minute. A creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.</p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="category">Wondrous item</set>
                <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
                <set name="type">Wondrous item</set>
                <set name="rarity">very rare</set>
                <set name="attunement" addition=" by a demi-dragon, dragonborn, or half-dragon">true</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
        <element name="Warmask of the Silver Dragon" type="Magic Item" source="Demi-Dragon" id="ID_ARON_DD_MAGIC_ITEM_WARMASK_OF_THE_SILVER_DRAGON">
            <description>
                <p>This ornamental mask of shimmering silver is stylized with the spiny frill of a silver dragon. While you are wearing the mask and attuned to it, you can access the following properties.</p>
                <p class="indent">Damage Protection. You have resistance against cold damage. If you already have resistance to cold damage from another source, you instead have immunity to cold damage.</p>
                <p class="indent">Dragon Tongue. You can speak and understand Draconic. You also have advantage on any Charisma check you make against Silver Dragons.</p>
                <p class="indent">Paralyzing Breath. As an action, you can use a charge of your breath weapon to exhale paralyzing gas in an area. The affected area is determined by your breath weapon. Each creature in that area must succeed on a Constitution saving throw with a DC equal to your breath weapon or be paralyzed until the end of their next turn. If the paralyzed target takes any damage, it can repeat the saving throw, ending the effect on a success</p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="category">Wondrous item</set>
                <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
                <set name="type">Wondrous item</set>
                <set name="rarity">very rare</set>
                <set name="attunement" addition=" by a demi-dragon, dragonborn, or half-dragon">true</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
    
    
</elements>