<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Demi-Dragon 4.0.2 Spells for Arbiter</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="spells-demi-dragon.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/aron/spells-demi-dragon.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Helpful Hand" type="Spell" source="Demi-Dragon" id="ID_ARON_DD_SPELL_HELPFUL_HAND">
        <description>
            <p>A phantasmal, floating hand appears at a point you choose within range. The hand lasts for the duration. The hand vanishes if it is ever outside the spell's range or if you cast this spell again.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can use your bonus action to control the hand. You can use the hand to take the Help action, manipulate an object, open an unlocked door or container, stow or retrieve an item from an open container, or pour the contents out of a vial. You can move the hand up to 30 feet each time you use it.</p>
            <p class="indent">The hand can't attack or carry more than 20 pounds.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">conjuration</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 10 minutes</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Warding Rune" type="Spell" source="Demi-Dragon" id="ID_ARON_DD_SPELL_WARDING_RUNE">
        <description>
            <p>When you cast this spell, you inscribe a rune that later unleashes a destructive blast. You inscribe it either on a surface (such as a table or a section of floor or wall) or within an object that can be closed (such as a book, a scroll, or a treasure chest) to conceal the rune. The rune can cover an area no larger than 5 feet in diameter. If the surface or object is moved more than 10 feet from where you cast this spell, the rune is broken, and the spell ends.</p>
            <p class="indent">The rune is nearly invisible and requires a successful Intelligence (Investigation) check against your spell save DC to be found.</p>
            <p class="indent">When a creature other than you comes within 5 feet of the rune, the rune erupts with magical energy in a 10-foot-radius sphere centered on the rune. The sphere spreads around corners. Each creature in the area must make a Dexterity saving throw. A creature takes 4d6 acid, cold, fire, lightning, or poison damage on a failed saving throw (your choice when you create the rune), or half as much damage on a successful one. The rune is then destroyed and the spell ends.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">evocation</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 minute</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">1 hour</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Wyrm-Mantle" type="Spell" source="Demi-Dragon" id="ID_ARON_DD_SPELL_WYRM_MANTLE">
        <description>
            <p>Choose a falling creature within range. The creature is held aloft by spectral draconic wings and hovers in place until the end of your next turn, after which they gently descend to the ground at a rate of 60 feet per round, taking no falling damage.</p>
            <p class="indent">While the creature is hovering in place, they have advantage on all ranged attacks. Additionally, a creature that uses a breath weapon while hovering in place imposes disadvantage on the saving throw against all targets of the breath weapon.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">transmutation</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 reaction, which you take when you or a creature within range falls</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">1 round</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Illusory Self" type="Spell" source="Demi-Dragon" id="ID_ARON_DD_SPELL_ILLUSORY_SELF">
        <description>
            <p>You project an illusion of a Huge creature of your choice over your own form. The illusion perfectly mimics your movements for the duration, reacts to external interaction, obscures your real form from sight, and appears to take up physical space in a 5-foot radius around you. Melee attacks made against the illusion automatically miss you, and ranged attacks made against you have disadvantage, but any attack reveals it to be an illusion to the attacker. Bystanders that witness such an attack remain fooled by the illusion's realistic reactions, but any creature that steps into the illusion's space immediately reveals it to be an illusion to anyone who witnesses it.</p>
            <p class="indent">A creature that uses its action to examine the image can determine that it is an illusion with a successful Intelligence (Investigation) check against your spell save DC. If a creature discerns the illusion for what it is, the creature can see through the image, and its other sensory qualities become faint to the creature.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">illusion</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self (5-foot radius)</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Faded Imprint" type="Spell" source="Demi-Dragon" id="ID_ARON_DD_SPELL_FADED_IMPRINT">
        <description>
            <p>You touch a point on the ground from which you call forth the memories of all that transpired within a radius of 20 feet within a duration of 2d4 hours before the spell was cast. While you maintain concentration on the spell, you can take an action to cause the spell to focus upon a particular point in time within that duration. The events that took place at that time replay as an illusory imprint that acts out everything that happened within the radius of the spell exactly as it transpired. The projection is obviously illusory to anyone who observes it, and can't be interacted with.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">4</set>
            <set name="school">divination</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 minute</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a fried pastry</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 10 minutes</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
</elements>