<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Various Wondrous Items</name>
        <update version="0.0.3">
            <file name="items-wondrous.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/options/items-wondrous.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Coin of Fortune" type="Magic Item" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_ZARKAS_RDDT_UA_MAGIC_ITEM_Coin of Fortune">
        <description>
            <p>This shiny coin has the golden face of a woman on one side and a purple face on the other. You can use a bonus action to flip and catch the coin, roll a d20 to determine your flip.</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d20</td><td>Coin flip result</td><td>Effect</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>Even number</td><td>Gold side</td><td>Good fortune: You have advantage on your next ability check, attack, or saving throw.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Odd number</td><td>Dark side</td><td>Misfortune: You have disadvantage on your next ability check, attack,or saving throw.</td></tr>
            </table>
            <p>The coin has 3 charges. Each use of the coin expends 1 charge. The coin regains all expended charges daily at dawn.</p>
            <p class="indent">The coin of fortune’s effects and luck points (<em>Player’s Handbook</em> pg. 167) cancel each other out.</p>
            <p class="indent">The coin’s effect(s) end after a day.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Sanctified Wings" type="Magic Item" source="Monkey DM" id="ID_MONKEYDB_RDDTUA_MAGIC_ITEM_SANCTIFIED_WINGS">
        <!-- https://www.reddit.com/r/UnearthedArcana/comments/mznz1c/sanctified_wings_let_your_righteous_fury_burn/ -->
        <description>
            <p>While attuned to this item, you have resistance to radiant damage and a flying speed of 40 feet.</p>
            <p class="indent">In addition, while attuned, you can, as a bonus action, summon the sacred powers held within the wings, transforming yourself into a celestial knight. You gain the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>Your creature type becomes Celestial.</li>
                <li>The first time you are reduced to 0 hit points but not killed outright during the transformation, you can drop to 1 hit point instead.</li>
                <li>You can use the wings to shield you against damage. When you are hit by an attack or you fail a Strength, Dexterity, or Constitution saving throw, you can use your reaction to gain a +2 bonus to your AC against that attack or a +4 bonus to that saving throw.</li>
                <li>You unleash a dangerously powerful light that radiates from your entire being, threatening to destroy all. You shed a bright light in a 10-foot radius and dim light for an additional 10 feet, and each time you deal damage to a creature, you deal additional radiant damage equal to your proficiency bonus.</li>
            </ul>
            <p class="indent">This transformation lasts for 1 minute and ends early if you fall unconscious. Once you've used the wings in this way, you can't do so again until you complete a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Artifact</set>
            <set name="attunement" addition="by a non-evil creature">true</set>
        </setters>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_RADIANT" />
            <stat name="speed:fly" value="40" bonus="base" />
        </rules>
    </element>

</elements>