<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Various Magical Weapons</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="items-magic-weapons.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/options/items-magic-weapons.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
	<element name="Sacrificial Dagger" type="Magic Item" source="Homebrewery" id="ID_UASCENDED_BEBOP_HOMEBREWERY_MAGIC_ITEM_WEAPON_SACRIFICIAL_DAGGER">
		<description>
			<p>This ceremonial blade has passed through the hands of many cult leaders and religious high priests alike.</p>
            <p class="indent">You have a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls with this items. Additionally, you may use it as a spellcasting focus. This weapon has 6 charges, and regains 1d6 charges at midnight. When you reduce a creature of size small or larger to 0 hit points you can expend 1 charge to make a sacrifice for one of the following effects:</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Fiendish Sacrifice.</strong> The dagger now deals an additional 1d4 fire damage and you gain advantage on all Charisma (Deception and Intimidation) checks.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Sacrifice To The Deep.</strong> The dagger now deals an additional 1d4 cold damage, you gain a swim speed of 20 feet and you can breathe underwater.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Ode To The Old Ones.</strong> The dagger now deals an additional 1d4 psychic damage and you can telepathically communicate with creatures you can see within 30 feet of you, as long as they can understand at least one language.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Prayer To The Gods.</strong> The dagger now deals an additional 1d4 radiant damage, you gain 4d4 temporary hit points and you have resistance to necrotic damage.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Divination (3 Charges).</strong> You gain the ability to cast <em>augury</em> and <em>speak with dead</em> once each, without material components. Additionally, you can cast <em>guidance</em> at will.</p>
            <p class="indent">Each of these effects lasts for 1 hour. You can only have one effect active at a time, using another will end the previous one.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="dagger">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">Dagger</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
    
</elements>