<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Forbidden Items</name>
        <update version="0.0.3">
            <file name="items-forbidden-items.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/options/items-forbidden-items.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Forbidden Items" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_FLASHPOINTBREWS_GMBINDER_SOURCE_Forbidden Items">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation">FI</set>
            <set name="url">https://www.gmbinder.com/share/-MAxg7mNT2ZGwLhz1rb-</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" abbreviation="FPB" url="https://www.gmbinder.com/profile/flashpointbrews">flashpointbrews</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20200821</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Band of the Buried" type="Magic Item" source="Forbidden Items" id="ID_FPB_FI_MAGIC_ITEM_BAND_OF_THE_BURIED">
        <description>
            <p>The ring has 3 charges. As an action, you can expend 1 charge to cast <i>dominate monster</i> (save DC 19) on an undead. The spell fails and the charge is wasted if you target any creature that’s not an undead. If an undead can see you when you cast this spell on it, the undead knows you tried to charm it. The ring regains all its charges 24 hours after its last charge is expended.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Curse.</i></b> Once you attune to this item, you can’t unattune to it unless you are targeted by the <i>remove curse</i> spell or similar magic. While wearing the ring, your spirit partially subsists in the Lower Planes. If you are not on a Lower Plane, using the ring’s <i>dominate monster</i> property activates its curse. Roll a d20. On a 1, you and every creature within 60 feet of you are transported to a random Lower Plane as if by the <i>plane shift</i> spell.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Rings</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="slot">ring</set>
            <set name="type">Ring</set>
            <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="charges">3</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Devil Tongue Charter" type="Magic Item" source="Forbidden Items" id="ID_FPB_FI_MAGIC_ITEM_DEVIL_TONGUE_CHARTER">
        <description>
            <p>Your Charisma score is 19 while you possess this charter. It has no effect on you if your Charisma is 19 or higher.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Curse.</i></b> Once you attune to this charter, you can’t unattune to it unless you are targeted by the remove curse spell or similar magic. While attuned to this contract, you have disadvantage on Wisdom ability checks and Wisdom saving throws against devils.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
	<element name="Humanoid Slayer" type="Magic Item" source="Forbidden Items" id="ID_FPB_FI_MAGIC_ITEM_HUMANOID_SLAYER">
		<description>
			<p>Forged by an ancient lich and used by his minions to harvest souls, this axe absorbs the blood of its victims and peels away bits of the soul. You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</p>
			<p class="indent">Additionally, when you hit a humanoid with this weapon, the target takes an extra 1d6 damage and must make a Constitution saving throw (DC 11). On a failure, the humanoid suffers one level of exhaustion. For the purpose of this weapon, "humanoid" refers to any creature with the humanoid type, including dragonborn and werewolves.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">axe, sword</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any axe">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_AXES</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Sacrifice" type="Magic Item" source="Forbidden Items" id="ID_FPB_FI_MAGIC_ITEM_SACRIFICE">
		<description>
			<p>While holding this shield, you have a +3 bonus to AC. This bonus is in addition to the shield’s normal bonus to AC.</p>
			<p class="indent">If you die while attuned to this shield, it is destroyed, and a random creature within 120 feet of your corpse must make a DC 20 Constitution saving throw. On a failure, the creature is disintegrated as if by the disintegrate spell, and the shield’s wielder is returned to life with 1 hit point as if by the revivify spell.</p>
			<p class="indent">Anyone who looks at this shield knows its properties, including its curse.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Curse.</i></b> Once you attune to this item, you can’t unattune to it unless you are targeted by the <i>wish</i> spell with the intent of doing so.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">shield</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="shield">Armor</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="armor">ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_SHIELD</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="enhancement">3</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

</elements>