<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Diarmuid’s Armament</name>
        <update version="0.0.2">
            <file name="items-diarmuids-armament.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/options/items-diarmuids-armament.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Diarmuid’s Armament" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_REDMORDRED_HOMEBREWERY_SOURCE_Diarmuid’s Armament">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p>Diarmuid Ua Duibhne was a demigod from times of yore. It is said in a single battle he alone killed over three thousand warriors in order to save another. These are the weapons he was blessed with during those fateful days.</p><p>Although Diarmuid certainly had quite the armament, he wasn’t the only one who wielded magical weapons in his time. From Fergus mac Róich to Cúchulainn, the Hound of Ulster, here are several weapons beyond Ua Duibhne’s own.</p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation">DMA</set>
            <set name="url">https://drive.google.com/file/d/1ZVSN1221mQ81NETt7XjS2tK_xrK7IqnS/view</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" abbreviation="URM" url="https://www.reddit.com/u/redmordred">u/redmordred</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20200727</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
	<element name="Gae Buidhe, the Yellow Spear" type="Magic Item" source="Diarmuid’s Armament" id="ID_URM_DMA_MAGIC_ITEM_GAE_BUIDHE">
		<description>
			<p>A golden spear clad in bronze and etched in runes. Those pierced by Gae Buidhe are given wounds that will not heal. Hit points lost to this weapon’s damage can be regained only through a short or long rest, rather than by regeneration, magic, or any other means. You gain +3 to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. Additionally, the spear also has 5 charges. While attuned to it, you can expend 1 charge and as part of the melee attack automatically cast <em>inflict wounds</em> on the enemy. The spear regains 1d4 + 1 expended charges daily at dawn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">spear</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="spear">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
            <set name="charges">5</set>
			<set name="weapon">Spear</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Gae Dearg, the Red Spear" type="Magic Item" source="Diarmuid’s Armament" id="ID_URM_DMA_MAGIC_ITEM_GAE_DEARG">
		<description>
			<p>A spear bound in crimson leather wraps and bearing a wolfshead at its base. It is said that any pierced by its point can no longer use magic. You gain +3 to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon and a creature damaged by Gae Dearg must make a DC17 Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, the creature is considered to be under the effects of the spell antimagic field for one minute. In addition, the spear has 5 charges. It can expend one of these charges to cast dispel magic as an action. The spear regains 1d4 + 1 expended charges daily at dawn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">spear</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="spear">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
            <set name="charges">5</set>
			<set name="weapon">Spear</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Moralltach, the Great Fury" type="Magic Item" source="Diarmuid’s Armament" id="ID_URM_DMA_MAGIC_ITEM_MORALLTACH">
		<description>
			<p>A sword said to leave no stroke or blow unfinished. This legendary longsword will cleave whosoever stands in its way. You gain +3 to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. In addition, the sword has 5 charges. Once per turn after missing an attack with this weapon, as a bonus action, you may expend a charge to deal 4d6 thunder damage to the target you missed instead. The sword regains 1d4 + 1 charges daily at dawn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">longsword</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="longsword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
            <set name="charges">5</set>
			<set name="weapon">Longsword</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Beagalltach, the Little Fury" type="Magic Item" source="Diarmuid’s Armament" id="ID_URM_DMA_MAGIC_ITEM_BEAGALLTACH">
		<description>
			<p>A blade as fast as the wind flies. This small, yet simple shortsword possesses unbelievable inner strength. You gain +3 to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. In addition, the sword has 3 charges. As a bonus action the wielder can choose to expend a charge to cast haste on themselves. The sword regains 1d3 expended charges daily at dawn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">shortsword</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="shortsword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
            <set name="charges">3</set>
			<set name="weapon">Shortsword</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Fragarach, the Retaliator" type="Magic Item" source="Diarmuid’s Armament" id="ID_URM_DMA_MAGIC_ITEM_FRAGARACH">
		<description>
			<p>A sword forged by the gods and said to whisper in a chosen’s ear. Fragarach is a frightful weapon of great potential. You gain +3 to attack and damage rolls and a targted creature’s AC is treated as 10 + their Dexterity modifier. Fragarach is sentient, with its mental stats and languages mirroring its attuned wielder. Fragarach can see and hear out 120ft and its alignment is chaotic good. In addition, the sword has 5 charges. As an action you can cosume a charge and cast the spell Zone of Truth. It regains 1d4 + 1 charges at dawn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">longsword</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="longsword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
            <set name="charges">5</set>
			<set name="weapon">Longsword</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Caladbolg, the Rainbow Sword" type="Magic Item" source="Diarmuid’s Armament" id="ID_URM_DMA_MAGIC_ITEM_CALADBOLG">
		<description>
            <p>A two-handed sword that makes a circle like the arc of a rainbow when swung and said to cut the tops off mountains. You gain +3 to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. Attacks with Caladbolg deal an additional 1d8 radiant damage. In addition, the weapon has 10 charges. You may expend a charge for the following effects:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>As an action, you may expend a charge, slamming the blade into the ground to create a shockwave. All creatures within 10ft must make DC15 Dexterity save or be knocked prone.</li>
                <li>As an action, you may expend multiple charges, to send an arc of radiant energy forward, making a ranged weapon attack dealing 1d8 slashing damage and 1d8 radiant damage per charge. The range of this attack must be within 30ft per charge.</li>
                <li>As an action, you may expend multiple charges, to create a wave of radiant energy. You make a 30ft-cone attack dealing 2d8 fire damage and 2d8 radiant damage per two charges.</li>
            </ul>
            <p>The greatsword regains 1d4 + 1 charges at dawn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">greatsword</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="greatsword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
            <set name="charges">10</set>
			<set name="weapon">Greatsword</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Gae Bulg, the Spear of Mortal Pain" type="Magic Item" source="Diarmuid’s Armament" id="ID_URM_DMA_MAGIC_ITEM_GAE_BULG">
		<description>
            <p>A spear made from the bones of a sea monster, when its head strikes true thirty painful barbs protrude into the wound and make it difficult to remove. You gain a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</p>
            <p class="indent">In addition, the weapon ignores resistance to piercing damage. When you roll a 20 on your attack roll with this magic weapon, your critical hit deals an extra 2d6 piercing damage and becomes stuck. To remove Gae Bulg afterwards you must succeed at DC15 Strength check. Upon succeeding you deal an additional 6d8 piercing damage to the target.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">spear</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="spear">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
			<set name="weapon">Spear</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

</elements>