<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Various Magical Weapons</name>
        <update version="0.0.2">
            <file name="items-magic-weapons.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/options/items-magic-weapons.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
	<element name="Sacrificial Dagger" type="Magic Item" source="Homebrewery" id="ID_UASCENDED_BEBOP_HOMEBREWERY_MAGIC_ITEM_WEAPON_SACRIFICIAL_DAGGER">
		<description>
			<p>This ceremonial blade has passed through the hands of many cult leaders and religious high priests alike.</p>
            <p class="indent">You have a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls with this items. Additionally, you may use it as a spellcasting focus. This weapon has 6 charges, and regains 1d6 charges at midnight. When you reduce a creature of size small or larger to 0 hit points you can expend 1 charge to make a sacrifice for one of the following effects:</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Fiendish Sacrifice.</strong> The dagger now deals an additional 1d4 fire damage and you gain advantage on all Charisma (Deception and Intimidation) checks.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Sacrifice To The Deep.</strong> The dagger now deals an additional 1d4 cold damage, you gain a swim speed of 20 feet and you can breathe underwater.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Ode To The Old Ones.</strong> The dagger now deals an additional 1d4 psychic damage and you can telepathically communicate with creatures you can see within 30 feet of you, as long as they can understand at least one language.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Prayer To The Gods.</strong> The dagger now deals an additional 1d4 radiant damage, you gain 4d4 temporary hit points and you have resistance to necrotic damage.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Divination (3 Charges).</strong> You gain the ability to cast <em>augury</em> and <em>speak with dead</em> once each, without material components. Additionally, you can cast <em>guidance</em> at will.</p>
            <p class="indent">Each of these effects lasts for 1 hour. You can only have one effect active at a time, using another will end the previous one.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="dagger">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">Dagger</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
    
    <element name="Slasher's Knife" type="Magic Item" source="NotTheSmooze" id="ID_source_abbreviation_MAGIC_ITEM_Slasher's Knife">
        <description>
            <p>For every mortal being, there is a breaking point: an extreme that, when reached, compels even the most noble to depths of unthinkable depravity. Some are closer than others, and when they might be coaxed towards peace, there is an invisible hand that will urge the opposite. This knife is that hand made metal.</p>
            <p class="indent">The slasher's knife is a magic, sentient dagger that doesn't require attunement. It grants a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with it, and deals an extra 3d4 slashing damage on a hit. In addition, when you hit a creature of CR 4 or lower with the slasher's knife, the creature instantly dies.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Dark Impulse.</i></b> A creature that touches the slasher's knife is marked with an invisible brand that resembles a knife wound. The knife can sense the emotional state and surface thoughts of any creature marked with its brand.</p>
            <p class="indent">The knife can teleport into the hand of any creature marked by its brand. The knife decides when to teleport, and can do it on any turn without using an action.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Sentience.</i></b> The knife is a sentient, chaotic evil weapon with an Intelligence of 13, a Wisdom of 20, and a Charisma of 17. It has hearing and darkvision out to a range of 120 feet.</p>
            <p class="indent">The knife can communicate telepathically with any creature marked by its brand, and understands the languages of every creature bearing one of its marks.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Personality.</i></b> Above all else, the knife wants to kill. It feeds on the violent impulses of its wielders, and leads them towards slaughter as best it can. The knife senses the emotions of any creature bearing its mark, and appears in their hand in the moment when they're most likely to use it.</p>
            <p class="indent">The knife rarely stays with one wielder for long, and never remains for the moments between bloodshed.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Escaping the Knife.</i></b> The knife cannot be destroyed while it has at least one creature marked by its brand. A remove curse spell can remove the knife's mark from a creature.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type" addition="dagger">Weapon</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
            <set name="rarity">Artifact</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
</elements>