<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Legendary Items that Evolve with Players</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="items-legendary-items.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/options/items-legendary-items.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Legendary Items by CrazyGeek" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_CG_HOMEBREWERY_SOURCE_Legendary Items by CrazyGeek">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation">CGLI</set>
            <set name="url">https://homebrewery.naturalcrit.com/share/Byolw5De7</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" abbreviation="CG" url="https://www.reddit.com/user/RomansAttemptToDM/">CrazyGeek31</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">true</set>
            <set name="release">20180608</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
	<element name="Archeart’s Wrath" type="Magic Item" source="Legendary Items by CrazyGeek" id="ID_CG_CGLI_MAGIC_ITEM_ARCHEARTS_WRATH">
		<description>
            <p>A longbow molded from a fledgling Tangled Spruce tree, the wood slowly transitioning from a young verdant green at the top to a deep rooted brown at the bottom. This bow was crafted and wielded by the Archeart themself. Any who trespass the lands of the Archeart had best brace themselves for the wrath of they who wield this bow. You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this weapon.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once per turn when you hit a target with an attack from this weapon, you can add 1d6 radiant damage. You can also cast the light cantrip on any ammunition fired from this weapon at-will, changing the piercing damage to radiant as well.</p>
            <h5>AWAKENED</h5>
            <p>When the user awakens the Archeart’s Wrath, apply the following effects:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>The bonus to attack and damage rolls increases to +2.</li>
                <li>The Archeart’s Wrath has 5 charges and regains 1d4 + 1 charges at dawn. You may cast the following spells with the Archeart’s Wrath: ensnaring strike (1 charge), hail of thorns (1 charge), conjure barrage (2 charges), lightning arrow (2 charges).</li>
                <li>Radiant Tracker: You can use an action to fire an arrow of pure radiant energy at a creature you can see within range. Make a ranged attack against the target, if it hits the target takes 3d8 radiant damage and is under the effects of a 3rd-level hunter’s mark spell that does not require concentration. You can use this ability once between long rests.</li>
            </ul>
            <h5>EXALTED</h5>
            <p>When the user exalts the Archeart’s Wrath, apply the following effects:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>The bonus to attack and damage rolls increases to +3.</li>
                <li>The radiant damage you can add once per turn becomes 2d6.</li>
                <li>The number of charges becomes 7, and it regains 1d6 + 1 charges at dawn. You gain these additional spells: swift quiver (3 charges), conjure volley (3 charges).</li>
                <li>Your Radiant Tracker ability can now be used twice between long rests.</li>
            </ul>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">longbow</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="longbow">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a ranger">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="weapon">Longbow</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Mageslayer Plate" type="Magic Item" source="Legendary Items by CrazyGeek" id="ID_CG_CGLI_MAGIC_ITEM_MAGESLAYER_PLATE">
		<description>
            <p>During the Age of Arcanum, a courageous knight with the blessing of the Allhammer set out to oppose those who had succumb to the raw magics of the world. This heavy plate was crafted for him by the highest priests of the Allhammer, bearing His sigil of a double-headed hammer. This armor can hold up to 5 charges, and recharges 1d4 daily at dawn.</p>
            <p class="indent">When you are targeted by an enemy’s spell, you can use your reaction to absorb part of the spell. The armor gains a number of charges equal to the spell level of the triggering spell. You are still subject to whatever effects the spell would normally inflict upon you. You cannot use this ability again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            <p class="indent">When you hit with an attack, you can choose to expend any number of charges from the armor, dealing an additional 1d6 force damage per charge expended, which is inflicted on the target of that attack. If your attack strikes multiple targets, you must choose one target from the group to be subject to this damage.</p>
            <h5>AWAKENED</h5>
            <p>When the user awakens the Mageslayer Plate, apply the following effects:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>You gain a +1 bonus to AC while wearing this armor.</li>
                <li>When using the armor’s ability to swallow a spell, you gain resistance to the damage of that spell.</li>
                <li>You can use the armor to cast counterspell at 4th level once per day. Your spell casting ability for this is Strength.</li>
                <li>The armor’s maximum charges becomes 7, and it regains 1d4 + 2 charges daily at dawn.</li>
            </ul>
            <h5>EXALTED</h5>
            <p>When the user exalts the Mageslayer Plate, apply the following effects:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>Increase the bonus to AC to +2</li>
                <li>You now cast counterspell as a 6th-level spell.</li>
                <li>The armor’s maximum charges becomes 10 and it regains 1d6 + 3 charges daily at dawn.</li>
            </ul>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">plate</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="slot">body</set>
			<set name="type" addition="plate">Armor</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="armor">Plate</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Oblivion’s Anchor" type="Magic Item" source="Legendary Items by CrazyGeek" id="ID_CG_CGLI_MAGIC_ITEM_OBLIVIONS_ANCHOR">
		<description>
            <p>Oblivion’s Anchor exudes an aura of darkness and shadows. This item resembles an old iron rail spike with arcane runes etched along it’s sides. In order to attune this item, you must stab yourself through the chest with it. Once attuned, the item disappears into the user’s chest and can only be seen through divination magic.</p>
            <p class="indent">While attuned to this item you can see through both natural and magical darkness. When a creature strikes you with a melee attack, they take 1d6 necrotic damage as the power of the Chained Oblivion escapes your body. You gain resistance to necrotic damage.</p>
            <h5>AWAKENED</h5>
            <p>When the user awakens Oblivion’s Anchor, apply the following effects:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>The damage creatures take when they hit you with a melee attack becomes 1d8.</li>
                <li>Your maximum hit points cannot be reduced.</li>
                <li>Chain Drain: This item has 7 charges, and regains 1 charge every time you reduce a creature to zero hit points. As an action you can attack a creature with spectral chains. Choose the number of expended charges and make an unarmed strike against a creature within 15 feet. On a hit the target takes 1d8 necrotic damage per charge expended and you regain half as many hit points.</li>
            </ul>
            <h5>EXALTED</h5>
            <p>When the user exalts Oblivion’s Anchor, apply the following effects:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>The damage creatures take when they hit you with a melee attack becomes 2d6.</li>
                <li>You gain immunity to necrotic damage.</li>
                <li>The item’s maximum charges becomes 10.</li>
                <li>If you are knocked unconcious by an attack or spell, you can choose to have all creatures within 10 feet of you suffer 1d4 necrotic damage. Any damage dealt you regain as hit points. You cannot use this ability again until you finish a long rest.</li>
            </ul>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">divination, scry</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot"></set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Pact Breaker" type="Magic Item" source="Legendary Items by CrazyGeek" id="ID_CG_CGLI_MAGIC_ITEM_PACT_BREAKER">
		<description>
            <p>A blood red stone seething with anger and hatred, the remnants of a fierce battle between warlock and patron. When the wearer begins casting spells the ring grows warm to the touch, the energy within nearly shaking the ring with power.</p>
            <p class="indent">While attuned to this item, you gain a +1 bonus to spell attack rolls and the saving throw DCs of your warlock spells. Once per turn when you hit a target with an attack, you can add (1d6 + your charisma modifier) necrotic damage to the damage roll.</p>
            <h5>AWAKENED</h5>
            <p>When the user awakens Pact Breaker, apply the following effects:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>Your bonus to spell attacks rolls and saving throw DCs increases to +2.</li>
                <li>Additional necrotic damage once per turn increases to (1d8 + your charisma modifier).</li>
                <li>Vitality Transfer: Your magic seeps into the muscles of your victim and saps away some of their vitality and grants it to you. Whenever you damage a creature with a spell its movement speed is reduced by 5 feet and your movement speed is increased by 5 feet until the start of your next turn.</li>
            </ul>
            <h5>EXALTED</h5>
            <p>When the user exalts Pact Breaker, apply the following effects:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>Your bonus to spell attack rolls and saving throw DCs increases to +3.</li>
                <li>Additional necrotic damage once per turn increases to (1d10 + your charisma modifier).</li>
                <li>Your Vitality Transfer ability now reduces the targets speed by 10 feet and increases your speed by 10 feet.</li>
                <li>When you score a critical hit against a creature, the target must succeed on a DC 17 Constitution saving throw or be paralyzed until the end of your next turn.</li>
            </ul>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Rings</set>
			<set name="type">Ring</set>
			<set name="slot">ring</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a non-good warlock">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="ac:misc" value="1" />
			<stat name="strength:save:misc" value="1" />
			<stat name="dexterity:save:misc" value="1" />
			<stat name="constitution:save:misc" value="1" />
			<stat name="intelligence:save:misc" value="1" />
			<stat name="wisdom:save:misc" value="1" />
			<stat name="charisma:save:misc" value="1" />
            <stat name="spellcasting:attack" value="1" />
		</rules>
	</element>


	<element name="Spire of Salamandra" type="Magic Item" source="Legendary Items by CrazyGeek" id="ID_CG_CGLI_MAGIC_ITEM_SPIRE_OF_SALAMANDRA">
		<description>
            <p>A gift from the Prime Metallic Dragon, Salamandra, to its followers among the Material Plane, a tall obsidian staff with strange bronze patterns that dance about the staff as it is being wielded. It is always warm to the touch.</p>
            <p class="indent">You gain a +1 to spell attack and damage rolls, while attuned to this staff. You add the shocking grasp and thunderclap cantrips and the witch bolt spell to your spell list, or replace them with another cantrip or spell if you already know them.</p>
            <p class="indent">Breath of the Dragon: Once per day, you can use an action to gain the ability to breathe the lightning of Salamandra. As a bonus action on each subsequent turn for 1 minute, you can exhale a line of lightning that is 20 feet long and 5 feet wide. Each creature in that line must make a Dexterity saving throw, taking 2d6 lightning damage on a fail, and half as much on a save.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can also store a number of sorcery points equal to 1 + your Charisma modifier in the Spire of Salamandra. It requires an action to store or withdraw from the staff. If you spend 1 hour meditating in a place with powerful ties to bronze dragons or a heavy storm, you gain 1d4 sorcery points.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">sorcerer</set>
			<set name="category">Staffs</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="4">4 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="weapon">Quarterstaff</set>
			<set name="type">Staff</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a sorcerer">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
		</setters>
        <rules>
            <stat name="spellcasting:attack" value="1" />
        </rules>
	</element>
        <element name="Spire of Salamandra: Awakened" type="Magic Item" source="Legendary Items by CrazyGeek" id="ID_CG_CGLI_MAGIC_ITEM_SPIRE_OF_SALAMANDRA_AWAKENED">
            <description>
                <p>A gift from the Prime Metallic Dragon, Salamandra, to its followers among the Material Plane, a tall obsidian staff with strange bronze patterns that dance about the staff as it is being wielded. It is always warm to the touch.</p>
                <p class="indent">You gain a +1 to spell attack and damage rolls, while attuned to this staff. You add the shocking grasp and thunderclap cantrips and the witch bolt spell to your spell list, or replace them with another cantrip or spell if you already know them.</p>
                <p class="indent">Breath of the Dragon: Once per day, you can use an action to gain the ability to breathe the lightning of Salamandra. As a bonus action on each subsequent turn for 1 minute, you can exhale a line of lightning that is 20 feet long and 5 feet wide. Each creature in that line must make a Dexterity saving throw, taking 2d6 lightning damage on a fail, and half as much on a save.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can also store a number of sorcery points equal to 1 + your Charisma modifier in the Spire of Salamandra. It requires an action to store or withdraw from the staff. If you spend 1 hour meditating in a place with powerful ties to bronze dragons or a heavy storm, you gain 1d4 sorcery points.</p>
                <h5>AWAKENED</h5>
                <p>When the user awakens the Spire of Salamandra, apply the following effects:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Your bonus to spell attack and damage rolls increases to +2.</li>
                    <li>You can add the call lightning and lightning bolt spells to your spell list.</li>
                    <li>Breath of the Dragon: The damage of your lightning breath increases to 4d6. You also gain a once per long rest use of a repulsion breath. You exhale a 20 foot cone of repulsion energy. Each creature in the area must succeed on a Strength saving throw or be pushed 40 feet away.</li>
                    <li>You can now store 2 + your Charisma modifier sorcery points in the Spire of Salamandra, and gain 2d4 when meditating.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="keywords">sorcerer</set>
                <set name="category">Staffs</set>
                <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
                <set name="weight" lb="4">4 lb.</set>
                <set name="slot">onehand</set>
                <set name="weapon">Quarterstaff</set>
                <set name="type">Staff</set>
                <set name="attunement" addition="by a sorcerer">true</set>
                <set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
            </setters>
            <rules>
                <stat name="spellcasting:attack" value="2" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Spire of Salamandra: Exalted" type="Magic Item" source="Legendary Items by CrazyGeek" id="ID_CG_CGLI_MAGIC_ITEM_SPIRE_OF_SALAMANDRA_EXALTED">
            <description>
                <p>A gift from the Prime Metallic Dragon, Salamandra, to its followers among the Material Plane, a tall obsidian staff with strange bronze patterns that dance about the staff as it is being wielded. It is always warm to the touch.</p>
                <p class="indent">You gain a +1 to spell attack and damage rolls, while attuned to this staff. You add the shocking grasp and thunderclap cantrips and the witch bolt spell to your spell list, or replace them with another cantrip or spell if you already know them.</p>
                <p class="indent">Breath of the Dragon: Once per day, you can use an action to gain the ability to breathe the lightning of Salamandra. As a bonus action on each subsequent turn for 1 minute, you can exhale a line of lightning that is 20 feet long and 5 feet wide. Each creature in that line must make a Dexterity saving throw, taking 2d6 lightning damage on a fail, and half as much on a save.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can also store a number of sorcery points equal to 1 + your Charisma modifier in the Spire of Salamandra. It requires an action to store or withdraw from the staff. If you spend 1 hour meditating in a place with powerful ties to bronze dragons or a heavy storm, you gain 1d4 sorcery points.</p>
                <h5>AWAKENED</h5>
                <p>When the user awakens the Spire of Salamandra, apply the following effects:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Your bonus to spell attack and damage rolls increases to +2.</li>
                    <li>You can add the call lightning and lightning bolt spells to your spell list.</li>
                    <li>Breath of the Dragon: The damage of your lightning breath increases to 4d6. You also gain a once per long rest use of a repulsion breath. You exhale a 20 foot cone of repulsion energy. Each creature in the area must succeed on a Strength saving throw or be pushed 40 feet away.</li>
                    <li>You can now store 2 + your Charisma modifier sorcery points in the Spire of Salamandra, and gain 2d4 when meditating.</li>
                </ul>
                <h5>EXALTED</h5>
                <p>When the user exalts the Spire of Salamandra, apply the following effects:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Your bonus to spell attack and damage rolls increases to +3.</li>
                    <li>You can add the storm sphere and chain lightning spells to your spell list.</li>
                    <li>Call the Dragon: Salamandra has seen fit to bestow upon you one of her prized guardians. You can spend 10 minutes performing a ritual to call a Winged Guard Drake to your side for 8 hours, after which it returns to the plane of Salamandra. This Drake will follow all your commands, and rolls its own initiative in combat. Once you use this ability, you cannot use it again for 7 days.</li>
                    <li>You can now store 3 + your Charisma modifier sorcery ponts in the Spire of Salamandra, and you gain 3d4 when meditating.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="keywords">sorcerer</set>
                <set name="category">Staffs</set>
                <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
                <set name="weight" lb="4">4 lb.</set>
                <set name="slot">onehand</set>
                <set name="weapon">Quarterstaff</set>
                <set name="type">Staff</set>
                <set name="attunement" addition="by a sorcerer">true</set>
                <set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
            </setters>
            <rules>
                <stat name="spellcasting:attack" value="3" />
            </rules>
        </element>


	<element name="Armor of the Ailuran" type="Magic Item" source="Legendary Items by CrazyGeek" id="ID_CG_CGLI_MAGIC_ITEM_ARMOR_OF_THE_AILURAN">
		<description>
            <p>Woven together by servants of the Spider Queen, stripped from the body of Tigres Ailur, and gifted to the Spider Queen’s champion Durdyn T’Sarran. A studded leather chest piece, shoulder guards, and chaps made from the distinct pelt of a Weretiger, all bearing the image of a waxing moon. Each piece lined and accented with the silk of a Midnight Spider. While attuned to this armor you gain a +1 bonus to AC. The AC bonus from this armor extends to any shape-shifted forms the wearer turns into.</p>
            <p class="indent">Your natural weapon attacks also deal an additional 1d4 damage.</p>
            <p class="indent">You also gain an additional use of your Wild Shape while attuned to this armor.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">leather</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="slot">body</set>
			<set name="type" addition="leather">Armor</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a druid">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="armor">Leather</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="ac:armored:enhancement" value="1" bonus="enhancement" />
		</rules>
	</element>
        <element name="Armor of the Ailuran: Awakened" type="Magic Item" source="Legendary Items by CrazyGeek" id="ID_CG_CGLI_MAGIC_ITEM_ARMOR_OF_THE_AILURAN_AWAKENED">
            <description>
                <p>Woven together by servants of the Spider Queen, stripped from the body of Tigres Ailur, and gifted to the Spider Queen’s champion Durdyn T’Sarran. A studded leather chest piece, shoulder guards, and chaps made from the distinct pelt of a Weretiger, all bearing the image of a waxing moon. Each piece lined and accented with the silk of a Midnight Spider. While attuned to this armor you gain a +1 bonus to AC. The AC bonus from this armor extends to any shape-shifted forms the wearer turns into.</p>
                <p class="indent">Your natural weapon attacks also deal an additional 1d4 damage.</p>
                <p class="indent">You also gain an additional use of your Wild Shape while attuned to this armor.</p>
                <h5>AWAKENED</h5>
                <p>When the user awakens the Armor of the Ailuran, apply the following effects:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Your bonus to AC becomes +2.</li>
                    <li>Your natural weapon additional damage increases to 1d8.</li>
                    <li>While attuned to this armor, the wearer chooses and imbues this armor with resistance to a damage type of your choice: fire, cold, acid, lightning, or necrotic. This choice can be changed during a short rest. This resistance persists through to shape shifted.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="keywords">leather</set>
                <set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
                <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
                <set name="slot">body</set>
                <set name="type" addition="leather">Armor</set>
                <set name="attunement" addition="by a druid">true</set>
                <set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
                <set name="armor">Leather</set>
                <set name="enhancement">2</set>
            </setters>
            <rules>
                <stat name="ac:armored:enhancement" value="2" bonus="enhancement" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Armor of the Ailuran: Exalted" type="Magic Item" source="Legendary Items by CrazyGeek" id="ID_CG_CGLI_MAGIC_ITEM_ARMOR_OF_THE_AILURAN_EXALTED">
            <description>
                <p>Woven together by servants of the Spider Queen, stripped from the body of Tigres Ailur, and gifted to the Spider Queen’s champion Durdyn T’Sarran. A studded leather chest piece, shoulder guards, and chaps made from the distinct pelt of a Weretiger, all bearing the image of a waxing moon. Each piece lined and accented with the silk of a Midnight Spider. While attuned to this armor you gain a +1 bonus to AC. The AC bonus from this armor extends to any shape-shifted forms the wearer turns into.</p>
                <p class="indent">Your natural weapon attacks also deal an additional 1d4 damage.</p>
                <p class="indent">You also gain an additional use of your Wild Shape while attuned to this armor.</p>
                <h5>AWAKENED</h5>
                <p>When the user awakens the Armor of the Ailuran, apply the following effects:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Your bonus to AC becomes +2.</li>
                    <li>Your natural weapon additional damage increases to 1d8.</li>
                    <li>While attuned to this armor, the wearer chooses and imbues this armor with resistance to a damage type of your choice: fire, cold, acid, lightning, or necrotic. This choice can be changed during a short rest. This resistance persists through to shape shifted.</li>
                </ul>
                <h5>EXALTED</h5>
                <p>When the user exalts the Armor of the Ailuran apply the following effects:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Your bonus to AC becomes +3.</li>
                    <li>Your natural weapon additional damage increases to 1d12.</li>
                    <li>The wearer may expend 2 uses of Wild Shape to assume the shape of a Weretiger with the wearer’s mental stats as per the Wildshape ability. You cannot pass on the curse of Lycanthropy from natural weapon attacks in this form.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="keywords">leather</set>
                <set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
                <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
                <set name="slot">body</set>
                <set name="type" addition="leather">Armor</set>
                <set name="attunement" addition="by a druid">true</set>
                <set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
                <set name="armor">Leather</set>
                <set name="enhancement">3</set>
            </setters>
            <rules>
                <stat name="ac:armored:enhancement" value="3" bonus="enhancement" />
            </rules>
        </element>


</elements>