<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Monastic Philosophy</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="options-monastic-philosophy.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/options/options-monastic-philosophy.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Monastic Philosophy" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_MRSILVERS_RDDTUA_SOURCE_MONASTIC_PHILOSOPHY">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation">MP</set>
            <set name="url">https://drive.google.com/file/d/1XLGjyt2gYBJbUp4GlSRlhTDEZIDKlt0V/view</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" abbreviation="MRS" url="https://www.reddit.com/user/Mr-Silvers/">u/Mr-Silvers</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20200602</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_MONK">
        <description>
            <div element="ID_MRS_MP_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_MONASTIC_PHILOSOPHY" />
        </description>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_ARCHETYPE_WAY_OF_THE_OPEN_HAND">
        <description>
            <div element="ID_MRS_MP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHILOSOPHY_OF_THE_OPEN_HAND" />
        </description>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MRS_MP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHILOSOPHY_OF_THE_OPEN_HAND" />
        </rules>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_ARCHETYPE_MONK_WAY_OF_THE_FOUR_ELEMENTS">
        <description>
            <div element="ID_MRS_MP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHILOSOPHY_OF_THE_FOUR_ELEMENTS" />
        </description>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MRS_MP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHILOSOPHY_OF_THE_FOUR_ELEMENTS" />
        </rules>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_ARCHETYPE_MONK_WAY_OF_SHADOW">
        <description>
            <div element="ID_MRS_MP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHILOSOPHY_OF_SHADOWS" />
        </description>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MRS_MP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHILOSOPHY_OF_SHADOWS" />
        </rules>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_WAY_OF_THE_DRUNKEN_MASTER">
        <description>
            <div element="ID_MRS_MP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHILOSOPHY_THE_DRUNKEN_MASTER" />
        </description>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MRS_MP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHILOSOPHY_THE_DRUNKEN_MASTER" />
        </rules>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_WAY_OF_THE_KENSEI">
        <description>
            <div element="ID_MRS_MP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHILOSOPHY_OF_THE_KENSEI" />
        </description>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MRS_MP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHILOSOPHY_OF_THE_KENSEI" />
        </rules>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_SCAG_ARCHETYPE_WAY_OF_THE_LONG_DEATH">
        <description>
            <div element="ID_MRS_MP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHILOSOPHY_OF_THE_LONG_DEATH" />
        </description>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MRS_MP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHILOSOPHY_OF_THE_LONG_DEATH" />
        </rules>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_WAY_OF_THE_SUN_SOUL">
        <description>
            <div element="ID_MRS_MP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHILOSOPHY_OF_THE_SUN_SOUL" />
        </description>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MRS_MP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHILOSOPHY_OF_THE_SUN_SOUL" />
        </rules>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_SCAG_ARCHETYPE_WAY_OF_THE_SUN_SOUL">
        <description>
            <div element="ID_MRS_MP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHILOSOPHY_OF_THE_SUN_SOUL" />
        </description>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MRS_MP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHILOSOPHY_OF_THE_SUN_SOUL" />
        </rules>
    </append>

    <element name="Monastic Philosophy" type="Class Feature" source="Monastic Philosophy" id="ID_MRS_MP_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_MONASTIC_PHILOSOPHY">
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">3rd-level monk feature (enhances Monastic Tradition)</p>
            <p>When you choose your Monastic Tradition at 3rd level, you can also choose to adopt the monastery’s philosophy as your own. Doing so can allow you to reach harmony, but may also suffer discord should the philosophy clash with your beliefs.</p>
            <p class="indent">Adopting a monastic philosophy is no simple task, as monks to who lead their lives by these creeds do not simply believe in them, but rather they live and breathe them as extensions of their own selves. Many young initiates who are brought up in monasteries are taught to follow these philosophies as part of their martial training. To these initiates, following the written word of these philosophies are not only paramount to mastering their discipline ─ It is synonymous with practicing it.</p>
            <p class="indent">While young and impressionable, oftentimes sheltered from the outside world within a remote monastery, few initiates ever question the philosophy of their chosen discipline. When they later end up leaving the monastery, for instance to become adventurers, they are suddenly met with a world that is vastly different from the dogmatic teachings with which they have lived and formed their entire lives.</p>
            <p class="indent">Some monks remain entirely ardent in their monastic philosophy regardless of what world they face on the outside. They see clashing ideas as challenges to be overcome and their belief in the monastic teachings are only strengthened by adversary. When an individual reaches a state of absolute conviction and faith, it attains what is known as harmony. In this state, the monk feels entirely vindicated in its monastic philosophy, believing themselves to have found but a single sliver of universal truth in the world. This state helps the monk refine its ki into a state of greater purity, and typically urges the monk to continue searching for both martial and spiritual awakening.</p>
            <p class="indent">On the flip side, some monks when faced with the outside world find themselves experiencing an entirely different sensation. When faced with situations that challenges the dogmatic teachings of their monastic philosophy, some monks find their own emotions to clash with the written word that up until then had completely defined them. They begin questioning everything they have been taught up until this point, experiencing what is known as discord.</p>
            <p class="indent">In this state, the monk tends to grow more uncertain in its own conviction, which serves to hamper and sometimes entirely cripple its ki flow. When a monk experiences great discord, it can temporarily drown out these feelings through meditation, but more often than not the monk must seek councel with either other monks, or persons of vast wisdom such as clerics or druids.</p>
            <p class="indent">Harmony and discords are not inherently good or bad, however. While harmony can lead a monk to enlightenment, the pursuit of such can also leave it blinded to its own shortcomings. Likewise, discord might provide a temporary distraction for a monk, but it can also pave way for self-realization, sometimes causing the monk to adopt an entirely different philosophy in life all-together.</p>
            <div class="sidebar">
                <h5 class="caption">VARIANT RULE: HARMONY AND DISCORD AS GAME MECHANICS</h5>
                <p>Harmony and discord are integral parts to the philosophy of martial arts, where one is a state of mind to strive for while the other serves as an obstacle to be overcome. Dungeon Masters can choose to integrate this feature into the game as a set mechanic more so than a roleplaying tool, using the rules below. Ultimately, the Dungeon Master has the final say in whether a monk has attained a high enough level of harmony or discord to gain either effect.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Harmony.</em></strong> While in a state of harmony, your mind, body and spirit all act as one which greatly increases your ability to harness ki. Whenever you make an ability check or saving throw while in this state, you can expend a number of ki points up to your proficiency bonus to gain a bonus to the roll equal to the number of ki points expended. This state lasts for 1 hour and once it ends, you cannot attain harmony again until you finish a long rest. When you reach 7th level, you can also use your Stillness of Mind feature to instantly end this state and regain a number of ki points equal to half your proficiency bonus (rounded down).</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Discord.</em></strong> While in a state of discord, your inner spirit is wrought with conflict and doubt which can greatly hamper your ability to harness ki. Whenever you attempt to use a ki feature in this state, you must succed on a DC 10 Wisdom saving throw or fail to use it. You lose any ki points expended in the attempt and become unable to use any ki feature until the start of your next turn. This state lasts until you spend 1 hour meditating to regain balance, which can be done as part of a short or long rest. When you reach 7th level, you can also use your Stillness of Mind feature to instantly end this state and regain a number of ki points equal to half your proficiency bonus (rounded down).</p>
            </div>
            <div element="ID_MRS_MP_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_MONASTIC_PHILOSOPHY" />
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="Philosophy of the Open Hand" type="Class Feature" source="Monastic Philosophy" id="ID_MRS_MP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHILOSOPHY_OF_THE_OPEN_HAND">
        <description>
            <p>Though different monasteries and individual teachers may place emphasis on different aspects, most monks of the open hand follow teachings similar to the following.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>True strength is internal.</em></strong> Strength of arms wins the battle, and strength of wits wins the war, but only strength of spirit can unify the two as one, becoming true strength.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Pride before the fall.</em></strong> Arrogance is a poison of the soul; humility and self-reflection alone hold the key to mastery.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Know your enemy to know yourself.</em></strong> Seek not only to battle your enemies, but to understand them. Only then will you find a true reason to fight.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>An open mind, as the open hand.</em></strong> When faced with new ideas, do not admonish or belittle them. Harken them instead, adopting what is useful and discarding what is not.</p>
            <div element="ID_MRS_MP_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_MONASTIC_PHILOSOPHY" />
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Philosophy of the Four Elements" type="Class Feature" source="Monastic Philosophy" id="ID_MRS_MP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHILOSOPHY_OF_THE_FOUR_ELEMENTS">
        <description>
            <p>Though different monasteries and individual teachers may place emphasis on different aspects, most monks of the four elements follow teachings similar to the following.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Flow like water.</em></strong> Water is mutable; it can flow around the rock, or crash against it. When challenged, be like water.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Roar like fire.</em></strong> Fire is fierce; relentlessly, it offers neither respite nor reprieve. When forced to battle, be like fire.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Bide like the mountains.</em></strong> Earth is patient; it can be stirred only by its own will. When provoked or insulted, be like earth.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Seek like the wind.</em></strong> Air is ardent; forever traveling, it yearns for new knowledge. When training, be like air.</p>
            <div element="ID_MRS_MP_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_MONASTIC_PHILOSOPHY" />
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Philosophy of Shadows" type="Class Feature" source="Monastic Philosophy" id="ID_MRS_MP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHILOSOPHY_OF_SHADOWS">
        <description>
            <p>Though different monasteries and individual teachers may place emphasis on different aspects, most shadow monks follow teachings similar to the following.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Duty to the clan.</em></strong> The clan is the body, you are its shadow, and shadows move only as the body commands.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Question not your methods.</em></strong> Perform your duty without query. Hesitation is an onus, cast it aside.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Shadows are silent.</em></strong> You must be silent, swift and efficient in your work. Like shadows cast by pale moonlight, none must ever consider your presence.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>All is fair in battle.</em></strong> Honor and valor are a fool’s errand, and fools do not get to choose how they die.</p>
            <div element="ID_MRS_MP_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_MONASTIC_PHILOSOPHY" />
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Philosophy the Drunken Master" type="Class Feature" source="Monastic Philosophy" id="ID_MRS_MP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHILOSOPHY_THE_DRUNKEN_MASTER">
        <description>
            <p>Though different monasteries and individual teachers may place emphasis on different aspects, most drunken master monks follow teachings similar to the following.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>A fool betrays all and none.</em></strong> Only those who laugh at themselves can laugh at others without looking the fool.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Humility is the best teacher.</em></strong> The greater pride is more often than not also the greater fool.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Trickery without falsity.</em></strong> Though you fight with guile and trickery, do not let yourself be mislead into carelessness. Arrogance will dull your wits.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Abstinence is folly.</em></strong> Abstinence is brother to greed, and just as perilous. Enjoy all aspects of the world’s pleasures in moderation.</p>
            <div element="ID_MRS_MP_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_MONASTIC_PHILOSOPHY" />
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Philosophy of the Kensei" type="Class Feature" source="Monastic Philosophy" id="ID_MRS_MP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHILOSOPHY_OF_THE_KENSEI">
        <description>
            <p>Though different monasteries and individual teachers may place emphasis on different aspects, most kensei monks follow teachings similar to the following.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>You and your blade are one.</em></strong> Treat your weapon as an extension of yourself. To lose it is to lose a vital limb.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Master the self.</em></strong> With discipline, wood will be as sharp as steel. Without discipline, steel will be as dull as wood.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>The blade should bend.</em></strong> Your blade should cut stone when you want it to cut, and leave paper untouched when you don’t.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Perfection is impossible.</em></strong> Perfection is an ideal, not a destination. Strive towards it not to achieve it, but to come closer than you were yesterday.</p>
            <div element="ID_MRS_MP_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_MONASTIC_PHILOSOPHY" />
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Philosophy of the Long Death" type="Class Feature" source="Monastic Philosophy" id="ID_MRS_MP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHILOSOPHY_OF_THE_LONG_DEATH">
        <description>
            <p>Though different monasteries and individual teachers may place emphasis on different aspects, most monks of the long death follow teachings similar to the following.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Death holds the key to life.</em></strong> Life and death are forever entwined; bring upon one and you shall have the other.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>What lays beyond matters not.</em></strong> The afterlife is of no consequence to the living. The passing itself is what matters.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>What is dead is not sacred.</em></strong> A dead body is neither holy nor unholy, but a riddle of life that must be unraveled.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>The living rule the dead.</em></strong> The understanding of death is the right of those who live, and no effort should be spared in the study of death.</p>
            <div element="ID_MRS_MP_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_MONASTIC_PHILOSOPHY" />
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Philosophy of the Sun Soul" type="Class Feature" source="Monastic Philosophy" id="ID_MRS_MP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHILOSOPHY_OF_THE_SUN_SOUL">
        <description>
            <p>Though different monasteries and individual teachers may place emphasis on different aspects, most monks of the sun soul follow teachings similar to the following.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>All lights as one.</em></strong> All living beings have a truth, a light, unique to themselves, and this light must be fostered and cherished.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Guide and be guided.</em></strong> It is through guiding others that we find our own path in life.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>No night lasts forever.</em></strong> Night may come, but never to stay. Like the dawn banishes the night, any darkness within a heart will be driven with the light of kindness.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>The sunless are lost.</em></strong> That which shuns the light cannot be saved; the undead must be vanquished, for that is the only mercy of their cursed existence.</p>
            <div element="ID_MRS_MP_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_MONASTIC_PHILOSOPHY" />
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

</elements>