<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="options-unearthed-arcana.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/options/options-unearthed-arcana.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>

  <!-- Bard -->
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_BARD_BARDIC_INSPIRATION">
        <rules>
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_BARD_MAGICAL_INSPIRATION" />
        </rules>
    </append>
    <element name="Magical Inspiration" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_BARD_MAGICAL_INSPIRATION">
        <description>
            <p>If a creature has a Bardic Inspiration die from you and casts a spell, the creature can roll that die and add the number rolled to one damage or healing roll of the spell. The Bardic Inspiration die is then lost.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>If a creature has a Bardic Inspiration die from you and casts a spell, the creature can roll that die and add the number rolled to one damage or healing roll of the spell. The Bardic Inspiration die is then lost.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_BARD_SPELLCASTING_BARD">
        <rules>
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_BARD_SPELL_VERSATILITY" />
        </rules>
    </append>
    <element name="Spell Versatility" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_BARD_SPELL_VERSATILITY">
        <description>
            <p>Whenever you finish a long rest, you can replace one spell you learned from this Spellcasting feature with another spell from the bard spell list. The new spell must be the same level as the spell you replace.</p>
            <div class="sidebar">
                <h5 class="caption">Rule Tip: Cantrips Are Spells</h5>
                <p>Cantrips are 0-level spells, which don’t use spell slots. When a feature applies to spells, that feature applies to cantrips, unless the feature specifies that the spells must be of 1st level or higher or must expend a spell slot.</p>
            </div>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Whenever you finish a long rest, you can replace one spell you learned from your Spellcasting feature with another spell from the bard spell list. The new spell must be the same level as the spell you replace.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

  <!-- Cleric -->
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_CLERIC_CHANNELDIVINITY">
        <rules>
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_CLERIC_CHANNELDIVINITY_HARNESS_DIVINE_POWER" />
        </rules>
    </append>
	<element name="Channel Divinity: Harness Divine Power" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_CLERIC_CHANNELDIVINITY_HARNESS_DIVINE_POWER">
		<description>
			<p>You can expend a use of your Channel Divinity to fuel your spells. As a bonus action, you touch your holy symbol, utter a prayer, and regain one expended 1st-level spell slot.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Harness Divine Power" action="Bonus Action" usage="Channel Divinity">
			<description>You touch your holy symbol, utter a prayer, and regain one expended 1st-level spell slot.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_CLERIC_SPELLCASTING_CLERIC">
        <rules>
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_CLERIC_CANTRIP_VERSATILITY" />
        </rules>
    </append>
    <element name="Cantrip Versatility" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_CLERIC_CANTRIP_VERSATILITY">
        <description>
            <p>Whenever you gain a level in this class, you can replace one cantrip you learned from this Spellcasting feature with another cantrip from the cleric spell list.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Whenever you gain a level in this class, you can replace one cantrip you learned from this Spellcasting feature with another cantrip from the cleric spell list.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

  <!-- Druid -->
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_DRUID_SPELLCASTING_DRUID">
        <rules>
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_DRUID_CANTRIP_VERSATILITY" />
        </rules>
    </append>
    <element name="Cantrip Versatility" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_DRUID_CANTRIP_VERSATILITY">
        <description>
            <p>Whenever you gain a level in this class, you can replace one cantrip you learned from this Spellcasting feature with another cantrip from the cleric spell list.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Whenever you gain a level in this class, you can replace one cantrip you learned from this Spellcasting feature with another cantrip from the cleric spell list.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_DRUID_WILDSHAPE">
        <rules>
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_DRUID_WILD_COMPANION" />
        </rules>
    </append>
    <element name="Wild Companion" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_DRUID_WILD_COMPANION">
        <description>
            <p>You gain the ability to summon a spirit that assumes an animal form: as an action, you can expend a use of your Wild Shape feature to cast the <em>find familiar</em> spell, without material components.</p>
            <p>When you cast the spell in this way, the familiar is a fey instead of a beast, and the familiar disappears after a number of hours equal to half your druid level.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Action" usage="Wild Shape">
            <description>You can expend a use of your Wild Shape feature to cast the find familiar spell, without material components. When you cast the spell in this way, the familiar is a fey instead of a beast, and the familiar disappears after {{level:druid:half}} hours.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIND_FAMILIAR" />
        </rules>
    </element>

  <!-- Martial Versatility -->
    <element name="Martial Versatility" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_VERSATILITY">
        <description>
            <p>Whenever you gain a level in a class that has the Fighting Style feature, you can replace a fighting style you know with another style available to your class. This change represents a shift of focus in your martial training and practice, causing you to lose the benefits of one style and gain the benefits of another style.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Whenever you gain a level in a class that has the Fighting Style feature, you can replace a fighting style you know with another style available to your class. This change represents a shift of focus in your martial training and practice, causing you to lose the benefits of one style and gain the benefits of another style.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
        <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE">
            <rules>
                <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_VERSATILITY" />
            </rules>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_PALADIN_FIGHTING_STYLE">
            <rules>
                <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_VERSATILITY" />
            </rules>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_WOTC_CLASSFEATURE_RANGER_FIGHTING_STYLE">
            <rules>
                <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_MARTIAL_VERSATILITY" />
            </rules>
        </append>


  <!-- Fighting Styles -->    
    <element name="Blind Fighting" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTING_STYLE_BLIND_FIGHTING">
        <supports>Fighting Style, Fighter, Paladin, Ranger</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Being unable to see a creature doesn’t impose disadvantage on your attack rolls against it, provided the creature isn’t hidden from you.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Being unable to see a creature doesn’t impose disadvantage on your attack rolls against it, provided the creature isn’t hidden from you.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Interception" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTING_STYLE_INTERCEPTION">
        <supports>Fighting Style, Fighter, Paladin, Ranger</supports>
        <description>
            <p>When a creature you can see hits a target that is within 5 feet of you with an attack, you can use your reaction to reduce the damage the target takes by 1d10 + your proficiency bonus (to a minimum of 0 damage). You must be wielding a shield or a simple or martial weapon to use this reaction.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Reaction">
            <description>When a creature you can see hits a target that is within 5 feet of you with an attack, you can reduce the damage the target takes by 1d10 + {{proficiency}}. You must be wielding a shield or a simple or martial weapon.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Thrown Weapon Fighting" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTING_STYLE_THROWN_WEAPON_FIGHTING">
        <supports>Fighting Style, Fighter, Paladin, Ranger</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You can draw a weapon that has the thrown property as part of the attack you make with the weapon.</p>
            <p class="indent">In addition, when you hit with a ranged attack using a thrown weapon, you gain a +1 bonus to the damage roll.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can draw a weapon that has the thrown property as part of the attack you make with the weapon. When you hit with a ranged attack using a thrown weapon, you gain a +1 bonus to the damage roll.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Unarmed Fighting" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTING_STYLE_UNARMED_FIGHTING">
        <supports>Fighting Style, Fighter, Paladin, Ranger</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Your unarmed strikes can deal bludgeoning damage equal to 1d6 + your Strength modifier. If you strike with two free hands, the d6 becomes a d8.</p>
            <p class="indent">When you successfully start a grapple, you can deal 1d4 bludgeoning damage to the grappled creature. Until the grapple ends, you can also deal this damage to the creature whenever you hit it with a melee attack.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Your unarmed strikes can deal bludgeoning damage equal to 1d6 + {{strength:modifier}}. If you strike with two free hands, the d6 becomes a d8. When you successfully start a grapple, you can deal 1d4 bludgeoning damage to the grappled creature. Until the grapple ends, you can also deal this damage to the creature whenever you hit it with a melee attack.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Superior Technique" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTING_STYLE_SUPERIOR_TECHNIQUE">
        <supports>Fighting Style, Fighter, Vanguard, Warlord, Ranger, Paladin</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You learn one maneuver of your choice from among those available to the Battle Master archetype. If a maneuver you use requires your target to make a saving throw to resist the maneuver’s effects, the saving throw DC equals 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Strength or Dexterity modifier (your choice).</p>
            <p>You gain one superiority die, which is a d6 (this die is added to any superiority dice you have from another source). This die is used to fuel your maneuvers. A superiority die is expended when you use it. You regain your expended superiority dice when you finish a short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
            <description>You learn one maneuver that is fueled by special dice called superiority dice. You have 1 superiority die which is a d{{superiority dice:size}}. DC {{superiority dice:dc}}</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
			<stat name="superiority dice:size" value="6" bonus="size"/>
			<stat name="superiority dice:dc" value="8" />
			<stat name="superiority dice:dc" value="proficiency" />
			<stat name="superiority dice:dc:ability" value="strength:modifier" bonus="ability"/>
			<stat name="superiority dice:dc:ability" value="dexterity:modifier" bonus="ability"/>
			<stat name="superiority dice:dc" value="superiority dice:dc:ability" />
			<select type="Archetype Feature" name="Superior Technique" supports="Maneuver,Battle Master" number="1" />
        </rules>
    </element>

    <!-- New Maneuvers -->
	<element name="Ambush" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MANEUVER_AMBUSH">
		<supports>Maneuver, Battle Master</supports>
		<description>
            <p>When you make a Dexterity (Stealth) check or an initiative roll, you can expend one superiority die and add the die to the roll.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When you make a Stealth check or an initiative roll, you can expend one superiority die and add the die to the roll.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Bait and Switch" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MANEUVER_BAIT_AND_SWITCH">
		<supports>Maneuver, Battle Master</supports>
		<description>
            <p>When you’re within 5 feet of an ally on your turn, you can expend one superiority die and switch places with that ally, provided you spend at least 5 feet of movement. This movement doesn’t provoke opportunity attacks.</p>
            <p class="indent">Roll the superiority die. Until the start of your next turn, the ally gains a bonus to AC equal to the number rolled.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When you’re within 5 feet of an ally on your turn, you can expend one superiority die and switch places with that ally, provided you spend at least 5 feet of movement. This movement doesn’t provoke opportunity attacks. Roll the superiority die. Until the start of your next turn, the ally gains a bonus to AC equal to the number rolled.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Brace" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MANEUVER_BRACE">
		<supports>Maneuver, Battle Master</supports>
		<description>
            <p>When an enemy you can see moves within 5 feet of you, you can use your reaction to expend one superiority die and make one weapon attack against that creature. If the attack hits, add the superiority die to the attack’s damage roll.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Reaction">
			<description>When an enemy you can see moves within 5 feet of you, you can expend one superiority die and make one weapon attack against that creature. If the attack hits, add the superiority die to the attack’s damage roll.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Restraining Strike" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MANEUVER_RESTRAINING_STRIKE">
		<supports>Maneuver, Battle Master</supports>
		<description>
            <p>Immediately after you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack on your turn, you can expend one superiority die and use a bonus action to grapple the target (see chapter 9 in the <em>Player’s Handbook</em> for rules on grappling). Add the superiority die to your Strength (Athletics) check. The target is also restrained while grappled in this way.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Bonus Action">
			<description>Immediately after you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack on your turn, you can expend one superiority die and use a bonus action to grapple the target. Add the superiority die to your Athletics check. The target is also restrained while grappled in this way.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Silver Tongue" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MANEUVER_SILVER_TONGUE">
		<supports>Maneuver, Battle Master</supports>
		<description>
            <p>When you make a Charisma (Deception) check or a Charisma (Persuasion) check, you can expend one superiority die, and add the superiority die to the ability check.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When you make a Deception check or a Persuasion check, you can expend one superiority die, and add the superiority die to the ability check.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Snipe" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MANEUVER_SNIPE">
		<supports>Maneuver, Battle Master</supports>
		<description>
            <p>As a bonus action, you can expend one superiority die and make a ranged weapon attack. You can draw a thrown weapon as part of making this attack. If you hit, add the superiority die to the attack’s damage roll.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Bonus Action">
			<description>You can expend one superiority die and make a ranged weapon attack. You can draw a thrown weapon as part of making this attack. If you hit, add the superiority die to the attack’s damage roll.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Studious Eye" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MANEUVER_STUDIOUS_EYE">
		<supports>Maneuver, Battle Master</supports>
		<description>
            <p>When you make a Wisdom (Insight) check or an Intelligence (Investigation) check, you can expend one superiority die, and add the superiority die to the ability check.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When you make a Insight check or an Investigation check, you can expend one superiority die, and add the superiority die to the ability check.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

    <!-- Monk Options -->
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_KI">
        <rules>
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_KI_KI_FUELED_STRIKE" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_KI_DISTANT_EYE" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_KI_QUICKENED_HEALING" />
        </rules>
    </append>
    <element name="Ki-Fueled Strike" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_KI_KI_FUELED_STRIKE">
        <description>
            <p>If you spend 1 ki or more as part of your action on your turn, you can then immediately make one unarmed strike as a bonus action.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="Ki">
            <description>If you spend 1 ki or more as part of your action on your turn, you can then immediately make one unarmed strike as a bonus action.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Distant Eye" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_KI_DISTANT_EYE">
        <description>
            <p>When you make a ranged weapon attack, you can spend 1 ki point to prevent attacking at long range from imposing disadvantage on your attack rolls until the end of the current turn</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="Ki">
            <description>When you make a ranged weapon attack, you can spend 1 ki point to prevent attacking at long range from imposing disadvantage on your attack rolls until the end of the current turn</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Quickened Healing" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_KI_QUICKENED_HEALING">
        <description>
            <p>As an action, you can spend 2 ki points and roll a Martial Arts die. You regain a number of hit points equal to the number rolled.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="Ki">
            <description>As an action, you can spend 2 ki points and roll a Martial Arts die. You regain a number of hit points equal to the number rolled.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    
    <!-- Paladin Harness Divine Power -->
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_PALADIN_SACRED_OATH">
        <rules>
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_PALADIN_CD_HARNESS_DIVINE_POWER" />
        </rules>
    </append>
    <element name="Channel Divinity: Harness Divine Power" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_PALADIN_CD_HARNESS_DIVINE_POWER">
        <description>
            <p>You can expend a use of your Channel Divinity to fuel your spells. As a bonus action, you touch your holy symbol, utter a prayer, and regain one expended 1st-level spell slot.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="Channel Divinity" alt="Harness Divine Power" action="Bonus Action">
            <description>You touch your holy symbol, utter a prayer, and regain one expended 1st-level spell slot.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Blessed Warrior" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTING_STYLE_BLESSED_WARRIOR">
        <supports>Fighting Style, Paladin</supports>
        <requirements>ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_PALADIN</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>You learn two cantrips of your choice from the cleric spell list. They count as paladin spells for you, and Charisma is your spellcasting ability for them. Whenever you gain a level in this class, you can replace one of these cantrips with another cantrip from the cleric spell list.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Whenever you gain a level in this class, you can replace one of these cantrips with another cantrip from the cleric spell list.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Blessed Warrior)" number="2" supports="Cleric,0" spellcasting="Paladin" known="true" allowReplace="true" />
        </rules>
    </element>

  <!-- Ranger -->
    <element name="Druidic Warrior" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTING_STYLE_DRUIDIC_WARRIOR">
        <supports>Fighting Style, Ranger</supports>
        <requirements>ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_RANGER||ID_DRACODRUID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FOCUSED_RANGER||ID_DRACODRUID_GM_BINDER_CLASS_URBAN_RANGER||ID_REGULAR_TVR3_CLASS_VERSATILE_RANGER</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>You learn two cantrips of your choice from the druid spell list. They count as ranger spells for you, and Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for them. Whenever you gain a level in this class, you can replace one of these cantrips with another cantrip from the druid spell list.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Whenever you gain a level in this class, you can replace one of these cantrips with another cantrip from the druid spell list.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Blessed Warrior)" number="2" supports="Druid,0" spellcasting="Ranger" known="true" allowReplace="true" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_CLASSFEATURE_RANGER_SPELLCASTING">
        <rules>
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_RANGER_SPELL_VERSATILITY" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_RANGER_SPELLCASTING_FOCUS" />
        </rules>
    </append>
    <element name="Spell Versatility" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_RANGER_SPELL_VERSATILITY">
        <description>
            <p>Whenever you finish a long rest, you can replace one spell you learned from this Spellcasting feature with another spell from the ranger spell list. The new spell must be the same level as the spell you replace.</p>
            <div class="sidebar">
                <h5 class="caption">Rule Tip: Cantrips Are Spells</h5>
                <p>Cantrips are 0-level spells, which don’t use spell slots. When a feature applies to spells, that feature applies to cantrips, unless the feature specifies that the spells must be of 1st level or higher or must expend a spell slot.</p>
            </div>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Whenever you finish a long rest, you can replace one spell you learned from your Spellcasting feature with another spell from the ranger spell list. The new spell must be the same level as the spell you replace.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Spellcasting Focus" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_RANGER_SPELLCASTING_FOCUS">
        <description>
            <p>You can use a druidic focus as a spellcasting focus for your ranger spells. See chapter 5, “Equipment,” of the <em>Player’s Handbook</em> for a list of things that count as druidic focuses.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can use a druidic focus as a spellcasting focus for your ranger spells.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_ARCHETYPEFEATURE_RANGER_RANGERS_COMPANION">
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BEAST_MASTER_COMPANION_OPTIONS" />
        </rules>
    </append>
    <element name="Ranger Companion Options" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BEAST_MASTER_COMPANION_OPTIONS">
        <description>
            <p>While wandering the wilds, a ranger encounters many sorts of animals, some of which the ranger might befriend. This friendship can arise from successful use of the Animal Handling skill or the <em>animal friendship</em> spell. If the resulting bond is strong enough, the animal might join the ranger on adventures.</p>
            <p class="indent">A ranger who has the Beast Master archetype can form an even stronger bond, feeling almost like a sibling to an animal. A special type of beast awaits a Beast Master in the wilds, a creature whose lineage stretches back to the beginnings of the world: a primal beast known as a Beast of the Air or a Beast of the Earth. Such a creature seeks out the type of companionship that a Beast Master offers, ready for the two of them to battle the imbalances in the natural world.</p>
            <p class="indent">The primal beast is a special creature that a Beast Master can choose for the Ranger’s Companion feature. When choosing such a creature, you decide whether it is a Beast of the Air or the Earth, and you determine its appearance. Stories describe primal beasts that mystically change form to align with the spirit of their companion.</p>
            <p class="indent">When a primal beast is met apart from a Beast Master, the creature takes the form a regular beast of challenge rating 1/4 or lower, as determined by the DM.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
	<element name="Beast of the Air" type="Companion" source="Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_COMPANION_BEAST_OF_THE_AIR">
		<description />
		<setters>
			<set name="strength">6</set>
			<set name="dexterity">16</set>
			<set name="constitution">13</set>
			<set name="intelligence">8</set>
			<set name="wisdom">14</set>
			<set name="charisma">11</set>
			<set name="ac">13</set>
			<set name="hp">equal the beast’s Constitution modifier + your Wisdom modifier + five times your ranger level (the beast has a number of Hit Dice [d6s] equal to your ranger level)</set>
			<set name="speed"></set>
			<set name="saves"> Dex +5, Con +3, Wis +4</set>
			<set name="skills">Perception +4, Stealth +5</set>
			<set name="senses">darkvision 60 ft., passive Perception 14</set>
			<set name="languages">understands the languages you speak</set>
			<set name="type">Beast</set>
			<set name="size">Small</set>
			<set name="alignment">neutral</set>
			<set name="challenge">0</set>
			<set name="traits">ID_WOTC_UA20191104_COMPANION_TRAIT_BOA_FLYBY, ID_WOTC_UA20191104_COMPANION_TRAIT_PRIMAL_REBIRTH, ID_WOTC_UA20191104_COMPANION_TRAIT_READY_COMPANION</set>
			<set name="actions">ID_WOTC_UA20191104_COMPANION_ACTION_BOA_SHRED</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="companion:ac" value="13" />
			<stat name="companion:hp:max" value="companion:constitution:modifier" />
            <stat name="companion:hp:max" value="wisdom:modifier" />
            <stat name="companion:hp:max" value="level:ranger" />
            <stat name="companion:hp:max" value="level:ranger" />
            <stat name="companion:hp:max" value="level:ranger" />
            <stat name="companion:hp:max" value="level:ranger" />
            <stat name="companion:hp:max" value="level:ranger" />
			<stat name="companion:speed" value="10" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="companion:speed:fly" value="60" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="companion:perception:proficiency" value="companion:proficiency" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="companion:stealth:proficiency" value="companion:proficiency" bonus="proficiency" />
			<stat name="companion:dexterity:save:proficiency" value="companion:proficiency" bonus="proficiency" />
			<stat name="companion:constitution:save:proficiency" value="companion:proficiency" bonus="proficiency" />
			<stat name="companion:wisdom:save:proficiency" value="companion:proficiency" bonus="proficiency" />
		</rules>
	</element>
        <element name="Flyby" type="Companion Trait" source="Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_COMPANION_TRAIT_BOA_FLYBY">
            <description>
                <p>The beast doesn’t provoke opportunity attacks when it flies out of an enemy’s reach.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>The beast doesn’t provoke opportunity attacks when it flies out of an enemy’s reach.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Primal Rebirth" type="Companion Trait" source="Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_COMPANION_TRAIT_PRIMAL_REBIRTH">
            <description>
                <p>If the beast has died within the last hour, you can use your action to touch it and expend a spell slot of 1st level or higher. The beast returns to life after 1 minute with all its hit points restored.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>If the beast has died within the last hour, you can use your action to touch it and expend a spell slot of 1st level or higher. The beast returns to life after 1 minute with all its hit points restored.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Ready Companion" type="Companion Trait" source="Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_COMPANION_TRAIT_READY_COMPANION">
            <description>
                <p>As a bonus action, you can command the beast to make its shred attack or to Hide.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>As a bonus action, you can command the beast to make its shred attack or to Hide.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Shred" type="Companion Action" source="Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_COMPANION_ACTION_BOA_SHRED">
            <description>
                <p>Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 1d6 + 3 slashing damage.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 1d6 + 3 slashing damage.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
	<element name="Beast of the Earth" type="Companion" source="Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_COMPANION_BEAST_OF_THE_EARTH">
		<description />
		<setters>
			<set name="strength">14</set>
			<set name="dexterity">14</set>
			<set name="constitution">15</set>
			<set name="intelligence">8</set>
			<set name="wisdom">14</set>
			<set name="charisma">11</set>
			<set name="ac">12</set>
			<set name="hp">equal the beast’s Constitution modifier + your Wisdom modifier + five times your ranger level (the beast has a number of Hit Dice [d8s] equal to your ranger level)</set>
			<set name="speed">40 ft., climb or swim 40 ft. (your choice when you bond with the beast)</set>
            <set name="saves">Dex +4, Con +4, Wis +4</set>
            <set name="skills">Perception +4, Stealth +4</set>
			<set name="senses">darkvision 60 ft., passive Perception 14</set>
			<set name="languages">understands the languages you speak</set>
			<set name="type">Beast</set>
			<set name="size">Medium</set>
			<set name="alignment">neutral</set>
			<set name="challenge">0</set>
			<set name="traits">ID_WOTC_UA20191104_COMPANION_TRAIT_BOE_CHARGE, ID_WOTC_UA20191104_COMPANION_TRAIT_PRIMAL_REBIRTH, ID_WOTC_UA20191104_COMPANION_TRAIT_READY_COMPANION</set>
			<set name="actions">ID_WOTC_UA20191104_COMPANION_ACTION_BOE_MAUL</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="companion:ac" value="12" />
			<stat name="companion:hp:max" value="companion:constitution:modifier" />
            <stat name="companion:hp:max" value="wisdom:modifier" />
            <stat name="companion:hp:max" value="level:ranger" />
            <stat name="companion:hp:max" value="level:ranger" />
            <stat name="companion:hp:max" value="level:ranger" />
            <stat name="companion:hp:max" value="level:ranger" />
            <stat name="companion:hp:max" value="level:ranger" />
			<stat name="companion:speed" value="40" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="companion:perception:proficiency" value="companion:proficiency" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="companion:stealth:proficiency" value="companion:proficiency" bonus="proficiency" />
			<stat name="companion:dexterity:save:proficiency" value="companion:proficiency" bonus="proficiency" />
			<stat name="companion:constitution:save:proficiency" value="companion:proficiency" bonus="proficiency" />
			<stat name="companion:wisdom:save:proficiency" value="companion:proficiency" bonus="proficiency" />
		</rules>
	</element>
        <element name="Charge" type="Companion Trait" source="Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_COMPANION_TRAIT_BOE_CHARGE">
            <description>
                <p>If the beast moves at least 20 feet straight toward a target and then hits it with a maul attack on the same turn, the target takes an extra 1d6 slashing damage. The DC equals your spell save DC. If the target is a creature, it must succeed on a Strength saving throw against your spell save DC or be knocked prone.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>If the beast moves at least 20 feet straight toward a target and then hits it with a maul attack on the same turn, the target takes an extra 1d6 slashing damage. The DC equals your spell save DC. If the target is a creature, it must succeed on a Strength saving throw against your spell save DC or be knocked prone.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Maul" type="Companion Action" source="Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_COMPANION_ACTION_BOE_MAUL">
            <description>
                <p>Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 1d6 + 2 slashing damage.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 1d6 + 2 slashing damage.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    <!-- Rogue Cunning Action -->
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_ROGUE_CUNNINGACTION">
        <rules>
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_ROGUE_CUNNING_ACTION_AIM" />
        </rules>
    </append>
    <element name="Cunning Action: Aim" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_ROGUE_CUNNING_ACTION_AIM">
        <description>
            <p>You gain an additional way to use your Cunning Action: carefully aiming your next attack. As a bonus action, you give yourself advantage on your next attack roll on the current turn. You can use this bonus action only if you haven’t moved during this turn, and after you use the bonus action, your speed is 0 until the end of the current turn.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="Cunning Action" alt="Aim" action="Bonus Action">
            <description>You give yourself advantage on your next attack roll on the current turn. You can use this bonus action only if you haven’t moved during this turn, and after you use the bonus action, your speed is 0 until the end of the current turn.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

  <!-- Sorcerer -->
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_SORCERER_SPELLCASTING_SORCERER">
        <rules>
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_SORCERER_SPELL_VERSATILITY" />
        </rules>
    </append>
    <element name="Spell Versatility" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_SORCERER_SPELL_VERSATILITY">
        <description>
            <p>Whenever you finish a long rest, you can replace one spell you learned from this Spellcasting feature with another spell from the sorcerer spell list. The new spell must be the same level as the spell you replace.</p>
            <div class="sidebar">
                <h5 class="caption">Rule Tip: Cantrips Are Spells</h5>
                <p>Cantrips are 0-level spells, which don’t use spell slots. When a feature applies to spells, that feature applies to cantrips, unless the feature specifies that the spells must be of 1st level or higher or must expend a spell slot.</p>
            </div>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Whenever you finish a long rest, you can replace one spell you learned from your Spellcasting feature with another spell from the sorcerer spell list. The new spell must be the same level as the spell you replace.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <!-- Font of Magic Options -->
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_SORCERER_FONT_OF_MAGIC">
        <rules>
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_SORCERER_FONT_OF_MAGIC_OPTIONS" />
        </rules>
    </append>
    <element name="Font of Magic Options" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_SORCERER_FONT_OF_MAGIC_OPTIONS">
        <description>
            <h5>EMPOWERING RESERVES</h5>
            <p>When you make an ability check on your turn, you can spend 2 sorcery points to gain advantage on the check.</p>
            <h5>IMBUING TOUCH</h5>
            <p>As an action, you can touch one nonmagical weapon and spend 2 sorcery points to imbue it with magic for 1 minute. For the duration, the weapon is considered magical for the purpose of overcoming immunity and resistance to nonmagical attacks.</p>
            <h5>SORCEROUS FORTITUDE</h5>
            <p>As an action, you can spend any number of sorcery points to roll a d4 for each point expended. You gain a number of temporary hit points equal to the total rolled.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you make an ability check on your turn, you can spend 2 sorcery points to gain advantage on the check.
            As an action, you can touch one nonmagical weapon and spend 2 sorcery points to imbue it with magic for 1 minute. For the duration, the weapon is considered magical for the purpose of overcoming immunity and resistance to nonmagical attacks.
            As an action, you can spend any number of sorcery points to roll a d4 for each point expended. You gain a number of temporary hit points equal to the total rolled.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <!-- Metamagic Options -->
    <element name="Elemental Spell" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_SORCERER_METAMAGIC_ELEMENTAL_SPELL">
        <supports>Metamagic</supports>
        <description>
            <p>When you cast a spell that deals a type of damage from the following list, you can spend 1 sorcery point to change that damage type to one of the other listed types: acid, cold, fire, lightning, thunder.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you cast a spell that deals a type of damage from the following list, you can spend 1 sorcery point to change that damage type to one of the other listed types: acid, cold, fire, lightning, thunder.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Seeking Spell" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_SORCERER_METAMAGIC_SEEKING_SPELL">
        <supports>Metamagic</supports>
        <description>
            <p>When you cast a spell that requires you to make a spell attack roll or that forces a target to make a Dexterity saving throw, you can spend 1 sorcery point to ignore the effects of half- and three-quarters cover against targets of the spell.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you cast a spell that requires you to make a spell attack roll or that forces a target to make a Dexterity saving throw, you can spend 1 sorcery point to ignore the effects of half- and three-quarters cover against targets of the spell.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Unerring Spell" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_SORCERER_METAMAGIC_UNERRING_SPELL">
        <supports>Metamagic</supports>
        <description>
            <p>If you make an attack roll for a spell and miss, you can spend 2 sorcery points to reroll the attack roll. You must use the result of the second roll.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can use Unerring Spell even if you have already used a different Metamagic option during the casting of the spell.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>If you make an attack roll for a spell and miss, you can spend 2 sorcery points to reroll the attack roll. You must use the result of the second roll. You can use Unerring Spell even if you have already used a different Metamagic option during the casting of the spell.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

  <!-- Warlock -->
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_SPELLCASTING_WARLOCK_PACT_MAGIC">
        <rules>
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_SPELL_VERSATILITY" />
        </rules>
    </append>
    <element name="Spell Versatility" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_SPELL_VERSATILITY">
        <description>
            <p>Whenever you finish a long rest, you can replace one spell you learned from this Pact Magic feature with another spell from the warlock spell list. The new spell must be the same level as the spell you replace.</p>
            <div class="sidebar">
                <h5 class="caption">Rule Tip: Cantrips Are Spells</h5>
                <p>Cantrips are 0-level spells, which don’t use spell slots. When a feature applies to spells, that feature applies to cantrips, unless the feature specifies that the spells must be of 1st level or higher or must expend a spell slot.</p>
            </div>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Whenever you finish a long rest, you can replace one spell you learned from your Pact Magic feature with another spell from the warlock spell list. The new spell must be the same level as the spell you replace.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <!-- Warlock Pact Boon -->
    <element name="Pact of the Talisman" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_PACT_OF_THE_TALISMAN"> 
        <supports>Pact Boon</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Your patron gives you a special amulet, a talisman that can aid you, or anyone else who wears it, when the need is great. When the wearer makes an ability check with a skill in which they lack proficiency, they can add a d4 to the roll.</p>
            <p class="indent">If you lose the talisman, you can perform a 1-hour ceremony to receive a replacement from your patron. This ceremony can be performed during a short or long rest, and it destroys the previous amulet.</p>
            <p class="indent">The talisman turns to ash when you die.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When the wearer of your patron’s amulet makes an ability check with a skill in which they lack proficiency, they can add a d4 to the roll.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <!-- Warlock Eldritch Invocations-->
    <element name="Bond of the Talisman" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_INVOCATION_BOND_OF_THE_TALISMAN">
        <supports>Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>12th level, Pact of the Talisman feature</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:12],ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_PACT_OF_THE_TALISMAN</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 12th level, Pact of the Talisman feature</p>
            <p>While someone else is wearing your talisman, you can use your action to teleport to the unoccupied space closest to them, provided the two of you are on the same plane of existence. The wearer of your talisman can do the same thing, using their action to teleport to you.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Action">
            <description>While someone else is wearing your talisman, you can teleport to the unoccupied space closest to them, provided the two of you are on the same plane of existence. The wearer of your talisman can do the same thing, using their action to teleport to you.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Chain Master’s Fury" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_INVOCATION_CHAIN_MASTERS_FURY">
        <supports>Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>9th level, Pact of the Chain feature</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:9],ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_PACT_BOON_PACT_OF_THE_CHAIN</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 9th level, Pact of the Chain feature</p>
            <p>As a bonus action, you can command your familiar to make one attack.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Bonus Action">
            <description>You can command your familiar to make one attack.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Eldritch Armor" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_INVOCATION_ELDRITCH_ARMOR">
        <supports>Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>Pact of the Blade feature</prerequisite>
        <requirements>ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_PACT_BOON_PACT_OF_THE_BLADE</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Pact of the Blade feature</p>
            <p>As an action, you can touch a suit of armor that isn’t being worn or carried by anyone and instantly don it, provided you aren’t wearing armor already. You are proficient with this suit of armor until it’s removed.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Action">
            <description>You can touch a suit of armor that isn’t being worn or carried by anyone and instantly don it, provided you aren’t wearing armor already. You are proficient with this suit of armor until it’s removed.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Eldritch Mind" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_INVOCATION_ELDRITCH_MIND">
        <supports>Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>Pact of the Tome feature</prerequisite>
        <requirements>ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_PACT_BOON_PACT_OF_THE_TOME</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Pact of the Tome feature</p>
            <p>You have advantage on Constitution saving throws that you make to maintain your concentration on a spell.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You have advantage on Constitution saving throws that you make to maintain your concentration on a spell.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Far Scribe" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_INVOCATION_FAR_SCRIBE">
        <supports>Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>5th level, Pact of the Tome feature</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:5],ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_PACT_BOON_PACT_OF_THE_TOME</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 5th level, Pact of the Tome feature</p>
            <p>A new page appears in your Book of Shadows. With your permission, a creature can use its action to write its name on that page, which can contain a number of names equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum of 1).</p>
            <p class="indent">You can cast the <em>sending</em> spell, targeting a creature whose name is on the page, without using a spell slot and without using material components. To do so, you must write the message on the page. The target hears the message in their mind, and if the target replies, their message appears on the page, rather than in your mind. The writing disappears after 1 minute.</p>
            <p class="indent">As an action, you can magically erase a name on the page by touching the name on it.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>A new page appears in your Book of Shadows. With your permission, a creature can use its action to write its name on that page, which can contain up to {{far-scribe:names}} names. You can cast the sending spell, targeting a creature whose name is on the page, without using a spell slot and without using material components. To do so, you must write the message on the page. As an action, you can magically erase a name on the page by touching the name on it.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="far-scribe:names" value="1" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="far-scribe:names" value="charisma:modifier" bonus="base" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SENDING" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Gift of the Protectors" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_INVOCATION_GIFT_OF_THE_PROTECTORS">
        <supports>Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>9th level, Pact of the Tome feature</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:9],ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_PACT_BOON_PACT_OF_THE_TOME</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 9th level, Pact of the Tome feature</p>
            <p>A new page appears in your Book of Shadows. With your permission, a creature can use its action to write its name on that page, which can contain a number of names equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum of 1).</p>
            <p class="indent">When any creature whose name is on the page is reduced to 0 hit points but not killed outright, the creature magically drops to 1 hit point instead. Once this magic is triggered, no creature can benefit from it until you finish a long rest.</p>
            <p class="indent">As an action, you can magically erase a name on the page by touching the name on it.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>A new page appears in your Book of Shadows. With your permission, a creature can use its action to write its name on that page, which can contain up to {{protectors-gift:names}} names. When any creature whose name is on the page is reduced to 0 hit points but not killed outright, the creature magically drops to 1 hit point instead. Once this magic is triggered, no creature can benefit from it until you finish a long rest. As an action, you can magically erase a name on the page by touching the name on it.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="protectors-gift:names" value="1" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="protectors-gift:names" value="charisma:modifier" bonus="base" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SENDING" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Investment of the Chain Master" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_INVOCATION_INVESTMENT_OF_THE_CHAIN_MASTER">
        <supports>Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>Pact of the Chain feature</prerequisite>
        <requirements>ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_PACT_BOON_PACT_OF_THE_CHAIN</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Pact of the Chain feature</p>
            <p>When you cast <em>find familiar</em>, you infuse the summoned familiar with a measure of your eldritch power, granting the creature the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>The familiar gains either a flying speed or a swimming speed (your choice) of 40 feet.</li>
                <li>The familiar no longer needs to breathe.</li>
                <li>The familiar’s weapon attacks are considered magical for the purpose of overcoming immunity and resistance to nonmagical attacks.</li>
                <li>If the familiar forces a creature to make a saving throw, it uses your spell save DC.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you cast find familiar, you infuse the summoned familiar with a measure of your eldritch power, granting the creature the following benefits: The familiar gains either a flying speed or a swimming speed (your choice) of 40 feet. The familiar no longer needs to breathe. The familiar’s weapon attacks are considered magical for the purpose of overcoming immunity and resistance to nonmagical attacks. If the familiar forces a creature to make a saving throw, it uses your spell save DC.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Protection of the Talisman" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_INVOCATION_PROTECTION_OF_THE_TALISMAN">
        <supports>Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>9th level, Pact of the Talisman feature</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:9],ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_PACT_OF_THE_TALISMAN</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 9th level, Pact of the Talisman feature</p>
            <p>When the wearer of your talisman makes a saving throw in which they lack proficiency, they can add a d4 to the roll.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When the wearer of your talisman makes a saving throw in which they lack proficiency, they can add a d4 to the roll.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Rebuke of the Talisman" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_INVOCATION_REBUKE_OF_THE_TALISMAN">
        <supports>Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>Pact of the Talisman feature</prerequisite>
        <requirements>ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_PACT_OF_THE_TALISMAN</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Pact of the Talisman feature</p>
            <p>When the wearer of your talisman is hit by an attacker you can see within 30 feet of you, you can use your reaction to deal psychic damage to the attacker equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum of 1 damage) and push it up to 10 feet away from the talisman’s wearer.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Reaction">
            <description>When the wearer of your talisman is hit by an attacker you can see within 30 feet of you, you can use your reaction to deal {{talisman-rebuke:damage}} psychic damage to the attacker and push it up to 10 feet away from the talisman’s wearer.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="talisman-rebuke:damage" value="1" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="talisman-rebuke:damage" value="charisma:modifier" bonus="base" />
        </rules>
    </element>

  <!-- Wizard -->
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_WIZARD_SPELLCASTING_WIZARD">
        <rules>
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_WIZARD_CANTRIP_VERSATILITY" />
        </rules>
    </append>
    <element name="Cantrip Versatility" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Class Feature Variants" id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_WIZARD_CANTRIP_VERSATILITY">
        <description>
            <p>Whenever you gain a level in this class, you can replace one cantrip you learned from this Spellcasting feature with another cantrip from the wizard spell list.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Whenever you gain a level in this class, you can replace one cantrip you learned from this Spellcasting feature with another cantrip from the wizard spell list.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <!-- expanded spell lists -->
    <!-- Bard -->
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_CAUSE_FEAR">
            <supports>Bard</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COLOR_SPRAY">
            <supports>Bard</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMMAND">
            <supports>Bard</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AID">
            <supports>Bard</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENLARGE/REDUCE">
            <supports>Bard</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_MIND_SPIKE">
            <supports>Bard</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MIRROR_IMAGE">
            <supports>Bard</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MASS_HEALING_WORD">
            <supports>Bard</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SLOW">
            <supports>Bard</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_TINY_SERVANT">
            <supports>Bard</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PHANTASMAL_KILLER">
            <supports>Bard</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONTACT_OTHER_PLANE">
            <supports>Bard</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RARYS_TELEPATHIC_BOND">
            <supports>Bard</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HEROES_FEAST">
            <supports>Bard</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_MENTAL_PRISON">
            <supports>Bard</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_SCATTER">
            <supports>Bard</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_TENSERS_TRANSFORMATION">
            <supports>Bard</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_POWER_WORD_PAIN">
            <supports>Bard</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PRISMATIC_SPRAY">
            <supports>Bard</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANTIPATHY_SYMPATHY">
            <supports>Bard</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAZE">
            <supports>Bard</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PRISMATIC_WALL">
            <supports>Bard</supports>
        </append>

    <!-- Cleric -->
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_CAUSE_FEAR">
            <supports>Cleric</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PBH_SPELL_WRATHFUL_SMITE">
            <supports>Cleric</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PBH_SPELL_BRANDING_SMITE">
            <supports>Cleric</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PBH_SPELL_AURA_OF_VITALITY">
            <supports>Cleric</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PBH_SPELL_AURA_OF_LIFE">
            <supports>Cleric</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PBH_SPELL_AURA_OF_PURITY">
            <supports>Cleric</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_SKILL_EMPOWERMENT">
            <supports>Cleric</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_WALL_OF_LIGHT">
            <supports>Cleric</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PBH_SPELL_POWER_WORD_HEAL">
            <supports>Cleric</supports>
        </append>

    <!-- Druid -->
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ACID_SPLASH">
            <supports>Druid</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_CEREMONY">
            <supports>Druid</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PROTECTION_FROM_EVIL_AND_GOOD">
            <supports>Druid</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AUGURY">
            <supports>Druid</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONTINUAL_FLAME">
            <supports>Druid</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENLARGE_REDUCE">
            <supports>Druid</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AURA_OF_VITALITY">
            <supports>Druid</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ELEMENTAL_WEAPON">
            <supports>Druid</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_REVIVIFY">
            <supports>Druid</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_THUNDER_STEP">
            <supports>Druid</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_WALL_OF_SAND">
            <supports>Druid</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DIVINATION">
            <supports>Druid</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIRE_SHIELD">
            <supports>Druid</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONE_OF_COLD">
            <supports>Druid</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_DAWN">
            <supports>Druid</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_IMMOLATION">
            <supports>Druid</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FLESH_TO_STONE">
            <supports>Druid</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SYMBOL">
            <supports>Druid</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INCENDIARY_CLOUD">
            <supports>Druid</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_MASS_POLYMORPH">
            <supports>Druid</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_POWER_WORD_HEAL">
            <supports>Druid</supports>
        </append>

    <!-- Paladin Spells -->
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GENTLE_REPOSE">
            <supports>Paladin</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PRAYER_OF_HEALING">
            <supports>Paladin</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WARDING_BOND">
            <supports>Paladin</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_LIFE_TRANSFERENCE">
            <supports>Paladin</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPIRIT_GUARDIANS">
            <supports>Paladin</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_DAWN">
            <supports>Paladin</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FLAME_STRIKE">
            <supports>Paladin</supports>
        </append>

    <!-- Ranger Spells -->
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENTANGLE">
            <supports>Ranger</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SEARING_SMITE">
            <supports>Ranger</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AID">
            <supports>Ranger</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GUST_OF_WIND">
            <supports>Ranger</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGIC_WEAPON">
            <supports>Ranger</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENHANCE_ABILITY">
            <supports>Ranger</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WARDING_BOND">
            <supports>Ranger</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLINDING_SMITE">
            <supports>Ranger</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MELD_INTO_STONE">
            <supports>Ranger</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_REVIVIFY">
            <supports>Ranger</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TONGUES">
            <supports>Ranger</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DEATH_WARD">
            <supports>Ranger</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DOMINATE_BEAST">
            <supports>Ranger</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AWAKEN">
            <supports>Ranger</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GREATER_RESTORATION">
            <supports>Ranger</supports>
        </append>

    <!-- Sorcerer Spells -->
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_PRIMAL_SAVAGERY">
            <supports>Sorcerer, Tweaked Sorcerer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GREASE">
            <supports>Sorcerer, Tweaked Sorcerer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PROTECTION_FROM_EVIL_AND_GOOD">
            <supports>Sorcerer, Tweaked Sorcerer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FLAME_BLADE">
            <supports>Sorcerer, Tweaked Sorcerer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FLAMING_SPHERE">
            <supports>Sorcerer, Tweaked Sorcerer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_VAMPIRIC_TOUCH">
            <supports>Sorcerer, Tweaked Sorcerer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIRE_SHIELD">
            <supports>Sorcerer, Tweaked Sorcerer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FLESH_TO_STONE">
            <supports>Sorcerer, Tweaked Sorcerer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DEMIPLANE">
            <supports>Sorcerer, Tweaked Sorcerer</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FORESIGHT">
            <supports>Sorcerer, Tweaked Sorcerer</supports>
        </append>

    <!-- Warlock Spells -->
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_THUNDERWAVE">
            <supports>Warlock</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_KNOCK">
            <supports>Warlock</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANIMATE_DEAD">
            <supports>Warlock</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_LIFE_TRANSFERENCE">
            <supports>Warlock</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MISLEAD">
            <supports>Warlock</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MODIFY_MEMORY">
            <supports>Warlock</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PLANAR_BINDING">
            <supports>Warlock</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TELEPORTATION_CIRCLE">
            <supports>Warlock</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_CREATE_HOMUNCULUS">
            <supports>Warlock</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGIC_JAR">
            <supports>Warlock</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PROJECT_IMAGE">
            <supports>Warlock</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ABIDALZIMS_HORRID_WILTING">
            <supports>Warlock</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GATE">
            <supports>Warlock</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHAPECHANGE">
            <supports>Warlock</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WEIRD">
            <supports>Warlock</supports>
        </append>

    <!-- Wizard Spells -->
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AUGURY">
            <supports>Wizard</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENHANCE_ABILITY">
            <supports>Wizard</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_DEAD">
            <supports>Wizard</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DIVINATION">
            <supports>Wizard</supports>
        </append>


</elements>