<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Compendium of Spells</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="compendium-of-spells.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/spells/compendium-of-spells.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Compendium of Spells" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_ANATHEMYS_HOMEBREWERY_SOURCE_COMPENDIUM_OF_SPELLS">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p>Many forms of magic have been created over the centuries, leading to a great diversity of different spells and effects. Some are powerful, and others weak, but all saw enough use for their creators to put ink to paper to remember them. The most useful, of course, are still commonly known, though they may have changed significantly from how they once were. Variations on quintessential spells such as fireball or planar binding come in all kinds, but there are more wonderous effects yet in old, forgotten magic.</p><p class="indent">These spells are rare, and might be the purview of secretive sects in far removed mountain valleys, or contained in the spellbooks of archmages long dead. Uncommon magic comes with uncommon strength, and many of these spells are difficult to find, let alone learn and comprehend. But for those with the will, the knowledge, the faith, or the skill to seek out this power, there is little common left in the world to learn.</p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation">COS</set>
            <set name="url">https://homebrewery.naturalcrit.com/share/NkSX48-Rl</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" url="https://www.reddit.com/u/Anathemys">u/Anathemys</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20200323</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Airboat" type="Spell" source="Compendium of Spells" id="ID_ANATHEMYS_COS_SPELL_AIRBOAT">
        <supports>Bard, Cleric, Druid, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>A boat formed from clouds comes into existence above the caster. This ship can be any sort of ship the caster has seen and remembers. The clouds that compose this ship do not block the majority of sunlight, and thus does not affect the light underneath it. This ship has 100 hit points, an AC of 12, and immunity to acid, cold, and poison damage. It has a fly speed of 120 feet, and can carry a number of creatures equal to three times the caster’s spellcasting ability modifier.</p>
            <p class="indent">Only the caster may pilot the ship. While piloting it, you may use your action to fire up to three bolts of lightning. Choose a single target or a number of targets within 60 feet, and make a ranged spell attack roll for each bolt of lighting. Each bolt deals 3d6 lighting damage on a hit.</p>
            <p class="indent">A gust of wind spell or similar magic halves the speed of the boat, and will dispel it entirely if it spends more than two rounds within the area of effect. The skywrite spell can be used to open up a hole in the ship, large enough only to drop a single creature from the craft.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">8</set>
            <set name="school">conjuration</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a wisp of wool covered in silver dust worth at least 100gp, which the spell consumes</set>
            <set name="duration">12 hours</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Behold" type="Spell" source="Compendium of Spells" id="ID_ANATHEMYS_COS_SPELL_BEHOLD">
        <supports>Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>As an action, you summon a Beholder’s eye ray to assault a creature that you can see within range. When you cast this spell, roll a d10 on the following table to determine the effect.</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d10</td><td>Effect</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td><strong>1. Charm Ray.</strong> The targeted creature must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be charmed by you for 1 minute, or until the caster or their allies harm the target. A creature immune to being charmed is not affected by this ray.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td><strong>2. Paralyzing Ray.</strong> The targeted creature must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or be paralyzed for 1 minute. The target can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on a success.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td><strong>3. Fear Ray.</strong> The targeted creature must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be frightened for 1 minute. The target can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on a success. A creature immune to being frightened is not affected by this ray.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td><strong>4. Slowing Ray.</strong> The target must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, the target’s speed is halved for 1 minute. In addition, the creature cannot take reactions, and can take either an action or a bonus action on its turn, not both. The target can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on a success.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td><strong>5. Enervation Ray.</strong> The targeted creature must make a Constitution saving throw, taking 10d6 necrotic damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td><strong>6. Telekinetic Ray.</strong> The target must make a Strength saving throw. On a failure, you may move the creature up to 30ft in any direction. The creature is restrained by the magic until the beginning of your next turn.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>7</td><td><strong>7. Sleep Ray.</strong> The targeted creature must make a Wisdom saving throw or fall asleep and remain unconscious for 1 minute. The target awakens if it takes damage or another creature takes an action to wake it. This ray has no effect on constructs or undead, or creatures immune to being charmed.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>8</td><td><strong>8. Petrification Ray.</strong> The targeted creature must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, the creature begins to turn to stone and is restrained, which lasts for one minute. The target can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on a success. If the effect lasts 1 minute, the target is petrified until freed by the greater restoration spell or other magic.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>9</td><td><strong>9. Disintegration Ray.</strong> The target must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or take 11d6 + 25 force damage. If this damage reduces the target to 0 hit points, its body is reduced to a fine gray dust.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>10</td><td><strong>10. Death Ray.</strong> The target succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or take 12d6 necrotic damage. The target dies if the ray reduces it to 0 hit points.</td></tr>
            </table>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When cast with an 8th level spell slot, you may target two creatures within range, which increases to three creatures when cast as a 9th level spell. When rolling for multiple targets, reroll any duplicate results. You must specify which ray will target which creature before you make the roll.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">7</set>
            <set name="school">evocation</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">an eyeball from a Beholder</set>
            <set name="duration">1 round</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Bend Time" type="Spell" source="Compendium of Spells" id="ID_ANATHEMYS_COS_SPELL_BEND_TIME">
        <supports>Bard, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>When you cast this spell, you warp time to bend magical forces to your will. As a part of casting this spell, choose another spell you have prepared of 3rd level or lower with a casting time of one action. You cast that spell at the same moment that you cast this one, expending both slots as normal. This spell also bypasses normal rules concerning casting more than one 1st level or higher spell in one turn.</p>
            <p class="indent">After casting this spell, you must make a Constitution saving throw as the normal flow of time re-asserts itself. On a failure, you are stunned until the end of your next turn. On a success, you are not stunned, but may only take an action or a bonus action on your next turn, not both.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">5</set>
            <set name="school">transmutation</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a crystal hourglass worth 75gp</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Conjure Azer" type="Spell" source="Compendium of Spells" id="ID_ANATHEMYS_COS_SPELL_CONJURE_AZER">
        <supports>Druid, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>An azer from the Plane of Fire appears in a space you designate within 30 feet. This azer is friendly towards you, and will perform a single service before disappearing, in exchange for the iron puzzle spell component. The azer can do one of the following things.</p>
            <p class="indent">As a master smith, the azer can repair up to 10 weapons or sets of armor, or one third (rounded down) as many if the items are magical. If the weapons or armor are magical, and had lost their magical effects due to being broken, those magical effects can be restored by spending a long rest re-attuning to the item. The azer completes its work in one hour, unless interrupted, in which case it disappears before finishing. If this occurs, the azer fails to complete one weapon or set of armor per minute of interruption.</p>
            <p class="indent">Alternatively, you may have the azer hone or strengthen up to 3 weapons or sets of armor, which may not be magical. After the azer completes its work, the items are considered +1 magic items for 24 hours, allowing them to bypass damage resistances or immunities. The azer completes its work in one hour, unless interrupted, in which case it may disappear before finishing. If this occurs, the azer fails to complete one weapon or set of armor per five minutes of interruption.</p>
            <p class="indent">The azer will not participate in combat. If attacked, the azer immediately disappears. Otherwise, a summoned azer disappears when it has finished the assigned task, or when the spell ends. There may be certain magic items that the azer cannot repair, as determined by your DM.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When cast as a 6th level spell, you may choose to summon either more azers, or a more skilled one. If you summon more, you summon three azers and must provide a 50gp iron puzzle for each one summoned. These azer can do quadruple the work in one hour, or complete the normal amount of work in twenty-five minutes, rather than an hour. If you wish to summon a more skilled azer, you must quadruple the normal material cost of this spell. The azer, once summoned, may give weapons and armor a +2 magical enchantment, rather than a +1. Alternatively, it may repair up to 3 magical weapons or armor, immediately restoring their enchantments.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">conjuration</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">30 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a finely crafted iron puzzle worth 50gp, which the spell consumes</set>
            <set name="duration">Conjuration, 1 hour</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Copy" type="Spell" source="Compendium of Spells" id="ID_ANATHEMYS_COS_SPELL_COPY">
        <supports>Bard, Cleric, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>When cast, this spell copies down writing and markings from one location onto a blank sheet. These markings can be on paper, leather, rock, metal, or any other form of discernible material. The copy will be just as legible, or not, as the original.</p>
            <p class="indent">This spell copies up to 20 pages of nonmagical text, or a single spell. If used to copy a spell, that spell can be copied into your wizard’s spellbook, but only if you have the rare inks required to copy that spell normally.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> For each level above 1st, a single casting of this spell copies 20 more pages or one additional spell.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">evocation</set>
            <set name="isRitual">true</set>
            <set name="time">10 minutes</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">blank sheet of paper or blank notebook</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Choke" type="Spell" source="Compendium of Spells" id="ID_ANATHEMYS_COS_SPELL_CHOKE">
        <supports>Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Using magical energy, you attempt to choke the life out of a creature. As an action, you choose a single target you can see within range. That creature makes a Constitution saving throw. On a failure, the creature begins to choke, taking 4d4 necrotic damage per turn. They may repeat the saving throw at the end of each of their turns, ending the effect on a success.</p>
            <p class="indent">While choking, all attacks against the creature have advantage, and the creature’s own attacks have disadvantage. Furthermore, the creature’s speed is halved. If the creature is still affected by the spell after one minute has passed, they fall unconscious. Creatures that do not need to breathe are unaffected by this spell.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">necromancy</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">30 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, 1 minute</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Death Mask" type="Spell" source="Compendium of Spells" id="ID_ANATHEMYS_COS_SPELL_DEATH_MASK">
        <supports>Bard, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>This spell disguises the appearance of a corpse, as if the disguise self spell had been cast on it. The corpse can be made to look like any dead creature of the same size and body format as the original corpse. This illusion does not withstand physical inspection. This corpse may also be animated using an animate dead spell, though it still acts mindless and directionless.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When cast as a 5th level or higher, this spell may disguise a corpse as a living creature, as well as a dead one. The illusion breathes shallowly and blinks, but not as much as an average living creature of its type; as though the creature was sleeping. A creature may discern this illusion with an Insight check against the caster’s spell save DC.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">illusion</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">1 hour</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Disjunction" type="Spell" source="Compendium of Spells" id="ID_ANATHEMYS_COS_SPELL_DISJUNCTION">
        <supports>Druid, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>When cast, all magical effects within 60 feet of the caster are dispelled, and any magical weapons within range are rendered nonmagical. Sentient items and artifacts are only temporarily de-powered, and regain their magic after a short rest, or 24 hours, whichever comes first. Any magical effects or items on the caster, or any creature they touch during the casting of the spell, are not affected by this spell.</p>
            <p class="indent">This spell even has a chance to dispel an antimagic field. This chance equals 1% per level of the caster of disjunction. If dispelled, any magic suppressed by the field is subjected to disjunction as normal. If the antimagic field isn’t dispelled, any magical effects or items suppressed within the field are unaffected by disjunction.</p>
            <p class="indent">Certain magic items can be repaired after being the subject of a disjunction or lesser disjunction spell. Magic items such as potions or scrolls are permanently destroyed. Other magical items with non-recharging uses (such as a chime of opening or a deck of illusions) are also permanently rendered nonmagical. Magic items with recharging uses will regain a single charge after twice the normal recharge time. Finally, an attuned magical item may be repaired by spending a long rest re-attuning to the item.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">9</set>
            <set name="school">abjuration</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self (60ft sphere)</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">an emerald worth at least 1,000gp, which the spell consumes</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Duplicate" type="Spell" source="Compendium of Spells" id="ID_ANATHEMYS_COS_SPELL_DUPLICATE">
        <supports>Bard, Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>This spell creates an illusory duplicate of a single item that can fit inside a 5ft cube. This can be any item, save for an artifact. This illusion feels real when handled, and can inflict damage if the original can, though this can deal no more than 1d6 damage of the same type as the duplicated weapon.</p>
            <p class="indent">Any creature struck with a duplicated weapon, or who has time to investigate another duplicated object, may detect the illusion with a successful Intelligence check against your spell save DC. After one hour, the illusion ends, and the duplicated object vanishes.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When cast with a 5th level slot, the duration of this spell increases to 8 hours. This further increases to 12 hours at 6th level, 24 hours at 7th level, one week at 8th level, and one month at 9th level.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">4</set>
            <set name="school">illusion</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">10 minutes</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a 50gp silver mirror</set>
            <set name="duration">1 hour</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Eye Ray" type="Spell" source="Compendium of Spells" id="ID_ANATHEMYS_COS_SPELL_EYE_RAY">
        <supports>Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>As an action, you release destructive energies in a wide ray from your eyes. You must have a clear line of sight to use this spell. You target a single creature within range that you can see, or two creatures if they are within 5ft of each other. Each creature must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failure, the creatures take 6d8 force damage, and are blinded until the end of their next turn. On a success, the creatures take half damage and are not blinded. You are also blinded until the end of your next turn.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When cast at higher levels, the damage increases by 1d8 per level above 3rd. If cast with a 5th level slot or higher, you may target three creatures within 5 feet with one casting of this spell. If cast with a 7th level or higher spell slot, you are not blinded after casting.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">evocation</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">90 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a burnt monocle</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Fool’s Gold" type="Spell" source="Compendium of Spells" id="ID_ANATHEMYS_COS_SPELL_FOOLS_GOLD">
        <supports>Bard, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Casting this spell is likely to make most town markets quite hostile, provided the caster is ever caught. As an action, you disguise normal currency as gold, thus disguising its true nature. You touch a number of copper coins equal to the amount of gold you would like to create, up to 500gp. These copper coins then become gold coins identical to the gold coin material component. The fake gold coins revert to copper if brought more than 15 feet away from the real gold coin, or whenever they are touched by cold iron.</p>
            <p class="indent">A creature carefully inspecting these coins may notice the illusion on a successful Intelligence check against your spell save DC. This may either be because the copper does not weigh as much as gold, or it might be due to subtle differences in the texture of the copper compared to the etchings shown on the gold coin.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">illusion</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a single real gold piece, and at least 1sp worth of copper</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, 4 hours</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Hesitation" type="Spell" source="Compendium of Spells" id="ID_ANATHEMYS_COS_SPELL_HESITATION">
        <supports>Cleric, Druid, Paladin</supports>
        <description>
            <p>This spell causes creatures to hesitate when acting in combat. Roll 10d8; the total is how many hit points of creature this spell can affect. Creatures within 20 feet of a point you choose within range are affected in ascending order of of their current hit points (ignoring unconscious creatures).</p>
            <p class="indent">Starting with the creature that has the lowest current hit points, each creature affected by this spell has their initiative reduced by 4. This does not affect the current round of combat, and takes effect at the highest initiative of the next round. A creature whose initiative drops to zero due to this spell instead has an initiative of 1, but is stunned until the end of their next turn. This effect lasts until a creature rolls initiative again.</p>
            <p class="indent">Undead are affected normally by this spell. Constructs and creatures who are immune to being charmed aren’t affected by this spell.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, roll an additional 2d8 for each slot above 2nd level.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">enchantment</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a small brass bell and several ball bearings</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Impossible Riddle" type="Spell" source="Compendium of Spells" id="ID_ANATHEMYS_COS_SPELL_IMPOSSIBLE_RIDDLE">
        <supports>Bard, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>This spell mimics the illusory script spell, but hides an insidious secret. Any creature reading the text must make a Wisdom saving throw, or be caught in the confusing riddle. A creature who is immune to being charmed is not affected by this spell, as is one actively engaged in combat or another hostile situation.</p>
            <p class="indent">While caught in the riddle, the creature desires to solve the question posed by the text. Most creatures will stand and look at the text, perhaps moving about slightly, pacing, or otherwise fidgeting while considering the query. The creature has disadvantage on any Wisdom (Perception) checks to perceive anything besides the words of the riddle. This enchantment breaks if the creature is in any way put in danger, or if another creature who has passed their save against the spell takes an action to explain the answer to them. The spell is also broken if the creature is forced to move further than 15 feet from the text. A creature will not become hostile to others who force it from its study.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">enchantment</set>
            <set name="isRitual">true</set>
            <set name="time">10 minutes</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">ink, and a thin silver wire worth 15gp which the spell consumes</set>
            <set name="duration">24 hours</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Inflame Emotions" type="Spell" source="Compendium of Spells" id="ID_ANATHEMYS_COS_SPELL_INFLAME_EMOTIONS">
        <supports>Cleric, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You attempt to strengthen strong emotions in a group of people. Each humanoid in a 20-foot-radius sphere centered on a point you choose within range must make a Charisma saving throw. If a creature fails its saving throw, choose one of the two following effects.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can strengthen an existing worry, anxiety, or concern into actual fear. The creature becomes frightened of whatever it was originally anxious about; for instance, a merchant worried about his goods being damaged might become panicked, while a guard being intimidated by a warrior might flee in fear. When this spell ends, the creature returns to its previous emotion, remembering that it had briefly panicked, but not remembering why.</p>
            <p class="indent">Alternatively, you can make a target become hostile about creatures of your choice that it was previously indifferent or conflicted about. You may not make friends or companions hostile towards one another, unless they were already engaged in a dispute or disagreement. While this spell lasts, the target quarrels loudly with the creatures you specify, arguing with them over petty and trivial matters. A normally non-violent creature will not resort to violence unless responding to violence done against it. However, a normally easily angered or aggressive creature might attack the creatures you mentioned. Each creature’s reaction is determined by your DM. Once this spell ends, the target’s inflamed anger calms, but it may remain hostile if actions taken by the other creature would be sufficient to anger it.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">enchantment</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, 1 minute</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Insatiable Thirst" type="Spell" source="Compendium of Spells" id="ID_ANATHEMYS_COS_SPELL_INSATIABLE_THIRST">
        <supports>Bard, Cleric, Druid, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>A creature affected by this spell is afflicted with a terrible, unquenchable thirst. A target you can see within range makes a Constitution saving throw. On a failure, the target feels as though it is dying of thirst. It immediately consumes any liquids on its person, and spends the next minute seeking out liquid. This includes potions, but does not include any fluid the creature knows to be poisonous, acidic, or otherwise harmful.</p>
            <p class="indent">Liquids which dehydrate, such as alcohol, will be drunk by the creature, but only up to the point at which they realize that the drink is not sating their thirst. Any normally hydrating drink will seem to be helping, even though the creature remains horribly thirsty. A creature may or may not become hostile to those who withhold liquid from them, depending on their temperament.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">enchantment</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">30 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a vial of sand</set>
            <set name="duration">1 minute</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Lesser Disjunction" type="Spell" source="Compendium of Spells" id="ID_ANATHEMYS_COS_SPELL_LESSER_DISJUNCTION">
        <supports>Bard, Druid, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>A weakened version of disjunction, this spell disrupts the magic of a single creature. You choose a single creature within range that you can see, and that creature makes a Dexterity saving throw. On a failure, all magical effects on the creature end, and all of the creature’s carried magical items are stripped of their magic. Sentient items and artifacts are only temporarily de-powered, and regain their magic after a short rest.</p>
            <p class="indent">Attuned magical items affected by this spell can be re-energized by spending a long rest re-attuning to the item. However, non-attuned items (like potions of healing or spell scrolls) are permanently rendered nonmagical.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> This spell affects one additional creature per level above 6th.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">6</set>
            <set name="school">abjuration</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">an emerald worth at least 500gp</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Lighten Load" type="Spell" source="Compendium of Spells" id="ID_ANATHEMYS_COS_SPELL_LIGHTEN_LOAD">
        <supports>Cleric, Druid, Paladin, Ranger</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Heavy objects are rendered lighter by this spell, for easier transportation. When cast, the caster touches a collection of objects not exceeding a 5ft cube. The weight of each of these items decreases by 50%. At the time when the spell ends, if a creature would be carrying more weight than they are normally able to, they must make a Strength saving throw, or fall prone from the sudden weight.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">transmutation</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a feather</set>
            <set name="duration">8 hours</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Minor Chronomancy" type="Spell" source="Compendium of Spells" id="ID_ANATHEMYS_COS_SPELL_MINOR_CHRONOMANCY">
        <supports>Bard, Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You warp time in a basic fashion to double one of your weakest magical effects. As a part of casting this spell, choose one cantrip that you know with a casting time of 1 action which does not allow you to make a weapon attack or more than one attack roll as part of the spell. You cast that cantrip twice during the casting of this spell. You may choose to target different creatures within range, or the same one. If the instead causes effects, you may choose to manifest two effects instead of one, or you may cause the same effect in different areas.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">transmutation</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">fine sand</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Revoke" type="Spell" source="Compendium of Spells" id="ID_ANATHEMYS_COS_SPELL_REVOKE">
        <supports>Bard, Cleric, Druid, Paladin, Warlock</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Bane of spellcasters, this spell forcefully expends one of the target’s spell slots. When cast, you choose one target you can see within range. That creature makes a saving throw using its spellcasting ability score; if the creature does not have a spellcasting ability score specified, they instead make a Constitution saving throw. Thus a creature with the sorcerer class would make a Charisma saving throw, since Charisma is the spellcasting ability for that class. If the creature targeted has no spell slots, the caster takes 2d6 damage per level of the slot expended on this spell.</p>
            <p class="indent">On a failed saving throw, the creature loses its highest level spell slot. It also takes 1d8 necrotic damage per level of the highest level slot lost. These slots can be regained as normal.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When cast as a 7th level spell, you remove instead the target’s two highest spell slots. When cast as a 9th level spell, you remove the target’s three highest spell slots.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">5</set>
            <set name="school">abjuration</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a burnt piece of paper from a dead wizard’s spellbook</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Spellburn" type="Spell" source="Compendium of Spells" id="ID_ANATHEMYS_COS_SPELL_SPELLBURN">
        <supports>Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Similar to the spell revoke, this magic targets spellcasters at the core of their magical ability. When you cast this spell, choose a target you can see within range. If the target has spell slots, it is subjected to a burning magic malaise. If the target does not have spell slots, you take 18d6 + 40 necrotic damage as the magic rebounds on you.</p>
            <p class="indent">Each time the creature casts a spell using a slot of 1st level or higher, they must make a saving throw with their spellcasting ability score. If the creature does not have a spellcasting ability score specified, it makes a Constitution saving throw instead.</p>
            <p class="indent">On a failure, the slot is expended, but the spell does not take effect. The target also then takes 2d8 necrotic damage per level of the slot expended. On a successful save, the spell is cast as normal, and the creature takes only half damage.</p>
            <p class="indent">After three successful saving throws, this effect ends for that creature. After three failed saving throws, the creature is rendered unable to cast spells until they complete a long rest. These successes and failures do not need to be consecutive, keep track of both until one of the two is reached.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">9</set>
            <set name="school">abjuration</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">the gemstone tooth of a demilich worth at least 1,000gp</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Sorrowful Shroud" type="Spell" source="Compendium of Spells" id="ID_ANATHEMYS_COS_SPELL_SORROWFUL_SHROUD">
        <supports>Cleric, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Lost, wailing souls surround the caster, defending them from harm and lashing out at the living around them. As an action, you surround yourself with dread energies, to protect yourself from harm. While this shroud covers you, all attacks against you have disadvantage. Additionally, you may take a bonus action on each of your turns to spin out a bit of necromantic power to strike at your enemies. You make a ranged spell attack against one creature you can see within 30 feet. On a hit, that creature takes 2d8 necrotic damage, and may not regenerate hit points until the start of your next turn.</p>
            <p class="indent">Additionally, mindless undead will not attack you while this shield persists. An intelligent undead, such as a lich or a vampire, must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw to strike you, choosing another target on a failure.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">4</set>
            <set name="school">necromancy</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a bit of dirt from an unmarked grave</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, 1 minute</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Suffocate" type="Spell" source="Compendium of Spells" id="ID_ANATHEMYS_COS_SPELL_SUFFOCATE">
        <supports>Cleric, Druid, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>All creatures within the area of this spell begin to suffocate immediately, gasping for air. Choose a point within view in range. All creatures within 20 feet of that point must make a Constitution saving throw. On a success, they are unaffected by the spell.</p>
            <p class="indent">On a failure, the creature begins to choke, taking 6d6 necrotic damage per turn. They may repeat the save at the end of each of their turns. While suffocating, all attacks against the creature have advantage, and all of the creature’s own attacks have disadvantage. Furthermore, the creature’s speed is halved, and the effect does not end if the creature leaves the radius of the spell.</p>
            <p class="indent">If the creature is still affected by the spell after one minute has passed, they fall unconscious. Creatures that do not need to breathe are unaffected by this spell.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">7</set>
            <set name="school">necromancy</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a bit of rope from a noose</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, 1 minute</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Transcribe Memory" type="Spell" source="Compendium of Spells" id="ID_ANATHEMYS_COS_SPELL_TRANSCRIBE_MEMORY">
        <supports>Bard, Cleric, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>For those wishing to create unerring accounts of events, no spell is better. By spending 1 hour meditating over a blank piece of paper or a blank notebook, you can record accurately your memories of a single event. This event must last no longer than 24 hours, and must have happened within the past week. This record must be written in a language you know. Any creature who reads your account will automatically understand exactly what you saw, though they are free to believe that you were mistaken in your perception, just not in your transcription. The writing created by this spell is nonmagical, and is written in a language you choose when casting the spell.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When cast with a 3rd level spell slot, the event may come from any time in the past month. If cast with a 4th level slot, the event may be from any time in the past year. And if cast with a 5th level spell slot, this event may be from any time in your life.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">divination</set>
            <set name="isRitual">true</set>
            <set name="time">1 hour</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">50gp of rare inks, which is consumed by the spell</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Walk with Spirits" type="Spell" source="Compendium of Spells" id="ID_ANATHEMYS_COS_SPELL_WALK_WITH_SPIRITS">
        <supports>Cleric</supports>
        <description>
            <p>As an action, you enter the realm of the dead, walking with the spirits of those whose bodies lie nearby. Best used in a graveyard or at the site of a battle, this spell allows the caster to speak with the spirits for advice, knowledge, and guidance. However, it also leaves them vulnerable to retribution from angry ghosts.</p>
            <p class="indent">When you cast this spell, you phase into the Border Ethereal. You may not move more than 100 feet away from the original location where you cast the spell. While in the Border Ethereal, you call forward the spirits of any bodies interred nearby; you may then ask questions of the spirits as with the speak with dead spell. You may ask each spirit up to five questions before it is released. These spirits are much freer to answer than with a typical speak with dead spell; the spirit may have learned something since its death, can speculate on the future, and might be able to suggest what questions to ask if it is of the desire to do so. These spirits are not required to answer truthfully, unless you command them to, in which case they will answer only three questions. Otherwise, these spirits can be asked five questions, before they are released from the spell.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once released, the spirit is free to return to rest, or to attack you as a banshee, ghost, or spectre (DM’s choice). You DM has the stats for this creature.</p>
            <p class="indent">A spirit might attack you if your questions disrespected or angered it, or if the person was antagonistic to you or your kind during life. Most spirits do not like being commanded in any way, and doing such might cause them to become angry. A spirit capable of possession will likely open with that ability, before resorting to other attacks. Once defeated, the spirit dissipates and returns to rest.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">6</set>
            <set name="school">necromancy</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 hour</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a bit of a gravestone, and 75gp of incense which is consumed by the spell</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, 1 hour</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Watery Double" type="Spell" source="Compendium of Spells" id="ID_ANATHEMYS_COS_SPELL_WATERY_DOUBLE">
        <supports>Bard, Cleric, Druid, Ranger, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Any still body of liquid this spell is cast on becomes a trap for the next creature to cast its reflection in the liquid. The first creature to cast its reflection in the liquid during the duration causes a watery double to rise from the surface. This creature’s size reflects the size of the body of liquid it comes from, but cannot exceed the size of the triggering creature. This watery double immediately begins attempting to touch the triggering creature, using that creature’s Strength bonus to attempt melee attacks. It has the same hit points, ability scores, and AC of the triggering creature at the time the spell is triggered, but it cannot use any class or racial features.</p>
            <p class="indent">If the watery double successfully touches the creature, it begins to cover it in liquid. The creature must then make a Strength saving throw. On a success, the watery double is destroyed, and the creature is soaked. On a failure, the creature begins taking 3d8 acid damage every turn. The creature also takes damage equal to half of any damage the watery double takes.</p>
            <p class="indent">Casting a create or destroy water spell or similar magic on the watery double immediately destroys it. Casting shape water allows the caster to make a check using their spellcasting ability modifier against the spell save DC of the caster of watery double. If there is no spell save DC available, the DC is 15.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> If cast with a 4th level slot, the duration is one week. When cast as a 5th level spell, the duration is one month. When cast as a 6th level spell, the duration is one year. Casting the spell with a 7th level slot makes the spell permanent.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">conjuration</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">24 hours</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Weight" type="Spell" source="Compendium of Spells" id="ID_ANATHEMYS_COS_SPELL_WEIGHT">
        <supports>Cleric, Paladin, Sorcerer</supports>
        <description>
            <p>This spell guards against theft by increasing the weight of a container when any creature besides the caster attempts to pick it up. This spell affects a single container, such as a chest or pouch, that is no larger than a 5ft cube. When any creature besides the caster attempts to pick up the container, the weight increases to 1d4+1 times the creature’s own weight. The caster may also specify a number of creatures equal to their spellcasting ability modifier, who may also pick up the container. Picking up a creature who has picked up the pouch does not cause this effect.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">transmutation</set>
            <set name="isRitual">true</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a small ball of lead</set>
            <set name="duration">8 hours</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Wild Guess" type="Spell" source="Compendium of Spells" id="ID_ANATHEMYS_COS_SPELL_WILD_GUESS">
        <supports>Bard, Druid, Ranger, Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>When this spell is cast, the caster makes an approximate guess at the number of individuals in a certain group. This can be a group of creatures or a pile of items, but the entire group must be within the range of the spell, and the caster must be able to see individual members of the group for them to be counted. This spell rounds to the largest factor of ten when estimating; thus a pile of 1,780 gold coins would result in a count of 2,000, while a group of 63 swordsmen would result in a count of 60.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell at higher levels, you may count with greater accuracy. Casting the spell with a 3rd level slot counts accurate to the second largest factor of ten, casting it with a 5th level slot counts to the third largest factor of ten, casting with a 7th level slot counts to the fourth largest factor of ten, and casting the spell with a 9th level slot counts to the fifth largest factor of ten.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">divination</set>
            <set name="isRitual">true</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">300 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a flower with all its petals</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

</elements>