<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Minor Necromancy Spells</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="minor-necromancy.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/spells/minor-necromancy.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Minor Necromancy" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_ENRARIC_GM_BINDER_SOURCE_MINOR_NECROMANCY">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p>Standing atop his tower, the lich sends an army of skeletons against the approaching adventurers. Deep in the bowels of his university, a furtive researcher complete the forbidden ritual, raising his recently-dead colleagues as ghouls.</p><p>The ability to create and manipulate undead is a narrative staple of being a necromancer - but what is a fledgling skeleton enthusiast to do when all the re-animating spells are too high-level for him? Use these lower-level necromancy spells, of course!</p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation"></set>
            <set name="url">https://www.gmbinder.com/share/-LZGxIE6yzcgjOYl1QNs</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" url="https://www.gmbinder.com/profile/enraric">u/Enraric</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20200330</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Grasp of the Grave" type="Spell" source="Minor Necromancy" id="ID_ENRARIC_MINOR_NECROMANCY_SPELL_GRASP_OF_THE_GRAVE">
        <supports>Cleric, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Choose a large or smaller creature within range that is not in the air. Decaying hands reach up from the ground to entrap them. The creature must make a Strength or Dexterity saving throw (its choice) or be grappled by the hands. The creature can re-attempt the saving throw as an action on each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">0</set>
            <set name="school">Necromancy</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">30 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a mummified hand</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute.</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Undead Puppet" type="Spell" source="Minor Necromancy" id="ID_ENRARIC_MINOR_NECROMANCY_SPELL_UNDEAD_PUPPET">
        <supports>Cleric, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>This spell creates an undead puppet for you to control. Choose a pile of bones or a corpse of a Medium or Small humanoid within range. Your spell imbues the target with foul energies that you can manipulate, raising it as an undead creature. The target becomes a skeleton if you chose bones or a zombie if you chose a corpse. The creature takes its turns immediately after yours.</p>
            <p class="indent">On each of your turns, you can use a bonus action to mentally command the creature you made with this spell if the creature is within 60 feet of you. You decide what action the creature will take and where it will move during its next turn. Issuing a general command, such as to guard a particular chamber or corridor, has no effect. If you issue no commands, the creature does nothing.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once the spell ends, the creature goes back to being an inanimate corpse or pile of bones.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> You can animate an additional corpse for each spell slot level above 2nd. As a bonus action on your turn, you can issue a single command to any number of undead you have animated via this spell.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Necromancy</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">10 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">fine string and a small piece of wood</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute.</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Raise Familiar" type="Spell" source="Minor Necromancy" id="ID_ENRARIC_MINOR_NECROMANCY_SPELL_RAISE_FAMILIAR">
        <supports>Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You gain the service of a familiar, a spirit that takes possession of the corpse of any animal form you can find: bat, cat, crab, crawling claw, frog (toad), hawk. lizard, octopus, owl, poisonous snake, fish (quipper), rat, raven, sea horse, spider, or weasel. Appearing in an unoccupied space within range, the familiar has the statistics of the chosen form, though it is undead instead of a beast. You choose if its appearance is zombified, mummified ro skeletal, depending on the state of the corpse you use to fashion it.</p>
            <p class="indent">Your familiar acts independently of you, but it always obeys your commands. In combat, it rolls its own initiative and acts on its own turn. A familiar can’t attack, but it can take other actions as normal.</p>
            <p class="indent">When the familiar drops to 0 hit points, or you dismiss it permanently, it returns to being an inanimate corpse. It reappears after you cast this spell again.</p>
            <p class="indent">While your familiar is within 100 feet of you, you can communicate with it telepathically. Additionally, as an action, you can see through your familiar’s eyes and hear what it hears until the start of your next turn, gaining the benefits of any special senses that the familiar has. During this time, you are deaf and blind with regard to your own senses.</p>
            <p class="indent">As an action, you can temporarily dismiss your familiar. It disappears into a pocket dimension where it awaits you summons. Alternatively, you can dismiss it forever. As an action while it is temporarily dismissed, you can cause it to reappear in any unoccupied space within 30 feet of you.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can’t have more than one familiar at a time, even if you know the <em>find familiar</em> spell. If you cast either spell while you already have a familiar, you dismiss it permanently and a new one is created. Choose one of the forms from the above list. Your familiar transforms into the chosen creature.</p>
            <p class="indent">Finally, when you cast a spell with a range of touch, your familiar can deliver the spell as if it had cast the spell. Your familiar must be within 100 feet of you, and it must use its reaction to deliver the spell when you cast it. If the spell requires an attack roll, you use your attack modifier for the roll.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Necromancy</set>
            <set name="time">1 hour</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="range">10 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">the corpse of whatever form you wish your familiar to take, 10 gp worth of charcoal, incense, and herbs that must be consumed by fire in a brass brazier</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
</elements>