<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>The Phantasmagoria: The Art of Verisimilitude</name>
        <author url="https://www.reddit.com/user/VampireSquid8/">u/VampireSquid8</author>
        <update version="0.0.2">
            <file name="phantasmagoria.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/spells/phantasmagoria.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="The Phantasmagoria" type="Source" source="The Phantasmagoria" id="ID_VAMPIRESQUID8_HOMEBREWERY_SOURCE_THE_PHANTASMAGORIA">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<h5>ILLUSION SUBTYPES</h5><p>An illusion’s subtype determines what senses it can affect and to what extent it is capable of affecting real creatures, objects, and events. Illusions can be broken down to five subtypes:</p><p class="indent">Figment: A figment spell creates an external, illusory sensory effect of something seen, heard, smelt, and/or felt. All those who perceive the figment perceive the same thing. Figments cannot cause damage to objects or creatures, support weight, provide nutrition, or provide protection from the elements. Consequently, these spells are useful for confounding or delaying foes, but useless for attacking them directly. (<i>minor illusion, silent image, major image</i>)</p><p class="indent">Glamer: A glamer spell changes a subject’s sensory qualities, making it look, feel, taste, smell, or sound like something else, or even seem to disappear. (<i>disguise self, invisibility</i>)</p><p class="indent">Pattern: Like a figment, a pattern spell creates an illusion that other creatures can perceive, but a pattern also affects the minds of those who see it or are caught in it. (<i>color spray, hypnotic pattern</i>)</p><p class="indent">Phantasm: A phantasm spell creates a mental impression that usually only the caster and the subject (or subjects) of the spell can perceive. This impression is totally in the minds of the subjects and not a fake picture or something that they actually see. Third parties viewing or studying the scene don’t notice the phantasm. (<i>phantasmal force, phantasmal killer</i>)</p><p class="indent">Shadow: A shadow spell creates something that is partially real from extradimensional energy. Such illusions can have real effects. Damage dealt by a shadow illusion is real. (<i>shadow blade, creation, mirage arcane</i>)</p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation"></set>
            <set name="url">https://homebrewery.naturalcrit.com/share/SkbyDhEbvr</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" url="https://www.reddit.com/user/VampireSquid8/">u/VampireSquid8</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20190521</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Arachnophobia" type="Spell" source="The Phantasmagoria" id="ID_PHANTASMAGORIA_SPELL_ARACHNOPHOBIA">
        <supports>Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You plant a terrifying phantasm of arachnids in the mind of a creature you can see within range. The creature must succeed on an Charisma saving throw or become convinced that it is covered in skittering, biting spiders until the beginning of its next turn. It takes 1d4 Psychic damage and can’t take reactions until the beginning of its next turn due to the distracting sensations.</p>
            <p class="indent">This spell’s damage increases by 1d4 when you reach 5th level (2d4), 11th level (3d4), and 17th level (4d4).</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">0</set>
            <set name="school">Illusion (Phantasm)</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="range">30 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a live spider</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Flashburn" type="Spell" source="The Phantasmagoria" id="ID_PHANTASMAGORIA_SPELL_FLASHBURN">
        <supports>Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You cause a dazzling pattern of light to appear briefly in a 5-foot cube within range; the pattern emits bright light in a 15-foot radius before immediately dissipating. A creature in the cube that sees the pattern must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or the pattern is burned into its vision, and it takes a 1d4 penalty to its next attack roll or sight-based ability check (whichever comes first). </p>
            <p class="indent">Once the attack or ability check is resolved, the spell ends and its vision is returned to normal. Sightless creatures are not affected by this spell.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">0</set>
            <set name="school">Illusion (Pattern)</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a bit of mangesium phosphate</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Minor Glamer" type="Spell" source="The Phantasmagoria" id="ID_PHANTASMAGORIA_SPELL_MINOR_GLAMER">
        <supports>Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You imbue a target you touch with a minor glamer that changes its perceived color. You can choose either a single, solid color, or a complex pattern of colors. A target can be no larger than a 5-foot cube (or a 5-foot square on a surface), and only its surface is affected. </p>
            <p class="indent">Medium-sized or smaller creatures may also be targeted by this spell. If the target is an unwilling creature or is an object held by such a creature, the creature must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw to avoid the spell’s effect. This spell can affect a target’s body and gear, but it doesn’t affect the creature’s vision.</p>
            <p class="indent">This spell cannot render a target invisible. When you cast this spell more than once, each new casting ends the effects of the previous casting.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">0</set>
            <set name="school">Illusion (Glamer)</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">1 hour</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">an octopus tentacle</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Shadow Bolt" type="Spell" source="The Phantasmagoria" id="ID_PHANTASMAGORIA_SPELL_SHADOW_BOLT">
        <supports>Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You create an illusory shadow-projectile in your hand and launch it with unerring precision at a creature you can see within range. The illusory projectile can look and sound like whatever you choose, provided it can fit in your hand. The target must succeed on an Intelligence saving throw or take 1d8 Psychic damage. The resulting wound looks and feels real, appropriate to the projectile, but all physical evidence of the attack disappears at the end of your turn. If this attack reduces a target’s HP to 0, the target is stable but Unconscious until it regains HP.</p>
            <p class="indent">This spell’s damage increases by 1d8 when you reach 5th level (2d8), 11th level (3d8), and 17th level (4d8).</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">0</set>
            <set name="school">Illusion (Shadow)</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="range">90 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent"></set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Throne of Shadows" type="Spell" source="The Phantasmagoria" id="ID_PHANTASMAGORIA_SPELL_THRONE_OF_SHADOWS">
        <supports>Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>By pulling together threads of shadow magic, you create a comfortable, partially real chair in an unoccupied space on the ground within range. The chair can be of any size, configuration, and appearance you choose, but it must fit within a 5-ft cube. It is feather-light and utterly  intangible to everything except you and creatures you invite to sit there; everything else simply passes through it. </p>
            <p class="indent">It has an AC of 10, but it will disappear if it takes any amount of damage, such as from an area of effect spell attack. </p>
            <p class="indent">The chair can be dispelled as a bonus  action. You can conjure only one chair at a time.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">0</set>
            <set name="school">Illusion (Shadow)</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">8 hours</set>
            <set name="range">10 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a cushion or pillow</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Ventriloquism" type="Spell" source="The Phantasmagoria" id="ID_PHANTASMAGORIA_SPELL_VENTRILOQUISM">
        <supports>Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Until the end of your next turn, you can make your voice (or any sound that you can normally make vocally) seem to issue from someplace else within range, such as from another creature, a statue, from behind a door, down a passage, etc. Anyone who hears the sound can make an Intelligence saving throw; on a success, the creature recognizes it as illusory (but still hears it).</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">0</set>
            <set name="school">Illusion (Figment)</set>
            <set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
            <set name="duration">1 round</set>
            <set name="range">30 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a piece of paper or parchment rolled into a cone</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Phantasmal Retribution" type="Spell" source="The Phantasmagoria" id="ID_PHANTASMAGORIA_SPELL_PHANTASMAL_RETRIBUTION">
        <supports>Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You point your finger, declaiming retribution, and the creature that discovered your illusion is then surrounded by a frightening phantasmal creature, object, or phenomenon that fits in a 10-foot circle centered on that creature. This illusion exists only in the target’s mind, and it can utilize whatever sensory effects you desire. The target must make an Intelligence saving throw, taking 1d10 Psychic damage on a failed save, or half as much on a successful one. Once the damage has been resolved, the illusion disappears.</p>
            <p class="indent">At Higher Levels:At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d10 for each slot level above 1st.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Illusion (Phantasm)</set>
            <set name="time">1 reaction in response to a creature using an action to successfully determine one of your illusions is fake</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="range">60 ft</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent"></set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Vertigo" type="Spell" source="The Phantasmagoria" id="ID_PHANTASMAGORIA_SPELL_VERTIGO">
        <supports>Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You warp the spatial dimensions immediately around a target, inflicting it with sensations of falling. Choose a creature that you can see within range to make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failure, the target of this spell becomes dizzy as the ground seems to drop away beneath its feet. It must succeed on a Dexterity (Acrobatics) check against your spell save DC at the start of its next turn to use its movement speed. If it fails, it cannot move, and if it fails the check by 5 or more, it falls Prone.
    While affected, the subject also takes a -1 penalty on attack rolls and saving throws. Flying creatures make the intial saving throw with advantage.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Illusion (Pattern)</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">1 round</set>
            <set name="range">30 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent"></set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Beastmask" type="Spell" source="The Phantasmagoria" id="ID_PHANTASMAGORIA_SPELL_BEASTMASK">
        <supports>Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The target is disguised with a glamer that causes beasts to believe that it is a member of their species or some other non-threatening beast. For example, an individual cloaked by this  glamer as a wolf might move through a wolfpack unhindered.</p>
            <p class="indent">You must choose the type of beast you’re masking the target from at the time of casting. If the form you choose is more than one size larger or two sizes smaller than the target’s size, the spell fails. This spell will also end if the target attacks a beast they’ve been masked from.</p>
            <p class="indent">This spell does not allow communication with beasts, nor is the subject granted any of beasts’s characteristics.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Illusion (Glamer)</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">10 minutes</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent"></set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Chameleon" type="Spell" source="The Phantasmagoria" id="ID_PHANTASMAGORIA_SPELL_CHAMELEON">
        <supports>Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>This spell alters the coloration of the target to match the surrounding environment. The target gains a +10 bonus to Dexterity (Stealth) checks for the duration. When moving through areas where the background changes gradually (such as stepping from the edge of a forest into a green field), the coloration of the target changes immediately.</p>
            <p class="indent">When the background changes abruptly (such as moving from a forest to a gray stone corridor), it will take the span of 1 round for the coloration to adjust again, effectively removing the bonus granted by the spell for that round.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Illusion (Glamer)</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">the shed skin of a lizard</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Fool’s Gold" type="Spell" source="The Phantasmagoria" id="ID_PHANTASMAGORIA_SPELL_FOOLS_GOLD">
        <supports>Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>This spell makes metal objects, such as a bronze statue or a handful of copper coins, appear to be made of gold. You can affect 1 cubic-foot of metal, the equivalent of about 150 coins or 3 pounds, per each slot level used to cast this spell. If you want to affect multiple objects, such as a chest full of coins, you only need to touch one of the objects, providing that all of the other objects to be affected are in contact with one another.</p>
            <p class="indent">A successful Intelligence (Investigation) check can determine that the objects are disguised by an illusion, and the illusion becomes faint to the creature who succeeds on that check.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Illusion (Glamer)</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">1 hour</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a powdered gem worth at least 5 gp per each cubic foot, which is consumed</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Phantom Threat" type="Spell" source="The Phantasmagoria" id="ID_PHANTASMAGORIA_SPELL_PHANTOM_THREAT">
        <supports>Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Reaching out to your foe’s mind, you cause it to feel as though a threat looms close behind, no matter which way it turns. Chooose a creature you can see within range to make an Intelligence saving throw. On a failure, it (and only it) perceives that it is threatened by more foes than it actually faces. Though the subject doesn’t actually perceive any additional enemies (and thus doesn’t waste any attacks on the phantasm), a creature affected by this spell is considered flanked*, even if not threatened by other creatures. No amount of convincing by others can help the subject of this spell avoid its effect. A creature that can’t be surprised is immune to this spell.</p>
            <p class="indent">(*Flanking is an optional rule. If your table does not employ this rule, this spell will be inappropriate for that setting.Flanking is an optional rule. If your table does not employ this rule, this spell will be inappropriate for that setting.)</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Illusion (Phantasm)</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">1 round</set>
            <set name="range">30 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent"></set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Towering Oak" type="Spell" source="The Phantasmagoria" id="ID_PHANTASMAGORIA_SPELL_TOWERING_OAK">
        <supports>Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You evoke the power of the forests, causing you to seem to loom over others like a mighty tree dwarfs lesser plants.</p>
            <p class="indent">For the duration, you appear one size category larger than normal and gain a +10 bonus on Charisma (Intimidate) checks and a +2 bonus to Strength (Athletics) checks. </p>
            <p class="indent">If a creature you encounter succeeds on an Insight check against your spell save DC, it can determine that your countenance is enhanced by illusion and the bonuses granted by this spell are not applied to intereactions with that creature. </p>
            <p class="indent">Likewise, your apparent change in size fails to hold up to physical inspection; interacting with the illusory extension reveals it to be an illusion, and the bonuses granted by this spell are not applied to interactions with creatures who physically interact with it or witness the same.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Illusion (Glamer)</set>
            <set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a leaf from an oak tree</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Shadow Binding" type="Spell" source="The Phantasmagoria" id="ID_PHANTASMAGORIA_SPELL_SHADOW_BINDING">
        <supports>Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You cause a multitude of ribbonlike shadows to instantaneously explode out of a 20-foot square within range. For the duration, non-magical dim light within this area becomes darkness, and non-magical bright light becomes dim. Creatures in the area must succeed on a Strength saving throw or be restrained by the shadows.</p>
            <p class="indent">A creature restrained by the shadows can use its action to make a Strength check against your spell save DC. On a success, it frees itself. When the spell ends, the shadows fade away.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Illusion (Shadow)</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="range">90 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a few links of an iron chain</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Bladeweave" type="Spell" source="The Phantasmagoria" id="ID_PHANTASMAGORIA_SPELL_BLADEWEAVE">
        <supports>Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You imbue your melee attacks with a fascinating pattern or rhythm that entrances your opponent. If you successfully hit a target with a melee attack while this spell is active, you can immediately make a second attack with that same weapon as a free action. If the second attack hits, it deals no damage; instead, the target must succeed on a Charisma saving throw or become Charmed by you until the end of its next turn.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Illusion (Pattern)</set>
            <set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
            <set name="duration">1 round</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent"></set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Dark Way" type="Spell" source="The Phantasmagoria" id="ID_PHANTASMAGORIA_SPELL_DARK_WAY">
        <supports>Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You create a shadowy, weightless, unbreakable bridge 5 feet wide, 20 feet long, and 1 inch thick that lasts until the end of your next turn. The dark way must be anchored at both ends to solid objects when created, and it must be continuous and unbroken when formed. </p>
            <p class="indent">A dark way can support a maximum of 200 pounds x your spellcasting modifier.  Creatures and objects that cause the total weight on the dark way to exceed this limit will fall through it as if it weren’t there. You never fall through the dark way unless your own weight exceeds the spell’s maximum capacity.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can only have one dark way in existence at a time.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Illusion (Shadow)</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">1 round</set>
            <set name="range">10 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent"></set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Color Surge" type="Spell" source="The Phantasmagoria" id="ID_PHANTASMAGORIA_SPELL_COLOR_SURGE">
        <supports>Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>All the colors of your body, clothes, and carried equipment shine for a brief moment before they surge away from you, forming a multicolored ray that strikes a creature that you can see within range. The target must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or take 1d10 Psychic damage and become Blinded until the end of its next turn. If it succeeds, it only takes half the damage and is not Blinded.</p>
            <p class="indent">Even if the target succeeds on its save or if some other effect  protects it from the attack’s effects, you become invisible until the end of your next turn or until you make an attack or cast a spell. You cannot cast Color Surge if you are invisible.</p>
            <p class="indent">At Higher Levels:At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d10 for each slot level above 2nd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Illusion (Pattern,</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">1 round</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a prism</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Phantom Trap" type="Spell" source="The Phantasmagoria" id="ID_PHANTASMAGORIA_SPELL_PHANTOM_TRAP">
        <supports>Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>This spell makes a lock or other small mechanism seem to be trapped to anyone who can detect traps. You place the spell upon any mechanism or device, such as a lock, hinge, hasp, cork, cap, or ratchet. Any creature able to detect traps, or who uses any spell or device that enables trap detection, is 100% certain a real trap exists. Of course, the effect is illusory and nothing happens if the trap is "sprung"; its primary purpose is to frighten away theives or make them waste precious time. Casting Detect MagicDetect Magic reveals that the object is affected by illusion magic; casting IdentifyIdentify reveals the nature of the spell(s) affecting the object.</p>
            <p class="indent">If another phantom trap is active within 50 feet when the spell is cast, the casting fails.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Illusion (Glamer)</set>
            <set name="time">1 minute</set>
            <set name="duration">Until dispelled</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">powdered iron pyrite worth at least 50 gp, which is consumed</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Gorgonize" type="Spell" source="The Phantasmagoria" id="ID_PHANTASMAGORIA_SPELL_GORGONIZE">
        <supports>Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The target’s face becomes horrible and terrifying to behold. You can create nearly any combination of hideous features such as rotting skin, a parrot beak, an elephantine nose, bloody tusks, or anything you can imagine. However, you cannot duplicate the appearance of any known creature.</p>
            <p class="indent">Excluding you and your allies, creatures who see the target of this spell must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or become Frightened of the target for the duration. A creature that can no longer see the target can make the saving throw again, ending the Frightened condition on a success.</p>
            <p class="indent">Physical interaction with protruding features (like tusks, horns, etc.) reveals them to be an Illusion, because things can pass through them.</p>
            <p class="indent">If a creature uses its action to examine the target’s features, the creature can determine that it is an illusion with a successful Intelligence (Investigation) check against your spell save DC. If a creature discerns the illusion for what it is, the illusion becomes faint to the creature.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Illusion (Glamer)</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">1 hour</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">assorted, exotic paints worth at least 25 gp, which are consumed</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Cacaphony" type="Spell" source="The Phantasmagoria" id="ID_PHANTASMAGORIA_SPELL_CACAPHONY">
        <supports>Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>For the duration, a deafening array of noises you choose fills a 20-foot-radius sphere centered on a point you choose within range. The noises are inaudible beyond the sphere’s radius. Any creature or object entirely inside the sphere is vulnerable to Thunder damage if it is not immune, and creatures are effectively deafened while entirely inside it; they can hear nothing but the noise produced by the spell. Spellcasters entirely in the sphere must succeed on a Concentration check against your spell save DC each time they cast a spell or be too distracted to successfully cast it.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Illusion (Figment)</set>
            <set name="time">10 minutes</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 10 minutes</set>
            <set name="range">120 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent"></set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Cruel Disappointment" type="Spell" source="The Phantasmagoria" id="ID_PHANTASMAGORIA_SPELL_CRUEL_DISAPPOINTMENT">
        <supports>Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Choose one creature you can see within range to make an Intelligence saving throw; on a failure, the next time the target uses an action that requires a die roll to determine success while this spell lasts, the action fails. However, the spell creates a phantasm in the subject’s mind that the action succeeded; it behaves accordingly for 1 round, rationalizing any illogical outcomes from interacting with the phantasm.</p>
            <p class="indent">After that round is over, the phantasm fades, the target realizes it was fooled, and the spell ends.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Illusion (Phantasm)</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent"></set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Delusions of Grandeur" type="Spell" source="The Phantasmagoria" id="ID_PHANTASMAGORIA_SPELL_DELUSIONS_OF_GRANDEUR">
        <supports>Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You plant a phantasm in the mind of a target, inflating its self-image. Choose one creature you can see within range to make a Charisma saving throw; on a failure, the subject believes that it is more competent than it really is, and it  considers any action it takes for the duration easily accomplished. Deadly wounds seem like mere scratches, stalwart foes appear weak and intimidated, and the subject’s own attacks seem stronger and more effective. </p>
            <p class="indent">As a result of its skewed perceptions, the target takes a -2 penalty on attack rolls, ability checks, and saving throws. During combat, the target is so completely enamored with its own (false) abilities that it will only take offensive actions, and scoff at the idea of retreat.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Illusion (Phantasm)</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Conentration, up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent"></set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="False Lie" type="Spell" source="The Phantasmagoria" id="ID_PHANTASMAGORIA_SPELL_FALSE_LIE">
        <supports>Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You cause a target to take on a shifty, dishonest demeanor. Choose one creature you can see within range to make a Charisma saving throw; on a failure, Wisdom (Insight) checks made against the subject take a -10 penalty for the duration, and any failure convinces the observer that the subject is lying, even if they are not.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Illusion (Glamer)</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="range">15 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a serpent’s tongue</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Hood of the Cobra" type="Spell" source="The Phantasmagoria" id="ID_PHANTASMAGORIA_SPELL_HOOD_OF_THE_COBRA">
        <supports>Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Choose one creature you can see within range to make an Intelligence saving throw; on a failure, the target (and only the target) will percieve that you have grown horrifying serpentine features, including a cobra’s hood, slitted eyes, shining scales, and venomous fangs, and will become Frightened of you for as long as it can see you for the duration.</p>
            <p class="indent">In addition, if you make a successful melee attack against the target while the spell lasts, it believes that it has been bitten by a venomous serpent and must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or take an extra 1d6 Poison damage on top of the attack damage. Vulnerability, resistance, and immunity to Poison damage applies normally against this effect; even though it isn’t real poison, the subject and its body both believe it to be real.</p>
            <p class="indent">A successful Intelligence save allows the target to recognize the illusion as unreal, which ends the spell’s effect.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Illusion (Phantasm)</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="range">30 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a bit of snake skin</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Eclipse" type="Spell" source="The Phantasmagoria" id="ID_PHANTASMAGORIA_SPELL_ECLIPSE">
        <supports>Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>A creeping pall of darkness flows like swirling black smoke over a creature you touch, obscuring its shape, motions, and appearance. For the duration, the target and its equipment are heavily obscured, though the target’s vision is unaffected. The shadow is mental as well as physical; darkvision cannot pierce it.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Illusion (Pattern)</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a vial of squid ink worth at least 10 gp</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="False Sending" type="Spell" source="The Phantasmagoria" id="ID_PHANTASMAGORIA_SPELL_FALSE_SENDING">
        <supports>Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You send a short message of twenty-five words or less to a creature with which you are familiar. That creature must succeed on an Intelligence saving throw or be convinced that the sender of the message is someone other than you (you choose the false sender upon casting the spell, but it must also be familiar to you). The creature hears the message in its mind, believes it came from the false sender, and can answer in a like manner immediately. The spell enables creatures with Intelligence scores of at least 1 to understand the meaning of your message. You can send the message across any distance and even to other planes of existence, but if the target is on a different plane than you, there is a 5% chance that the message doesn’t arrive.</p>
            <p class="indent">If the target succeeds on its saving throw, it hears the message and can respond, but will be suspicious of the source.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Illusion (Glamer)</set>
            <set name="time">10 minutes</set>
            <set name="duration">1 round</set>
            <set name="range">Unlimited</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a corroded piece of copper wire</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="False Vision" type="Spell" source="The Phantasmagoria" id="ID_PHANTASMAGORIA_SPELL_FALSE_VISION">
        <supports>Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You touch an object, and in a 20-foot radius around the object, any divination spell used to view anything within the area of this spell instead receives a false image (using the parameters of the Major Image spell), as defined by you at the time of casting.</p>
            <p class="indent">For the duration, you can use an action to change the image as desired.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Illusion (Glamer)</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">1 hour</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">powdered jade worth at least 250 gp, which is consumed</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Illusory Feast" type="Spell" source="The Phantasmagoria" id="ID_PHANTASMAGORIA_SPELL_ILLUSORY_FEAST">
        <supports>Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>In a space you can see within range that is 10 feet wide and 40 feet long, a illusory table full of tantalizing food and drink appears. A creature that can sense the feast must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or become Charmed by the illusion. A creature Charmed by this spell stops its current activities, drops held or carried items, and begins consuming the illusory food and drink. The food looks, feels, smells, tastes, and even sounds real to the affected creature, and it appears to be whatever kind of food the creature prefers. An attack on an affected creature frees it from the spell immediately. Sightless creatures are still affected by this spell due to its effect on all the senses. Creatures that do not eat are unaffected by this spell.</p>
            <p class="indent">Only creatures that are Charmed by this illusion can physically interact with it; all other creatures will simply pass through it when they try to interact with it, and they understand it to be an illusion.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Illusion (Pattern)</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">1 minute</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a piece of trail rations</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Invisible Fire" type="Spell" source="The Phantasmagoria" id="ID_PHANTASMAGORIA_SPELL_INVISIBLE_FIRE">
        <supports>Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The ground in a 20-foot radius centered on a point within range is engulfed in invisible flames. Invisible flames are silent and emit no light, heat, or smoke, but may still cause damage to those who come into contact with them.  A creature within 10 feet of the flaming area must succeed on a Perception check against your spell save DC to be able to detect the presence of the flames. On a successful check, a creature registers a vague distortion in the air like a heat haze. On a failure, it fails to notice the flames at all. Since you cast the spell, you do not need to make this check, but be careful: neither you nor your allies are immune to its damage.</p>
            <p class="indent">When a creature moves into or within the area, it takes 2d4 Psychic damage for every 5 feet it travels. The damage a creature takes from an invisible flame feels like a real burn. Creatures that are normally immune or resistant to Fire damage may find this spell especially troublesome. </p>
            <p class="indent">Invisible fire has no effect on inanimate objects or plants, but all creatures that come within its area are subject to its damage. It spreads around corners, up walls, and will even burn over the surface of water. As an action, you can dispel the invisible flames in line 5-feet wide and 20-feet long. At the beginning of the next round after doing so, the flames reignite in that area. </p>
            <p class="indent">If you cast Dispel MagicDispel Magic on the flames, it ends the spell and extinguishes them, but a caster who is not you must succeed on a spellcasting ability check against your spell save DC or only extinguish 75% of the invisible flames.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Illusion (Shadow)</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">1 minute</set>
            <set name="range">30 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">diamond dust worth at least 100 gp, which is consumed</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Rainbow Pattern" type="Spell" source="The Phantasmagoria" id="ID_PHANTASMAGORIA_SPELL_RAINBOW_PATTERN">
        <supports>Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>A glowing, rainbow-hued pattern of interweaving colors appears in a 20-foot cube in a space you can see within range. Each creature in the area who sees the pattern must make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, the creature becomes Charmed for the duration. As a bonus action, you can make the rainbow pattern move up to 60 feet per round (moving its effective point of origin). </p>
            <p class="indent">While Charmed by this spell, creatures behave in the following ways:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>They will follow the rainbow of light when it moves, moving up to their maximum speeds, and will try to get or remain within the effect. They take no actions, bonus actions, or reactions except those that will better enable them to follow the pattern or get within its area of effect (such as the Dash action).</li>
                <li>Charmed creatures who are restrained or removed from the pattern still try to follow it. </li>
                <li>If the pattern leads its subjects into an obviously dangerous area, each charmed creature gets a second saving throw, which is made with advantage. An attack on a Charmed creature automatically ends the effect for that creature.</li>
                <li>If the view of the lights is completely blocked, Charmed creatures who can’t see them are no longer affected.</li>
            </ul>
            <p>The spell does not affect sightless creatures.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">4</set>
            <set name="school">Illusion (Pattern)</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="range">120 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a crystal prism worth at least 100 gp</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Overturning" type="Spell" source="The Phantasmagoria" id="ID_PHANTASMAGORIA_SPELL_OVERTURNING">
        <supports>Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You create an illusory pattern that fits in a 10-foot-radius, 100-foot high cylinder centered on a point within range (if cast indoors, the cylinder ends at the cieling of the area in question). From outside the pattern, space appears warped within it, roiling and contorting on itself. Each creature within the area when this spell is cast or that enters it on a turn must succeed on an Intelligence saving throw or believe that the world itself has turned upside down.</p>
            <p class="indent">On a successful save, creatures merely fall Prone due to the vertigo-inducing effect, but are otherwise unharmed.</p>
            <p class="indent">On a failure, they lose all physical connection with their bodies and believe that they are falling down endlessly into the open air, becoming Stunned. If cast indoors, the cieling seems infinitely far away as they tumble ever towards it. They are unable to take any action except clawing desperately at the air around in the hopes of stopping their apparent fall.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">4</set>
            <set name="school">Illusion (Pattern)</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="range">120 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a gyroscope</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Fantastic Machine" type="Spell" source="The Phantasmagoria" id="ID_PHANTASMAGORIA_SPELL_FANTASTIC_MACHINE">
        <supports>Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>By weaving together threads of shadow magic, you create an illusory, many-armed, noisy mechanical construct of impressively massive appearance that fits in a 10-foot cube.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can command the machine to perform any simple, physical task that you can describe in 25 words or less. You can order the machine to perform the same task over and over, but you can’t change the task. You must specify the task when you cast the spell.</p>
            <p class="indent">The machine always acts on your turn in the initiative order, and can act during the turn you cast the spell.</p>
            <p class="indent">The machine functions as a Large construct and has the following properties:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>It has a movement speed of 40 feet.</li>
                <li>It can swim or fly at a speed of 10 feet, but can fly or swim only when lightly loaded.</li>
                <li>It has 22 hit points, an Armor Class of 14.</li>
                <li>Its saving throw modifiers are Constitution +1, Dexterity +1, and Wisdom -4.</li>
                <li>A light load for the machine is up to 230 pounds, a heavy load is 231-460 pounds, and a heavy load is 461-700 pounds.</li>
                <li>The machine can lift a weight of up to 1,400 pounds to a height of 15 feet.</li>
                <li>It can push or drag 3,500 pounds.</li>
                <li>It can excavate 7,000 pounds of loose rock each minute (which is sufficient to clear a 5-foot cube of space in 3 rounds). It can excavate sand or loose soil at twice that rate.</li>
                <li>The machine has a +5 attack bonus and can make one slam attack each round that deals 1d8+4 points of Bludgeoning damage on a hit. This damage is tripled when weilded against stone or metal.</li>
                <li>The machine can hurl Small rocks (if any are at hand) with an attack bonus of +3 up to 150 feet. A thrown rock deals 2d6+4 points of Bludgeoning damage.</li>
            </ul>
            <p class="indent">When this spell ends, the machine ceases its activities immediately and disappears.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">6</set>
            <set name="school">Illusion (Shadow)</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="range">100 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">Tinker’s tools</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <!-- Magic Items -->
    <element name="Self-Inking Quill" type="Magic Item" source="The Phantasmagoria" id="ID_PHANTASMAGORIA_MAGIC_ITEM_SELFINKING_QUILL">
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">A large plumed quill that was plucked from an unknown creature.</p>
            <p class="indent">This flashy looking quill is capable of writing without an inkpot, as it produces its own lead-based ink in any color you desire. However, the ink it produces is not of the quality necessary to copy spells into a spell book or to write a spell scroll; those materials must still be acquired separately.</p>
            <p class="indent">The quill also contains 4 charges. You can spend 1 charge as an action to cast Illusory Script without using a spell slot or material components.</p>
            <p class="indent">As part of spending a charge or as an action on your turn, you can verbally dictate to the quill while you are within 10 feet of it, and it will write whatever you command in a language you specify at a rate of 25 words per each of your turns until you command it to stop (you must know the language).</p>
            <p class="indent">If all the charges are used, roll a d20. On a 1, the quill sprays you with ink and becomes a non-magical quill. Otherwise, the item regains all charges each dawn.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Mnemosphere" type="Magic Item" source="The Phantasmagoria" id="ID_PHANTASMAGORIA_MAGIC_ITEM_MNEMOSPHERE">
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">A black orb that fits in your hand. Holding it gives the feeling that you’re being watched.</p>
            <p class="indent">By speaking a command word as an action, this orb will begin recording events that occur within 30 feet of it for a span of up to 1 hour. You do not need to be in contact with the sphere to activate it, but you must be within 30 feet of it. You can also end the recording by using an action to speak a command word.</p>
            <p class="indent">When it is finished recording, you can use an action to speak another command word, triggering the orb to project an illusion of what it “saw” during the recording in a 30-foot circle centered on the orb. This projected illusion only incorporates the visual and auditory information of the events the orb records. Creatures that are shielded from the effects of divination spells will not appear in the projection.</p>
            <p class="indent">As a bonus action, you can speak yet another command word to prompt the illusion to speed up, slow down, or pause the projected events. The sphere can only record one memory at a time; using the sphere again will erase the previous memory stored within it.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a spellcaster">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Illusory Companion" type="Magic Item" source="The Phantasmagoria" id="ID_PHANTASMAGORIA_MAGIC_ITEM_ILLUSORY_COMPANION">
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">A ring set with a stone of unknown origin in which the moving image of a small animal can be seen. Every so often, it will produce a tiny sound appropriate to the animal’s type.</p>
            <p class="indent">Upon attunement with this item, you give it a name of your choice. As an action while wearing the ring, you can speak the name to summon the illusion of the creature depicted on it, which is one of the following: a Bat, Cat, Crab, Frog (Toad), Hawk, Lizard, Octopus, Owl, Poisonous Snake, Fish (Quipper), Rat, Raven, Sea Horse, Spider, or Weasel.</p>
            <p class="indent">The image appears in an unoccupied space you can see within 10 feet of you, and it lasts until it fades. It seems completely real, including sounds, smells, and temperature appropriate to the creature it depicts, but it cannot physically interact with objects or creatures beyond resting on a surface. It moves using the creature’s movement speeds, but has no restrictions regarding environment (as it’s not real). For example, a swimming creature can fly through the air like water.</p>
            <p class="indent">Your illusory companion acts independently of you, but it always obeys your commands. In combat, it acts on your Initiative. An illusory companion can’t Attack, but it can take the Help, Search, or Hide action using the characteristics of the creature it depicts.</p>
            <p class="indent">If you don’t give it a command, it will act naturally and follow you when you move. The illusion cannot move further than 100 feet from you; if it does, it fades away and must be resummoned.</p>
            <p class="indent">The companion is immune to all conditions, and if it is hit by an attack, it immediately fades away and must be resummoned.</p>
            <p class="indent">Similarly, physical interaction with the image reveals it to be an illusion, because things can pass through it. A creature that uses its action to examine the image can determine that it is an illusion with a successful Intelligence (Investigation) check against your spell save DC. If a creature discerns the Illusion for what it is, the illusory companion fades away and must be resummoned.</p>
            <p class="indent">Over a short or long rest, you can speak the name of your companion again to resummon it.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Rings</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="slot">ring</set>
            <set name="type">Ring</set>
            <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Wizard’s Beard" type="Magic Item" source="The Phantasmagoria" id="ID_PHANTASMAGORIA_MAGIC_ITEM_Wizard’s Beard">
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">A small tin of waxy substance to be applied to the face. It seems to be enough for one use only. The lid depicts the image of a flowing, luxurious beard.</p>
            <p class="indent">You apply the wax to your face along your jawline and around your lips. After one hour, a floor-length beard will sprout from the applied area. As an action, you can stroke the beard to alter its style and color to something that suits you, but it will never be less than 5 feet in length.</p>
            <p class="indent">With a maximum reach of five feet, the beard is prehensile, and can perform any almost task that you could with one hand. In effect, it becomes a third hand; it is capable of using tools with your proficiency, and it can deliver Touch-range spells like your hands could. However, the beard isn’t quite capable of weilding a shield, weapons to attack, or arcane foci.</p>
            <p class="indent">The beard does not allow you any more actions than your class or feats allow; you can simply opt to use your beard instead of your hands to perform a task. If you would otherwise take damage from physical contact with an object or creature, using your beard will not spare you any damage since it’s now a part of your body.</p>
            <p class="indent">Variant: Feylocks. Feylocks are the same in principle as a Wizard’s Beard, but must be applied to the scalp, and will instead produce long, flowing locks of hair that possess the same properties and reach as described above.</p>
            <p class="indent">Curse: If the hair/beard is cut or shaved, it will instantly regrow and attack the one who cut it (including you). Using your stats to roll an unarmed strike (with advantage if you are the target), it deals 1d4 Bludgeoning damage on a hit. Hit or miss, it will only attack once. Only casting Remove Curse can permanently remove the beard and your attunement to it.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
            <set name="attunement" addition="by a Druid, Sorcerer or Wizard">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

</elements>