<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>D&amp;D Beyond Homebrew Spells</name>
        <update version="0.0.6">
            <file name="spells.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/spells/spells.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Aurial’s Glacial Blast" type="Spell" source="D&amp;D Beyond Homebrew" id="ID_DDB_HB_SPELL_AURIALS_GLACIAL_BLAST">
        <supports>Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>A blast of ice forming a line 100 feet long and 5 feet wide blasts out from you in a direction you choose. Each creature in the line must make a Dexterity saving throw. A creature takes 8d6 cold damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</p>
            <p class="indent">The icy blast freezes any liquids in the area that aren’t being worn or carried.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b>At Higher Levels. </b>When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 3rd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">cold, damage</set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 Action</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="range">Self/100 ft.</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a white dragon’s scale</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Deep Freeze" type="Spell" source="D&amp;D Beyond Homebrew" id="ID_DDB_HB_SPELL_DEEP_FREEZE">
        <supports>Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You focus on a target or point within range and cause an eruption of jagged ice crystals to form in all directions instantaneously. Each creature in a 20-foot-radius sphere centered on that point must make a Dexterity saving throw. A target takes 8d6 cold damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</p>
            <p class="indent">Any non-magical fires are snuffed out in the area of effect which becomes difficult terrain till the end of the next turn at which point the magical ice evaporates.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b>At Higher Levels. </b>When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 3rd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">cold, damage</set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 Action</set>
            <set name="duration">duration</set>
            <set name="range">150 ft (20 ft sphere)</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">A diamond worth at least 25 gp</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
  <!-- Other homebrew spells -->
    <element name="Rain of Spiders" type="Spell" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_KB_RDDT_UA_SPELL_RAIN_OF_SPIDERS">
        <supports>Druid, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard, Witch</supports>
        <description>
            <p>A vertical column of spiders begins to rain down in a location you specify. Each creature that starts its turn within the 20-foot radius, 40-foot high cylinder must make a Dexterity saving throw. A Swarm of Spiders (<i>Monster Manual</i>, pg 334) descends onto each creature within the cylinder. On a failed saving throw, this swarm has full hit points (22). On a successful save, this swarm has half hit points (11).</p>
            <p class="indent">This swarm is considered to be climbing on the target creature and moves with them, even if they leave the affected area, and takes its turn immediately after that creature’s turn. A creature can make use of its action to attempt to get them off, making a Strength (Athletics) or Dexterity (Acrobatics) check against the spell save DC of the caster.</p>
            <p class="indent">If a creature is already swarmed by spiders starts their turn in the area of effect, they repeat the saving throw. The swarm on that creature gains 22 current and maximum hit points on a failed save, and 11 current and maximum hitpoints on a success save. The swarm’s hit points cannot go above 22 for a medium creature, 44 for a large or larger creature.</p>
            <p class="indent">Any spiders that remain when the spell ends disappear after 1d4 rounds.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Conjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a spider leg</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Colossification" type="Spell" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GANNOH2_GMBINDER_SPELL_COLOSSIFICATION">
        <supports>Druid, Wizard, Warlock</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Touching a willing beast or familiar and gently whispering words of power, you make it grow to incredible proportions. It gains the following benefits while the spell lasts.</p>
            <ul>
                <li>The touched creature become Gargantuan. If there isn't enough room for it to increase size, it makes a Strength (Athletics) check to break through the surrounding material. It otherwise attains the maximum possible size in the space available.</li>
                <li>Its current and maximum hit points increase to 200.</li>
                <li>Its Strength and Constitution scores increase to 26.</li>
                <li>It can take the Attack action.</li>
                <li>Its reach becomes 15 feet.</li>
                <li>If it already has an attack, that attack now deals 34 (4d12 + 8) damage.</li>
                <li>Whether or not it originally had an attack, it can perform a bite attack that deals 34 (4d12 + 8) piercing damage. If the target is a creature, it is grappled (escape DC 20). Until this grapple ends, the target is restrained, and the familiar can't bite another target.</li>
                <li>As an action, the familiar can make one bite attack against a Large or smaller creature it is grappling. If the attack hits, the target takes the bite's damage, the target is swallowed, and the grapple ends. While swallowed, the creature is blinded and restrained, it has total cover against attacks and other effects outside the familiar, and it takes 28 (8d6) acid damage at the start of each of the familiar's turns. If the familiar takes 30 damage or more on a single turn from a creature inside it, the familiar must succeed on a DC 20 Constitution saving throw at the end of that turn or regurgitate all swallowed creatures, which fall prone in a space within 10 feet of the familiar.</li>
                <li>It has advantage on Strength checks and Strength saving throws.</li>
                <li>It adds your proficiency bonus to its attack rolls, Strength checks, AC, and saving throws.</li>
                <li>Its attacks deal double damage against objects and structures and count as magical for the purpose of overcoming resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage.</li>
                <li>It becomes immune to being charmed and frightened.</li>
                <li>Once during the spell, it can choose to succeed on a saving throw.</li>
                <li>It does not disappear when reduced to 0 hit points. Instead, it makes death saving throws like you do. It disappears if it has three failed death saving throws.</li>
                <li>It ignores difficult terrain as it simply powers through it.</li>
            </ul>
            <p>While transformed, your familiar cannot be dismissed and then resummoned. If any creatures are inside it when the spell ends, they fall prone within in a space which the familiar previously occupied. You can end the spell early as an action.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">9</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="duration">8 hours</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a willing beast or familiar</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
</elements>