<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Chronomancy Spells</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="spells-more-chronomancy.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/spells/spells-more-chronomancy.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="More Chronomancy Spells" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_ANDOMAN_HOMEBREWERY_SOURCE_MORE_CHRONOMANCY_SPELLS">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation">MCS</set>
            <set name="url">https://homebrewery.naturalcrit.com/share/NkSX48-Rl</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" url="https://www.reddit.com/user/Andoman36/">u/Andoman36</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20181201</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Backwards Gaze" type="Spell" source="More Chronomancy Spells" id="ID_ANDOMAN_MCS_SPELL_BACKWARDS_GAZE">
        <supports>Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Your eyes glaze over as visions of the past fill your perception. When casting, choose a point in time from within the past 100 years. For the duration of the spell, you view events at that time as if you were physically present, although you are rooted in place and cannot actually interact with objects, creatures, or the environment. You still have any special senses you have in the present, such as Darkvision, when viewing the past. You may dismiss this spell with a bonus action at any time. When viewing the past, you are deaf and blind with regards to your own senses in the present.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Divination (chronomancy)</set>
            <set name="isRitual">true</set>
            <set name="time">1 minute</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a cracked pair of eyeglasses</set>
            <set name="duration">Up to 1 hour</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Dampening Field" type="Spell" source="More Chronomancy Spells" id="ID_ANDOMAN_MCS_SPELL_DAMPENING_FIELD">
        <supports>Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>This spell slows the movement of any creature within a 15-foot radius cylinder you choose within range. Creatures entering the area must make a Wisdom save or have their speed reduced by 10 feet while in the area. This spell has no effect on falling objects or forced movement. This spell cannot decrease a creature’s speed below 5.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell at 3rd level or higher, speed reduction increases by 5 feet for each slot level above 2nd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation (chronomancy)</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 10 minutes</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Delay Pain" type="Spell" source="More Chronomancy Spells" id="ID_ANDOMAN_MCS_SPELL_DELAY_PAIN">
        <supports>Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>With a flash of blue, an enemy’s attack appears to pass right through you—that is, until a few minutes later when the cuts spontaneously appear on your chest! As a reaction upon being hit by an attack, but before damage is taken, you may choose instead to take no damage. The DM records the amount and type of damage you would have taken. You take this damage immediately when the spell ends or if you lose concentration.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">4</set>
            <set name="school">Abjuration (chronomancy)</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 reaction</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">an empty locket</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 10 minutes</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Fasttrack" type="Spell" source="More Chronomancy Spells" id="ID_ANDOMAN_MCS_SPELL_FASTTRACK">
        <supports>Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>A stream of quickened time unfurls from your hand in a straight line in front of you, speeding travel along its length. A 60 foot line of accelerated space appears in a line in front of you, originating from your position. You may choose whether the line accelerates towards you or away from you. Creatures moving through this area in the declared direction may move 2 feet for every one foot of spent movement. You may reposition the track and/or change its flow direction as a bonus action on your turn; one end must still originate from your current location.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">4</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation (chronomancy)</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a length of blue ribbon</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Indefinite Preservation" type="Spell" source="More Chronomancy Spells" id="ID_ANDOMAN_MCS_SPELL_INDEFINITE_PRESERVATION">
        <supports>Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You reach out in an attempt to suspend a Medium or smaller creature in time. Target creature must make a Charisma saving throw. On a failure, the creature is stunned as it begins to dissociate from the timeline. After this, the creature must make another Charisma saving throw the the beginning of its turn. On a success, the spell ends. On a failure, the creature is suspended in time, appearing as only a faint frozen image. To determine how many days the creature stays suspended, the DM secretly rolls 1d10 and records this number. During this time, the creature is considered to have the Petrified condition, except it cannot affect or be affected by other creatures in any way. A creature may choose to willingly fail any of these saving throws.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">8</set>
            <set name="school">Abjuration (chronomancy)</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a chunk of amber with an insect preserved inside</set>
            <set name="duration">1d10 days</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Paradoxical Summons" type="Spell" source="More Chronomancy Spells" id="ID_ANDOMAN_MCS_SPELL_PARADOXICAL_SUMMONS">
        <supports>Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>In a moment of need, you reach out and find the exact item you need dropped into your hand, sent by your future self. Choose any small or smaller nonmagical object of value 100gp or less. That item instantly appears in your hand or within 5 feet of you. Afterwards, you must then send the item back to yourself in an hour long ritual during a short or long rest (this does not require consumption of a spell slot). You may send back the very same item you received if it is still in the same condition you received it; otherwise, you will need to acquire a suitable replacement to send back. You cannot cast Paradoxical Summons again until you have returned any previous outstanding Paradoxical Summons.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">5</set>
            <set name="school">Conjuration (chronomancy)</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">the item being sent back in time</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Quicken Thought" type="Spell" source="More Chronomancy Spells" id="ID_ANDOMAN_MCS_SPELL_QUICKEN_THOUGHT">
        <supports>Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Your eyes jitter back in forth in your head as you overclock your perception of the world, giving yourself minutes of subjective time to react to threats. For the duration, you have advantage on Intelligence and Dexterity checks and saves and you cannot be surprised. In addition, attacks against you from sources you can see have disadvantage. However, your quickened perceptions make it difficult to engage with people moving at normal speed. You have disadvantage on Charisma checks for the duration, and you must use an action to communicate non-telepathically with anyone around you. Immediately after the spell ends, you must succeed on a DC 15 Constitution saving throw or suffer one level of exhaustion.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">6</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation (chronomancy)</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a page torn from an otherwise whole book</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 10 minutes</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Rending Distortion" type="Spell" source="More Chronomancy Spells" id="ID_ANDOMAN_MCS_SPELL_RENDING_DISTORTION">
        <supports>Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>With a murmur and a series of complex gestures, you cause the time around a creature to rapidly accelerate and decelerate in random patches, tearing their body as they attempt to move through the time flux. Target creature must make a Constitution save, taking 6d10 slashing damage on a failure and half as much on a success.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">4</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation (chronomancy)</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">120 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Time Trot" type="Spell" source="More Chronomancy Spells" id="ID_ANDOMAN_MCS_SPELL_TIME_TROT">
        <supports>Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Time pauses as you focus on carefully extricating yourself from a sticky situation. Whenever you take the Dash action on your turn for the duration of the spell, you are not impeded by difficult terrain, are considered to be under the influence of a Water Walk spell, and do not provoke opportunity attacks when you move out of an enemy’s reach.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Abjuration (chronomancy)</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Timewalk" type="Spell" source="More Chronomancy Spells" id="ID_ANDOMAN_MCS_SPELL_TIMEWALK">
        <supports>Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You fall into a deep trance as your mind explores back hundreds of years. When casting, choose a point in time within the past 1000 years. For the duration of the spell, you view events at that time as if you were physically present, although you cannot actually interact with objects, creatures, or the environment. You can move up to 300 feet from the point of casting, but trying to move further reveals only reality fading to an inky blackness. You still have any special senses you have in the present, such as Darkvision, when viewing the past. You may dismiss this spell with a bonus action at any time. When viewing the past, you are deaf and blind with regards to your own senses in the present.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">5</set>
            <set name="school">Divination (chronomancy)</set>
            <set name="isRitual">true</set>
            <set name="time">1 minute</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a large emerald worth at least 100gp, etched with the image of a timepiece</set>
            <set name="duration">Up to 1 hour</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Waypoint" type="Spell" source="More Chronomancy Spells" id="ID_ANDOMAN_MCS_SPELL_WAYPOINT">
        <supports>Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You pound an ornate stake into the ground, magically anchoring your presence and the presence of up to 8 others to a specific fork in the current timeline. For the next 24 hours, you may return in time to this waypoint, undoing everything that had happened in the intervening time and leaving you and others affected by the spell with only memories to show for the undone time. You may dictate during casting the conditions for your return (common choices include death, failure of an objective, or a spoken passphrase). Returning to the waypoint consumes the stake. After casting a waypoint, that portion of the timeline is temporally locked; no other waypoints from any source may be placed within 24 hours in either direction of that time.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">9</set>
            <set name="school">Abjuration (chronomancy)</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 hour</set>
            <set name="range">30 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">an ornately carved, mastercraft stake costing at least 5000 gp</set>
            <set name="duration">24 hours</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
</elements>