<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>D&amp;D Beyond Homebrew Spells</name>
        <update version="0.0.5">
            <file name="spells.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/spells/spells.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Aurial’s Glacial Blast" type="Spell" source="D&amp;D Beyond Homebrew" id="ID_DDB_HB_SPELL_AURIALS_GLACIAL_BLAST">
        <supports>Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>A blast of ice forming a line 100 feet long and 5 feet wide blasts out from you in a direction you choose. Each creature in the line must make a Dexterity saving throw. A creature takes 8d6 cold damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</p>
            <p class="indent">The icy blast freezes any liquids in the area that aren’t being worn or carried.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b>At Higher Levels. </b>When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 3rd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">cold, damage</set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 Action</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="range">Self/100 ft.</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a white dragon’s scale</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Deep Freeze" type="Spell" source="D&amp;D Beyond Homebrew" id="ID_DDB_HB_SPELL_DEEP_FREEZE">
        <supports>Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You focus on a target or point within range and cause an eruption of jagged ice crystals to form in all directions instantaneously. Each creature in a 20-foot-radius sphere centered on that point must make a Dexterity saving throw. A target takes 8d6 cold damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</p>
            <p class="indent">Any non-magical fires are snuffed out in the area of effect which becomes difficult terrain till the end of the next turn at which point the magical ice evaporates.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b>At Higher Levels. </b>When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 3rd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">cold, damage</set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 Action</set>
            <set name="duration">duration</set>
            <set name="range">150 ft (20 ft sphere)</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">A diamond worth at least 25 gp</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
  <!-- Other homebrew spells -->
    <element name="Rain of Spiders" type="Spell" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_KB_RDDT_UA_SPELL_RAIN_OF_SPIDERS">
        <supports>Druid, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard, Witch</supports>
        <description>
            <p>A vertical column of spiders begins to rain down in a location you specify. Each creature that starts its turn within the 20-foot radius, 40-foot high cylinder must make a Dexterity saving throw. A Swarm of Spiders (<i>Monster Manual</i>, pg 334) descends onto each creature within the cylinder. On a failed saving throw, this swarm has full hit points (22). On a successful save, this swarm has half hit points (11).</p>
            <p class="indent">This swarm is considered to be climbing on the target creature and moves with them, even if they leave the affected area, and takes its turn immediately after that creature’s turn. A creature can make use of its action to attempt to get them off, making a Strength (Athletics) or Dexterity (Acrobatics) check against the spell save DC of the caster.</p>
            <p class="indent">If a creature is already swarmed by spiders starts their turn in the area of effect, they repeat the saving throw. The swarm on that creature gains 22 current and maximum hit points on a failed save, and 11 current and maximum hitpoints on a success save. The swarm’s hit points cannot go above 22 for a medium creature, 44 for a large or larger creature.</p>
            <p class="indent">Any spiders that remain when the spell ends disappear after 1d4 rounds.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Conjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a spider leg</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>


</elements>