<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>D&amp;D Beyond and Other Homebrew Spells</name>
        <update version="0.0.11">
            <file name="spells.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/spells/spells.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Aurial’s Glacial Blast" type="Spell" source="D&amp;D Beyond Homebrew" id="ID_DDB_HB_SPELL_AURIALS_GLACIAL_BLAST">
        <supports>Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>A blast of ice forming a line 100 feet long and 5 feet wide blasts out from you in a direction you choose. Each creature in the line must make a Dexterity saving throw. A creature takes 8d6 cold damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</p>
            <p class="indent">The icy blast freezes any liquids in the area that aren’t being worn or carried.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b>At Higher Levels. </b>When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 3rd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">cold, damage</set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 Action</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="range">Self/100 ft.</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a white dragon’s scale</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Deep Freeze" type="Spell" source="D&amp;D Beyond Homebrew" id="ID_DDB_HB_SPELL_DEEP_FREEZE">
        <supports>Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You focus on a target or point within range and cause an eruption of jagged ice crystals to form in all directions instantaneously. Each creature in a 20-foot-radius sphere centered on that point must make a Dexterity saving throw. A target takes 8d6 cold damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</p>
            <p class="indent">Any non-magical fires are snuffed out in the area of effect which becomes difficult terrain till the end of the next turn at which point the magical ice evaporates.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b>At Higher Levels. </b>When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 3rd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">cold, damage</set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 Action</set>
            <set name="duration">duration</set>
            <set name="range">150 ft (20 ft sphere)</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">A diamond worth at least 25 gp</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
  <!-- Other homebrew spells -->
    <element name="Rain of Spiders" type="Spell" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_KB_RDDT_UA_SPELL_RAIN_OF_SPIDERS">
        <supports>Druid, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard, Witch</supports>
        <description>
            <p>A vertical column of spiders begins to rain down in a location you specify. Each creature that starts its turn within the 20-foot radius, 40-foot high cylinder must make a Dexterity saving throw. A Swarm of Spiders (<i>Monster Manual</i>, pg 334) descends onto each creature within the cylinder. On a failed saving throw, this swarm has full hit points (22). On a successful save, this swarm has half hit points (11).</p>
            <p class="indent">This swarm is considered to be climbing on the target creature and moves with them, even if they leave the affected area, and takes its turn immediately after that creature’s turn. A creature can make use of its action to attempt to get them off, making a Strength (Athletics) or Dexterity (Acrobatics) check against the spell save DC of the caster.</p>
            <p class="indent">If a creature is already swarmed by spiders starts their turn in the area of effect, they repeat the saving throw. The swarm on that creature gains 22 current and maximum hit points on a failed save, and 11 current and maximum hitpoints on a success save. The swarm’s hit points cannot go above 22 for a medium creature, 44 for a large or larger creature.</p>
            <p class="indent">Any spiders that remain when the spell ends disappear after 1d4 rounds.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Conjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a spider leg</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Colossification" type="Spell" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GANNOH2_GMBINDER_SPELL_COLOSSIFICATION">
        <supports>Druid, Wizard, Warlock</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Touching a willing beast or familiar and gently whispering words of power, you make it grow to incredible proportions. It gains the following benefits while the spell lasts.</p>
            <ul>
                <li>The touched creature become Gargantuan. If there isn’t enough room for it to increase size, it makes a Strength (Athletics) check to break through the surrounding material. It otherwise attains the maximum possible size in the space available.</li>
                <li>Its current and maximum hit points increase to 200.</li>
                <li>Its Strength and Constitution scores increase to 26.</li>
                <li>It can take the Attack action.</li>
                <li>Its reach becomes 15 feet.</li>
                <li>If it already has an attack, that attack now deals 34 (4d12 + 8) damage.</li>
                <li>Whether or not it originally had an attack, it can perform a bite attack that deals 34 (4d12 + 8) piercing damage. If the target is a creature, it is grappled (escape DC 20). Until this grapple ends, the target is restrained, and the familiar can’t bite another target.</li>
                <li>As an action, the familiar can make one bite attack against a Large or smaller creature it is grappling. If the attack hits, the target takes the bite’s damage, the target is swallowed, and the grapple ends. While swallowed, the creature is blinded and restrained, it has total cover against attacks and other effects outside the familiar, and it takes 28 (8d6) acid damage at the start of each of the familiar’s turns. If the familiar takes 30 damage or more on a single turn from a creature inside it, the familiar must succeed on a DC 20 Constitution saving throw at the end of that turn or regurgitate all swallowed creatures, which fall prone in a space within 10 feet of the familiar.</li>
                <li>It has advantage on Strength checks and Strength saving throws.</li>
                <li>It adds your proficiency bonus to its attack rolls, Strength checks, AC, and saving throws.</li>
                <li>Its attacks deal double damage against objects and structures and count as magical for the purpose of overcoming resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage.</li>
                <li>It becomes immune to being charmed and frightened.</li>
                <li>Once during the spell, it can choose to succeed on a saving throw.</li>
                <li>It does not disappear when reduced to 0 hit points. Instead, it makes death saving throws like you do. It disappears if it has three failed death saving throws.</li>
                <li>It ignores difficult terrain as it simply powers through it.</li>
            </ul>
            <p>While transformed, your familiar cannot be dismissed and then resummoned. If any creatures are inside it when the spell ends, they fall prone within in a space which the familiar previously occupied. You can end the spell early as an action.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">9</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="duration">8 hours</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a willing beast or familiar</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Reality Marble" type="Spell" source="Gannoh2" id="ID_GANNOH2_GMB_SPELL_REALITY_MARBLE">
        <supports>Bard, Cleric, Druid, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You draw all creatures within 100 feet of you into a plane of your own creation. This is accompanied by a dramatic but harmless phenomenon such a flash of light or what appears to be a surge of fire.</p>
            <p class="indent">The space is infinite in size, has normal air and gravity, and is devoid of life other than plants. It could be a naturalistic landscape such as a grassy field, a desert, or icy tundra. It could also include features such as innumerable swords scattered across the space or a massive temple complex. Regardless, you cannot create the space with enough precision to give yourself a tactical advantage. For example, if you created a desert space, you could not designate certain areas as quicksand.</p>
            <p class="indent">The space has a general theme, so it could not be part snowy mountains and part lush jungle. The space may include streams and ponds, but not large rivers or bodies of water. It can be unpleasantly hot or cold, but not sufficiently so as to cause immediate harm. Any structures or items in the space can be used and interacted with, but disappear once the spell ends. The items are mundane and cannot include valuable material components.</p>
            <p class="indent">In addition to creating the plane, you can rearrange the location of the creatures drawn into it. You can place each creature in any unoccupied space of your choice within 300 feet of you (but not midair).</p>
            <p class="indent">The spell can be ended early if the caster spends an action to do so. The spell also ends if the caster leaves the space via Plane Shift or falls to 0 hit points. Once the spell ends, all creatures in the plane return to the same space they originally were in.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">9</set>
            <set name="school">Conjuration</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">100 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">10 minutes</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Legend" type="Spell" source="Homebrewery" id="ID_HOMEBREWERY_SPELL_LEGEND">
        <!-- https://homebrewery.naturalcrit.com/share/P9opZxK-S -->
        <supports>Wizard, Bard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>By means of this spell, you warp the fabric of reality to create a legendary truth about your subject, imbuing them with the qualities of a mythic hero. Select one creature within range and create a legend surrounding either the resilience, guile, or ferocity of your target. As you cast the spell, the legend is read aloud and consumed, becoming part of the narrative weave which drives and shapes this universe. Depending on the legend, the target gains one of the following effects for the spell’s duration:</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Legendary Physcial Resistance (3/Day).</i></b> If the target fails a Strength, Dexterity, or Constitution saving throw, it can choose to succeed instead.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Legendary Mental Resistance (3/Day).</i></b> If the target fails an Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma saving throw, it can choose to succeed instead.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Legendary Actions.</i></b> The target can take 2 legendary actions, choosing from the options below. Only one legendary action option can be used at a time and only at the end of another creature’s turn. The target regains spent legendary actions at the start of its turn.</p>
            <ul>
                <li><i>Move.</i> The target moves up to its speed without provoking opportunity attacks.</li>
                <li><i>Attack.</i> The target makes a melee or ranged attack.</li>
                <li><i>Cast.</i> The target casts a spell it already knows, using spell slots as usual. The spell cannot take longer than 1 action to cast. If the spell is not a cantrip, the casting costs two legendary actions.</li>
            </ul>
            <p class="indent">Casting this spell on the same target every day for a year makes this effect permanent. The effects of this spell may only be removed by a wish spell. A target may only benefit from one casting of this spell while the spell’s effects are active.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">9</set>
            <set name="school">abjuration</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">10 minutes</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">A scroll or record detailing the legendary accomplishments of the target, which the spell consumes</set>
            <set name="duration">1 day</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Speak with Objects" type="Spell" source="Homebrewery" id="ID_HOMEBREWERY_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_OBJECTS">
        <!-- https://homebrewery.naturalcrit.com/share/YyoLuAot9 -->
        <supports>Artificer, Bard, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You imbue objects within 30 feet of you with limited sentience and animation. You can question objects within 30 feet of you about events in the spell’s area within the past day, gathering information on who has used the object, creature’s passing through, or other nearby happenings.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can also manipulate objects in the area. When you cast this spell, and as your action each round for the duration, you can move one Small or smaller object up to 30 feet in any direction, but not beyond the range of the spell.</p>
            <p class="indent">Objects might also be able to perform tasks on your behalf, at the DM’s discretion. You might convince a lock to open itself, a trap to not spring, or even a catapult to fire prematurely.</p>
            <p class="indent">This spell has no effect on objects that are being worn or carried by creatures (other than yourself). If a magical object is in the area, you can communicate with it, but you gain no magical ability to influence it.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Divination</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self (30ft radius)</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">10 minutes</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="False Identity" type="Spell" source="NotTheSmooze" id="ID_NOTTHESMOOZE_GMBINDER_SPELL_FALSE_IDENTITY">
        <!-- https://www.gmbinder.com/share/-LqCmhciN0Y6aowqP0m4 -->
        <supports>Bard, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You blanket a glamour over the mind of a creature you can see within range, forcing them to make an Intelligence saving throw. On a failed save, the target is stunned for the duration. The stunned target is unaware of its surroundings. If it takes any damage or is targeted by another spell, this spell ends.</p>
            <p class="indent">If you concentrate on this spell for its full duration, you can weave the glamour into a new identity. The creature loses all memory of its former self. You decide which proficiencies and langauges the creature retains, if any, and if it can use any of its class features, if it has them. You can also reduce the target’s Intelligence, Wisdom, and Charisma scores to a minimum of 8. You can’t use this spell to change a creature’s alignment.</p>
            <p class="indent">You decide the new identity’s past and personality, creating memories, beliefs, and desires as you choose. The creature’s mind fills in any gaps in the identity’s details. If the creature’s alignment conflicts with its new identity, it justifies it as best as it can, dismissing it as a sense of unease or discomfort.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can also weave the glamour into a new appearance. You decide what the target’s new identity looks like, though your choice doesn’t affect its statistics. You can’t weave the glamour to change the target’s size or its basic shape. The glamour is deep enough to be tangible: physical interaction with the glamour doesn’t reveal it to be an illusion.</p>
            <p class="indent">A <i>greater restoration</i>, <i>heal</i>, or <i>wish</i> spell cast on the target can restore the creature’s true identity.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">9</set>
            <set name="school">illusion</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">30 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a blank sheet of paper, stone, or metal</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 10 minutes</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Brightlance" type="Spell" source="Brightlance" id="ID_SURREALISTICK_HOMEBREWERY_SPELL_BRIGHTLANCE">
        <supports>Cleric</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You hurl, slash or stab crackling radiant energy at a creature or object within range. This energy takes on the shape of a weapon of your choice. If the target is within 5 feet of you, make a melee spell attack against it, otherwise make a ranged spell attack against it. This attack roll is made with disadvantage if the target is further than 60 feet from you. On a hit, the target takes 1d4 radiant damage and 1d4 lightning damage.</p>
            <p class="indent">The radiant and lightning damage dealt by this spell each increase by 1d4 when you reach 5th level (2d4), 11th level (3d4), and 17th level (4d4).</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">0</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">120 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
</elements>