<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Weaver Spells</name>
        <update version="0.0.2">
            <file name="weaver-spells.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/spells/weaver-spells.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Weaver Spells" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_PSITHURI_HOMEBREWERY_SOURCE_Weaver Spells">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation"></set>
            <set name="url">https://homebrewery.naturalcrit.com/share/B10PtEiag</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" url="https://www.reddit.com/user/Psithuri/">u/Psithuri</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20170411</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Araneation" type="Spell" source="Weaver Spells" id="ID_PSITHURI_WEAVER_SPELLS_SPELL_ARANEATION">
        <supports>Druid, Ranger, Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Invoking your arachnid spirit, you create one of the following effects within range.</p>
            <ul>
                <li>You instantaneously cover an object in harmless cobwebs, or remove small cobwebs from an area of up to one square foot.</li>
                <li>If there is a normal, nonmagical spider within 30 feet, you cause it to crawl onto your hand.</li>
                <li>You create an illusory image of Tiny-sized spider crawling on your body or an object within range for one minute. Its appearance is up to you, though it must clearly be a spider.</li>
                <li>You alter your appearance to seem more spiderlike for the duration, such as turning your eyes black, making your skin glisten like a carapace or sprout hairy fur, or making your teeth appear fanglike for 1 minute.</li>
                <li>You alter a spider web within range to display words or simple pictures formed from silk.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">0</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">30 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">1 minute</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>    
    <element name="Stasis Cocoon" type="Spell" source="Weaver Spells" id="ID_PSITHURI_WEAVER_SPELLS_SPELL_STASIS_COCOON">
        <supports></supports>
        <description>
            <p>You attempt to wrap one creature you can see within range in a magical cocoon. If the target is Large or smaller, the creature must make a Strength saving throw. On a failed save, it is restrained as magical webbing restricts its movement. On a successful save, the creature isn’t affected.</p>
            <p class="indent">A creature restrained by this spell must make another Strength saving throw at the end of each of its turns. If it successfully saves against this spell three times, the spell ends. If it fails saves three times, it is completely wrapped in the cocoon and is considered unconscious and incapacitated until the spell ends. While incapacitated in this way, it has total cover against attacks, doesn’t need to eat, drink, or breathe, and ages at one tenth the normal rate. The successes and failures don’t need to be consecutive, keep track of both until the target collects three of a kind.</p>
            <p class="indent">If you maintain your concentration on this spell for the entire possible duration, the cocoon lasts until the effect is removed.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">6</set>
            <set name="school">Conjuration</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a piece of ice and a string</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>    
    <element name="Toxin Expulsion" type="Spell" source="Weaver Spells" id="ID_PSITHURI_WEAVER_SPELLS_SPELL_TOXIN_EXPULSION">
        <supports>Cleric, Druid, Paladin, Ranger</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You touch a creature and can end one poison or disease afflicting it. Then, immediately choose another creature within 30 feet of you. That creature must make a Constitution saving throw or be affected by the same poison or disease you cured, with the same remaining duration as on the original creature affected by the condition. If the saving throw is successful, you must make a DC 10 Constitution saving throw or be affected by the condition yourself.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Abjuration</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a small straw</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>    
    <element name="Bristle Burst" type="Spell" source="Weaver Spells" id="ID_PSITHURI_WEAVER_SPELLS_SPELL_BRISTLE_BURST">
        <supports></supports>
        <description>
            <p>You create an explosion of stinging hairs that pierce creatures in the vicinty. Each creature within 5 feet of you must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, a target takes 2d8 piercing damage and has disadvantage on Strength (Athletics) checks until they use an action to clear the needles from their body. On a successful save, the creature takes half damage, but suffers no other effect.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3nd level or higher, the range increases by 5 feet for each spell slot above the 2nd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self (5-foot radius)</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a pinch of tarantula hair</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>    
    <element name="Huntsman’s Eye" type="Spell" source="Weaver Spells" id="ID_PSITHURI_WEAVER_SPELLS_SPELL_HUNTSMANS_EYE">
        <supports></supports>
        <description>
            <p>You choose a creature you can see and focus on it as your prey. Until the spell ends, you deal an extra 1d6 damage to the target whenever you hit it with a melee attack. While the spell lasts, nonmagical difficult terrain doesn’t cost you extra movement while you are moving towards the creature affected by this spell, and you have advantage on Strength (Athletics) and Dexterity (Acrobatics) checks made to cross obstacles on your way to reach them.</p>
            <p class="indent">If the target drops to 0 hit points before this spell ends, you can use a bonus action on a subsequent turn of yours to mark a new creature.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd or 4th level, you can maintain your concentration on the spell for up to 8 hours. When you use a spell slot of 5th level or higher, you can maintain your concentration on the spell for up to 24 hours.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Enchantment</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
            <set name="range">90 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 hour</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>    
    <element name="Spider Servitor" type="Spell" source="Weaver Spells" id="ID_PSITHURI_WEAVER_SPELLS_SPELL_SPIDER_SERVITOR">
        <supports></supports>
        <description>
            <p>You create a Large spectral spider in an unoccupied space you can see within range. The spider lasts for the spell’s duration, and obeys your verbal commands.</p>
            <p class="indent">This spider is a magical construct, and doesn’t do anything you don’t order it to do. It has an AC of 20 and hit points equal to your hit point maximum. If it drops to 0 hit points, the spell ends. It has a Strength of 20 (+5) and Dexterity of 16 (+3).</p>
            <p class="indent">When you cast the spell and as a bonus action on your subsequent turns, you can move the spider up to 60 feet along a floor, wall, or ceiling and give it one of the following orders.</p>
            <p class="indent">Spiderbite The spider sinks its fangs into a creature within 5 feet of it. Make a melee spell attack for the spider using your own game statistics. On a hit, the target takes 4d8 piercing damage. The spider has advantage on attack rolls against a target it is grappling.</p>
            <p class="indent">Entangle The spider attempts to snare a Huge or smaller creature within 60 feet of it with silk. Have the spider make a ranged attack roll against the creature, using the spider’s Dexterity score and adding your own proficiency bonus. On a hit, the target is considered grappled by the spider, and to escape, must make a Strength (Athletics) or Dexterity (Acrobatics) check against your spell save DC. While the spider is grappling a target, you can order it to real the creature in. As a bonus action, you cause a creature smaller than Huge that the spider has grappled is moved up to 30 feet towards the spider.</p>
            <p class="indent">Guard The spider moves between you and a creature you choose until you give the spider a different comand. The spider moves with you, providing you with half cover against the target.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 6th level or higher, the damage from the spiderbite option increases by 2d8 and the range of the entangle increases by 5 feet for each slot level above 5th.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">5</set>
            <set name="school">Conjuration</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">120 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a dead insect</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>    
    <element name="Sticky Stringtrap" type="Spell" source="Weaver Spells" id="ID_PSITHURI_WEAVER_SPELLS_SPELL_STICKY_STRINGTRAP">
        <supports></supports>
        <description>
            <p>When you cast this spell, you hide a magical trap that can cover a creature in webbing when triggered. When you cast this spell, choose a 5-foot surface that cannot be moved (such as a floor, wall, or ceiling) to place the trap upon. The glyph is nearly invisible, requiring a successful Intelligence (Investigation) check against your spell save DC to be found.</p>
            <p class="indent">When a creature comes within 5 feet of a trap cast on the floor, within 15 feet of it horizontally (measuring perpendicular to the wall) when cast on a wall, or within 5 feet of a 30-foot space beneath it if cast on a ceiling, the trap triggers. The creature that triggered the trap and any creatures within 10 feet of them that have line of sight on the trap must make a Deterity saving throw. On a failed save, a creature falls prone and is blinded and restrained for 1 hour, or until another creature uses its action to remove the webbing. Any creature that succeeds on the saving throw is still blinded until it uses an action to remove the webbing from its eyes. When you cast the spell, you can specify certain creatures that the trap will ignore, or cause it to only trigger on certain creatures.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Conjuration</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 minute</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">powdered spiderwebs</set>
            <set name="duration">24 hours</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>    
    <element name="Arachnophobia" type="Spell" source="Weaver Spells" id="ID_PSITHURI_WEAVER_SPELLS_SPELL_ARACHNOPHOBIA">
        <supports></supports>
        <description>
            <p>You evoke extreme paranoia of spiders in creatures you can see. One creature and any more you choose within 5 feet of it must make a Wisdom saving throw. Creatures that can see a spider make this save at disadvantage. On a failed save, an affected creature must take the dash action and move away from all spiders it can see by the safest available route on each of its turns, unless there is nowhere to move. If there are no spiders in its visual range, it instead runs from you. While frightened in this fashion, the creature has disadvantage on saving throws made to escape or avoid getting caught in spider webs.</p>
            <p class="indent">If the creature ends its turn in a location where it doesn’t have line of sight on a spider, the creature can make a Wisdom saving throw. On a successful save, the spell ends for that creature.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a slot of 4th level or higher, you may target one additional creature within 5 feet of the original target for each spell slot above 3rd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Illusion</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a spider’s egg sac</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>    
    <element name="Silken Simulacrum" type="Spell" source="Weaver Spells" id="ID_PSITHURI_WEAVER_SPELLS_SPELL_SILKEN_SIMULACRUM">
        <supports></supports>
        <description>
            <p>You shape a duplicate of yourself formed from a discarded shell. The duplicate is a creature, slightly smaller than you in appearance and half your weight, and can take actions and otherwise be affected as a normal creature. It has half of your hit point maximum, is formed without any equipment, and cannot cast spells. It can use your class abilities as if it were level 5 in one class that you are at least level 5 in, as well as Extra Attack if you have it. Otherwise, the shell’s statistics are an exact duplicate of yours.</p>
            <p class="indent">The simulacrum is friendly to you and creatures you designate. It obeys your spoken commands, moving and acting in accordance with your wishes and acting on our turn in combat. It cannot regain hit points.</p>
            <p class="indent">If you cast this spell again, any currently active duplicates you created with this spell are instantly destroyed.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong>When you cast this spell using a 6th or 7th level spell slot, the duration is up to 8 hours. With an 8th level spell slot, the duration is up to 24 hours and you no longer need to concentrate. With a 9th level spell slot, the duration is permanent until dispelled.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">5</set>
            <set name="school">Necromancy</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">10 minutes</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a tarantula’s molted skin</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 hour</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>    
    <element name="Segment Legs" type="Spell" source="Weaver Spells" id="ID_PSITHURI_WEAVER_SPELLS_SPELL_SEGMENT_LEGS">
        <supports></supports>
        <description>
            <p>Your appendages grow longer and segmented. For the duration of this spell, your reach increases by 5 feet, and you have advantage on saving throws against being knocked prone.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>    
    <element name="Arachnid’s Fang" type="Spell" source="Weaver Spells" id="ID_PSITHURI_WEAVER_SPELLS_SPELL_ARACHNIDS_FANG">
        <supports></supports>
        <description>
            <p>As part of the action used to cast this spell, you must make a melee attack against one creature within the spell’s range, otherwise the spell fails. On a hit, the target suffers the attack’s normal effects, and (if it is not immune to poison) a pulsing toxin enters its veins that compels it to remain in your proximity. If it ends its next turn while more than 15 feet away from you, it immediately takes 1d8 poison damage, and the spell ends.</p>
            <p class="indent">This spell’s damage increases when you reach higher levels. At 5th level, the melee attack deals an extra 1d8 poison damage to the target, and the damage the target takes for being more than 15 feet away from you increases to 2d8. Both damage rolls increase by 1d8 at 11th level and 17th level.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">0</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">5 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">1 round</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>    
    <element name="Diving Orb" type="Spell" source="Weaver Spells" id="ID_PSITHURI_WEAVER_SPELLS_SPELL_DIVING_ORB">
        <supports></supports>
        <description>
            <p>You create a bubble of air that can propel you and your allies through water. When you cast this spell, you create a bubble that encases you and up to four Medium-sized creatures standing within 5 feet of you. While the spell persists, you gain a swimming speed of 30 feet, and the magical air of the bubble allows you to breathe normally. Allied creatures inside the bubble can use their reaction to travel with it, staying within 5 feet of you whenever you move using this swimming speed.</p>
            <p class="indent">Creatures traveling through water in the bubble are not considered to be immersed in that water.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the duration increases by 1 hour for each slot level above 3rd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="isRitual">true</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a flat metal ring</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 hour</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>    
    <element name="Tarantism" type="Spell" source="Weaver Spells" id="ID_PSITHURI_WEAVER_SPELLS_SPELL_TARANTISM">
        <supports></supports>
        <description>
            <p>You begin a frenzied dance that compels others to join in. Choose any number of creatures you can see within range, and each makes a Charisma saving throw. Creatures that can’t be charmed are immune to this spell.</p>
            <p class="indent">On a failed save, each creature takes 5d8 psychic damage and begins to dance uncontrollably. At the start of each of its turns, an affected creature spends all of its movement to dance 10 feet in a random direction, and has disadvantage on attack rolls against both you and against other creatures affected by the spell. Roll a d8 for the direction: 1, north; 2, northeast; 3, east; 4, southeast; 5, south; 6, southwest; 7, west; or 8, northwest. On a successful save, a creature takes half damage and isn’t otherwise affected.</p>
            <p class="indent">A creature outside the radius of the spell recovers from its effects at the end of their next turn.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">6</set>
            <set name="school">Enchantment</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self (20-foot radius)</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a tiny tamborine</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>    
    <element name="Venom Spray" type="Spell" source="Weaver Spells" id="ID_PSITHURI_WEAVER_SPELLS_SPELL_VENOM_SPRAY">
        <supports></supports>
        <description>
            <p>You summon a spray of deadly neurotoxin that surges forth from your hands. Each creature within range must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes 4d8 poison damage and is poisoned for 1 minute. While poisoned in this way, a creature automatically fails Intelligence checks, and has disadvantage on Intelligence saving throws. On a successful save, a creature takes half damage and isn’t poisoned.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 6th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 5th.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">4</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self (30-foot cone)</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a black widow’s fang</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>    
    <element name="Insidious Implantation" type="Spell" source="Weaver Spells" id="ID_PSITHURI_WEAVER_SPELLS_SPELL_INSIDIOUS_IMPLANTATION">
        <supports></supports>
        <description>
            <p>You attempt to implant an insidious egg sac within a creature within range. Make a ranged spell attack against the target. On a hit, the target takes 2d8 piercing damage as the egg sac is embedded in its body. On a miss, choose an unoccupied space within 5 feet of the target to attach the egg sac to. Before the spell ends, you can use your action to cause the egg sac to explode. All creatures within 10 feet of it must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, a target takes 5d8 necrotic damage, or half as much on a successful save. When you take this action, or if a creature the egg sac is attached to dies before the spell ends, the egg sac bursts into a Swarm of Spiders that occupies the creature’s space. The swarm acts directly after your turn in the initiative order, and attacks the closest living creature besides you. If you stop concentrating before the egg sac bursts, it vanishes. However, once the Swarm of Spiders have hatched, they remain for the full duration of the spell, even if you no longer concentrate on it.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, the damage of the egg sac burst increases by 1d8, and you summon one additional Swarm of Spiders on a nearby space, for each slot level above 4th.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">5</set>
            <set name="school">Conjuration</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a spider’s egg sac</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>    
    <element name="Gossamer Wings" type="Spell" source="Weaver Spells" id="ID_PSITHURI_WEAVER_SPELLS_SPELL_GOSSAMER_WINGS">
        <supports></supports>
        <description>
            <p>You sprout silken wings of gossamer from your back that slow your descent. Your rate of descent slows to 60 feet per round until the spell ends, and you can move 10 feet horizontally in a direction of your choice for each 10 feet you fall. If you land before the spell ends, you take no falling damage. While the spell persists, you automatically fail saving throws against being moved by wind.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 reaction</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">1 minute</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>    
    <element name="Derive Sustenance" type="Spell" source="Weaver Spells" id="ID_PSITHURI_WEAVER_SPELLS_SPELL_DERIVE_SUSTENANCE">
        <supports></supports>
        <description>
            <p>You convert a corpse you touch into useful nutritious material. When you touch one Small beast corpse, or one Small or Medium humanoid corpse, it is slowly wrapped in silk over the 1 minute cast time of this spell. If your concentration is broken during this time, the spell fails and the spell slot is wasted. At the end of this time, the corpse shrinks to a fist-sized package of silk, while any magical or inorganic material is pushed out onto nearby unoccupied spaces. Any creature can use its action to unwrap the silk and consume its contents or feed them to another creature. The meal contains enough nourishment to sustain a creature for one day, and restores 1d8 hit points plus additonal hit points equal to the consumed creature’s challenge rating (rounded down, minimum of 0).</p>
            <p class="indent">You may have a number of silken packages created with this spell equal to your spellcasting ability modifier (minimum of 1). If you create a new one over this limit, the oldest one disintegrates.</p>
            <p class="indent">When a creature that cannot cast this spell consumes one of the silken packages, it must make a DC 10 Constitution saving throw or vomit and gain no benefits from the spell.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the amount of hit points restored increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 1st.</p>
            <p class="indent">With a 3rd level spell slot or higher, you may affect one Medium beast corpse.</p>
            <p class="indent">With a 5th level spell slot or higher, you may affect one Large beast or humanoid corpse.</p>
            <p class="indent">With a 6th level spell slot or higher, you may affect up to one Huge beast, humanoid, or giant corpse, or up to three Medium or Small ones simultaneously. When you affect multiple corpses at the same time, you create only one meal, and combine their challenge ratings together to determine the additional hit points restored.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Necromancy</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 minute</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">the corpse of a creature that died in the past 24 hours, which the spell consumes</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>    
    <element name="Itsy Bitsy" type="Spell" source="Weaver Spells" id="ID_PSITHURI_WEAVER_SPELLS_SPELL_ITSY_BITSY">
        <supports></supports>
        <description>
            <p>Your touch causes a creature to shrink down to a very small size. When you cast this spell on an unwilling creature, it must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, it shrinks to Small size, and its speed is becomes 25 feet if it was higher. On a successful save, the spell does not take effect immediately, but continues to affect the creature.</p>
            <p class="indent">A creature affected by this spell must make another Constitution saving throw at the end of each of its turns. If it successfully saves against this spell three times, the spell ends. If it fails a second time, it shrinks to Tiny size, and all of its weapon attacks deal half damage. If it fails a third time, it becomes smaller than Tiny size. While affected in this way, the creature’s speed becomes 5 feet if it was higher, and it cannot make attacks.</p>
            <p class="indent">If you maintain your concentration on this spell for the entire possible duration, the creature stays this size until the effect is dispelled.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">7</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a raindrop</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>    
    <element name="Liquid Silk" type="Spell" source="Weaver Spells" id="ID_PSITHURI_WEAVER_SPELLS_SPELL_LIQUID_SILK">
        <supports></supports>
        <description>
            <p>You launch two globs of silk, laced with potent acidic liquid, at two areas you can see. Choose two points within range. From each of these points, a 5-foot wide line of caustic liquid lands and extends in a 30-foot line in a direction of your choice, splattering everything it touches with acid. Each creature in one of these lines must make a Dexterity saving throw. A creature takes 8d6 acid damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. A creature can only be damaged by this spell once per casting, even if it is hit by both lines of acid.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d6 for each slot above 3rd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a pestle</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>    
    <element name="Curse of Puncturing" type="Spell" source="Weaver Spells" id="ID_PSITHURI_WEAVER_SPELLS_SPELL_CURSE_OF_PUNCTURING">
        <supports></supports>
        <description>
            <p>You point at a creature within range and instill within it a fear of needles. Whenever you deal piercing damage to an affected creature, it has disadvantage on its next saving throw to avoid poison damage or the poisoned condition during the spell’s duration.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Enchantment</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">30 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a needle</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>    
</elements>