<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Eldritch Warrior Martial Archetype</name>
        <author url="https://www.gmbinder.com/share/-LC0ZBpknRuHUFC5DnXo">u/devikyn</author>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="fighter-eldritch-warrior.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/gm-binder-devikyn/eldritch-arcana/fighter-eldritch-warrior.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Elritch Warrior" type="Archetype" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_ELDRITCH_WARRIOR">
        <supports>Martial Archetype</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The archetypal Eldritch Warrior sees otherworldly knowledge as a means to exceed and transcend their mortal limits. As a way to unlock their hidden potential, these fighters perform an ancient rite which forges a link from their mind and body to an otherworldly entity. They utilize the resulting knowledge and magical power to great effect, but not without cost; such a forceful method exacts its toll on them. Such fighters believe that the key to progress lies in harnessing the power hidden in these eldritch rites, and they are willing to bear the burden required for their discoveries.</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Fighter Level</td><td>Feature</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>3rd</td><td>Otherwordly Rite, Rite Magic</td></tr>
                <tr><td>7th</td><td>Rite Invocations, Rite of the Armory</td></tr>
                <tr><td>10th</td><td>Crackling Surge</td></tr>
                <tr><td>15th</td><td>Leeching Strike</td></tr>
                <tr><td>18th</td><td>Seal-breaking Sigil</td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_WARRIOR_OTHERWORLDLY_RITE" />
            <div element="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_WARRIOR_RITE_MAGIC" />
            <div element="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_WARRIOR_RITE_INVOCATIONS" />
            <div element="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_WARRIOR_RITE_OF_THE_ARMORY" />
            <div element="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_WARRIOR_CRACKLING_SURGE" />
            <div element="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_WARRIOR_LEECHING_STRIKE" />
            <div element="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_WARRIOR_SEALBREAKING_SIGIL" />
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_WARRIOR_OTHERWORLDLY_RITE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_WARRIOR_RITE_MAGIC" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_WARRIOR_RITE_INVOCATIONS" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_WARRIOR_RITE_OF_THE_ARMORY" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_WARRIOR_CRACKLING_SURGE" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_WARRIOR_LEECHING_STRIKE" level="15" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_WARRIOR_SEALBREAKING_SIGIL" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Otherworldly Rite" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_WARRIOR_OTHERWORLDLY_RITE">
        <description>
            <p>At 3rd level, you have completed an ancient rite, creating a link between yourself and an otherworldly being. Through this link, the being’s strongest emotion seeps through along with its knowledge.</p>
            <p class="indent">Choose one option from the "Rite Links" detailed below. Your choice grants you an ability, gained through the link, as well as a debilitation, which is a cost of absorbing knowledge you aren’t equipped to comprehend.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Rite Link" supports="Rite Link" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Rite Magic" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_WARRIOR_RITE_MAGIC">
        <description>
            <p>The magic bestowed by your rite, and your understanding of its magical knowledge, have given you facility with spells. See the <i>Player’s Handbook:</i> chapter 10 for the general rules of spellcasting and chapter 11 for the warlock spell list.</p>
            <h5>CANTRIPS</h5>
            <p>You know two cantrips of your choice from the warlock spell list. You learn another warlock cantrip of your choice at 10th level.</p>
            <h5>SPELL SLOTS</h5>
            <p>The Eldritch Warrior table shows how many spell slots you have. The table also shows what the level of those slots is; all of your spell slots are the same level. To cast one of your warlock spells of 1st level or higher, you must expend a spell slot. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            <p class="indent">For example, when you are 7th level, you have two 2nd-level spell slots. To cast the 1st-level spell thunderwave, you must spend a spell slot, and you cast it as a 2nd-level spell.</p>
            <h5>SPELLS KNOWN OF 1ST LEVEL AND HIGHER</h5>
            <p>The Spells Known Column of the Eldritch Warrior table shows how many spells you know. You can choose each 1st spell of 1st level or higher from the warlock spell list. A spell you choose must be of a level no higher than what’s shown in the table’s Slot Level column for your level. When you reach 16th level, for example, you learn a new warlock spell, which can be 1st, 2nd, or 3rd level.</p>
            <p class="indent">Additionally, when you gain a level in this class, you can choose one of the warlock spells you know and replace it with another spell from the warlock spell list, which also must be of a level for which you have spell slots.</p>
            <h5>SPELLCASTING ABILITY</h5>
            <p>Charisma is your spellcasting ability for your warlock spells, so you use your Charisma whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Charisma modifier when setting the saving throw DC for and when making an attack roll with a warlock spell.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Spell save DC </strong>= 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Spell attack modifier </strong>your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="spellcaster">true</set>
            <set name="spellcastingAbility">Charisma</set>
            <set name="spellcastingClass">Eldritch Warrior</set>
        </setters>
        <spellcasting name="Eldritch Warrior" ability="Charisma" prepare="false">
            <list>Warlock</list>
        </spellcasting>
        <sheet>
            <description>You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a short or long rest.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <!-- add not full but single _not counting as multiclass spellcaster due to pact magic -->
            <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS_SPELLCASTING_SLOTS_SOLO" requirements="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS"/>

            <stat name="eldritch warrior:spellcasting:slots:count" value="1" level="3"/>
            <stat name="eldritch warrior:spellcasting:slots:count" value="1" level="4"/>

            <stat name="eldritch warrior:spellcasting:slot" value="1" level="3" />
            <stat name="eldritch warrior:spellcasting:slot" value="1" level="7" />
            <stat name="eldritch warrior:spellcasting:slot" value="1" level="13" />
            <stat name="eldritch warrior:spellcasting:slot" value="1" level="19" />
            
            <!-- negative count to remove slots -->
            <stat name="eldritch warrior:spellcasting:slots:1" value="eldritch warrior:spellcasting:slots:count" level="3" />
            <stat name="eldritch warrior:spellcasting:slots:1" value="-eldritch warrior:spellcasting:slots:count" level="7" />
            <stat name="eldritch warrior:spellcasting:slots:2" value="eldritch warrior:spellcasting:slots:count" level="7" />
            <stat name="eldritch warrior:spellcasting:slots:2" value="-eldritch warrior:spellcasting:slots:count" level="13" />
            <stat name="eldritch warrior:spellcasting:slots:3" value="eldritch warrior:spellcasting:slots:count" level="13" />
            <stat name="eldritch warrior:spellcasting:slots:3" value="-eldritch warrior:spellcasting:slots:count" level="19" />
            <stat name="eldritch warrior:spellcasting:slots:4" value="eldritch warrior:spellcasting:slots:count" level="19" />

            <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Eldritch Warrior)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),0" level="1" number="2" spellcasting="Eldritch Warrior" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Eldritch Warrior)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),0" level="10" spellcasting="Eldritch Warrior" />

            <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Eldritch Warrior)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="3" number="2" spellcasting="Eldritch Warrior"/>
            <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Eldritch Warrior)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="4" spellcasting="Eldritch Warrior"/>
            <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Eldritch Warrior)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="7" spellcasting="Eldritch Warrior"/>
            <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Eldritch Warrior)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="10" spellcasting="Eldritch Warrior"/>
            <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Eldritch Warrior)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="13" spellcasting="Eldritch Warrior"/>
            <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Eldritch Warrior)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="16" spellcasting="Eldritch Warrior"/>
            <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Eldritch Warrior)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="19" spellcasting="Eldritch Warrior"/>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Rite Invocations" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_WARRIOR_RITE_INVOCATIONS">
        <description>
            <p>As you harness more power through your rite, you gain the ability to draw out rite invocations, fragments of forbidden knowledge that imbue you with an abiding magical ability.</p>
            <p class="indent">At 7th level, you gain two Rite Invocations of your choice. When you gain certain fighter levels, shown in the Eldritch Warrior table, you gain additional invocations of your choice. You cannot gain an invocation with the same name more than once, even if another class feature allows you to, unless the invocation’s description specifically says you can.</p>
            <p class="indent">Additionally, when you gain a level in this class, you can choose one of the invocations you know and replace it with another invocation that you could learn at that level. A level prerequisite in an invocation refers to fighter level, not character level.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Rite Invocation (Eldritch Warrior)" number="2" supports="Rite Invocation" allowreplace="true" />
            <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Rite Invocation (Eldritch Warrior)" number="1" supports="Rite Invocation" allowreplace="true" level="13" />
            <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Rite Invocation (Eldritch Warrior)" number="1" supports="Rite Invocation" allowreplace="true" level="19" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Rite of the Armory" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_WARRIOR_RITE_OF_THE_ARMORY">
        <description>
            <p>Also at 7th level, your rite’s magic manifests as the ability to manipulate your weapons, or even to create new ones.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can use your bonus action to create a rite weapon in one or both of your empty hands. You can choose the form that each of these weapons take each time you create them (see <i>Player’s Handbook:</i> chapter 5 for weapon options). The weapons count as magical for the purpose of overcoming resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once per turn when you hit a creature with one of your rite weapons, you can spend an eldritch warrior spell slot to deal an extra 1d8 force damage to the target, plus another 1d8 per level of the spell slot, and you can knock the target prone if it is Huge or smaller.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can transform one magic weapon into one of your rite weapons by performing a special ritual while you hold the weapon. You perform the ritual over the course of 1 hour, which can be done during a short rest. You can then dismiss the weapon (no action required), shunting it into an extradimensional space, and it appears whenever you create your rite weapon thereafter. The weapon ceases being your pact weapon if you die or if you use a 1-hour ritual to break your bond to it.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can transform up to two magic weapons into your rite weapons; if you perform the special 1-hour ritual again while you already have two, then one of your current rite weapons ceases to be a rite weapon for you. The weapon appears at your feet if it is in the extradimensional space when the bond breaks.</p>
            <p class="indent">A rite weapon of yours disappears if it is more than 5 feet away from you for 1 minute or more. It also disappears if you use this feature again, if you dismiss the weapon, or if you die.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Bonus Action">
            <description>You can create a rite weapon in one or both of your empty hands. You can choose the form that each of these weapons take each time you create them. The weapons count as magical for the purpose of overcoming resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage. Once per turn when you hit a creature with one of your rite weapons, you can spend an eldritch warrior spell slot to deal an extra 1d8 force damage to the target, plus another 1d8 per level of the spell slot, and you can knock the target prone if it is Huge or smaller.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Crackling Surge" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_WARRIOR_CRACKLING_SURGE">
        <description>
            <p>At 10th level, your surges of energy imbue your attacks with crackling eldritch power.</p>
            <p class="indent">Whenever you hit with an attack made via your Action Surge’s additional action, you can deal extra force damage to the target equal to your Charisma modifier.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Whenever you hit with an attack made via your Action Surge’s additional action, you can deal {{charisma:modifier}} points extra force damage.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Leeching Strike" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_WARRIOR_LEECHING_STRIKE">
        <description>
            <p>At 15th level, when you score a critical hit, you can use your reaction to regain hit points equal to the extra damage dealt by the hit.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Reaction">
            <description>When you score a critical hit, you can regain hit points equal to the extra damage dealt by the hit.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Seal-breaking Sigil" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_WARRIOR_SEALBREAKING_SIGIL">
        <description>
            <p>At 18th level, you carve into your body a specialized sigil which can expand your rite link for a fleeting burst of power and speed.</p>
            <p class="indent">On your turn, you can invoke this sigil, causing it to glow a faint blue color and crackle with power. Until the end of your turn, you can take one additional action and you gain one additional eldritch warrior spell slot. At the end of the turn, you must make a DC 18 Charisma saving throw. On a failed save, you take four times your fighter level in necrotic damage, which cannot be reduced by any means.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you have used this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>On your turn, you can invoke this sigil, causing it to glow a faint blue color and crackle with power. Until the end of your turn, you can take one additional action and you gain one additional eldritch warrior spell slot. At the end of the turn, you must make a DC 18 Charisma saving throw. On a failed save, you take four times your fighter level in necrotic damage, which cannot be reduced by any means.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <!-- Otherworldly Rites -->
    <element name="Compassion" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RITE_LINK_COMPASSION">
        <supports>Rite Link</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Your otherworldly being is compassionate, which grants you the ability to sense the most prevalent emotion of one creature of your choice within 30 feet of you as a bonus action. However, you have disadvantage on Wisdom (Insight) checks to determine if a creature is lying.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet alt="Rite Link: Compassion" action="Bonus Action">
            <description>You the ability to sense the most prevalent emotion of one creature of your choice within 30 feet of you as a bonus action.
            However, you have disadvantage on Wisdom (Insight) checks to determine if a creature is lying.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Disdain" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RITE_LINK_DISDAIN">
        <supports>Rite Link</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Your otherworldly being is a hateful thing. You can deal an extra 2 necrotic damage to one of the targets whenever you deal damage with an attack. However, when you are dying, you must succeed one additional death saving throw to stabilize yourself.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet alt="Rite Link: Disdain">
            <description>You can deal an extra 2 necrotic damage to one of the targets whenever you deal damage with an attack.
            However, when you are dying, you must succeed one additional death saving throw to stabilize yourself.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Fury" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RITE_LINK_FURY">
        <supports>Rite Link</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Your otherworldly being emits ceaseless fury. When you make an attack roll with advantage, you can add a +2 bonus to the attack roll. However, you make initiative rolls with disadvantage.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet alt="Rite Link: Fury">
            <description>When you make an attack roll with advantage, you can add a +2 bonus to the attack roll.
            However, you make initiative rolls with disadvantage.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Honor" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RITE_LINK_HONOR">
        <supports>Rite Link</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Your otherworldly being imparts a fierce sense of honor. You can cast <i>compelled duel</i> without expending a spell slot once per short or long rest. However, you have disadvantage on saving throws against being charmed.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet alt="Rite Link: Honor" usage="1/Short Rest">
            <description>You can cast compelled duel without expending a spell slot once per short or long rest.
            However, you have disadvantage on saving throws against being charmed.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMPELLED_DUEL" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Intuition" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RITE_LINK_INTUITION">
        <supports>Rite Link</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Your otherworldly being is sharp, seeing through deceit. You can use your action to see the true form of any creature or object concealed by an illusion as long as that creature is hostile to you. However, you have disadvantage on Charisma checks made as part of a lie.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet alt="Rite Link: Intuition" action="Action">
            <description>You can use your action to see the true form of any creature or object concealed by an illusion as long as that creature is hostile to you.
            However, you have disadvantage on Charisma checks made as part of a lie.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Knowledge" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RITE_LINK_KNOWLEDGE">
        <supports>Rite Link</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Your otherworldly being craves knowledge. You have advantage on Intelligence checks. However, whenever you fail an Intelligence check, you cannot add your proficiency bonus to further Intelligence checks until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet alt="Rite Link: Knowledge">
            <description>You have advantage on Intelligence checks.
            However, whenever you fail an Intelligence check, you cannot add your proficiency bonus to further Intelligence checks until you finish a short or long rest.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Mercy" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RITE_LINK_MERCY">
        <supports>Rite Link</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Your otherworldly being abhors violence. You can cast the <i>spare the dying</i> cantrip at will. However, whenever you kill a creature, the first ability check or attack roll you make within the next minute is made with disadvantage.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet alt="Rite Link: Mercy">
            <description>You can cast the spare the dying cantrip at will.
            However, whenever you kill a creature, the first ability check or attack roll you make within the next minute is made with disadvantage.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPARE_THE_DYING" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Paranoia" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RITE_LINK_PARANOIA">
        <supports>Rite Link</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Your otherworldly being’s influence exudes paranoia. You gain 2 temporary hit points at the start of each of your turns if no ally is within 30 feet of you. However, any healing you receive from other creatures is reduced by 1, to a minimum of 1.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet alt="Rite Link: Paranoia">
            <description>You gain 2 temporary hit points at the start of each of your turns if no ally is within 30 feet of you.
            However, any healing you receive from other creatures is reduced by 1, to a minimum of 1.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <!-- Rite Invocations -->
    <element name="Call of the Lost" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RITE_INVOCATION_CALL_OF_THE_LOST">
        <supports>Rite Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite></prerequisite>
        <requirements></requirements>
        <description>
            <p>You can cast <i>phantasmal force</i> once, without expending a spell slot or material components. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>You can cast phantasmal force once, without expending a spell slot or material components.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Cloak of Flies" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RITE_INVOCATION_CLOAK_OF_FLIES">
        <supports>Rite Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>13th level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:fighter:13]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisites: 13th level</p>
            <p>As a bonus action, you can surround yourself with a magical aura that looks like buzzing flies. The aura extends 5 feet from you in every direction, but not through total cover. It lasts until you’re incapacitated or you dismiss it as a bonus action.</p>
            <p class="indent">The aura grants you advantage on Charisma (Intimidation) checks but disadvantage on all other Charisma checks. Any other creature that starts its turn in the aura takes poison damage equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum of 0 damage).</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you use this invocation, you can’t use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="1/Short Rest">
            <description>You can surround yourself with a magical aura that looks like buzzing flies. The aura extends 5 feet from you in every direction, but not through total cover. It lasts until you’re incapacitated or you dismiss it as a bonus action.
            You have advantage on Charisma (Intimidation) checks but disadvantage on all other Charisma checks. Any other creature that starts its turn in the aura takes poison damage equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum of 0 damage).</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="cloak-of-flies:damage" value="0" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="cloak-of-flies:damage" value="charisma:modifier" bonus="base" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Devil’s Sight" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RITE_INVOCATION_DEVILS_SIGHT">
        <supports>Rite Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite></prerequisite>
        <requirements></requirements>
        <description>
            <p>You can see normally in darkness, both magical and non-magical, to a distance of 120 feet.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can see normally in darkness, both magical and non-magical, to a distance of 120 feet.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Eyes of the Runekeeper" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RITE_INVOCATION_EYES_OF_THE_RUNEKEEPER">
        <supports>Rite Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite></prerequisite>
        <requirements></requirements>
        <description>
            <p>You automatically understand the meaning of any non-magical writing that you read, and you can see writing that is invisible.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You automatically understand the meaning of any non-magical writing that you read, and you can see writing that is invisible.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Gaze of Two Minds" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RITE_INVOCATION_GAZE_OF_TWO_MINDS">
        <supports>Rite Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite></prerequisite>
        <requirements></requirements>
        <description>
            <p>You can use your action to touch a willing humanoid and perceive through its senses until the end of your next turn. As long as the creature is on the same plane of existence as you, you can use your action on subsequent turns to maintain this connection, extending the duration until the end of your next turn. While perceiving through the other creature’s senses, you benefit from any special senses possessed by that creature, and you are blinded and deafened to your own surroundings.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Action">
            <description>You touch a willing humanoid and perceive through its senses until the end of your next turn. As long as the creature is on the same plane of existence as you, you can use your action on subsequent turns to maintain this connection, extending the duration until the end of your next turn. While perceiving through the other creature’s senses, you benefit from any special senses possessed by that creature, and you are blinded and deafened to your own surroundings.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Gift of the Depths" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RITE_INVOCATION_GIFT_OF_THE_DEPTHS">
        <supports>Rite Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>13th level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:fighter:13]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisites: 13th level</p>
            <p>You can breathe underwater, and you gain a swimming speed equal to your walking speed.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can also cast <i>water breathing</i> once without expending a spell slot. You regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can breathe underwater, and you gain a swimming speed equal to your walking speed.
            You can also cast water breathing once without expending a spell slot. You regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="speed:swim" value="speed" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WATER_BREATHING" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Ghostly Gaze" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RITE_INVOCATION_GHOSTLY_GAZE">
        <supports>Rite Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>19th level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:fighter:19]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisites: 19th level</p>
            <p>As an action, you gain the ability to see through solid objects to a range of 30 feet. Within that range, you have darkvision if you don’t already have it. This special sight lasts for 1 minute or until your concentration ends (as if you were concentrating on a spell). During that time, you perceive objects as ghostly, transparent images.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you use this invocation, you can’t use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Short Rest">
            <description>You can see through solid objects to a range of 30 feet. Within that range, you have darkvision if you don’t already have it. This lasts for 1 minute or until your concentration ends (as if you were concentrating on a spell). During that time, you perceive objects as ghostly, transparent images.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Hex Pursuit" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RITE_INVOCATION_HEX_PURSUIT">
        <supports>Rite Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>19th level, hex spell</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:fighter:19],ID_PHB_SPELL_HEX</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisites: 19th level, hex spell</p>
            <p>As a bonus action, you can magically teleport up to 30 feet to an unoccupied space you can see within 5 feet of the target cursed by your hex spell. To teleport in this way, you must be able to see the cursed target.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description action="Action">You can magically teleport up to 30 feet to an unoccupied space you can see within 5 feet of the target cursed by your hex spell. To teleport in this way, you must be able to see the cursed target.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Horrific Shackles" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RITE_INVOCATION_HORRIFIC_SHACKLES">
        <supports>Rite Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>19th level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:fighter:19]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisites: 19th level</p>
            <p>You can cast <i>phantasmal killer</i> once without expending a spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>You can cast phantasmal killer once without expending a spell slot.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PHANTASMAL_KILLER" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Insidious Nerves" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RITE_INVOCATION_INSIDIOUS_NERVES">
        <supports>Rite Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>19th level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:fighter:19]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisites: 19th level</p>
            <p>You can cast <i>confusion</i> once using an eldritch warrior spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>You can cast confusion once using an eldritch warrior spell slot.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONFUSION" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Melder of Beasts" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RITE_INVOCATION_MELDER_OF_BEASTS">
        <supports>Rite Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>19th level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:fighter:19]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisites: 19th level</p>
            <p>You can cast <i>polymorph</i> once using an eldritch warrior spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>You can cast polymorph once using an eldritch warrior spell slot.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_POLYMORPH" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Numb Synapses" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RITE_INVOCATION_NUMB_SYNAPSES">
        <supports>Rite Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>13th level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:fighter:13]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisites: 13th level</p>
            <p>You can cast <i>slow</i> once without expending a spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>You can cast slow once without expending a spell slot.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SLOW" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="One with Shadows" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RITE_INVOCATION_ONE_WITH_SHADOWS">
        <supports>Rite Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>13th level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:fighter:13]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisites: 13th level</p>
            <p>When you are in an area of dim light or darkness, you can use your action to become invisible until you move, take an action or a reaction.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Action">
            <description>When you are in an area of dim light or darkness, you can use your action to become invisible until you move, take an action or a reaction.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Speech of the Breathless" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RITE_INVOCATION_SPEECH_OF_THE_BREATHLESS">
        <supports>Rite Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite></prerequisite>
        <requirements></requirements>
        <description>
            <p>You can cast silence once without expending a spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>You can cast silence once without expending a spell slot.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SILENCE" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Tomb of Levistus" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RITE_INVOCATION_TOMB_OF_LEVISTUS">
        <supports>Rite Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>13th level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:fighter:13]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisites: 13th level</p>
            <p>As a reaction when you take damage, you can entomb yourself in ice, which melts away at the end of your next turn. You gain 10 temporary hit points per fighter level, which take as much of the triggering damage as possible. Immediately after you take the damage, you gain vulnerability to fire damage, your speed is reduced to 0, and you are incapacitated. These effects, including any remaining temporary hit points, all end when the ice melts.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you use this invocation, you can’t use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Short Rest" action="Reaction">
            <description>When you take damage, you can entomb yourself in ice, which melts away at the end of your next turn. You gain {{tomb-of-levistus:temp-hp}} temporary hit points, which take as much of the triggering damage as possible. Immediately after you take the damage, you gain vulnerability to fire damage, your speed is reduced to 0, and you are incapacitated. These effects, including any remaining temporary hit points, all end when the ice melts.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="tomb-of-levistus:temp-hp" value="10" requirements="[level:fighter:1]" />
            <stat name="tomb-of-levistus:temp-hp" value="10" requirements="[level:fighter:2]" />
            <stat name="tomb-of-levistus:temp-hp" value="10" requirements="[level:fighter:3]" />
            <stat name="tomb-of-levistus:temp-hp" value="10" requirements="[level:fighter:4]" />
            <stat name="tomb-of-levistus:temp-hp" value="10" requirements="[level:fighter:5]" />
            <stat name="tomb-of-levistus:temp-hp" value="10" requirements="[level:fighter:6]" />
            <stat name="tomb-of-levistus:temp-hp" value="10" requirements="[level:fighter:7]" />
            <stat name="tomb-of-levistus:temp-hp" value="10" requirements="[level:fighter:8]" />
            <stat name="tomb-of-levistus:temp-hp" value="10" requirements="[level:fighter:9]" />
            <stat name="tomb-of-levistus:temp-hp" value="10" requirements="[level:fighter:10]" />
            <stat name="tomb-of-levistus:temp-hp" value="10" requirements="[level:fighter:11]" />
            <stat name="tomb-of-levistus:temp-hp" value="10" requirements="[level:fighter:12]" />
            <stat name="tomb-of-levistus:temp-hp" value="10" requirements="[level:fighter:13]" />
            <stat name="tomb-of-levistus:temp-hp" value="10" requirements="[level:fighter:14]" />
            <stat name="tomb-of-levistus:temp-hp" value="10" requirements="[level:fighter:15]" />
            <stat name="tomb-of-levistus:temp-hp" value="10" requirements="[level:fighter:16]" />
            <stat name="tomb-of-levistus:temp-hp" value="10" requirements="[level:fighter:17]" />
            <stat name="tomb-of-levistus:temp-hp" value="10" requirements="[level:fighter:18]" />
            <stat name="tomb-of-levistus:temp-hp" value="10" requirements="[level:fighter:19]" />
            <stat name="tomb-of-levistus:temp-hp" value="10" requirements="[level:fighter:20]" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Trickster’s Escape" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RITE_INVOCATION_TRICKSTERS_ESCAPE">
        <supports>Rite Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>19th level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:fighter:19]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisites: 19th level</p>
            <p>You can cast <i>freedom of movement</i> once on yourself without expending a spell slot. You regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>You can cast freedom of movement once on yourself without expending a spell slot.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FREEDOM_OF_MOVEMENT" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Thief of Five Fates" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RITE_INVOCATION_THIEF_OF_FIVE_FATES">
        <supports>Rite Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite></prerequisite>
        <requirements></requirements>
        <description>
            <p>You can cast <i>bane</i> once without expending a spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>You can cast bane once without expending a spell slot.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BANE" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Two Wise Monkeys" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RITE_INVOCATION_TWO_WISE_MONKEYS">
        <supports>Rite Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite></prerequisite>
        <requirements></requirements>
        <description>
            <p>You can cast <i>blindness/deafness</i> once without expending a spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>You can cast blindness/deafness once without expending a spell slot.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLINDNESS_DEAFNESS" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Warrior’s Rite Weapon" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RITE_INVOCATION_WARRIORS_RITE_WEAPON">
        <supports>Rite Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite></prerequisite>
        <requirements></requirements>
        <description>
            <p>You can use any weapon you summon with your Rite of the Armory feature as a spellcasting focus for your warlock spells. In addition, the weapon gains a +1 bonus to its attack and damage rolls, unless it is a magic weapon that already has a bonus to those rolls. This bonus increases to +2 at 13th level and +3 at 19th level.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can use any weapon you summon with your Rite of the Armory feature as a spellcasting focus for your warlock spells. In addition, the weapon gains a +1 bonus to its attack and damage rolls, unless it is a magic weapon that already has a bonus to those rolls.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="warriors-right:bonus" value="1" />
            <stat name="warriors-right:bonus" value="1" requirements="[level:fighter:13]" />
            <stat name="warriors-right:bonus" value="1" requirements="[level:fighter:19]" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Weaver of Nightmares" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RITE_INVOCATION_WEAVER_OF_NIGHTMARES">
        <supports>Rite Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite></prerequisite>
        <requirements></requirements>
        <description>
            <p>You can cast web once without expending a spell slot. You regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>You can cast web once without expending a spell slot.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WEB" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Withering Influence" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eldritch Arcana" id="ID_EA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RITE_INVOCATION_WITHERING_INFLUENCE">
        <supports>Rite Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>13th level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[level:fighter:13]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisites: 13th level</p>
            <p>You can cast bestow curse once using an eldritch warrior spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>You can cast bestow curse once using an eldritch warrior spell slot.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BESTOW_CURSE" />
        </rules>
    </element>
</elements>