<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Fae Knight: Nymph Martial Archetype</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="fighter-fae-knight-nymph.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/subclasses/fighter/fighter-fae-knight-nymph.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Fae Knight: Nymph" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_GANNOH2_GMBINDER_SOURCE_Fae Knight: Nymph">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation">FKN</set>
            <set name="url">https://www.gmbinder.com/share/-M1CO3UCNFp4M8E7ld4K</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" abbreviation="G2" url="https://www.gmbinder.com/profile/gannoh2">Gannoh2</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20200609</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Fae Knight" type="Archetype" source="Fae Knight: Nymph" id="ID_G2_FKN_ARCHETYPE_FIGHTER_FAE_KNIGHT">
        <supports>Martial Archetype</supports>
        <requirements>[cha:14]</requirements>
        <prerequisite>Charisma 14</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p>Fae knights are warriors blessed or cursed by a particular group of fey creature. This boon grants supernatural powers, but always comes with a price.</p>
            <p class="indent">Fae knights that receive the gift of a nymph receive her incredible attractiveness. In return, she demands that you protect the beauty of the world.</p>
            <p class="indent">Prerequisite: Although nymphs mean well, they are somewhat superficial, and they only give their gift to individuals they already consider attractive. You must have a Charisma score of at least 14 to take this subclass.</p>
            <div element="ID_G2_FKN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FAE_KNIGHT_FEY_TOUCHED" />
            <div element="ID_G2_FKN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FAE_KNIGHT_UNEARTHLY_GRACE" />
            <div element="ID_G2_FKN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FAE_KNIGHT_DISTRACTING_GLANCE" />
            <div element="ID_G2_FKN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FAE_KNIGHT_BLINDING_BEAUTY" />
            <div element="ID_G2_FKN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FAE_KNIGHT_STUNNING_GLANCE" />
            <div element="ID_G2_FKN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FAE_KNIGHT_CHARM_PROOF" />
            <div element="ID_G2_FKN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FAE_KNIGHT_SLAYING_BEAUTY" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_G2_FKN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FAE_KNIGHT_FEY_TOUCHED" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_G2_FKN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FAE_KNIGHT_UNEARTHLY_GRACE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_G2_FKN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FAE_KNIGHT_DISTRACTING_GLANCE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_G2_FKN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FAE_KNIGHT_BLINDING_BEAUTY" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_G2_FKN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FAE_KNIGHT_STUNNING_GLANCE" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_G2_FKN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FAE_KNIGHT_CHARM_PROOF" level="15" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_G2_FKN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FAE_KNIGHT_SLAYING_BEAUTY" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Fey-Touched" type="Archetype Feature" source="Fae Knight: Nymph" id="ID_G2_FKN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FAE_KNIGHT_FEY_TOUCHED">
            <description>
                <p>At 3rd level, you learn the Sylvan language. You have advantage on Intelligence checks to recall information about Fey. Fey creatures recognize that you have been touched by one of their own, giving you advantage on Charisma checks when dealing with them.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You have advantage on Intelligence checks to recall information about Fey. Fey creatures recognize that you have been touched by one of their own, giving you advantage on Charisma checks when dealing with them.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_SYLVAN" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Unearthly Grace" type="Archetype Feature" source="Fae Knight: Nymph" id="ID_G2_FKN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FAE_KNIGHT_UNEARTHLY_GRACE">
            <description>
                <p>When you take this archetype at 3rd level, a nymph bestows upon you incredible beauty. Choose either your Strength score or your Dexterity score. Your Charisma score increases to match that score, unless your Charisma score is already higher. This feature cannot increase your Charisma score above 16.</p>
                <p class="indent">In addition, you can now use Charisma instead of Strength and Dexterity for weapon attacks.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can use Charisma instead of Strength and Dexterity for weapon attacks.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="unearthly-grace:ability-score:base" value="strength" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="unearthly-grace:ability-score:base" value="dexterity" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="unearthly-grace:ability-score:cha-base" value="charisma" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="unearthly-grace:ability-score:cha-base" value="1" />
                <stat name="charisma:score:set" value="16" requirments="![cha:17],[unearthly-grace:ability-score:base:16]" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="charisma:score:set" value="unearthly-grace:ability-score:base" requirments="![cha:17],[unearthly-grace:ability-score:base:unearthly-grace:ability-score:cha-base]" bonus="base" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Distracting Glance" type="Archetype Feature" source="Fae Knight: Nymph" id="ID_G2_FKN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FAE_KNIGHT_DISTRACTING_GLANCE">
            <description>
                <p>At 3rd level, you can use your remarkable good looks to great effect. When a creature you can see within 30 feet of you that can see you makes an attack, you can use your reaction to impose disadvantage on it. Creatures immune to being charmed are unaffected. You can use this feature on an individual creature only once every 24 hours.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier. You regain any expended uses when you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Reaction" usage="{{charisma:modifier}}/Long Rest">
                <description>When a creature you can see within 30 feet of you that can see you makes an attack, you can use your reaction to impose disadvantage on it. Creatures immune to being charmed are unaffected. You can use this feature on an individual creature only once every 24 hours.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Blinding Beauty" type="Archetype Feature" source="Fae Knight: Nymph" id="ID_G2_FKN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FAE_KNIGHT_BLINDING_BEAUTY">
            <description>
                <p>At 7th level, your beauty is such that it can blind. As an action, choose any creatures within 30 feet of you that can see you. They must make a Constitution saving throw. Creatures that fail are blinded for 1 minute. Affected creatures can repeat the saving throw at the end of their turns, ending the effect on a success.</p>
                <p class="indent">The DC of this feature and other features from this subclass is 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
                <div class="sidebar">
                    <h5 class="caption">Did you Know?</h5>
                    <p>The 2nd edition Monstrous Manual said, "If the nymph is nude or disrobes, an onlooker will die unless a saving throw versus spell is successful."</p>
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Short Rest">
                <description>Choose any creatures within 30 feet of you that can see you. They must make a Constitution saving throw (save DC {{blinding-beauty:save-dc}}). Creatures that fail are blinded for 1 minute. Affected creatures can repeat the saving throw at the end of their turns, ending the effect on a success.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="blinding-beauty:save-dc" value="8" />
                <stat name="blinding-beauty:save-dc" value="proficiency" />
                <stat name="blinding-beauty:save-dc" value="charisma:modifier" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Stunning Glance" type="Archetype Feature" source="Fae Knight: Nymph" id="ID_G2_FKN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FAE_KNIGHT_STUNNING_GLANCE">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 10th level, you can focus your intense beauty on a single creature. As an action, you can choose one creature within 30 feet of you that you can see and that can see you. It must make a Constitution saving throw. If it fails, it is stunned until the end of your next turn. You can target an individual creature with this feature only once every 24 hours.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>You can choose one creature within 30 feet of you that you can see and that can see you. It must make a Constitution saving throw (save DC {{blinding-beauty:save-dc}}). If it fails, it is stunned until the end of your next turn. You can target an individual creature with this feature only once every 24 hours.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Charm-Proof" type="Archetype Feature" source="Fae Knight: Nymph" id="ID_G2_FKN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FAE_KNIGHT_CHARM_PROOF">
            <description>
                <p>At 15th level, you have become so skilled at charming that other creatures’ wiles have no effect on you. You are immune to being charmed.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You are immune to being charmed.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Slaying Beauty" type="Archetype Feature" source="Fae Knight: Nymph" id="ID_G2_FKN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FAE_KNIGHT_SLAYING_BEAUTY">
            <description>
                <p>At 18th level, your beauty is such that it can kill. When a creature rolls a natural 1 on its saving throw against your Blinding Beauty or Stunning Glance features, it must make a Constitution saving throw. If it fails, it takes no damage, but falls unconscious for 1 hour or until a creature spends an action to wake it up or until it takes damage. However, if it fails the saving throw by more than 5, it instead immediately falls to 0 hit points. And, if it fails the saving throw by more than 10, it immediately dies.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When a creature rolls a natural 1 on its saving throw against your Blinding Beauty or Stunning Glance features, it must make a Constitution saving throw (save DC {{blinding-beauty:save-dc}}). If it fails, it takes no damage, but falls unconscious for 1 hour or until a creature spends an action to wake it up or until it takes damage. However, if it fails the saving throw by more than 5, it instead immediately falls to 0 hit points. And, if it fails the saving throw by more than 10, it immediately dies.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
    
</elements>