<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Yorviing’s Hidden Vault Weapons</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="items-weapons.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/yorviings-hidden-vault/items-weapons.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
	<element name="Vineheart" type="Magic Item" source="Yorviing’s Hidden Vault" id="ID_YORVIING_YHV_MAGIC_ITEM_GREATSWORD_VINEHEART">
        <!-- https://drive.google.com/file/d/1eirO5i5ocjSW4AkBuhr6ECJjq5CZlbHl/view -->
		<description>
            <p class="flavor">A lightweight yet massive blade, Vineheart is a sword whose cross guard hilt, and pommel are covered in a living weave of rose vines and thorns, which never burn, fade in color, or wilt. Whenever its edge strikes something solid the sent of rose petals lingers in the air for several minutes. Its handle is painful to touch to any not attuned to it, yet when one is attuned to Wneheart, they become accustomed to the prick of the thorns. It is said that this blade carries the name ofits original wielder; the paladin Syvereth Wneheart, Guardian of the Crimsonwood.</p>
            <p>You gain a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls you make with this magic weapon. When you hit with it, the target takes an extra 2d6 poison damage.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Mastery of Rose and Vine.</strong> You gain the following benefits while you are attuned to Vineheart:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>You can speak, read, and write Sylvan.</li>
                <li>You have resistance to poison damage and advantage on saving throws against being poisoned.</li>
                <li>You can cast <em>entangle</em> (save DC 17) centered on yourself by piercing the ground with the point of Vineheart. When you do so, the vines created by <em>entangle</em> are intermingled with brilliantly colored roses. When you cast this spell, you can designate any number of creatures you can see to be unaffected by it. Once you cast <em>entangle</em> in this way, this property of Vineheart can’t be used again until the next dawn.</li>
                <li>You cannot be disarmed of this weapon, as the vines wrap firmly around your hand and forearm.</li>
            </ul>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">sword</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="greatsword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">2</set>
			<set name="weapon">Greatsword</set>
			<set name="name-format">Vineheart</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
    
</elements>