<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Path of the Sacrifice Primal Path</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="barbarian-path-of-the-sacrifice.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/subclasses/barbarian/barbarian-path-of-the-sacrifice.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Path of the Sacrifice" type="Archetype" source="Genuine Fantasy Press" id="ID_GFP_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_PATH_OF_THE_SACRIFICE">
        <supports>Primal Path</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Everyone dies, but your death was written in the stars hemselves, ordained within the blood and entrails of a ying beast, and whispered of by the falling bones and huffling cards of the diviners. You are going to die, and our death is going to mean something. The rise of a great vil, or the end of an era. The destruction of all you hold ear, or the redemption of your blackened soul. The arrival f the legions of light, or the end of fear itself. In the end, ou’ll be dead – sacrificed as an offering to fate and slain y a prophecy that cannot be changed by wishes alone. You mbrace your fury in defiance of that prophecy, or to ensure hat it arrives as was written. You scream with rage because our life means more than just an ending. When the time omes, you will be waiting, bloodstained weapon in hand.</p>
            <h5>DESTINED END</h5>
            <p>Those who walk this path are rare, and for good reason, as heir deaths often come with catastrophic consequences. hen choosing this path, work with your group to create he prophecy that speaks of your death. Remember hat prophecies are often extremely vague, subject to isinterpretation, and can be self-fulfilling, or even entirely ntrue. For some, these supposed prophecies could be imply the ravings of a lunatic blessed with incredible luck nd martial skill, while for others these prophecies are the urest expressions of universal truth.</p>
            <h5>DETERMINE YOUR FATE</h5>
            <p>When creating a prophecy, there are several factors you hould consider. First, think about the end outcome. What s supposed to happen when you die? Consult the following able, or create an outcome of your own.</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d6</td><td>Upon My Death...</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>A star will shine no longer, and something shall stare out rom the void that remains.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>My homeland will soon burn and fall to ruin, destroyed y enemies from within and without.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>A heavenly host will know that the time has come to escend to punish the wicked and unrighteous.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>My weapon will shatter into six pieces, and a demon shall ater rise from each piece to wreak havoc.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>My sacrifice will inspire others to rise against an ppressor and overcome their vile rule.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>A gateway to paradise will open, but only one will be able o enter and enjoy an eternity of pleasure and indolence.</td></tr>
            </table>
            <h5>OMENS OF DOOM</h5>
            <p>When creating a prophecy, refrain from mentioning specific ates or times that it will come true, as these are unreliable. nstead, create omens and motifs that herald specific parts f the prophecy. For example, mentioning events that could e interpreted in a variety of ways, such as “When the raven ries” or “When the stars fall” is an excellent way to add rgency, tension, and confusion to a prophecy.</p>
            <div element="ID_GFP_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GRIM_PROPHECY" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LAMB_TO_THE_SLAUGHTER" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CRUEL_FATE" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RISE_AND_FALL" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BLOOD_FOR_BLOOD" />
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GRIM_PROPHECY" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LAMB_TO_THE_SLAUGHTER" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CRUEL_FATE" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RISE_AND_FALL" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BLOOD_FOR_BLOOD" level="14" />
            <select type="List" name="Determine Your Fate">
                <item id="1">A star will shine no longer, and something shall stare out rom the void that remains.</item>
                <item id="2">My homeland will soon burn and fall to ruin, destroyed y enemies from within and without.</item>
                <item id="3">A heavenly host will know that the time has come to escend to punish the wicked and unrighteous.</item>
                <item id="4">My weapon will shatter into six pieces, and a demon shall ater rise from each piece to wreak havoc.</item>
                <item id="5">My sacrifice will inspire others to rise against an ppressor and overcome their vile rule.</item>
                <item id="6">A gateway to paradise will open, but only one will be able o enter and enjoy an eternity of pleasure and indolence.</item>
            </select>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Grim Prophecy" type="Archetype Feature" source="Genuine Fantasy Press" id="ID_GFP_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GRIM_PROPHECY">
        <description>
            <p>At 3rd level, you discover or accept that your death is fated, but this knowledge gives you a certain insight. You can cast <em>augury</em> at will as an action without using a material component, relying on your prophetic destiny to guide you. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for this spell. You can’t cast this spell in this way more than once per minute.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Action" usage="At will">
            <description>You can cast augury without using a material component. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for this spell. You can’t cast this spell in this way more than once per minute.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AUGURY" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Lamb to the Slaughter" type="Archetype Feature" source="Genuine Fantasy Press" id="ID_GFP_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LAMB_TO_THE_SLAUGHTER">
        <description>
            <p>Also at 3rd level, your fate affords those that surround you a measure of protection. Once per turn when you take damage while raging, you can choose to grant a friendly creature that you can see within 30 feet of you other than yourself temporary hit points equal to half the damage you took. These temporary hit points last for one minute.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Once per turn when you take damage while raging, you can choose to grant a friendly creature that you can see within 30 feet of you other than yourself temporary hit points equal to half the damage you took. These temporary hit points last for one minute.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Cruel Fate" type="Archetype Feature" source="Genuine Fantasy Press" id="ID_GFP_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CRUEL_FATE">
        <description>
            <p>At 6th level, your death draws ever closer, but your skill grows in turn. If the <em>augury</em> spell would give you a random result, the result is Woe. Each time you cast <em>augury</em>, critically hit with an attack, or fail a death saving throw, you gain a defiance die, which is a d6. You can have up to two defiance dice at a time. Once per turn when you take damage from an attack, you can expend and roll one of your defiance dice, adding the roll to the damage result. When you do, you also add the same result to your next attack roll and damage roll.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>If the augury spell would give you a random result, the result is Woe. Each time you cast augury, critically hit with an attack, or fail a death saving throw, you gain a d6 defiance die, up to two at a time. Once per turn when you take damage from an attack, you can expend and roll one of your defiance dice, adding the roll to the damage result. When you do, you also add the same result to your next attack roll and damage roll.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Rise and Fall" type="Archetype Feature" source="Genuine Fantasy Press" id="ID_GFP_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RISE_AND_FALL">
        <description>
            <p>At 10th level, your destiny overpowers the lesser lives of others. When you have 0 hit points and a creature within 0 feet of you is reduced to 0 hit points, you can choose to expend and roll your defiance die to recover hit points equal to the result.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you have 0 hit points and a creature within 0 feet of you is reduced to 0 hit points, you can choose to expend and roll your defiance die to recover hit points equal to the result.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Blood for Blood" type="Archetype Feature" source="Genuine Fantasy Press" id="ID_GFP_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BLOOD_FOR_BLOOD">
        <description>
            <p>At 14th level, your destined death awaits your arrival, and you refuse to surrender before the end of your journey. Whenever you lose hit points while raging, you gain temporary hit points equal to half the amount of hit points you lost. These temporary hit points last until the start of our next turn.</p>
            <p class="indent">Whenever you are reduced to 0 hit points while you are raging, you can use your reaction to make a single melee weapon attack against a target within your reach. If this attack hits, it is a critical hit.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Whenever you lose hit points while raging, you gain temporary hit points equal to half the amount of hit points you lost. These temporary hit points last until the start of our next turn. Whenever you are reduced to 0 hit points while you are raging, you can use your reaction to make a single melee weapon attack against a target within your reach. If this attack hits, it is a critical hit.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
</elements>