<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Elegant Archer Roguish Archetype</name>
        <author url="https://www.reddit.com/user/J4DEhunter/">r/J4DEhunter</author>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="rogue-elegant-archer.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/subclasses/rogue/rogue-elegant-archer.xml" />
        </update>
        <!-- https://www.gmbinder.com/share/-Lya51XYtzFUu9cKQDH2 -->
    </info>
    
    <element name="Elegant Archer" type="Archetype" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_J4DEHUNTER_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_ROGUE_ELEGANT_ARCHER">
        <supports>Roguish Archetype</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You are a whisper in the night, the string of your bow makes nary a sound as you draw it to your cheek. You take your time with your breathing. In... out... in... out — loose. The fletching of your arrow nicks your cheek as it flies straight and true to embed itself in the throat of your target. You're gone without a sound. Fast, clean, deadly. These are the tennants of the Elegant Archer.</p>
            <div element="ID_J4DEHUNTER_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEGANT_ARCHER_THE_RIGHT_TOOLS" />
            <div element="ID_J4DEHUNTER_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEGANT_ARCHER_UNOBSTRUCTED_AIM" />
            <div element="ID_J4DEHUNTER_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEGANT_ARCHER_HINDERING_SHOT" />
            <div element="ID_J4DEHUNTER_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEGANT_ARCHER_NOCK_TWO" />
            <div element="ID_J4DEHUNTER_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEGANT_ARCHER_MEASURED_BREATHING" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_J4DEHUNTER_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEGANT_ARCHER_THE_RIGHT_TOOLS" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_J4DEHUNTER_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEGANT_ARCHER_UNOBSTRUCTED_AIM" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_J4DEHUNTER_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEGANT_ARCHER_HINDERING_SHOT" level="9" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_J4DEHUNTER_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEGANT_ARCHER_NOCK_TWO" level="13" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_J4DEHUNTER_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEGANT_ARCHER_MEASURED_BREATHING" level="17" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="The Right tools" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_J4DEHUNTER_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEGANT_ARCHER_THE_RIGHT_TOOLS">
            <description>
                <p>When you choose this archetype at 3rd level you must learn to keep your hands and breath steady so you can make even the most difficult shots, and you will need to be trained with the appropriate weaponry. You gain proficiency with longbows and with calligrapher's supplies.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_LONGBOW" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_CALLIGRAPHERS_SUPPLIES" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Unobstructed Aim" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_J4DEHUNTER_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEGANT_ARCHER_UNOBSTRUCTED_AIM">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 3rd level you gain an additional way to use your Sneak Attack; you don't need advantage on the attack roll to use your sneak attack against a creature if you are 30 or more feet away from it and you have no enemies adjacent to you.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You don't need advantage on the attack roll to use your sneak attack against a creature if you are 30 or more feet away from it and you have no enemies adjacent to you.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Hindering Shot" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_J4DEHUNTER_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEGANT_ARCHER_HINDERING_SHOT">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 9th level you may choose to forgoe damage for utility when you sneak attack a target. When you would deal Sneak Attack damage to a target you may choose to deal 2d6 less damage in order to aim for a specific body part and cause one of the following secondary effects:</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Arm.</em></strong> It's hard to fight with an arrow lodged in your bicep, the target has disadvantage on their next attack roll.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Leg.</em></strong> No one is moving very far with an arrow in their knee, the target's movement speed is halved until the end of their next turn.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Hand.</em></strong> An arrow to the knuckle will cause anyone to lose their grip. The target drops whatever they are holding in the hand you aimed for in their space.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You may choose to forgoe damage for utility when you sneak attack a target. When you would deal Sneak Attack damage to a target you may choose to deal 2d6 less damage in order to aim for a specific body part. Arm: target has disadvantage on their next attack roll. Leg: target's movement speed is halved until the end of their next turn. Hand: target drops whatever they are hold in the targeted hand.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Nock Two" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_J4DEHUNTER_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEGANT_ARCHER_NOCK_TWO">
            <description>
                <p>By 13th level you have become so confident with your weapon of choice that you can use it in more complex ways. You can nock and fire two arrows instead of one when you take the Attack action with a shortbow or a longbow. These attacks can be made against the same target or two different targets. If you could sneak attack both targets, you may choose to split your sneak attack dice between the two targets. For example, if you have 7d6 sneak attack dice you may choose to deal 4d6 to one target and 3d6 to the other, or 5d6 to one target and 2d6 to the other, or any other combination.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can nock and fire two arrows instead of one when you take the Attack action with a shortbow or a longbow. These attacks can be made against the same target or two different targets. If you could sneak attack both targets, you may choose to split your sneak attack dice between the two targets.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Measured Breathing" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_J4DEHUNTER_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEGANT_ARCHER_MEASURED_BREATHING">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 17th level you have become a master sniper. At a moments notice you can alter your breathing to steady your bow. As a bonus action on your turn, you may steady your breathing to give yourself advantage on all attack rolls you make with a shortbow or longbow until the end of your turn. You can use this feature a number of times equal to 1 + your Intelligence modifier. When you finish a long rest, you regain all expended uses. </p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="{{measured-breathing:uses}}/Long Rest">
                <description>You may steady your breathing to give yourself advantage on all attack rolls you make with a shortbow or longbow until the end of your turn.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="measured-breathing:uses" value="1" />
                <stat name="measured-breathing:uses" value="intelligence:modifier" />
            </rules>
        </element>
    
</elements>