<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Shadow Dancer Roguish Archetype</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="rogue-shadow-dancer.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/subclasses/rogue/rogue-shadow-dancer.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="The Shadow Dancer" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_AEVILOK_GM_BINDER_SOURCE_The Shadow Dancer">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation"></set>
            <set name="url">https://www.gmbinder.com/share/-LcVBDkyHrLNj2oHElOG</set>
            <set name="image">https://66.media.tumblr.com/730348685ef23465a1119ef37bfa0730/tumblr_nafqkcSjY31rjtyvjo1_1280.jpg</set>
            <set name="author" url="https://www.gmbinder.com/profile/aevilok">Aevilok</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20200318</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Shadow Dancer" type="Archetype" source="The Shadow Dancer" id="ID_AEVILOK_SHADOWDANCER_ARCHETYPE_ROGUE_SHADOW_DANCER">
        <supports>Roguish Archetype</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Rogues who learn the techniques of Shadow Dancing make for formidable foes. Disappearing seemingly at will and wielding supernatural powers to manipulate shadows around them, they make perfect spies when the task is too difficult for a common scoundrel. A Shadow Dancer’s minions usually set up the stage by terrifying their victims, as the Dancer closes in for the kill.</p>
            <div element="ID_AEVILOK_SHADOWDANCER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOW_DANCER_RAISE_SHADE" />
            <div element="ID_AEVILOK_SHADOWDANCER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOW_DANCER_UMBRAL_SIGHT" />
            <div element="ID_AEVILOK_SHADOWDANCER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOW_DANCER_EXPLOIT_FEAR" />
            <div element="ID_AEVILOK_SHADOWDANCER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOW_DANCER_UNEARTHLY_DODGE" />
            <div element="ID_AEVILOK_SHADOWDANCER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOW_DANCER_WALK_THROUGH_SHADOWS" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AEVILOK_SHADOWDANCER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOW_DANCER_RAISE_SHADE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AEVILOK_SHADOWDANCER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOW_DANCER_UMBRAL_SIGHT" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AEVILOK_SHADOWDANCER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOW_DANCER_EXPLOIT_FEAR" level="9" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AEVILOK_SHADOWDANCER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOW_DANCER_UNEARTHLY_DODGE" level="13" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AEVILOK_SHADOWDANCER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOW_DANCER_WALK_THROUGH_SHADOWS" level="17" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Raise Shade" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Shadow Dancer" id="ID_AEVILOK_SHADOWDANCER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOW_DANCER_RAISE_SHADE">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 3rd level, you can manipulate your own shadow, employing it in exploration and battle alike.</p>
                <p class="indent">As an action, you can cause your shadow to materialize, and become a Shade under your control. The Shade has immunity to all except radiant damage, has 1 hitpoint and an AC of 10 and uses your skill modifiers. It has the same speed as you and can move during your turn but takes no actions or reactions without your command. It is incorporeal and does not hinder the movement of creatures that pass through it.</p>
                <p class="indent">As a bonus action on your turn, you can mentally command one Shade within 120 feet of you under your control to use its reaction and take one of the following actions:</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong>Change Form.</strong> The Shade changes shape according to your will but its size remains the same.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong>Hide.</strong> The Shade takes the Hide action.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong>Shadow replacement.</strong> You and a Shade that is within 20 feet of you teleport to each other’s location.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong>Shapes in the dark.</strong> Target a creature that is within 10 ft of the Shade. The Shade changes form, resembling the silhouette of the target’s worst fears and forces them to make a saving throw. On a failure, the target is frightened of the Shade until the end of your next turn. The DC for this saving throw is equal to 8 + your Charisma modifier + your proficiency bonus. A target that can’t see the Shade immediately succeeds in this saving throw.</p>
                <p class="indent">After a Shade spawned this way dies, you can not summon another for the next minute. You do not cast a shadow while you control a Shade and you can freely dismiss any number of Shades on your turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>You can cause your shadow to materialize, and become a Shade under your control. As a bonus action on your turn, you can mentally command one Shade within 120 feet of you under your control to use its reaction and take one of the following actions: Change Form, Hide, Shadow replacement, or Shapes in the Dark.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Umbral Sight" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Shadow Dancer" id="ID_AEVILOK_SHADOWDANCER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOW_DANCER_UMBRAL_SIGHT">
            <description>
                <p>At 3rd level, your affiliation with the shadows allows you to see through them. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness, both magical and nonmagical, as if it were dim light. Your connection to the Shadowfell affects this darkvision; everything you see is in a shade of indigo.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness, both magical and nonmagical, as if it were dim light. Your connection to the Shadowfell affects this darkvision; everything you see is in a shade of indigo.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Exploit Fear" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Shadow Dancer" id="ID_AEVILOK_SHADOWDANCER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOW_DANCER_EXPLOIT_FEAR">
            <description>
                <p>At 9th level, you have learned how to turn fear into paranoia.</p>
                <p class="indent">As a reaction to seeing a creature suffer the frightened condition, you can enchant them, letting fear overcome their senses and making them paranoid. A paranoid creature is deafened, perceives anything beyond a 10ft radius from it as magical darkness and attacks against it have advantage. This effect persists for as long as the target remains frightened.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Reaction">
                <description>As a reaction to seeing a creature suffer the frightened condition, you can enchant them, letting fear overcome their senses and making them paranoid. A paranoid creature is deafened, perceives anything beyond a 10ft radius from it as magical darkness and attacks against it have advantage. This effect persists for as long as the target remains frightened.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Unearthly Dodge" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Shadow Dancer" id="ID_AEVILOK_SHADOWDANCER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOW_DANCER_UNEARTHLY_DODGE">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 13th level, while in dim light or darkness, immediately after using your Uncanny Dodge, you can teleport up to 10 feet away from your attacker leaving a Shade in your place. The Shade tries to frighten your attacker, taking the Shapes In The Dark action and targeting your attacker.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can have a maximum number of Shades equal to 1 + your Charisma modifier (minimum 1) at all times and can freely dissipate any number of Shades on your turn. If you exceed this maximum, the oldest Shade immediately dissipates.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>While in dim light or darkness, immediately after using your Uncanny Dodge, you can teleport up to 10 feet away from your attacker leaving a Shade in your place. The Shade tries to frighten your attacker, taking the Shapes In The Dark action and targeting your attacker. You can have up to {{raise-shade:count}} shades at a time.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="raise-shade:count" value="1" />
                <stat name="raise-shade:count" value="charisma:modifier" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Walk Through Shadows" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Shadow Dancer" id="ID_AEVILOK_SHADOWDANCER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOW_DANCER_WALK_THROUGH_SHADOWS">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 17th level, your affiliation with shadows allows you to briefly merge with one.</p>
                <p class="indent">Choose a creature you can see that casts a shadow and is unaware of you or frightened, within 60 feet. As an action, you are teleported to a demiplane where you can sense everything your host can. You can stay in that demiplane for up to 8 hours, after which you appear 5 feet behind your host. You can end this effect early as a bonus action. While in the demiplane, a creature with truesight, or one that can see into the ethereal plane sees a spectral version of you standing behind the creature.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t do so again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Short Rest">
                <description>Choose a creature you can see that casts a shadow and is unaware of you or frightened, within 60 feet. You teleport to a demiplane where you can sense everything your host can. You can stay in that demiplane for up to 8 hours, after which you appear 5 feet behind your host. You can end this effect early as a bonus action. While in the demiplane, a creature with truesight, or one that can see into the ethereal plane sees a spectral version of you standing behind the creature.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

</elements>