<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Mage Slayer Roguish Archetype</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="rogue-mage-slayer.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/subclasses/rogue/rogue-mage-slayer.xml" />
        </update>
        <url>https://homebrewery.naturalcrit.com/share/HkhUpg1oH</url>
    </info>

    <element name="Mage Slayer" type="Archetype" source="Homebrewery" id="ID_HOMEBREWERY_ARCHETYPE_ROGUE_MAGE_SLAYER">
        <supports>Roguish Archetype</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Trained in the arcane arts, a mage slayer targets those that abuse their talents. Their tactics involve disrupting spells that a caster might attempt to use, or restraining the spell slinger to prevent somatic components. Often times, a mage slayer is called upon from nobility to disable another warring kingdom’s source of magic.</p>
            <div element="ID_HOMEBREWERY_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MAGE_SLAYER_BONUS_PROFICIENCY" />
            <div element="ID_HOMEBREWERY_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MAGE_SLAYER_ARCANE_DISARMING" />
            <div element="ID_HOMEBREWERY_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MAGE_SLAYER_FOCUSED_SHOT" />
            <div element="ID_HOMEBREWERY_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MAGE_SLAYER_UNWAVERING_OBJECTIVE" />
            <div element="ID_HOMEBREWERY_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MAGE_SLAYER_ENHANCED_REFLEXES" />
            <div element="ID_HOMEBREWERY_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MAGE_SLAYER_QUICK_FIRE" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_HOMEBREWERY_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MAGE_SLAYER_BONUS_PROFICIENCY" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_HOMEBREWERY_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MAGE_SLAYER_ARCANE_DISARMING" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_HOMEBREWERY_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MAGE_SLAYER_FOCUSED_SHOT" level="9" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_HOMEBREWERY_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MAGE_SLAYER_UNWAVERING_OBJECTIVE" level="9" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_HOMEBREWERY_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MAGE_SLAYER_ENHANCED_REFLEXES" level="13" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_HOMEBREWERY_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MAGE_SLAYER_QUICK_FIRE" level="17" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Bonus Proficiency" type="Archetype Feature" source="Homebrewery" id="ID_HOMEBREWERY_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MAGE_SLAYER_BONUS_PROFICIENCY">
            <description>
            <p>When you take this archetype at 3rd level, you gain proficiency in the Intelligence (Arcana) skill if you are not already proficient.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ARCANA" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Arcane Disarming" type="Archetype Feature" source="Homebrewery" id="ID_HOMEBREWERY_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MAGE_SLAYER_ARCANE_DISARMING">
            <description>
            <p>Also at 3rd level, you have insight on how spellcasters protect their valuables. Whenever you make a successful Intelligence (Investigation) or Intelligence (Arcana) check on a magical trap or lock, you learn the following - the school of magic that radiates from the object, the spell level, and the effective range that will cause harm.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Whenever you make a successful Investigation or Arcana check on a magical trap or lock, you learn the  school of magic that radiates from the object, the spell level, and the effective range that will cause harm.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Focused Shot" type="Archetype Feature" source="Homebrewery" id="ID_HOMEBREWERY_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MAGE_SLAYER_FOCUSED_SHOT">
            <description>
            <p>At 9th level, you can target the focus of a spellcaster and disrupt their concentration. When you make a melee or ranged attack on a target and have the benefits of a sneak attack, you can opt to remove the spellcasting focus out of their hand. If the attack hits, the spellcasting focus falls to the ground in front of the caster, and the concentration on their spell ends.</p>
            <p class="indent">The target does not take any damage from this attack. You may only use this feature once per round, and must use your sneak attack feature.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Sneak Attack">
                <description>When you make a melee or ranged attack on a target and have the benefits of a sneak attack, you can opt to remove the spellcasting focus out of their hand. If the attack hits, the spellcasting focus falls to the ground in front of the caster, and the concentration on their spell ends. The target does not take any damage from this attack. You may only use this feature once per round, and must use your sneak attack feature.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Unwavering Objective" type="Archetype Feature" source="Homebrewery" id="ID_HOMEBREWERY_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MAGE_SLAYER_UNWAVERING_OBJECTIVE">
            <description>
            <p>Also at 9th level, you can navigate areas that who make others lost. You cannot be lost by magical means, as long as you know the target location you are traveling towards.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You cannot be lost by magical means, as long as you know the target location you are traveling towards.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Enhanced Reflexes" type="Archetype Feature" source="Homebrewery" id="ID_HOMEBREWERY_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MAGE_SLAYER_ENHANCED_REFLEXES">
            <description>
            <p>At 13th level, you can tell when a deadly blast of magical energy will occur, and how to resist it. Whenever you are forced to make a saving throw against a spell, you may use your reaction to instead make an Intelligence or Wisdom saving throw instead.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Reaction">
                <description>Whenever you are forced to make a saving throw against a spell, you may use your reaction to instead make an Intelligence or Wisdom saving throw instead.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Quick Fire" type="Archetype Feature" source="Homebrewery" id="ID_HOMEBREWERY_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MAGE_SLAYER_QUICK_FIRE">
            <description>
            <p>Finally at 17th level, you can time yourself to disable more than one foe. Whenever you use your Attack action for the Focused Shot feature, you can use your bonus action to make one additional attack.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Whenever you use your Attack action for the Focused Shot feature, you can use your bonus action to make one additional attack.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

</elements>