<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Path of the Blighted Primal Path</name>
        <author url="http://guidetohomebrew.blogspot.com/">Jonoman3000</author>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="barbarian-path-of-the-blighted.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/sprouting-chaos-players-companion/barbarian-path-of-the-blighted.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Path of the Blighted" type="Archetype" source="Sprouting Chaos Player’s Companion" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_SCPC_ARCHETYPE_BARBARIAN_PATH_OF_THE_BLIGHTED">
        <supports>Primal Path</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The Path of the Blighted is a path of unholy origin, traced back to the same origin of the Blights: the Gulthias Tree. By gaining power from this evil source, you can channel your rage to shift your physical form, becoming a monstrous abomination of vines and branches. While transformed, you engulf and constrict your enemies as you tear them apart.</p>
            <p class="indent"></p>
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_SCPC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATH_OF_THE_BLIGHTED_BLIGHTED_TRANSFORMATION" />
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_SCPC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATH_OF_THE_BLIGHTED_FALSE_APPEARANCE" />
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_SCPC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATH_OF_THE_BLIGHTED_UNNATURAL_GROWTH" />
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_SCPC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATH_OF_THE_BLIGHTED_REACTIVE_TENDRILS" />
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_SCPC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATH_OF_THE_BLIGHTED_BLIGHTED_TRANSFORMATION" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_SCPC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATH_OF_THE_BLIGHTED_FALSE_APPEARANCE" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_SCPC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATH_OF_THE_BLIGHTED_UNNATURAL_GROWTH" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_SCPC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATH_OF_THE_BLIGHTED_REACTIVE_TENDRILS" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Blighted Transformation" type="Archetype Feature" source="Sprouting Chaos Player’s Companion" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_SCPC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATH_OF_THE_BLIGHTED_BLIGHTED_TRANSFORMATION">
            <description>
                <p>Starting when you choose this path at 3rd level, you become a blighted monster when you rage. For the duration of your rage, when you hit a creature with a weapon attack on your turn, you can use a bonus action to attempt to grapple the target with blighted vines that sprout out of your body. This grapple does not require a free hand, but otherwise follows all of the rules for grappling. You can have 1 creature grappled with this feature at a time.</p>
                <p class="indent">If you already have a creature grappled with this feature, this bonus action instead constricts the target, causing them to take bludgeoning damage equal to half your barbarian level, rounded up.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>For the duration of your rage, when you hit a creature with a weapon attack on your turn, you can use a bonus action to attempt to grapple the target with blighted vines that sprout out of your body. This grapple does not require a free hand, but otherwise follows all of the rules for grappling. You can have 1 creature grappled with this feature at a time. If you already have a creature grappled with this feature, this bonus action instead constricts the target, causing them to take {{level:barbarian:half}} points bludgeoning damage.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="False Appearance" type="Archetype Feature" source="Sprouting Chaos Player’s Companion" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_SCPC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATH_OF_THE_BLIGHTED_FALSE_APPEARANCE">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 6th level, your body is now able to become temporarily plantlike to hide from foes. As an action, you can camouflage yourself against the surface of a plant, such as the bark of a tree, a large bush, or an area of thick vines. When you do so, you make a Dexterity (Stealth) check with advantage, remaining camouflaged until you move or take an action.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>You can camouflage yourself against the surface of a plant, such as the bark of a tree, a large bush, or an area of thick vines. When you do so, you make a Dexterity (Stealth) check with advantage, remaining camouflaged until you move or take an action.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Unnatural Growth" type="Archetype Feature" source="Sprouting Chaos Player’s Companion" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_SCPC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATH_OF_THE_BLIGHTED_UNNATURAL_GROWTH">
            <description>
                <p>At 10th level, you can cast the <em>plant growth</em> spell once with this feature, and you regain the ability to cast it this way once you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You can cast plant growth.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PLANT_GROWTH" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Reactive Tendrils" type="Archetype Feature" source="Sprouting Chaos Player’s Companion" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_SCPC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PATH_OF_THE_BLIGHTED_REACTIVE_TENDRILS">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 14th level, whenever you take damage from a creature within 5 feet of you while you’re raging, you can use your reaction to release grasping vines at the attacker, attempting to grapple the target. This grapple does not require a free hand, and you can have 1 creature grappled with this feature at a time.</p>
                <p class="indent">If you use your Blighted Transformation feature to constrict a creature you’re grappling, you deal damage to both the creature you’re grappling with Blighted Transformation as well as the creature you’re grappling with Reactive Tendrils.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Reaction">
                <description>Whenever you take damage from a creature within 5 feet of you while you’re raging, you can use your reaction to release grasping vines at the attacker, attempting to grapple the target. This grapple does not require a free hand, and you can have 1 creature grappled with this feature at a time. If you use your Blighted Transformation feature to constrict a creature you’re grappling, you deal damage to both the creature you’re grappling with Blighted Transformation as well as the creature you’re grappling with Reactive Tendrils.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
    
</elements>