<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Bard College of the Ancients</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="bard-college-of-the-ancients.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/sprouting-chaos-players-companion/bard-college-of-the-ancients.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="College of the Ancients" type="Archetype" source="Sprouting Chaos Player’s Companion" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_SCPC_ARCHETYPE_BARD_COLLEGE_OF_THE_ANCIENTS">
        <supports>Bard College</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Bards of the College of the Ancients have deep knowledge in the area of nature magic, and they often wander the wilderness, collecting knowledge on the magic of the earth. They are most often wandering singers and skalds, traveling through ancient forests and long abandoned roads, often singing to nobody at all. They wish, first and foremost, to protect and honor nature. They tell tales of great floods and good harvests, tremendous storms and frightening gales. They learn to be one with nature.</p>
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_SCPC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_THE_ANCIENTS_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" />
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_SCPC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_THE_ANCIENTS_WORDS_OF_THE_ANCIENTS" />
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_SCPC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_THE_ANCIENTS_HAND_OF_THE_ANCIENTS" />
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_SCPC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_THE_ANCIENTS_SONG_OF_AWAKENING" />
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_SCPC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_THE_ANCIENTS_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_SCPC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_THE_ANCIENTS_WORDS_OF_THE_ANCIENTS" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_SCPC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_THE_ANCIENTS_HAND_OF_THE_ANCIENTS" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_SCPC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_THE_ANCIENTS_SONG_OF_AWAKENING" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Bonus Proficiencies" type="Archetype Feature" source="Sprouting Chaos Player’s Companion" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_SCPC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_THE_ANCIENTS_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES">
            <description>
                <p>When you join the College of the Ancients at 3rd level, you gain proficiency with medium armor, shields, and the Nature skill.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_MEDIUM_ARMOR" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_SHIELDS" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_NATURE" />
            </rules>
        </element>    
        <element name="Words of the Ancients" type="Archetype Feature" source="Sprouting Chaos Player’s Companion" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_SCPC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_THE_ANCIENTS_WORDS_OF_THE_ANCIENTS">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 3rd level, you learn how to command plants to sprout up and grasp at the heels of your foes, impeding their movement.</p>
                <p class="indent">When a creature that you can see within 60 feet of you begins moving, you can use your reaction to expend one of your uses of Bardic Inspiration, rolling a Bardic Inspiration die and reducing the creature’s speed by a number of feet equal to the number rolled x 5 until the end of their turn. This cannot reduce a creature’s speed below 5 feet.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Reaction">
                <description>When a creature that you can see within 60 feet of you begins moving, you can expend one of your uses of Bardic Inspiration, rolling a Bardic Inspiration die and reducing the creature’s speed by a number of feet equal to the number rolled x 5 until the end of their turn. This cannot reduce a creature’s speed below 5 feet.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>    
        <element name="Hand of the Ancients" type="Archetype Feature" source="Sprouting Chaos Player’s Companion" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_SCPC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_THE_ANCIENTS_HAND_OF_THE_ANCIENTS">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 6th level, you can cast gaea’s hand at will, without expending a spell slot or material components.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="At will">
                <description>You can cast gaea’s hand, without expending a spell slot or material components.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_SCPC_SPELL_GAEAS_HAND" />
            </rules>
        </element>    
        <element name="Song of Awakening" type="Archetype Feature" source="Sprouting Chaos Player’s Companion" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_SCPC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_THE_ANCIENTS_SONG_OF_AWAKENING">
            <description>
                <p>At 14th level, you learn an ancient melody that can awaken a small non-magical shrub. While standing next to a shrub, you may sing for 1 minute and roll a Bardic Inspiration die, awakening the shrub and adding the number rolled as temporary hit points for the creature, which uses the statistics for the awakened shrub. The shrub remains awakened and under your command until you complete a long rest, at which point it returns to being a normal plant.</p>
                <p class="indent">As a bonus action on your turn, you can command any shrubs awakened with this feature to move and use their actions. Additionally, whenever you cast a spell, an awakened shrub can deliver the spell as if it had cast the spell. The shrub must be within 60 feet of you, and it must use its reaction to deliver the spell when you cast it. If the spell requires an attack roll, you use your attack modifier for the roll.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>While standing next to a shrub, you may sing for 1 minute and roll a Bardic Inspiration die, awakening the shrub and adding the number rolled as temporary hit points for the creature, which uses the statistics for the awakened shrub. The shrub remains awakened and under your command until you complete a long rest, at which point it returns to being a normal plant. As a bonus action on your turn, you can command any shrubs awakened with this feature to move and use their actions. Additionally, whenever you cast a spell, an awakened shrub can deliver the spell as if it had cast the spell. The shrub must be within 60 feet of you, and it must use its reaction to deliver the spell when you cast it. If the spell requires an attack roll, you use your attack modifier for the roll.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>    
</elements>