<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Circle of the Seedling Druid Circle</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="druid-circle-of-the-seedling.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/sprouting-chaos-players-companion/druid-circle-of-the-seedling.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Circle of the Seedling" type="Archetype" source="Sprouting Chaos Player’s Companion" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_SCPC_ARCHETYPE_DRUID_CIRCLE_OF_THE_SEEDLING">
        <supports>Druid Circle</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Druids of the Circle of the Seedling delve more completely into the ancient rituals and hidden knowledge of plant magic. These druids meet together in their Plant Wild Shape, sharing their wisdom and arcane secrets with each other in Druidic, while appearing to just be a small bunch of shrubs and trees. As a member of this circle, your magic allows you to be one with your surroundings, gaining intricate control over the plants around you.</p>
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_SCPC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_SEEDLING_PLANT_WILDSHAPE" />
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_SCPC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_SEEDLING_PLANTSPEAKER" />
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_SCPC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_SEEDLING_TAKE_ROOT" />
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_SCPC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_SEEDLING_GUARDIAN_OF_THE_FOREST" />
            <div element="ID_JONOMAN3000_SCPC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_SEEDLING_ONE_WITH_NATURE" />
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_SCPC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_SEEDLING_PLANT_WILDSHAPE" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_SCPC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_SEEDLING_PLANTSPEAKER" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_SCPC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_SEEDLING_TAKE_ROOT" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_SCPC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_SEEDLING_GUARDIAN_OF_THE_FOREST" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_SCPC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_SEEDLING_ONE_WITH_NATURE" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Plant Wildshape" type="Archetype Feature" source="Sprouting Chaos Player’s Companion" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_SCPC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_SEEDLING_PLANT_WILDSHAPE">
            <description>
                <p>When you choose this circle at 2nd level, you gain the ability to use Wild Shape to assume the shape of a plant creature.</p>
                <p class="indent">When you transform into a plant creature, the Max CR that you can transform into is increased to 1. Starting at 6th level, you can transform into a Plant with a challenge rating as high as your druid level divided by 3, rounded down.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Wild Shape">
                <description>You can use Wild Shape to assume the shape of a plant creature. You can transform into a plant creature with a Max CR of 1.</description>
                <description level="6">You can use Wild Shape to assume the shape of a plant creature. you can transform into a Plant with a Max CR as high as your druid level divided by 3, rounded down.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Plantspeaker" type="Archetype Feature" source="Sprouting Chaos Player’s Companion" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_SCPC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_SEEDLING_PLANTSPEAKER">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 2nd level, when you are transformed into a plant creature you gain the ability to command nearby mundane plants. As an action, you can turn difficult terrain caused by plant growth into ordinary terrain in a 5 foot radius centered on you, or you can turn ordinary terrain where plants are present into difficult terrain in a 5 foot radius centered on you. After a 10 minute duration, the plants return to their original condition.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, while you are transformed into a plant creature you ignore difficult terrain caused by plants.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>When you are transformed into a plant creature you gain the ability to command nearby mundane plants. You can turn difficult terrain caused by plant growth into ordinary terrain in a 5 foot radius centered on you, or you can turn ordinary terrain where plants are present into difficult terrain in a 5 foot radius centered on you. Additionally, while you are transformed into a plant creature you ignore difficult terrain caused by plants.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Take Root" type="Archetype Feature" source="Sprouting Chaos Player’s Companion" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_SCPC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_SEEDLING_TAKE_ROOT">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 6th level, you gain the ability to root yourself in the ground while in your normal form, forming a protective armor of bark around yourself. As an action on your turn, you can root yourself in the ground, reducing your speed to 0 and granting you advantage on checks made to avoid being moved.</p>
                <p class="indent">Until you end this effect by using your bonus action or fall unconscious, you have resistance to slashing, bludgeoning and piercing damage from non-magical weapons.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>You can root yourself in the ground, reducing your speed to 0 and granting you advantage on checks made to avoid being moved. Until you end this effect by using your bonus action or fall unconscious, you have resistance to slashing, bludgeoning and piercing damage from non-magical weapons.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Guardian of the Forest" type="Archetype Feature" source="Sprouting Chaos Player’s Companion" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_SCPC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_SEEDLING_GUARDIAN_OF_THE_FOREST">
            <description>
                <p>At 10th level, you can expend two uses of Wild Shape at the same time to transform into a Unicorn. Once you use this feature, you cannot use it again until you have completed a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You can expend two uses of Wild Shape at the same time to transform into a Unicorn.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="One with Nature" type="Archetype Feature" source="Sprouting Chaos Player’s Companion" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_SCPC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_SEEDLING_ONE_WITH_NATURE">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 14th level, you gain the ability to cast <em>barkskin</em> and <em>speak with plants</em> at will, without expending a spell slot or material components.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can cast barkskin and speak with plants at will, without expending a spell slot or material components.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BARKSKIN" prepared="true" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_PLANTS" prepared="true" />
            </rules>
        </element>
</elements>