<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Vegepygmy Race</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="race-vegepygmy.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/sprouting-chaos-players-companion/race-vegepygmy.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Vegepygmy" type="Race" source="Sprouting Chaos Player’s Companion" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_SCPC_RACE_VEGEPYGMY">
        <description>
            <p>Vegepygmies, also called mold folk or moldies, are fungus creatures that live in simple tribal units, hunting for sustenance and spreading the spores from which they reproduce. Spawned by a unique mold called russet mold, Vegepygmies infest forests, caverns, and ruins where this strange mold grows. Reddish brown in color, russet mold grows only in places that are dark, warm, and wet. This in turn means that Vegepygmy settlements are also in these same conditions.</p>
            <p class="indent">No one knows for sure where russet mold came from. One historical account tells of adventurers in a forbidding mountain range discovering russet mold and vegepygmies in a peculiar metal dungeon full of strange life. Another story says that explorers found russet mold in a crater left by a falling star, with vegepygmies infesting the dense jungle nearby.</p>
            <h4>PRIMITIVE PLANTS</h4>
            <p>Vegepygmies are most commonly found underground or in dense forests where little sunlight penetrates. A vegepygmy instinctively feels kinship with other plant and fungus creatures, and thus vegepygmy tribes coexist well with creatures such as myconids, shriekers, and violet fungi.</p>
            <p class="indent">Although they prefer to eat fresh meat, bone, and blood, vegepygmies can absorb nutrients from soil and many sorts of organic matter, meaning that they rarely go hungry. All vegepygmies can hiss and make other noises by forcing air through their mouth, but only a select few can speak in a conventional sense. Those that can often become tribal leaders, and they may even interact and speak with the other races. Among themselves, vegepygmies communicate by hissing, gestures, and rhythmic tapping on the body. Vegepygmies build and craft little; any gear they have is acquired from other creatures or built by copying simple construction they have witnessed.</p>
            <h4>MOLD BEGETS MOLD</h4>
            <p>Vegepygmies originate from the remains left behind when a humanoid or a giant is killed by russet mold. One or more vegepygmies emerge from the corpse a day later. If a beast such as a dog or a bear dies from russet mold, the result is a bestial moldie called a thorny instead of a humanoid-shaped vegepygmy.</p>
            <p class="indent">Thornies are less intelligent than vegepygmies, but have greater size and ferocity, as well as a thorn-covered body. Vegepygmies often keep them as pets, utilizing them as “guard dogs.”</p>
            <h4>VEGEPYGMY NAMES</h4>
            <p>Vegepygmies don’t generally have names, and the ones that do have names don’t follow any specific naming convention. Their names are generally just short, single-syllable sounds that are easy to remember.</p>
            <h4>VEGEPYGMY TRAITS</h4>
            <p>As a Vegepygmy, you have the following traits:</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong> Your Dexterity score increases by 2, and your Constitution score increases by 1.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Age.</em></strong> Vegepygmies are short-lived beings that are born fully grown. While most don’t live long enough to see old age, those that do end up dying after about 30 years.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Alignment.</em></strong> Vegepygmies are simple creature that don’t tend towards good nor evil; lawful nor chaotic. They are most often true neutral.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Size.</em></strong> Vegepygmies average at about 3 feet in height and they weigh about 40 pounds. Your size is Small.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Speed.</em></strong> Your base walking speed is 30 feet.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Darkvision.</em></strong> Accustomed to life in the dark conditions that russet mold prefers, you have superior vision in dark and dim conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can’t discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Grounded.</em></strong> You have resistance to lightning damage.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Perceptive.</em></strong> You have proficiency in the Perception skill.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Plant Camouflage.</em></strong> When standing still, you have advantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks you make while obscured by plants.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Regeneration.</em></strong> At the start of each of your turns, you regain 1 hit point if you have taken damage since the end of your last turn. This feature has no effect when you are unconscious.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Languages.</em></strong> You can speak, read, and write Common and Vegepygmy.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <setters>
            <set name="names" type="male"></set>
            <set name="names" type="female"></set>
            <set name="names" type="clan">not used</set>
            <set name="names-format">{{name}}</set>
            <set name="height" modifier="2d6">2’6"</set>
            <set name="weight" modifier="1d4">30 lb.</set>
        </setters>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_SCPC_RACIAL_TRAIT_VEGEPYGMY_DARKVISION" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_SCPC_RACIAL_TRAIT_VEGEPYGMY_GROUNDED" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_SCPC_RACIAL_TRAIT_VEGEPYGMY_PERCEPTIVE" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_SCPC_RACIAL_TRAIT_VEGEPYGMY_PLANT_CAMOUFLAGE" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_SCPC_RACIAL_TRAIT_VEGEPYGMY_REGENERATION" />
            <stat name="dexterity" value="2" />
            <stat name="constitution" value="1" />
            <grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_SMALL" />
            <stat name="innate speed" value="30" bonus="base" />
            <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON" />
            <grant type="Language" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_SCPC_LANGUAGE_VEGYPYGMY" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Darkvision" type="Racial Trait" source="Sprouting Chaos Player’s Companion" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_SCPC_RACIAL_TRAIT_VEGEPYGMY_DARKVISION">
            <description>
                <p>Accustomed to life in the dark conditions that russet mold prefers, you have superior vision in dark and dim conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can’t discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_DARKVISION" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Grounded" type="Racial Trait" source="Sprouting Chaos Player’s Companion" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_SCPC_RACIAL_TRAIT_VEGEPYGMY_GROUNDED">
            <description>
                <p>You have resistance to lightning damage.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_LIGHTNING" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Perceptive" type="Racial Trait" source="Sprouting Chaos Player’s Companion" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_SCPC_RACIAL_TRAIT_VEGEPYGMY_PERCEPTIVE">
            <description>
                <p>You have proficiency in the Perception skill.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Plant Camouflage" type="Racial Trait" source="Sprouting Chaos Player’s Companion" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_SCPC_RACIAL_TRAIT_VEGEPYGMY_PLANT_CAMOUFLAGE">
            <description>
                <p>When standing still, you have advantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks you make while obscured by plants.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When standing still, you have advantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks you make while obscured by plants.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Regeneration" type="Racial Trait" source="Sprouting Chaos Player’s Companion" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_SCPC_RACIAL_TRAIT_VEGEPYGMY_REGENERATION">
            <description>
                <p>At the start of each of your turns, you regain 1 hit point if you have taken damage since the end of your last turn. This feature has no effect when you are unconscious.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>At the start of each of your turns, you regain 1 hit point if you have taken damage since the end of your last turn. This feature has no effect when you are unconscious.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

        <element name="Vegepygmy" type="Language" source="Sprouting Chaos Player’s Guide" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_SCPC_LANGUAGE_VEGYPYGMY">
            <description>
                <p>Typically spoken by vegepygmies.</p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="exotic">true</set>
                <set name="speakers">Vegepygmy</set>
                <set name="script"></set>
            </setters>
        </element>
</elements>