<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Blazing Dawn Player’s Companion Spells</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="spells.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/blazing-dawn-players-companion/spells.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Aegis" type="Spell" source="Blazing Dawn Player’s Companion" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_BDPC_SPELL_AEGIS">
        <supports>Artificer, Cleric, Paladin, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You touch a nonmagical suit of armor. Until the spell ends, that suit of armor becomes a magical suit of armor that grants a +1 bonus to its wearer’s AC. Also, for the duration the wearer has resistance to damage from spells.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 6th level or higher, the AC bonus increases to +2. When you use a spell slot of 8th level or higher, the AC bonus increases to +3.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">4</set>
            <set name="school">transmutation</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 hour</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Ambrosia" type="Spell" source="Blazing Dawn Player’s Companion" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_BDPC_SPELL_AMBROSIA">
        <supports>Cleric, Paladin</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You spend the casting time speaking a prayer, and then touch the three glass bottles used as this spell’s material component. Each of the bottles become filled with a sweet, aromatic liquid that glows with divine magic. When the spell ends, this liquid instantly evaporates if it was not consumed.</p>
            <p class="indent">As an action, a creature can drink a bottle of ambrosia or administer it to another creature. The creature is cured of any disease or poison afflicting it, and for the next hour it is rendered immune to disease, poison damage, and the poisoned condition, For the same duration, it has advantage on Constitution saving throws. Also, the ambrosia provides enough nourishment (both food and drink) to sustain a creature for 1 day.</p>
            <p class="indent">Consistently drinking ambrosia can confer longevity upon those that consume it. A creature that drinks ambrosia every day for 30 days begins to reap this benefit. As long as the creature continues to drink ambrosia every day, it ages at half the normal rate. If the creature ever misses a day, it must drink for another 30 days before its aging begins to slow down again.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 6th level or higher, 1 additional bottles-worth of ambrosia is conjured for each slot level above 5th. Additional glass bottles must be provided for each additional bottles-worth of ambrosia.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">5</set>
            <set name="school">conjuration</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 minute</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">three fine glass bottles, worth at least 5 gp each</set>
            <set name="duration">8 hours</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Angel Wings" type="Spell" source="Blazing Dawn Player’s Companion" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_BDPC_SPELL_ANGEL_WINGS">
        <supports>Cleric</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You point your finger, and the creature that would’ve been reduced to 0 hit points instead drops to 1 hit point, and then regains additional hit points equal to your spellcasting ability modifier (minimum 1). The creature is also bestowed with large, angelic wings that allow it to immediately use its reaction to fly up to 30 feet without provoking opportunity attacks. The wings disappear at the end of the turn, causing the creature to fall if it ended the turn in the air.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 6th level or higher, the healing increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 5th.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">5</set>
            <set name="school">conjuration</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 reaction, which you take when a creature within 60 feet of you that you can see would be reduced to 0 hit points but not killed outright.</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Arsenal of Flame" type="Spell" source="Blazing Dawn Player’s Companion" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_BDPC_SPELL_ARSENAL_OF_FLAME">
        <supports>Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You cause an array of flaming, spectral weaponry to spark into existence, and begin to assault your foes. Choose up to six creatures you can see within range. For each creature you target, you conjure a flaming weapon in an unoccupied space within 5 feet of the target. Each weapon then makes a melee spell attack against its target using your spell attack modifier, dealing 6d6 fire damage on a hit.</p>
            <p class="indent">At the start of each of your turns, each weapon attempts to move up to 30 feet closer to its target if the target is outside of its 5-foot reach, and then repeats its attack if it successfully reached its target. Also, if a weapon’s target leaves its 5-foot reach, the weapon can make an opportunity attack against the target, following the regular rules for opportunity attacks. Each weapon can only make one opportunity attack per round.</p>
            <p class="indent">If a weapon’s target dies, that weapon dissipates into ash.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 8th level or higher, you can target two additional creatures for each slot level above 7th.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">7</set>
            <set name="school">conjuration</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 10 minutes</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Bind Spirit" type="Spell" source="Blazing Dawn Player’s Companion" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_BDPC_SPELL_BIND_SPIRIT">
        <supports>Cleric</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You touch the piece of jewelry that serves as the material component for this spell to a creature that has died within the last hour. If the creature’s soul is willing, it becomes bound to that piece of jewelry for the duration.</p>
            <p class="indent">While the soul is bound in this way, it can telepathically communicate with any creature that wears the jewelry it is bound to, and that creature can telepathically communicate to it as well.</p>
            <p class="indent">The spell ends if the jewelry is destroyed, if the bound creature is returned to life, or if this spell is cast again on the same creature and the creature chooses to leave to the new jewelry.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">necromancy</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a golden ring, bracelet, or necklace inlaid with a ruby, worth at least 200 gp in total</set>
            <set name="duration">10 days</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Boil" type="Spell" source="Blazing Dawn Player’s Companion" id="ID_JONOMAN3000_BDPC_SPELL_BOIL">
        <supports>Druid, Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You cause the area of a 40-foot cube within range to instantly increase in temperature. This temperature increase lasts for the duration. When the area appears, each creature in it must make a Constitution saving throw. A creature takes 3d6 fire damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. A creature must also make this saving throw when it enters the spell's area for the first time on a turn or ends its turn there.</p>
            <p class="indent">This spell has additional effects when overlapping with areas of water. Being underwater does not confer resistance against the fire damage dealt by this spell. Also, any underwater areas within the spell’s area start bubbling furiously, turning those areas into difficult terrain and causing them to be heavily obscured.</p>
            <p class="indent">Above water, however, this spell can be difficult to see. A creature that starts its turn within 60 feet of the area and can see the area must make a Wisdom (Perception) check to notice the heat haze caused by this spell, and therefore notice the spell’s effect. The DC for this check equals your spell save DC.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 3rd.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">transmutation</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">90 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
</elements>