<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>KibblesTasty’s Psion Class 1.5</name>
        <update version="0.0.6">
            <file name="class-psion.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/kibblestasty/psion/class-psion.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Psion" type="Class" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_PSION">
        <description>
            <p>A large orc is flung across the room, smashing through tables and chairs before hitting the wall with a thunderous crash, collapsing dazed. A human, her eyes still glowingwith unearthly power, tosses a few extra coins on the bar. "Sorry for themess. If he wakes up, tell him to try picking on someone his own size next time".</p>
            <p class="indent">The prisoner’s expression turns from defiant to puzzled as the interrogator asks no questions, merely stares at them silently. His puzzled expression turns worried as he finds himself, unbidden, recalling where he stashed the loot. "Under the stables behind the Rusty Hook Inn" the interrogator finally speaks, as the thief’s expression becomes terrified.</p>
            <p class="indent">"Ain’t you... cold or somethin’?" the dwarf asks the elf as they trudge through the snow, eying her simple robe and bare feet. "I just think ’warm’" the elf replies with a distracted air. The dwarf snorts, a puff of chilled air. Typical elf nonsense. Except... they haven’t frozen to death yet. "Say... could you think some ’warm’ this way?" the dwarf asks hopefully. To the dwarfs surprise, the chill of the snow fades away completely "that’s downright creepy... hey don’t stop now! Was jus’ sayin’ it was creepy."</p>
            <p class="indent">Psions are those who have tapped into a special otherworldly force, with the ability to actualize the power of their mind to accomplish impossible feats. Reading minds, lifting vast weights, and transcending physical limitations, they tend to inspire awe and terror in equal measure.</p>
            <p class="indent">The exact nature of what is Psionic power might be a question answered in your setting, or it might not be. Most view Psionic power as coming from within, though other answers exist - anything from the leaking power of the Far Realm, to an alternate way to express magic, to an actualization of an individuals will upon the world.</p>
            <h4>POWERFUL MINDS</h4>
            <p>Since a psion’s weapon is their mind, they are always a careless thought away from harming those around them. For a psion, the line between thinking and doing can be very thin, forcing them to keep their thoughts and emotions in check, lest their powers run amok. This leads to many of them developing odd behaviors or mannerisms to help them control their state of mind, frequently seeming quite eccentric to an outside observer.</p>
            <p class="indent">Consider how your psion keeps their powers in check, and how much their power bleeds into their everyday life. How reading minds may effect their body language or habits. Do they add wood to the campfire from the comfort of their bedroll, or do they restrain themselves from using their power for trivial matters lest they slip up?</p>
            <h4>MISUNDERSTOOD POWER</h4>
            <p>In a world of widespread magic, many will assume a Psion to be a type of Sorcerer or Wizard, mistaking their powers for the common applications of magic. The common villager keeps only one mental category for the supernatural and creepy people that bend reality their will. But even among magic users, a Psion’s powers will frequently be found unnerving.</p>
            <p class="indent">It is often those who do understand magic that find a Psion’s abilities the most aberrant. A force that intersects the magical weave rather than obeys it, the nature of the power that the psion wields one can only contemplate with unease.</p>
            <h4>CREATING A PSION</h4>
            <p>When creating a Psion, consider your character’s background. How did you become a Psion? Were you born with latent powers? Or did something happen to you granting your powers? Or did you intentionally train yourself through rigorous mental exercise to leverage them? Consider how developing a rare and mysterious power would have affected your interactions with people.</p>
            <p class="indent">Consider what your purpose is with your newfound powers, or how you plan to use your powers. Do you intend to be taken for a Wizard casting magic, or are you freely open about being of a... different nature?</p>
            <h5>QUICK BUILD</h5>
            <p>You can make a Psion quickly by following these suggestions. First, make Intelligence your highest ability score, followed by Dexterity or Constitution. Second, choose the Acolyte, Far Traveler or Hermit background.</p>
            <h2>CLASS FEATURES</h2>
            <p>As a psion, you gain the following class features.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">HIT POINTS</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Hit Dice:</strong> 1d6 per psion level</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at 1st Level:</strong> 6 + your Constitution modifier</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at Higher Levels:</strong> 1d6 (or 5) + your Constitution modifier per lowercaseclassname level after 1st</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">PROFICIENCIES</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled mb">
                <li><strong>Armor:</strong> Light armor.</li>
                <li><strong>Weapons:</strong> Simple weapons.</li>
                <li><strong>Tools:</strong> None.</li>
            </ul>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Saving Throws:</strong> Wisdom, Intelligence</li>
                <li><strong>Skills:</strong> Choose two from Deception, History, Insight, Intimidation, Investigation, Medicine, Perception, or Religion.</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">EQUIPMENT</h5>
            <p>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>(a) a quarterstaff or (b) a dagger</li>
                <li>(a) leather armor</li>
                <li>(a) a scholar’s pack or (b) an explorer’s pack</li>
            </ul>
			<h5 class="caption">THE PSION</h5>
            <table class="class-features">
                <thead>
                    <tr><th class="col-5">Level</th><th>Proficiency Bonus</th><th class="left">Features</th><th>Psi Points</th><th>Psi Limit</th><th>Psionic Talents</th></tr>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                    <tr><td>1st</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Psionic Archetype, Psionics</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>--</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>2nd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Psionic Talents</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>2</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Secondary Discipline, Psionic Archetype Feature</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>2</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>4th</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>4</td><td>2</td><td>2</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Psionic Mastery</td><td>5</td><td>3</td><td>3</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>6th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Psionic Archetype Feature</td><td>6</td><td>3</td><td>3</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>7th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">─</td><td>7</td><td>4</td><td>4</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>8th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>8</td><td>4</td><td>4</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">─</td><td>9</td><td>5</td><td>5</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>10th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Psionic Archetype Feature</td><td>10</td><td>5</td><td>5</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>11th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Innate Psionic Ability (6th level)</td><td>11</td><td>6</td><td>5</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>12th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>12</td><td>6</td><td>6</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>13th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Innate Psionic Ability (7th level)</td><td>13</td><td>7</td><td>6</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>14th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Psionic Archetype Feature</td><td>14</td><td>7</td><td>6</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>15th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Innate Psionic Ability (8th level)</td><td>15</td><td>8</td><td>7</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>16th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>16</td><td>8</td><td>7</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>17th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Innate Psionic Ability (9th level)</td><td>17</td><td>9</td><td>7</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>18th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Third Discipline</td><td>18</td><td>9</td><td>8</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>19th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>19</td><td>10</td><td>8</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>20th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Ascension</td><td>20</td><td>10</td><td>8</td></tr>
                </tbody>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PSIONIC_ARCHETYPE" />
            <div element="ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PSIONICS" />
            <div element="ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PSIONIC_TALENTS" />
            <div element="ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_SECOND_DISCIPLINE" />
            <div element="ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" />
            <div element="ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PSIONIC_MASTERY" />
            <div element="ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_INNATE_PSIONICS" />
            <div element="ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_THIRD_DISCIPLINE" />
            <div element="ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_ASCENSION" />
            <h2>MULTICLASSING</h2>
            <p>Should you want to multiclass into Psion, the prerequisites and proficiencies are listed below:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>Prerequisite: 13 Intelligence</li>
                <li>Proficiencies gained: Psionics</li>
            </ul>
            <p class="indent">Psionic powers can be weird, strange, and rare. Your DM may place additional restrictions or requirements into multiclassing into Psionic classes.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="hd">d6</set>
            <set name="short">A master of the power of the mind.</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" requirements="!ID_KT_PSION_MULTICLASS_PSION" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" requirements="!ID_KT_PSION_MULTICLASS_PSION" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_WISDOM" requirements="!ID_KT_PSION_MULTICLASS_PSION" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_INTELLIGENCE" requirements="!ID_KT_PSION_MULTICLASS_PSION" />
            <grant type="Proficency" id="ID_KT_PSION_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PSIONICS" />
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency, Psion" number="2" supports="Skill,Kibbles Psion" requirements="!ID_KT_PSION_MULTICLASS_PSION" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PSIONIC_ARCHETYPE" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PSIONICS" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PSIONIC_TALENTS" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_SECOND_DISCIPLINE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" level="4" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PSIONIC_MASTERY" level="5" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_INNATE_PSIONICS" level="11" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_THIRD_DISCIPLINE" level="18" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_ASCENSION" level="20" />
        </rules>
        <multiclass id="ID_KT_PSION_MULTICLASS_PSION">
            <prerequisite>Intelligence 13</prerequisite>
            <requirements>[int:13]</requirements>
            <setters>
                <set name="multiclass proficiencies">Psionics</set>
            </setters>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS" />
            </rules>
        </multiclass>
    </element>
        <element name="Psionic Archetype" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PSIONIC_ARCHETYPE">
            <description>
                <p>At 1st level, you pick the archetype of Psion you embody, choosing from Awakened, Unleashed, Transcended, or Shaper, each of which are are detailed at the end of the class description. Your choice grants you features at 1st level, and again at 3rd, 6th, 10th, and 14th level.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Archetype" name="Psionic Archetype" supports="Kibbles Psionic Archetype" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Psionics" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PSIONICS">
            <description>
                <h5>PSIONIC DISCIPLINES</h5>
                <p>You are granted access to a psionic discipline (such as Telepathy or Telekinesis) by your chosen archetype. A psionic discipline comes with a passive feature that expands your character’s capabilities and an active psionic power that can be modified and empowered with Psi Points. Additionally you can use your discipline in more detailed applications to recreate the effect of certain spells, listed at the end of the discipline description. At 3rd level you can select a second discipline, and 18th level you can select a 3rd discipline.</p>
                <p class="indent">Psionic powers are suppressed by anti-magic fields and can be dispelled with <em>dispel magic</em>, but are only affected by <em>counterspell</em> if recreating the effect of a spell. Any check required to dispel magic, counterspell or identify a spell being cast with Psionics is made at disadvantage unless the caster also has the Psionics feature. The spell <em>detect magic</em> will detect the usage of psionics, but not their nature - it will show up as a mysterious untyped power, even if being used to generate the effect of a spell.</p>
                <p class="indent">When recreating a spell through a Psionic effect (using a Psionic discipline to cast the spell) the spell has no Material or Verbal components, but always requires Somatic components and causes the Psion to vibrantly glow with the otherworldly psionic energies they are controlling.</p>
                <h5>PSI POINTS</h5>
                <p class="indent">Starting at 1st level, you gain access to Psi Points used to fuel psionic discipline powers and effects. You have a number of Psi Points equal to your Psion level, and regain all spent points after completing a short or long rest. You can spend a number of Psi Points equal to half your Psion level (rounded up) at a time (for example, at level 5, you can spend 3 psi points on psionic power or cast a spell with cost of 3 psi points).</p>
                <h5>PSIONIC ABILITY</h5>
                <p class="indent">Psionic powers, psionic talents, and spells gained through this class use your Psionic ability.</p>
                <center>
                    <li><strong>Psionic Ability save DC</strong> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier</li>
                    <li><strong>Psionic Ability attack modifier</strong> = your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier</li>
                </center>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="{{psi:points}} Psi Points/Short Rest">
                <description>You can expend up to {{psi:limit}} Psi Points at one time.</description>
            </sheet>
            <spellcasting name="Psion" ability="Intelligence" prepare="false">
                <list>Kibbles Psion</list>
            </spellcasting>
            <rules>
                <stat name="psi:points" value="level:psion" />
                <stat name="psi:limit" value="level:psion:half:up" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Psionic Talents" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PSIONIC_TALENTS">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 2nd level, you gain access to a Psionic Talent allowing you to further specialize. Pick two talents from the list of Psionic talents presented at the end of the class description. You can pick a new Psionic talent at 5th, 7th, 9th, 12th, 15th, and 18th level. When you level up, you can replace a Psionic talent you have previously selected with a different option.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Psionic Talent" number="2" supports="Kibbles Psionic Talent" level="2" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Psionic Talent" supports="Kibbles Psionic Talent" level="5" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Psionic Talent" supports="Kibbles Psionic Talent" level="7" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Psionic Talent" supports="Kibbles Psionic Talent" level="9" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Psionic Talent" supports="Kibbles Psionic Talent" level="12" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Psionic Talent" supports="Kibbles Psionic Talent" level="15" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Psionic Talent" supports="Kibbles Psionic Talent" level="18" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Second Discipline" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_SECOND_DISCIPLINE">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 3rd level, you can select a second Psionic Discipline from the list of Psionic Disciplines. You cannot select a Discipline you already know. You gain all features of a Psionic Discipline when selecting it.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Second Discipline" supports="Kibbles Psionic Discipline" level="3" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Ability Score Improvement" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Psion 4)" supports="Improvement Option,Psion,4" level="4" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Psion 8)" supports="Improvement Option,Psion,8" level="8" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Psion 12)" supports="Improvement Option,Psion,12" level="12" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Psion 16)" supports="Improvement Option,Psion,16" level="16" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Psion 19)" supports="Improvement Option,Psion,19" level="19" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Psionic Mastery" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_PSIONIC_MASTERY">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 5th level, you gain mastery of your psionic powers. At the start of your turn you get 1 free Psi Point. This can be spent to empower Psionic Disciplines, but not to recreate spells or fuel Psionic Talents. If you have any unspent free Psi Points left at the end of your turn, then they are lost.</p>
                <p class="indent">At 11th level, this is increased to 2 free Psi points, and at 17th level, this is increased to 3. Points can be split between different abilities.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>At the start of your turn you get 1 free Psi Point. This can be spent to empower Psionic Disciplines, but not to recreate spells or fuel Psionic Talents. If you have any unspent free Psi Points left at the end of your turn, then they are lost.</description>
                <description level="11">At the start of your turn you get 2 free Psi Points. This can be spent to empower Psionic Disciplines, but not to recreate spells or fuel Psionic Talents. If you have any unspent free Psi Points left at the end of your turn, then they are lost.</description>
                <description level="17">At the start of your turn you get 3 free Psi Points. This can be spent to empower Psionic Disciplines, but not to recreate spells or fuel Psionic Talents. If you have any unspent free Psi Points left at the end of your turn, then they are lost.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Innate Psionics" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_INNATE_PSIONICS">
            <description>
                <p>At 11th level, you gain the ability to exert great feats of psionic power. Choose one 6th-level spell from the Psion spell list as an innate ability. You can use this innate ability to cast this spell once. You must finish a long rest before you can do so again. At higher level, you gain more innate abilities of your choice that can be used in this way: one 7th level spell at 13th level, one 8th level spell at 15th level, and one 9th-level spell at 17th level. You regain all uses of your Innate Psionics when you finish a long rest.</p>
                <p class="indent">Innate Psionics are well beyond the normal scope of your powers and are not restricted by what disciplines you have. Unlike psionic disciplines, they require any component the spell requires.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1 each/Long Rest">
                <description>You can use your innate ability to cast your 6th level Psion spell once.</description>
                <description level="13">You can use your innate ability to cast each of your 6th, and 7th level Psion spells once.</description>
                <description level="15">You can use your innate ability to cast each of your 6th, 7th, and 8th level Psion spells once.</description>
                <description level="17">You can use your innate ability to cast each of your 6th, 7th, 8th, and 9th level Psion spells once.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Third Discipline" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_THIRD_DISCIPLINE">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 18th level, you can select a third Psionic Discipline from the list of Psionic Disciplines. You cannot select a Discipline you already know. You gain all features of a Psionic Discipline when selecting it.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Third Discipline" supports="Kibbles Psionic Discipline" level="18" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Ascension" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_ASCENSION">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 20th level, if you die you can choose to become a incorporeal entity on the ethereal plane at the spot you died in the material plane at the start of your next turn. This entity has the physical ability scores (Strength, Dexterity, Constitution) and abilities of a Ghost, but has your mental ability scores (Intelligence, Wisdom, Charimsa) and your Psion class abilities.</p>
                <p class="indent">When you take this form your current and maximum hit points becomes that of the ghost. While you are in the form, if you have less than 10 psi points, have 10 psi points. While in this form you cannot rest to regain spent abilities. If you exhaust all Psi Points or the ghost is destroyed, you die as a normal creature would.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>If you die you can choose to become a incorporeal entity on the ethereal plane at the spot you died in the material plane at the start of your next turn, becoming a ghost. While you are in the form, if you have less than 10 psi points, have 10 psi points. While in this form you cannot rest to regain spent abilities. If you exhaust all Psi Points or the ghost is destroyed, you die as a normal creature would.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

  <!-- Psionic Archetypes -->
    <element name="Awakened Mind" type="Archetype" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_PSION_AWAKENED_MIND">
        <supports>Kibbles Psionic Archetype</supports>
        <description>
            <p>An Awakened Mind is a Psion who had their psionic power awakened within them by an encounter, event, or circumstance. Perhaps their powers were latent or perhaps their destiny had been that of a normal creature until powers were suddenly thrust on them. Perhaps they brushed the Far Realm in a vivid dream, perhaps they wandered the Feywild and came back warped, perhaps they merely glimpsed the eyes of creature that did not belong walking down the street.</p>
            <p class="indent">An awakening is often somewhat traumatic. Psions are not well understood and the first power they manifest - telepathy - is one of the most feared and shunned abilities, often viewed for its rather creepy potential.</p>
            <p class="indent">An Awakened can be either empathetic or cruel, good or evil. Knowing what is on the minds of others affects people in different ways, driving some away from society as they see its true face, while others feel drawn to help the problems only they can see.</p>
            <div element="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AWAKENED_OPENED_MIND" />
            <div element="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AWAKENED_MENTAL_AWARENESS" />
            <div element="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AWAKENED_MIND_READER" />
            <div element="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AWAKENED_EMPOWERED_PSIONICS" />
            <div element="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AWAKENED_ALL_SEEING_EYE" />
            <div element="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AWAKENED_FULL_AWAKENING" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AWAKENED_OPENED_MIND" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AWAKENED_MENTAL_AWARENESS" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AWAKENED_MIND_READER" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AWAKENED_EMPOWERED_PSIONICS" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AWAKENED_ALL_SEEING_EYE" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AWAKENED_FULL_AWAKENING" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Opened Mind" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AWAKENED_OPENED_MIND">
            <description>
                <p>At 1st level when you select this Archetype, your mind awakens the ability to directly connect to the minds of other creatures, granting the psionic discipline of Telepathy.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE_TELEPATHY_DISCIPLINE" level="1" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Mental Awareness" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AWAKENED_MENTAL_AWARENESS">
            <description>
                <p>Additionally starting at 1st level, you can use Intelligence instead of Wisdom when making an Insight check against a creature with an Intelligence ability score of 6 or higher.</p>
                <p class="indent">Further, if you have telepathically communicated with a willing creature, you know their general location (direction and rough estimate of distance) for the next hour as long as you are on the same plane as them.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can use Intelligence instead of Wisdom when making an Insight check against a creature with an Intelligence ability score of 6 or higher. Further, once you have telepathically communicated with an allied creature, you know their location for next hour  as long as you are on the same plane as them.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Mind Reader" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AWAKENED_MIND_READER">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 3rd level, when you use Telepathic intrusion, you can force the target to make an Intelligence saving throw instead of a Wisdom saving throw against the power (deciding when you use the ability).</p>
                <p class="indent">When a creature fails a saving throw against your Telepathic Intrusion, you gain a d4. Until the end of your next turn, if you make an attack roll against the creature or the creature makes a saving throw against a Psionic power other than Telepathic Intrusion against you, you can add or subtract the d6 from the roll (deciding to roll before you roll the attack or use the power).</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>When you use Telepathic intrusion, you can force the target to make an Intelligence saving throw instead of a Wisdom saving throw against the power (deciding when you use the ability). When a creature fails a saving throw against your Telepathic Intrusion, you gain a d4. Until the end of your next turn, if you make an attack roll against the creature or the creature makes a saving throw against a Psionic power other than Telepathic Intrusion against you, you can add or subtract the d6 from the roll (deciding to roll before you roll the attack or use the power).</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Empowered Psionics" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AWAKENED_EMPOWERED_PSIONICS">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 6th level, when you deal damage with a Psionic Discipline power you can add your Intelligence modifier to the damage dealt.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you deal damage with a psionic discipline you can add {{intelligence:modifier}} to the damage.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="All Seeing Eye" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AWAKENED_ALL_SEEING_EYE">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 10th level, you can see a creature by its mind. You gain a mindsight of 60 feet, allowing you to see creatures with an Intelligence of 6 or higher within range as if by blindsight. A creature you are unaware of can still be hidden from you, but you can use your Intelligence modifier instead of your Wisdom modifier with making Perception checks to detect creatures.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You gain mindsight with a range of 60 feet, but it only sees creatures with an intelligence of 6 or higher. A creature you are unaware of can still be hidden from you, but you can use your Intelligence modifier instead of your Wisdom modifier with making Perception checks to detect creatures.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Full Awakening" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AWAKENED_FULL_AWAKENING">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 14th level, you can briefly fully awaken your expanded mind to true comprehension. As a bonus action, you can expend 2 Psi Points to gain advantage on all saving throws and attack rolls until the start of your next turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="2 Psi Points">
                <description>You can expend 2 Psi Points to gain advantage on all saving throws and attack rolls until the start of your next turn.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    <element name="Unleashed Mind" type="Archetype" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_PSION_UNLEASHED_MIND">
        <supports>Kibbles Psionic Archetype</supports>
        <description>
            <p>An Unleashed Mind Psion’s power is most often an innate force they struggle to understand or control, a reflection of their state of mind and mood projected onto the world around them, often to devastating results. The life of an Unleashed Psion is frequently their journey to control their unruly powers... or one of embracing the destructive powers they grant fully.</p>
            <p class="indent">What the wellspring of their innate power is varies - they could be a psionic race, born under the influence of distant twisted powers, warped by fey blood, or a herald of something more sinister brushing against the material world. Sometimes their power will show itself in simple applications, but most often their power becomes known and feared when their temper flares.</p>
            <p class="indent">Their alignment frequently depends on the approach to their powers they have taken, an Unleashed Psion who emphasizes control and restraint, keeping their emotions from running wild and their powers from running rampant will most often be lawful, following strict personal codes. On the other hand, an Unleashed Psion who lets their power run rampant will almost always be chaotic in nature, acting on impulse... with great emphasis.</p>
            <div element="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNLEASHED_UNSHACKLED_POWER" />
            <div element="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNLEASHED_OVERWHELMING_POWER" />
            <div element="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNLEASHED_RAMPAGING_POWER" />
            <div element="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNLEASHED_EMPOWERED_PSIONICS" />
            <div element="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNLEASHED_UNCONTROLLABLE_MIND" />
            <div element="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNLEASHED_UNSTOPPABLE_RAMPAGE" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNLEASHED_UNSHACKLED_POWER" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNLEASHED_OVERWHELMING_POWER" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNLEASHED_RAMPAGING_POWER" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNLEASHED_EMPOWERED_PSIONICS" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNLEASHED_UNCONTROLLABLE_MIND" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNLEASHED_UNSTOPPABLE_RAMPAGE" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Unshackled Power" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNLEASHED_UNSHACKLED_POWER">
            <description>
                <p>At 1st level when you select this Archetype, you gain the ability to unleash your mind to physically interact with the world around you, granting you the psionic discipline Telekinesis.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE_TELEKINESIS_DISCIPLINE" level="1" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Overwhelming Power" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNLEASHED_OVERWHELMING_POWER">
            <description>
                <p>Additionally at 1st level, you gain the ability to cast <i>thaumaturgy</i> with your psionic powers. When you cast in this way, you have an additional option:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>You cause up to 10 pounds of loose objects within 10 feet of you to start floating for 1 minute.</li>
                    <li>You can force all targets within 5 feet to make a Strength saving throw, or be pushed by 5 feet away from you.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you cast thaumaturgy using your psionic powers, you can also cause up to 10 pounds of loose objects within 10 feet of you to start floating for 1 minute, or you can force all targets within 5 feet to make a Strength saving throw, or be pushed by 5 feet away from you.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_THAUMATURGY" spellcasting="Psion" known="true" allowReplace="false" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Rampaging Power" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNLEASHED_RAMPAGING_POWER">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 3rd level, you gain a d4 rampage die. Once per turn during your turn when you make a damage roll, you can add this rampage die to the damage roll. If you dealt damage during your last turn, your rampage die becomes a d6, increasing with each subsequent turn you deal damage by one step, up to a d12; if you did not deal damage during your last turn or become incapacitated, it becomes a d4 once more. If a maintain a continuous d12 rampage die for more than one minute, you gain a level of exhaustion.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You gain a d4 rampage die. Once per turn during your turn when you make a damage roll, you can add this rampage die to the damage roll. If you dealt damage during your last turn, your rampage die increases one step each turn, up to a d12; if you did not deal damage during your last turn or become incapacitated, it decreases. If a maintain a continuous d12 rampage die for more than one minute, you gain a level of exhaustion.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Empowered Psionics" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNLEASHED_EMPOWERED_PSIONICS">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 6th level, when you deal damage with a psionic discipline you can add your Intelligence modifier to one damage roll of that power.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you deal damage with a psionic discipline you can add {{intelligence:modifier}} to one damage roll of that power.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Uncontrollable Mind" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNLEASHED_UNCONTROLLABLE_MIND">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 10th level, the strength of your rampaging mind is such that others’ attempts to control it are futile. You gain immunity to charm, fear, and effects that would control your mind while your rampage die is a d8 or more.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You gain immunity to charm, fear, and effects that would control your mind while your rampage die is a d8 or more.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Unstoppable Rampage" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNLEASHED_UNSTOPPABLE_RAMPAGE">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 14th level, when an attack reduces you to zero hit points, you can roll your rampage die. If your roll + your Constitution modifier is higher than the excess damage you took, you are instead reduced to one hit point. You can expend 2 psi points to roll an additional rampage die, adding it to the result.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="2 Psi Points">
                <description>Starting at 14th level, when an attack reduces you to 0 hit points, you can roll your rampage die. If your roll + {{constitution:modifier}} is higher than the excess damage you took, you are instead reduced to 1 hit point. You can expend 2 psi points to roll an additional rampage die, adding it to the result.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    <element name="Transcended Mind" type="Archetype" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_PSION_TRANSCENDED_MIND">
        <supports>Kibbles Psionic Archetype</supports>
        <description>
            <p>A Transcended Psion is most often one that has found their path to psionic powers through a mental epiphany, realizing the place of their mind within the multiverse and how it ties to everything else, seeing the keys and levers to the world laid out before them in their mind’s eye.</p>
            <p class="indent">Most often achieved either intentionally or accidentally through meditation and ritual, this can sometimes even be a passed on technique to reliably transcended the strictly material concerns, and explore the more cognitive realm and powers within.</p>
            <p class="indent">Transcended Psions tend to have the best grasp on their powers in control and principle, having come to understanding of the greater cosmos, but lack the reckless abandon some other Psions may have. Unfortunately less transcendent minds frequently cannot understand the greater truths they have learned and may view a Transcended Psion as a bit... peculiar.</p>
            <div element="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRANSCENDED_ENLIGHTENED" />
            <div element="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRANSCENDED_STATE_OF_MIND" />
            <div element="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRANSCENDED_BALANCE_OF_POWER" />
            <div element="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRANSCENDED_PERFECTED_ENHANCEMENT" />
            <div element="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRANSCENDED_MENTAL_CONTROL" />
            <div element="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRANSCENDED_MIND_OVER_MATTER" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRANSCENDED_ENLIGHTENED" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRANSCENDED_STATE_OF_MIND" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRANSCENDED_BALANCE_OF_POWER" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRANSCENDED_PERFECTED_ENHANCEMENT" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRANSCENDED_MENTAL_CONTROL" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRANSCENDED_MIND_OVER_MATTER" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Enlightened" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRANSCENDED_ENLIGHTENED">
            <description>
                <p>At 1st level when you select this Archetype, you gain the ability to empower your body with the power of your mind, granting you the psionic discipline of Enhancement.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE_ENHANCEMENT_DISCIPLINE" level="1" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="State of Mind" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRANSCENDED_STATE_OF_MIND">
            <description>
                <p>Additionally at 1st level, you can ignore the effects of extreme heat or cold, hold your breath twice as long as normal, and can go twice as long without eating or sleeping before suffering exhaustion.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can ignore the effects of extreme heat or cold, hold your breath twice as long as normal, and can go twice as long without eating or sleeping before suffering exhaustion.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Balance of Power" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRANSCENDED_BALANCE_OF_POWER">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 3rd level, when you use a psionic ability (power or spell) to restore hit points or grant temporary hit points, you can add the hit points granted to a stored pool. The maximum value of the pool is your psion level, and any points beyond the maximum are lost. The next time you make a damage roll, you can expend the pool to add damage equal to the stored value to one target effected by the damage roll. This stored damage is lost if not spent within 1 minute.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you use a psionic ability (power or spell) to restore hit points or grant temporary hit points, you can add the hit points granted to a stored pool, to a maximum of {{level:psion}} and any points beyond the maximum are lost. The next time you make a damage roll, you can expend the pool to add damage equal to the stored value to one target effected by the damage roll. This stored damage is lost if not spent within 1 minute.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Perfected Enhancement" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRANSCENDED_PERFECTED_ENHANCEMENT">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 6th level, when you grant temporary hit points with a psionic power you can add your proficiency bonus to the temporary hit points gained by one creature.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Starting at 6th level, when you grant temporary hit points with a psionic power you can {{proficiency}} to the temporary hit points gained by one creature.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Mental Control" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRANSCENDED_MENTAL_CONTROL">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 10th level, when you have to make a Constitution saving throw to avoid losing concentration on an effect from a psionic discipline, you can add your Intelligence modifier to the saving throw.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you have to make a Constitution saving throw to avoid losing concentration on an effect from a psionic discipline, you can add {{intelligence:modifier}} to the saving throw.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Mind Over Matter" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRANSCENDED_MIND_OVER_MATTER">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 14th level, when you roll a Strength, Dexterity, or Constitution saving throw, you can expend 2 Psi Points to roll an Intelligence saving throw instead.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, when you roll a Death Saving throw, you can expend 4 Psi Points to roll a 20.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you roll a Strength, Dexterity, or Constitution saving throw, you can expend 2 Psi Points to roll an Intelligence saving throw instead. Additionally, when you roll a Death Saving throw, you can expend 4 Psi Points to roll a 20.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    <element name="Shaper’s Mind" type="Archetype" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_PSION_SHAPERS_MIND">
        <supports>Kibbles Psionic Archetype</supports>
        <description>
            <p>A Shaper is a Psion that specializes in the materialization of their imagination, projecting it out into the world. No mere conjurers borrowing the powers of other planes, a Shaper manifests things from nothing but their own mind, weaving their creations into existence through the exertion of raw psionic power and imagination.</p>
            <p class="indent">A Shaper’s mind is tool of nearly unrivaled power possessing both boundless creativity and inexorable will, but if that will is overrun, the world would do well to fear a Shaper’s nightmares.</p>
            <div element="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHAPER_CREATORS_MIND" />
            <div element="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHAPER_BOUNDLESS_IMAGINATION" />
            <div element="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHAPER_ASTRAL_METASTABILITY" />
            <div element="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHAPER_EMPOWERED_CONSTRUCT" />
            <div element="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHAPER_ASTRAL_GUARDIAN" />
            <div element="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHAPER_IMAGINARY_ARMY" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHAPER_CREATORS_MIND" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHAPER_BOUNDLESS_IMAGINATION" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHAPER_ASTRAL_METASTABILITY" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHAPER_EMPOWERED_CONSTRUCT" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHAPER_ASTRAL_GUARDIAN" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHAPER_IMAGINARY_ARMY" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Creator’s Mind" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHAPER_CREATORS_MIND">
            <description>
                <p>At 1st level when you select this Archetype, you gain the ability to will contents of your mind into the world, granting you the psionic discipline Projection.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE_PROJECTION_DISCIPLINE" level="1" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Boundless Imagination" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHAPER_BOUNDLESS_IMAGINATION">
            <description>
                <p>Additionally at 1st level, when you conjure your Astral Construct, you can apply one of the following powers to it:</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong>Devastating Weapons.</strong> You imagine more deadly armaments - from a greatsword to vicious fangs - causing your Astral Construct to grow more deadly. The Astral Construct’s damage becomes 1d12</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong>Psionic Conduit.</strong> You can use your Psionic powers through your Astral Construct, as if you were where it is.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong>Vivid Existence.</strong> Your Astral Construct fully materializes and automatically uses Solidify at the start of its turn without requiring a command to do so.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can change which benefit you grant it for the duration of the effect as a bonus action.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can conjure new powers for your Astral Construct in your mind and project them into reality. You can only apply one of the following properties at a time: Devastating Weapons, Psionic Conduit, or Vivid Existence.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Astral Metastability" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHAPER_ASTRAL_METASTABILITY">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 3rd level, when you use your Psionic powers to create an Astral Construct, it does not require concentration to maintain, and lasts until dismissed, but you cannot summon another one while you have one summoned.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you use your Psionic powers to create an Astral Construct, it does not require concentration to maintain, and lasts until dismissed, but you cannot summon another one while you have one summoned.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Empowered Construct" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHAPER_EMPOWERED_CONSTRUCT">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 6th level, when you deal damage with an Astral Construct, you can add your Intelligence modifier to the damage dealt.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you deal damage with an Astral Construct, you can add {{intelligence:modifier}} to the damage dealt.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Astral Guardian" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHAPER_ASTRAL_GUARDIAN">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 10th level, when you would take damage while you have an Astral Construct within 30 feet of you, you can use your reaction to conjure it to you (sharing your space) and expend a psi point to Solidify it, transposing it between you and the source of damage. It takes the damage instead of you. If the attack deals more damage than it has hit points (from Solidify), you take the remainder of the damage.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you would take damage while you have an Astral Construct within 30 feet of you, you can use your reaction to conjure it to you (sharing your space) and expend a psi point to Solidify it, transposing it between you and the source of damage. It takes the damage instead of you. If the attack deals more damage than it has hit points (from Solidify), you take the remainder of the damage.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Imaginary Army" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHAPER_IMAGINARY_ARMY">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 14th level, you can allow your mind to run wild, letting an astral army spring forth into reality. When you use Replicate, one additional Astral Construct is created and can by controlled with your action (commands only effect one of your choice). This additional construct last until the start of your next turn and cannot be sustained.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you create an additional duplicate, you cannot do so again until you complete a short or long rest.</p>          
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
                <description>When you use Replicate, one additional Astral Construct is created and can by controlled with your action (commands only effect one of your choice). This additional construct last until the start of your next turn and cannot be sustained.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    <element name="Wandering Mind" type="Archetype" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_PSION_WANDERING_MIND">
        <supports>Kibbles Psionic Archetype</supports>
        <description>
            <p>A Wandering Mind is among the more mysterious incarnates of psions, these are individuals that just aren’t quite rooted in the same reality everyone else is... they find it more pliable and slippery, and prone to jumping right through it on occasion.</p>
            <p class="indent">How they get their powers varies. Some were born in the ethereal plane or went through a portal too young. Sometimes it is just that their mind just works along an axis most people cannot understand. No matter its source, they manifest a truly unique ability to treat certain aspects of the metaphysical with a certain mundanity, and are prone to treating their powers as absolutely natural things as one might use an arm or a leg.</p>
            <p class="indent">They tend toward curious and chaotic, unbounded and hard to pin down, they are natural wanderings in mind and body.</p>
            <div element="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WANDERING_MIND_SPACIAL_MANIPULATION" />
            <div element="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WANDERING_MIND_NOMADS_GEAR" />
            <div element="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WANDERING_MIND_CUNNING_STRIKES" />
            <div element="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WANDERING_MIND_CURIOUS_MIND" />
            <!--<div element="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WANDERING_MIND_AGILE_SLIDER" />-->
            <div element="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WANDERING_MIND_PHASE_DANCER" />
            <div element="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WANDERING_MIND_FLICKERING_PRESENCE" />
            <div element="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WANDERING_MIND_PLANESWALKER" />
            <div element="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WANDERING_MIND_WINDING_PATHS" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WANDERING_MIND_SPACIAL_MANIPULATION" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WANDERING_MIND_NOMADS_GEAR" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WANDERING_MIND_CUNNING_STRIKES" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WANDERING_MIND_CURIOUS_MIND" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WANDERING_MIND_AGILE_SLIDER" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WANDERING_MIND_PHASE_DANCER" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WANDERING_MIND_FLICKERING_PRESENCE" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WANDERING_MIND_PLANESWALKER" level="14" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WANDERING_MIND_WINDING_PATHS" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Spacial Manipulation" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WANDERING_MIND_SPACIAL_MANIPULATION">
            <description>
                <p>At 1st level when you select this archetype, you mind grows a greater perspective on the nature of space and dimensions, allowing you to manipulate it and your relation to it, granting you the psionic discipline of Transposition.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE_TRANSPOSITION_DISCIPLINE" level="1" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Nomad’s Gear" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WANDERING_MIND_NOMADS_GEAR">
            <description>
                <p>Additionally at 1st level, you gain proficiency with martial weapons and medium armor.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_MARTIAL_WEAPONS" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_MEDIUM_ARMOR" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Cunning Strikes" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WANDERING_MIND_CUNNING_STRIKES">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 3rd level, you gain the Rift Strike talent. If you already have the Rift Strike talent, you can select another talent. It does not count against your Psionic Talents known, but cannot be switched out on leveling up.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Psionic Talent, Wandering Mind" supports="Kibbles Psionic Talent" default="ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSIONIC_TALENT_RIFT_STRIKE" allowReplace="false" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Curious Mind" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WANDERING_MIND_CURIOUS_MIND">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 3rd level, your wandering mind adapts to new situations constantly. At the end of a long rest select two skills you do not have proficiency in, until the end of your next long rest, you can add half your proficiency modifier (rounded down) to ability checks for those skills.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>At the end of a long rest select two skills you do not have proficiency in, until the end of your next long rest, you can add half your proficiency modifier (rounded down) to ability checks for those skills.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <!--<element name="Agile Slider" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WANDERING_MIND_AGILE_SLIDER">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 6th level, you get one free psi point at the start of your turn you can spend on the Long, Blurring or Ethereal modifiers of Phase Rift.</p>
                <p class="indent">If you have any unspent free psi points left at the end of your turn, then they are lost.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You get one free psi point at the start of your turn you can spend on the Long, Blurring or Ethereal modifiers of Phase Rift. If you have any unspent free psi points left at the end of your turn, then they are lost.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>-->
        <element name="Phase Dancer" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WANDERING_MIND_PHASE_DANCER">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 6th level, you automatically gain one illusory duplicate as per the blurring modifier when using your Phase Rift power and your first attack roll before the end of your turn after using Phase Rift gains advantage.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You automatically gain one illusory duplicate as per the blurring modifier when using your Phase Rift power and your first attack roll before the end of your turn after using Phase Rift gains advantage.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <!--<element name="Dimension Strider" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WANDERING_MIND_PHASE_DANCER">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 6th level, the base distance of your Phase Rift is increased by 10 feet.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>The base distance of your Phase Rift is increased by 10 feet.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>-->
        <element name="Flickering Presence" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WANDERING_MIND_FLICKERING_PRESENCE">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 10th level, your unspent Psionic Mastery points are not lost until the start of your next turn, but can only be used to cast <i>flicker</i>.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, when you roll for the effect of <i>flicker</i> or <i>blink</i> you can expend 1 psi point to reroll the result. You can select which of the two results you would like to use.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Your unspent Psionic Mastery points are not lost until the start of your next turn, but can only be used to cast flicker. Additionally, when you roll for the effect of flicker or blink you can expend 1 psi point to reroll the result. You can select which of the two results you would like to use.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Planeswalker" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WANDERING_MIND_PLANESWALKER">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 14th level, your understanding of how to traverse space expands to a previously incomprehensible scale. You gain the ability to cast <i>planeshift</i> and <i>teleport</i>. You can cast one of these spells per day once without expending a spell slot or use of innate psionics. Once you do this, you must complete a long rest before you can use them again, or use your 7th level or Higher use of Innate Psionics instead of the spell selected for that level to cast these spells again before completing a long rest. If you already have one of these spells selected for your 7th level Innate Psionic power, you can select a new 7th level spell from the Psion list for that slot.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You can cast either planeshift or teleport without expending a spell slot or use of psionics. You can use your 7th level or Higher use of Innate Psionics to cast plane shift and teleport instead of the spell selected for that level as normal.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PLANE_SHIFT" spellcasting="Psion" known="true" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TELEPORT" spellcasting="Psion" known="true" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Winding Paths" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WANDERING_MIND_WINDING_PATHS">
            <description>
                <p>Additionally at 14th level, your <i>phase rift</i> no longer has to go in a straight line, though it must be made up of consecutive ten foot straight lines and cannot overlap with itself.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Your phase rift no longer has to go in a straight line, though it must be made up of consecutive ten foot straight lines and cannot overlap with itself.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    <element name="Elemental Mind" type="Archetype" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_PSION_ELEMENTAL_MIND">
        <supports>Kibbles Psionic Archetype</supports>
        <description>
            <p>An Elemental Mind Psion carries a psionic link to a primal power, some have a link to a particular element while others find all elements within their mind, raging an eternal war. Often viewed as dangerous, they can erupt with power if not careful, but in time can gain great mastery over the elements.</p>
            <div element="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_MIND_ELEMENTAL_POWER" />
            <div element="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_MIND_ONE_WITH_THE_ELEMENTS" />
            <div element="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_MIND_LIVING_POWER" />
            <div element="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_MIND_EMPOWERED_PSIONICS" />
            <div element="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_MIND_FULL_MANIFESTATION" />
            <div element="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_MIND_ELEMENTAL_FORM" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_MIND_ELEMENTAL_POWER" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_MIND_ONE_WITH_THE_ELEMENTS" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_MIND_LIVING_POWER" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_MIND_EMPOWERED_PSIONICS" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_MIND_FULL_MANIFESTATION" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_MIND_ELEMENTAL_FORM" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Elemental Power" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_MIND_ELEMENTAL_POWER">
            <description>
                <p>At 1st level when you select this archtype, you gain a deep intrinsic tie to elemental power, granting you the ability to manipulate it. You gain the psionic discipline of Psychokinetics.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE_PSYCHOKINETICS_DISCIPLINE" level="1" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <!--<element name="One with the Elements" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_MIND_ONE_WITH_THE_ELEMENTS">
            <description>
                <p>Additionally at 1st level, you learn the absorb elements spell, and can expend 1 psi point to cast it.</p>
                <p class="indent">If you selected a specialization of the Psychokinetics discipline, you can only cast it when effected by that element’s type (cold, fire or lightning), but casting it does not require any psi points.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can expend 1 psi point to cast absorb elements. If you selected a specialization of the Psychokinetics discipline, you can only cast it when effected by that element’s type, but casting it does not require any psi points.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>-->
        <element name="Primordial Aspect" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_MIND_PRIMORDIAL_ASPECT">
            <description>
                <p>Additional at 1st level, when you deal fire, cold, lightning or force damage, you take on an aspect of that element until the end of your next turn or you take a new primordial aspect.</p>
                <ul>
                    <li><b>Cold:</b> You gain an icy shell, reducing any nonmagical bludgeoning, piercing or slashing damage taken by your proficiency bonus.</li>
                    <li><b>Fire:</b> You gain a firey aura, once per turn, a creature within 5 feet that hits you with a melee attack takes fire damage equal to your proficiency bonus.</li>
                    <li><b>Lightning:</b> You flicker with lightning. Your walking speed is increased by 5 feet for the duration.</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">You can additionally spend 1 psi point to gain resistance to the element to the start of your next turn. If you are a specialized in an element, you you can do this without spending a psi point for the element you are specialized in.</p>
                <div class="sidebar">
                    <h5 class="caption">Aspect Appearance</h5>
                    <p>The appearence of the aspect manifesting itself may vary, perhaps your hair becomes fire and radiate heat or your skin takes on an icy sheen, but whatever the nature and consequence of the aspect is apparent to observers.</p>
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you deal fire, cold, lightning or force damage, you take on an aspect of that element until the end of your next turn or you take a new primordial aspect.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Living Power" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_MIND_LIVING_POWER">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 3rd power, your powers become a living extension of your mind, weaving an extension of your will into reality, allowing you to manipulate your powers in more advanced ways. When you use a power or alternate effect of psychokinetics, you can apply one of the following modifiers:</p>
                <h5>Shaped Power</h5>
                <p>When you use a power or spell that makes a ranged spell attack, you can convert it to a melee spell attack (such as forming it a weapon shape), and when you would make an attack that would make a melee spell attack, you can instead form into a shape and hurl it at a target within 15 feet making a ranged spell attack.</p>
                <h5>Controlled Power</h5>
                <p>When you use a spell or power that targets an area, you can select a number of creatures equal to the psi points spent in the area of effect for the spell or power to be ignored. The power passes harmless around these creatures and they automatically suceeed on their saving throw against the effect, and they take no damage if they would normally take half damage on a successful save against the effect.</p>
                <h5>Raging Power</h5>
                <p>When you use a spell or power, you can let it rage out of control. When you roll damage for the power or spell, you can reroll 1 + the number of psi points spent on the power or spell dice. You can must use the new roll.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you use a power or alternate effect of psychokinetics, you can apply one of the following modifiers: Shaped Power, Controlled Power, or Raging Power.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Empowered Psionics" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_MIND_EMPOWERED_PSIONICS">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 6th level, when you deal damage with a Psionic Discipline power you can add your Intelligence modifier to the damage dealt.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you deal damage with a Psionic Discipline power you can add {{intelligence:modifier}} damage dealt.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Full Manifestation" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_MIND_FULL_MANIFESTATION">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 10th level, when you enter a primordial aspect, you can expend 1 psi point to fully manifest that element, replacing the primordial aspect with the following effect. If you are specialized in that element, it does not require a psi point to fully manifest the power.</p>
                <ul>
                    <li><b>Cold:</b> Your movement speed becomes zero until the end of your next turn, but you have resistance to all damage types beside fire and force.</li>
                    <li><b>Fire:</b> Fire fills a 10 foot radius around you. When the creature enters the area for the first time on a turn or starts its turn there, it takes fire damage equal to 1d4 + your proficiency bonus.</li>
                    <li><b>Lightning:</b> You can user your movement speed to teleport for the duration.</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">If you are not in a primordial aspect, you can fully manifest a power as bonus bonus action for 2 psi points (or 1 psi point if are specialized in that power).</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="1-2 psi points">
                <description>When you enter a primordial aspect, you can expend 1 psi point to fully manifest that element, replacing the primordial aspect with the full manifestation. If you are not in a primordial aspect, you can fully manifest a power as bonus bonus action for 2 psi points (or 1 psi point if are specialized in that power).</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Supercharge" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_MIND_ELEMENTAL_FORM">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 14th level, you can expend 5 psi points to cast <i>shapeshift</i> to assume elemental forms. When you cast <i>shapeshift</i> in this way it has nor verbal or material components, but you can only assume the form of a Water Elemental, Fire Elemental, or Air Elemental. If you are specialized in an element, the cost is reduced to 3 psi points, but you can only assume the form associated with your specialization (Water Elemental for cold, Fire Elemental for fire, or Air Elemental for lightning). A Water Elemental assumed with this form does not have the Freeze property.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you cast <i>shapeshift</i> this way, you cannot do so until you complete a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="5 psi points, 1/Short Rest">
                <description>You can cast shapeshift to assume Water, Fire, or Air elemental form without verbal or material components. If you are specialized in an element, the cost is reduced to 3 psi points, but you can only assume the form associated with your specialization.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    <element name="Consuming Mind" type="Archetype" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_PSION_CONSUMING_MIND">
        <supports></supports>
        <description>
            <p>A dangerous branch of psionics that are born from the ability to sap energy from other creatures, tearing from them their thoughts, their mind, and ultimately their vitality for your own consumption. A feared branch of power, it is often believed to be one of the roots of psionic power as it is a branch of power found in many of the most ancient and terrible practitioners of psionics, such as Illithids and Aboleths.</p>
            <p class="indent">It has been refined by those that seek greater power either from ambition or desperation, and unlocks a terrible but effective path. One example of mortal creatures walking this path is the drow House Oblodra, who developed their dark powers from their study of feral vampiric mindflayers.</p>
            <div element="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CONSUMING_MIND_PSIONIC_PREDATOR" />
            <div element="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CONSUMING_MIND_DARK_LURKER" />
            <div element="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CONSUMING_MIND_RAVENOUS_POWERS" />
            <div element="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CONSUMING_MIND_EMPOWERED_PSIONICS" />
            <div element="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CONSUMING_MIND_MIND_VAMPIRE" />
            <div element="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CONSUMING_MIND_SHATTERED_HUSKS" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CONSUMING_MIND_PSIONIC_PREDATOR" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CONSUMING_MIND_DARK_LURKER" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CONSUMING_MIND_RAVENOUS_POWERS" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CONSUMING_MIND_EMPOWERED_PSIONICS" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CONSUMING_MIND_MIND_VAMPIRE" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CONSUMING_MIND_SHATTERED_HUSKS" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Psionic Predator" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CONSUMING_MIND_PSIONIC_PREDATOR">
            <description>
                <p>At 1st level when you select this archetype, you gain the ability to consume the psionic power of others. You gain the psionic discipline of Consumption.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE_CONSUMPTION_DISCIPLINE" level="1" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Dark Lurker" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CONSUMING_MIND_DARK_LURKER">
            <description>
                <p>Additionally at 1st level, your powers grant you intuition that allows you to better adapt and survive as a mind hunter. You gain proficiency in Stealth and Deception.</p>
                <p class="indent">When you use psionic abilities, you can make an Intelligence (Deception) check contested by a target’s Wisdom (Insight) to conceal your use of psionic powers, suppressing their usual visible indicators. If you spend psi points on the ability, you must subtract the psi points spent from your Intelligence (Deception) roll result (concealing greater uses of psionics being more difficult).</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you use psionic abilities, you can make an Deception check contested by a target’s Insight to conceal your use of psionic powers, suppressing their usual visible indicators. If you spend psi points on the ability, you must subtract the psi points spent from your Deception roll result.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_STEALTH" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_DECEPTION" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Ravenous Powers" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CONSUMING_MIND_RAVENOUS_POWERS">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 3rd level, you gain the psionic talent Mind Devourer; this talent ignores the normal level restriction, and does not count against your Psionic Talents known, but cannot be switched out on leveling up.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, you can gain the benefit of this talent from a range of 30 feet when the creature is killed by one of your Psionic powers.</p>
                <div class="sidebar">
                    <h5>CONSUMPTION &amp; TELEPATHY</h5>
                    <p>As with all Psion subclasses, the 2nd psionic discipline can be selected from any of the available options, but the combination of Consumption and Telepathy is the default selection. Your features do not rely on this combination, but it opens some interesting possibilities in the Talents, and will best represent some of the sources of inspiration for the subclass.</p>
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can use Mind Devourer to a range of 30 feet.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSIONIC_TALENT_MIND_DEVOURER" level="3" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Empowered Psionics" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CONSUMING_MIND_EMPOWERED_PSIONICS">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 6th level, when you deal damage with a Psionic Discipline power you can add your Intelligence modifier to the damage dealt.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you deal damage with a Psionic Discipline power you can add {{intelligence:modifier}} to the damage dealt.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Mind Vampire" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CONSUMING_MIND_MIND_VAMPIRE">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 10th level, you can trigger Mind Devourer anytime you deal psychic damage to a target within 30 feet, regardless if it kills the target or not.</p>
                <p class="indent">Further, you can have additional psi points (over your normal limit) equal to your half your Intelligence modifier (rounded down) when gaining psi points from Mind Devourer, but any additional psi points are lost when you complete a short or long rest.</p>
                <div class="sidebar">
                    <h5>LIMITATIONS</h5>
                    <p>Even when used with Mind Vampire, Mind Devourer still requires a reaction to use, meaning that it can still effectively trigger once per round. All normal restrictions of Mind Devourer still apply (such as a minimum Intelligence ability score of the target.)</p>
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can trigger Mind Devourer anytime you deal psychic damage to a target within 30 feet, regardless if it kills the target or not. Further, you can have additional psi points (over your normal limit) equal to your half your Intelligence modifier (rounded down) when gaining psi points from Mind Devourer, but any additional psi points are lost when you complete a short or long rest.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Shattered Husks" type="Archetype Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CONSUMING_MIND_SHATTERED_HUSKS">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 14th level, your Mind Leech ability always gains the Shredding modifier, and it does not cost a psi point to add the modifier.</p>
                <p class="indent">Further, you can use additional power to leave their mind further vulnerable. You can spend additional psi points on the Shredding modifier to further reduce their next Wisdom, Intelligence or Charisma saving throw (up to 2 additional points to reduce it by a total of 3d4). Once this is effect has been applied to a creature, you cannot spend additional psi points on the Shredding modifier against the creature until 1 hour has passed.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Your Mind Leech ability always gains the Shredding modifier, and it does not cost a psi point to add the modifier. Further, you can use additional power to leave their mind further vulnerable. You can spend additional psi points on the Shredding modifier to further reduce their next Wisdom, Intelligence or Charisma saving throw (up to 2 additional points to reduce it by a total of 3d4). Once this is effect has been applied to a creature, you cannot spend additional psi points on the Shredding modifier against the creature until 1 hour has passed.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>

  <!-- Psion Skills -->    
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_DECEPTION">
        <supports>Kibbles Psion</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_HISTORY">
        <supports>Kibbles Psion</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT">
        <supports>Kibbles Psion</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INTIMIDATION">
        <supports>Kibbles Psion</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INVESTIGATION">
        <supports>Kibbles Psion</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_MEDICINE">
        <supports>Kibbles Psion</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION">
        <supports>Kibbles Psion</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_RELIGION">
        <supports>Kibbles Psion</supports>
    </append>

  <!-- Feats -->
    <element name="Psionic Mind" type="Feat" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_FEAT_PSIONIC_MIND">
        <requirements>ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_KT_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE</requirements>
        <prerequisite>The ability to use at least one Psionic Discipline</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: The ability to use at least one Psionic Discipline</p>
            <p>You tap deeper into your psionic potential drawing out a new talent. You can select a psionic talent from the Psion class psionic talent list. You cannot select a talent you already know, or one that requires a level restriction, even if you are already of that level.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Psionic Talent" supports="Kibbles Psionic Talent,!Level Minimum" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Psionic Adept" type="Feat" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_FEAT_PSIONIC_ADEPT">
        <requirements></requirements>
        <prerequisite></prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p>You develop a minor grasp of psionic power, either uncovering an innate potential within yourself, through contact with a psionic source, or through training. You gain one of the psionic disciplines of the Psion class, gaining the attached psionic feature and psionic power, but you do not gain use of any associated spells when gain a Discipline from this feat.</p>
            You gain 1 psi point that you can use to empower the Discipline. You regain use of this Psi Point when you complete a short or long rest.
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1 Psi Point/Short Rest">
            <description>You have 1 Psi Point that you can use to empower your chosen Psionic Discipline. You do not gain the Altered Effects options from the discipline.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="psi:points" value="1" />
            <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_KT_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Psionic Discipline (Psionic Adept)" supports="Kibbles Psionic Adept Discipline" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Inner Power" type="Feat" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_FEAT_INNER_POWER_PSI">
        <requirements>[psi:points:1],![ki:points:1]</requirements>
        <prerequisite>At least 1 psi or ki point</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: At least 1 psi or ki point</p>
            <p>Your body is powered by the inner powers that course through it. Your maximum psi or ki points (if you have both, your choice of which) increases by one.</p>
            <p class="indent">At the end of your turn after expending one or more psi or ki points during your turn (not counting temporary or free points, such as those from Psionic Mastery), you heal for a number of hit points equal to the psi or ki points spent.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>At the end of your turn after spending one or more psi (not counting temporary or free points, such as those from Psionic Mastery) during your turn, you heal for a number of hit points equal to the psi or ki points spent, up to a maximum {{inner-power:hp}}.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="psi:points" value="1" />
            <stat name="inner-power:hp" value="1" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="inner-power:hp" value="constitution:modifier" bonus="base" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Inner Power" type="Feat" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_FEAT_INNER_POWER_KI">
        <requirements>[ki:points:1],![psi:points:1]</requirements>
        <prerequisite>At least 1 psi or ki point</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: At least 1 psi or ki point</p>
            <p>Your body is powered by the inner powers that course through it. Your maximum psi or ki points (if you have both, your choice of which) increases by one.</p>
            <p class="indent">At the end of your turn after expending one or more psi or ki points during your turn (not counting temporary or free points), you heal for a number of hit points equal to the psi or ki points spent.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>At the end of your turn after spending one or more ki points (not counting temporary or free points) during your turn, you heal for a number of hit points equal to the psi or ki points spent, up to a maximum {{inner-power:hp}}.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="ki:points" value="1" />
            <stat name="inner-power:hp" value="1" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="inner-power:hp" value="constitution:modifier" bonus="base" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="War Psion" type="Feat" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_FEAT_WAR_PSION">
        <requirements>ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_KT_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: The ability to use at least one Psionic Discipline</p>
            <p class="indent">You have mastered utilizing psionics in the midst of combat, learning techniques that grant you the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>You have advantage on Constitution saving throws that you make to maintain your concentration on a psionic ability when you take damage.</li>
                <li>You can perform the somatic components of psionic abilities even when you have weapons or a shield in one or both hands.</li>
                <li>When a hostile creature’s movement provokes an opportunity attack from you, you can use your reaction to use a psionic discipline power or spell targeting the creature, rather than making an opportunity attack. The spell must have a casting time of 1 action and must target only that creature.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You have advantage on Constitution saving throws that you make to maintain your concentration on a psionic ability when you take damage. You can perform the somatic components of psionic abilities even when you have weapons or a shield in one or both hands. When a hostile creature’s movement provokes an opportunity attack from you, you can use your reaction to use a psionic discipline power or spell targeting the creature, rather than making an opportunity attack. The spell must have a casting time of 1 action and must target only that creature.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="Psionic Discipline" type="Grants" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_KT_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE" />

    <element name="Psioncis" type="Proficiency" source="Kibbles’ Psion" id="ID_KT_PSION_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PSIONICS">
        <supports>Skill,Psion</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Psionics a new Intelligence based skill that serves to understand things of a Psionic nature as Arcana might understand things of an arcane nature. It is a skill to help you identify Psionic objects, phenomena and creatures.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can {{proficiency}} to any check you make to identify Psionic objects, phenomena and creatures.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

</elements>