<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>KibblesTasty’s Psion Expanded v1.4</name>
        <update version="0.0.15">
            <file name="psion-expanded.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/kibblestasty/psion/psion-expanded.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>

  <!-- Psion Class Options -->
    <append id="ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_PSION">
        <description>
            <div element="ID_KT_KTPE_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_PSION_THIS_IS_YOUR_LIFE" />
        </description>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_KT_KTPE_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_PSION_THIS_IS_YOUR_LIFE" level="1" />
        </rules>
    </append>
        <element name="This is Your Life" type="Background Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion Expanded" id="ID_KT_KTPE_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_PSION_THIS_IS_YOUR_LIFE">
            <description>
                <h5>CLASS TRAINING</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>d8</td><td>I became a Psion because...</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1</td><td>My dreams touched the far realm as a child. I had nightmares for years that started manifest into reality.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>2</td><td>One of my parents was enslaved to Aboleth at one point, passing along a psionic abnormality.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3</td><td>In my youth I met a strange but friendly madman who taught me before disappearing one day.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>4</td><td>A Warlock of the Great Old spoke to me telepathically, and something... changed.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5</td><td>I discovered it within myself during a particularly intense meditation.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>6</td><td>I was adopted by a strange order of monks who taught my their secrets.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>7</td><td>A passing adventurer sensed my powers and happened to share them, teaching my to control my powers.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>8</td><td>I grew up in a Mindflayer colony, the process of ceremorphosis failed leaving me with powers.</td></tr>
                </table>
                <h5>QUIRKS</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>d12</td><td>Quirk</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1</td><td>After long periods of meditation, you find parts of your personality you haven’t talked to in awhile and have a good conversation.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>2</td><td>You think Divine and Arcane magic is unnatural and creepy, and suffer it’s effects only reluctantly.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3</td><td>You keep a set of beads on a thread, idly counting them.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>4</td><td>You are surprised when people talk outloud using their mouths.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5</td><td>Keep meticulous notes in a language only you understand.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>6</td><td>You hold lengthy conversations with things that don’t seem to respond.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>7</td><td>You worry about people learning your name, and use a pseudonym.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>8</td><td>You have come up with names for most of the stars.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9</td><td>You never tell the same origin story twice.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>10</td><td>You use your powers unnecessarily and incessantly.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>11</td><td>You occasionally assure people that you cannot read their mind. Particularly when they seem to think you might be.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>12</td><td>You spurn material positions as mere bondage of mortal shackles.</td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="List" name="I became a Psion because...">
                    <item id="1">My dreams touched the far realm as a child. I had nightmares for years that started manifest into reality.</item>
                    <item id="2">One of my parents was enslaved to Aboleth at one point, passing along a psionic abnormality.</item>
                    <item id="3">In my youth I met a strange but friendly madman who taught me before disappearing one day.</item>
                    <item id="4">A Warlock of the Great Old spoke to me telepathically, and something... changed.</item>
                    <item id="5">I discovered it within myself during a particularly intense meditation.</item>
                    <item id="6">I was adopted by a strange order of monks who taught my their secrets.</item>
                    <item id="7">A passing adventurer sensed my powers and happened to share them, teaching my to control my powers.</item>
                    <item id="8">I grew up in a Mindflayer colony, the process of ceremorphosis failed leaving me with powers.</item>
                </select>
                <select type="List" name="Quirk">
                    <item id="1">After long periods of meditation, you find parts of your personality you haven’t talked to in awhile and have a good conversation.</item>
                    <item id="2">You think Divine and Arcane magic is unnatural and creepy, and suffer it’s effects only reluctantly.</item>
                    <item id="3">You keep a set of beads on a thread, idly counting them.</item>
                    <item id="4">You are surprised when people talk outloud using their mouths.</item>
                    <item id="5">Keep meticulous notes in a language only you understand.</item>
                    <item id="6">You hold lengthy conversations with things that don’t seem to respond.</item>
                    <item id="7">You worry about people learning your name, and use a pseudonym.</item>
                    <item id="8">You have come up with names for most of the stars.</item>
                    <item id="9">You never tell the same origin story twice.</item>
                    <item id="10">You use your powers unnecessarily and incessantly.</item>
                    <item id="11">You occasionally assure people that you cannot read their mind. Particularly when they seem to think you might be.</item>
                    <item id="12">You spurn material positions as mere bondage of mortal shackles.</item>
                </select>
            </rules>
        </element>
  <!-- Additional Psionic Disciplines -->


    



  <!-- Additional Psion Archetypes -->

  <!-- Additional Psionic Spells -->
    <element name="Inner World" type="Spell" source="Kibbles’ Psion Expanded" id="ID_KT_KTPE_SPELL_INNER_WORLD">
        <supports>Kibbles Psion</supports>
        <description>
            <p>As an action, you create and enter an imaginary world. All other creatures within 120 feet are pulled this world with you. This world is centered on you, and extends in 120 feet in all directions.</p>
            <p class="indent">A creature that reaches the edge of this world can make a Charisma saving throw to attempt to exit, spending 5 feet of movement to return where they were before being pulled into the world on success, and being unable to move out the world until the start of their next turn on failure. A creature outside the world can attempt to enter it by moving to where you cast the spell (which is marked by a glowing psionic rift) and making a Charisma saving throw to enter the world. You can allow a creature to automatically pass their save to enter or exit the world.</p>
            <p class="indent">When you create this world, you can create obstacles and terrain of your choice, creating walls, pillars, and other obstacles that take up to twenty 5 by 5 square foot areas (stylistically, these can appear however you choose). These can be placed consecutive or spread out in any method of your choosing, but any area with a creature must contain an path that creature can fit through to both you and the edge of the of the world.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can additionally create up to five hazardous spaces on the ground that are 5 foot squares. These can be fires, spikes, biting mouthes, or whatever you choose, but regardless of its form if a creature takes 4d4 + 4 psychic damage when it enters the effect’s area for the first time on a turn or starts its turn there. Each of these hazards must be at least 20 feet from another hazard.</p>
            <p class="indent">While in this inner world, if you fail saving throw, you choose to succeed instead. You can do up to 3 times during the duration of the spell. All spells and powers have their psi point cost reduced by one.</p>
            <p class="indent">During the spell, as an action, you can cause attempt to destroy a creature within the world. The target must make an Intelligence saving throw. On failure, it takes 8d8 + 8 psychic damage and is removed from the imaginary world, returning to where they were before being pulled into it.</p>
            <p class="indent">The world can be bright or dim light, and you control the weather within it.</p>
            <p class="indent">When the spell ends, you and any creature that remains in the world exit the world returning to space you entered the world from.</p>
            <div class="sidebar">
                <h5 class="caption">QUICKLY CONSTRUCTED WORLDS</h5>
                <p>The casting time of this spell is 1 action, which is 6 seconds in game. While this should not be taken literally, it is also an indication that this is a quickly constructed world. It is recommended that that you come up with a general layout and any resources needed for this spell in collaboration with your DM when you select the spell, and make at most minor changes to the world when casting it. It is reasonable for a DM to limit world planning time to one minute.</p>
            </div>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">8</set>
            <set name="school">psionic</set>
            <set name="time">: 1 action.</set>
            <set name="range">Self.</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, Up to 1 minute.</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>


  <!-- Additional Talents -->
    <element name="Master of Stolen Power" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion Expanded" id="ID_KT_KTPE_CLASS_FEATURE_PSIONIC_TALENT_MASTER_OF_STOLEN_POWER">
        <supports>Kibbles Psionic Talent,Level Minimum</supports>
        <requirements>ID_KT_PSION_EXP_CLASS_FEATURE_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE_CONSUMPTION_DISCIPLINE, [level:psion:15]</requirements>
        <prerequisite>Consumption Discipline, 15th-level Psion</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Consumption Discipline, 15th-level Psion</p>
            <p class="indent">While you are in a boosted state from Mind Leech (with an additional 1d6 damage to add to psionic power), you gain an additional psi point from Psionic Mastery.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>While you are in a boosted state from Mind Leech (with an additional 1d6 damage to add to psionic power), you gain an additional psi point from Psionic Mastery.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Mind Feast" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion Expanded" id="ID_KT_KTPE_CLASS_FEATURE_PSIONIC_TALENT_MIND_FEAST">
        <supports>Kibbles Psionic Talent,Level Minimum</supports>
        <requirements>ID_KT_KTPE_ARCHETYPE_PSION_CONSUMING_MIND,[level:psion:9]</requirements>
        <prerequisite>Consuming Mind, 9th-level Psion</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Consuming Mind, 9th-level Psion</p>
            <p class="indent">You can gain further nourishment by literally consuming the minds of your fallen foes, adapting your metabolism. If you take a short or long rest while having access to the corpse of a fallen foe that died in the last hour and that had an Intelligence of 8 or higher, you can consume part of their mind, gaining extra psi points over your normal limit equal to the creature’s CR (up to your proficiency bonus).</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>If you take a short or long rest while having access to the corpse of a fallen foe that died in the last hour and that had an Intelligence of 8 or higher, you can consume part of their mind, gaining extra psi points over your normal limit equal to the creature’s CR (up to {{proficiency}}).</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>


  <!-- Additional Psion Talents -->
    <element name="Beam of Annihilation" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion Expanded" id="ID_KT_KTPE_CLASS_FEATURE_PSIONIC_TALENT_BEAM_OF_ANNIHILATION">
        <supports>Kibbles Psionic Talent,Level Minimum</supports>
        <requirements>[level:psion:11],ID_KT_KTPE_ARCHETYPE_PSION_ELEMENTAL_MIND</requirements>
        <prerequisite>11th level Psion, Elemental Mind subclass</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 11th level Psion, Elemental Mind subclass</p>
            <p class="indent">You gain the ability to cast <i>beam of annihilation</i> for 6 psi points. If you have a specialization of Psychokinentics, you can only select the related elemental damage type, but the beam’s damage ignores resistance to that damage type any creatures caught in the beam might have.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="6 Psi Points">
            <description>You can cast beam of annihilation. If you have a specialization of Psychokinentics, you can only select the related elemental damage type, but the beam’s damage ignores resistance to that damage type.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_KT_KTPE_SPELL_BEAM_OF_ANNIHILATION" spellcasting="Psion" known="true" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Imaginary Mount" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion Expanded" id="ID_KT_KTPE_CLASS_FEATURE_PSIONIC_TALENT_IMAGINARY_MOUNT">
        <supports>Kibbles Psionic Talent</supports>
        <requirements>ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE_PROJECTION_DISCIPLINE</requirements>
        <prerequisite>Projection Discipline</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Projection Discipline</p>
            <p class="indent">You gain the ability to cast <i>phantom steed</i>. You do not need to expend spell slots or psi points to cast it, but cannot cast the spell again in this way until you complete a short or long rest. Casting this spell while an astral construct is active ends the astral construct power, and casting astral construct during the <i>phantom steed</i> duration ends the <i>phantom steed</i> spell.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
            <description>You can cast phantom steed without expending spell slots or psio points. Casting this spell while an astral construct is active ends the astral construct power, and casting astral construct during the phantom steed duration ends the phantom steed spell.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PHANTOM_STEED" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Swfit Strike" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion Expanded" id="ID_KT_KTPE_CLASS_FEATURE_PSIONIC_SWIFT_STRIKE">
        <supports>Kibbles Psionic Talent</supports>
        <requirements>[level:psion:5],ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE_ENHANCEMENT_DISCIPLINE</requirements>
        <prerequisite>5th-level Psion, Enhancement Discipline</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 5th-level Psion, Enhancement Discipline</p>
            <p class="indent">When you grant Swift with your Enhancing Surge ability, the target can use the action granted to take the Attack action (one weapon attack only).</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you grant Swift with your Enhancing Surge ability, the target can use the action granted to take the Attack action (one weapon attack only).</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Tranquil Meditation" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion Expanded" id="ID_KT_KTPE_CLASS_FEATURE_PSIONIC_TALENT_TRANQUIL_MEDITATION">
        <supports>Kibbles Psionic Talent</supports>
        <requirements>ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE_ENHANCEMENT_DISCIPLINE</requirements>
        <prerequisite>Enhancement Discipline</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Enhancement Discipline</p>
            <p class="indent">When you take a short rest and expend hit dice, both you and any allied creatures that takes a short rest within 60 feet of you regains additional hit points equal to the number of hit dice you expend + your intelligence modifier.</p>
            <div class="sidebar">
                <h5 class="caption">NOTE: NUMBER OF HIT DICE</h5>
                <p>This restores hit points equal to the number of hit dice rolled, not the value rolled on them. For example, if you expend two hit dice rolling 4, and 5, you grant allied creatures 2 + your intelligence modifier additional hit points regained.</p>
            </div>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you take a short rest and expend hit dice, both you and any allied creatures that takes a short rest within 60 feet of you regains additional hit points equal to the number of hit dice you expend + {{intelligence:modifier}}.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

  <!-- Additional Psionic Feats -->
     <!--<element name="Psionic Mind" type="Feat" source="Kibbles’ Psion Expanded" id="ID_KT_KTPE_FEAT_PSIONIC_MIND">
        <requirements>ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_KT_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE</requirements>
        <prerequisite>The ability to use at least one Psionic Discipline</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: The ability to use at least one Psionic Discipline</p>
            <p class="indent">You tap deeper into your psionic potential drawing out a new talent. You gain the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>Your Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma score increases by 1.</li>
                <li>You can select a psionic talent from the Psion class psionic talent list. You cannot select a talent you already know, or one that requires a level restriction, even if you are already of that level.</li>
            </ul>
            <p class="indent">You can take this feat multiple times, selecting a different talent each time.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
			<select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Athlete" supports="ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_INTELLIGENCE|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_WISDOM|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_CHARISMA" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Psionic Talent" supports="Kibbles Psionic Talent,!Level Minimum" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Psionic Mind" type="Feat" source="Kibbles’ Psion Expanded" id="ID_KT_KTPE_FEAT_PSIONIC_MIND2">
            <requirements>ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_KT_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE,ID_KT_KTPE_FEAT_PSIONIC_MIND</requirements>
            <prerequisite>The ability to use at least one Psionic Discipline</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: The ability to use at least one Psionic Discipline</p>
                <p class="indent">You tap deeper into your psionic potential drawing out a new talent. You gain the following benefits:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Your Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma score increases by 1.</li>
                    <li>You can select a psionic talent from the Psion class psionic talent list. You cannot select a talent you already know, or one that requires a level restriction, even if you are already of that level.</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">You can take this feat multiple times, selecting a different talent each time.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
    			<select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Athlete" supports="ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_INTELLIGENCE|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_WISDOM|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_CHARISMA" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Psionic Talent" supports="Kibbles Psionic Talent,!Level Minimum" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Psionic Mind" type="Feat" source="Kibbles’ Psion Expanded" id="ID_KT_KTPE_FEAT_PSIONIC_MIND3">
            <requirements>ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_KT_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE,ID_KT_KTPE_FEAT_PSIONIC_MIND2</requirements>
            <prerequisite>The ability to use at least one Psionic Discipline</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: The ability to use at least one Psionic Discipline</p>
                <p class="indent">You tap deeper into your psionic potential drawing out a new talent. You gain the following benefits:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Your Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma score increases by 1.</li>
                    <li>You can select a psionic talent from the Psion class psionic talent list. You cannot select a talent you already know, or one that requires a level restriction, even if you are already of that level.</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">You can take this feat multiple times, selecting a different talent each time.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
    			<select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Athlete" supports="ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_INTELLIGENCE|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_WISDOM|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_CHARISMA" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Psionic Talent" supports="Kibbles Psionic Talent,!Level Minimum" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Psionic Mind" type="Feat" source="Kibbles’ Psion Expanded" id="ID_KT_KTPE_FEAT_PSIONIC_MIND4">
            <requirements>ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_KT_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE,ID_KT_KTPE_FEAT_PSIONIC_MIND3</requirements>
            <prerequisite>The ability to use at least one Psionic Discipline</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: The ability to use at least one Psionic Discipline</p>
                <p class="indent">You tap deeper into your psionic potential drawing out a new talent. You gain the following benefits:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Your Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma score increases by 1.</li>
                    <li>You can select a psionic talent from the Psion class psionic talent list. You cannot select a talent you already know, or one that requires a level restriction, even if you are already of that level.</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">You can take this feat multiple times, selecting a different talent each time.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
    			<select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Athlete" supports="ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_INTELLIGENCE|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_WISDOM|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_CHARISMA" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Psionic Talent" supports="Kibbles Psionic Talent,!Level Minimum" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Psionic Mind" type="Feat" source="Kibbles’ Psion Expanded" id="ID_KT_KTPE_FEAT_PSIONIC_MIND5">
            <requirements>ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_KT_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE,ID_KT_KTPE_FEAT_PSIONIC_MIND4</requirements>
            <prerequisite>The ability to use at least one Psionic Discipline</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: The ability to use at least one Psionic Discipline</p>
                <p class="indent">You tap deeper into your psionic potential drawing out a new talent. You gain the following benefits:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Your Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma score increases by 1.</li>
                    <li>You can select a psionic talent from the Psion class psionic talent list. You cannot select a talent you already know, or one that requires a level restriction, even if you are already of that level.</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">You can take this feat multiple times, selecting a different talent each time.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
    			<select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Athlete" supports="ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_INTELLIGENCE|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_WISDOM|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_CHARISMA" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Psionic Talent" supports="Kibbles Psionic Talent,!Level Minimum" />
            </rules>
        </element>
    <element name="Psionic Adept" type="Feat" source="Kibbles’ Psion Expanded" id="ID_KT_KTPE_FEAT_PSIONIC_ADEPT">
        <description>
            <p>You develop a minor grasp of psionic power, either uncovering an innate potential within yourself, through contact with a psionic source, or through training. You gain one of the psionic disciplines of the Psion class, gaining the attached psionic feature and psionic power, but you do not gain use of any associated spells when gain a Discipline from this feat.</p>
            <p class="indent">You gain 1 psi point that you can use to empower the Discipline. You regain use of this Psi Point when you complete a short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1 Psi Point/Short Rest">
            <description>You have 1 psi point to use for any psionic powers.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_KT_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Psionic Discipline" supports="Kibbles Psionic Discipline" />
            <stat name="psi:points" value="1" />
        </rules>
    </element>-->
    <element name="Inner Power" type="Feat" source="Kibbles’ Psion Expanded" id="ID_KT_KTPE_FEAT_INNER_POWER">
        <requirements>([psi:points:1]||[ki:points:1])</requirements>
        <prerequisite>At least 1 psi or ki point</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: At least 1 psi or ki point</p>
            <p class="indent">Your body is powered by the inner powers that course through it. Your maximum psi or ki points (if you have both, your choice of which) increases by one.</p>
            <p class="indent">At the end of your turn after spending one or more psi or ki points during your turn, you heal for a number of hit points equal to the psi or ki points spent, up to a maximum of your Constitution modifier (minimum 1).</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>At the end of your turn after spending one or more psi or ki points during your turn, you heal for a number of hit points equal to the psi or ki points spent, up to a maximum of {{inner-power:hp}}.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="psi:points" value="1" requirements="psi:points:1" />
            <stat name="ki:points" value="1" requirements="ki:points:1" />
            <stat name="inner-power:hp" value="1" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="inner-power:hp" value="constitution:modifier" bonus="base" />
        </rules>
    </element>
   <element name="Combat Psionics" type="Feat" source="Kibbles’ Psion Expanded" id="ID_KT_KTPE_FEAT_COMBAT_PSIONICS">
        <requirements>ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_KT_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE</requirements>
        <prerequisite>The ability to use at least one Psionic Discipline</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: The ability to use at least one Psionic Discipline</p>
            <p class="indent">You have mastered utilizing psionics in the midst of combat, learning techniques that grant you the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>You have advantage on Constitution saving throws that you make to maintain your concentration on a psionic ability when you take damage.</li>
                <li>You can perform the somatic components of psionic abilities even when you have weapons or a shield in one or both hands.</li>
                <li>When a hostile creature’s movement provokes an opportunity attack from you, you can use your reaction to use a psionic discipline power or spell targeting the creature, rather than making an opportunity attack. The spell must have a casting time of 1 action and must target only that creature.</li>
            </ul>
            <div>
                <h5 class="caption">WAR CASTER &amp; SPELL SNIPER</h5>
                <p>Obviously Combat Psionics and Psionic Sniper are parallels to the spell casting feats War Caster and Spell Sniper, but with some tweaks to apply to psionics and better fit in with how they work. You can alternatively allow those feats to work with Psionics if you and your DM prefer.</p>
            </div>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You have advantage on Constitution saving throws that you make to maintain your concentration on a psionic ability when you take damage. You can perform the somatic components of psionic abilities even when you have weapons or a shield in one or both hands. When a hostile creature’s movement provokes an opportunity attack from you, you can use your reaction to use a psionic discipline power or spell targeting the creature, rather than making an opportunity attack. The spell must have a casting time of 1 action and must target only that creature.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Psionic Reach" type="Feat" source="Kibbles’ Psion Expanded" id="ID_KT_KTPE_FEAT_PSIONIC_REACH">
        <requirements>ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_KT_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE</requirements>
        <prerequisite>The ability to use at least one Psionic Discipline</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: The ability to use at least one Psionic Discipline</p>
            <p class="indent">You have learned techniques to enhance your attacks with certain kinds of spells, gaining the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>The range of psionic powers and spells cast through psionic abilities are doubled so long as that power or spell only targets a single creature.</li>
                <li>Your ranged psionic attacks ignore half cover, and ignore all cover if they deal psychic or force damage.</li>
            </ul>
            <div>
                <h5 class="caption">WAR CASTER &amp; SPELL SNIPER</h5>
                <p>Obviously Combat Psionics and Psionic Sniper are parallels to the spell casting feats War Caster and Spell Sniper, but with some tweaks to apply to psionics and better fit in with how they work. You can alternatively allow those feats to work with Psionics if you and your DM prefer.</p>
            </div>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>The range of psionic powers and spells cast through psionic abilities are doubled so long as that power or spell only targets a single creature. Your ranged psionic attacks ignore half cover, and ignore all cover if they deal psychic or force damage.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Planar Mind" type="Feat" source="Kibbles’ Psion Expanded" id="ID_KT_KTPE_FEAT_PLANAR_MIND">
        <requirements>ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_KT_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE</requirements>
        <prerequisite>The ability to use at least one Psionic Discipline</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: The ability to use at least one Psionic Discipline</p>
            <p class="indent">You’ve honed your mind to understand the planar nature of the world around you, existing in the material, ethereal, and astral planes simultaneously in harmony.</p>
            <ul>
                <li>You can see creatures in the ethereal plane within 20 feet of you.</li>
                <li>While in the ethereal or astral plane, any movement speed you have is doubled.</li>
                <li>As a bonus action you can enter the ethereal or astral plan completely until the start of your next turn. If you enter the ethereal plane, you reappear at a space of your choosing within 10 feet of where your entered it. If you enter that astral plane, you reappear 10d10 feet in a direction of your choosing at the start of your next turn; if you would reappear within the space of a solid object or creature, you are moved to the closest free space taking 1d10 force damage for every 5 feet you are forced to move. Once you phase into another plane using this feat, you cannot do so again until you complete a short or long rest.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Bonus Action">
            <description>You can see creatures in the ethereal plane within 20 feet of you. While in the ethereal or astral plane, any movement speed you have is doubled. As a bonus action you can enter the ethereal or astral plan completely until the start of your next turn. If you enter the ethereal plane, you reappear at a space of your choosing within 10 feet of where your entered it. If you enter that astral plane, you reappear 10d10 feet in a direction of your choosing at the start of your next turn.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Warped Mind" type="Feat" source="Kibbles’ Psion Expanded" id="ID_KT_KTPE_FEAT_WARPED_MIND">
        <requirements>ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_KT_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE</requirements>
        <prerequisite>The ability to use at least one Psionic Discipline</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: The ability to use at least one Psionic Discipline</p>
            <p class="indent">The alien influence of psionic powers on your mind have left it warped in a way in a way that grants a unique perspective, and makes it difficult for other creatures to manipulate. You gain the following benefits.</p>
            <ul>
                <li>Your Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma score increases by 1.</li>
                <li>You have advantage on saving throws against being magically charmed or frightened, and are immune to <i>dominate person</i>.</li>
                <li>When a creature attempts to read your mind (such as with the spell <i>detect thoughts</i>) the attempt fails and they take damage equal to your Proficiency character level.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You have advantage on saving throws against being magically charmed or frightened, and are immune to dominate person. When a creature attempts to read your mind (such as with the spell detect thoughts) the attempt fails and they take {{proficiency}} psychic damage.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Athlete" supports="ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_INTELLIGENCE|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_WISDOM|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_CHARISMA" />
        </rules>
    </element>

    <!-- Advanced Psionic Options -->
        <element name="Psionic Synthesis" type="Feat" source="Kibbles’ Psion Expanded" id="ID_KT_KTPE_FEAT_PSIONIC_SYNTHESIS">
            <requirements>[level:psion:4],ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSION_SECOND_DISCIPLINE</requirements>
            <prerequisite>4th level Psion, 2 or more Psionic Disciplines known</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 4th level Psion, 2 or more Psionic Disciplines known</p>
                <p class="indent">You gain the ability to meld your Psionic abilities together to produce potent new effects. When you select this feat, you can select one Fusion talent for free. You can only select fusion talents when you have all the Disciplines in their prerequisite.</p>
                <div class="sidebar">
                    <h5 class="caption">Warning! Playtest Material</h5>
                    <p>This section document opens up a lot of new interactions for the already quite modular Psion class, and is still under review and playtesting (and will be for sometime). If you’re a DM and you have concerns with an interaction, feel free to work with your player on modifications or reach out to me for clarity.</p>
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false" />
            <rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Psionic Synthesis Talent" supports="Kibbles Psionic Talent,Psionic Synthesis" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Enhanced Constructs" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion Expanded" id="ID_KT_KTPE_CLASS_FEATURE_PSIONIC_TALENT_ENHANCED_CONSTRUCTS">
            <supports>Kibbles Psionic Talent,Psionic Synthesis</supports>
            <requirements>ID_KT_KTPE_FEAT_PSIONIC_SYNTHESIS,ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE_ENHANCEMENT_DISCIPLINE,ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE_PROJECTION_DISCIPLINE</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Psionic Synthesis, Enhancement Discipline, Projection Discipline</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Psionic Synthesis, Enhancement Discipline, Projection Discipline</p>
                <p class="indent">Your Astral Construct can be affected by Enhancing Surge, and for the purposes of Talents, is considered you, though you must choose if you or it receive the benefits. Additionally, you can consider your Astral Construct a creature for the purposes of Enhancement Alternate Effects in the following ways:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Any time it gains hit points or temporary hit points, it becomes Solidified and gains those hit points until they are depleted; it can have a maximum hit points equal to your Psion level.</li>
                    <li>Increased Movement Speed increases the distance you can move it, including movement gained from the Dash action.</li>
                    <li>Any additional actions it gains, it can take during your turn at your direction (no action required).</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, when you use an Enhancing Surge or Alternate Effect, you can double the psi points spent to make it affect both you and your Astral Construct (you cannot exceed your normal psi point limit doing this).</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Your Astral Construct can be affected by Enhancing Surge, and for the purposes of Talents, is considered you, though you must choose if you or it receive the benefits.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Elemental Phasing" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion Expanded" id="ID_KT_KTPE_CLASS_FEATURE_PSIONIC_TALENT_ELEMENTAL_PHASING">
            <supports>Kibbles Psionic Talent,Psionic Synthesis</supports>
            <requirements>ID_KT_KTPE_FEAT_PSIONIC_SYNTHESIS,ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE_TRANSPOSITION_DISCIPLINE,ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE_PSYCHOKINETICS_DISCIPLINE</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Psionic Synthesis, Psychokinetics Discipline, Transposition Discipline</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Psionic Synthesis, Psychokinetics Discipline, Transposition Discipline</p>
                <p class="indent">As you step between planes, you can tap into the Elemental Planes, bringing their power into the material with you. You can use Psychokinetic modifiers on Phase Rift (excluding Massive).</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, whenever you deal damage to an area with a Psychokinetics ability that would include yourself, you can phase yourself out of reality taking no damage from the effect.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can use Psychokinetic modifiers on Phase Rift (excluding Massive). Additionally, whenever you deal damage to an area with a Psychokinetics ability that would include yourself, you can phase yourself out of reality taking no damage from the effect.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Kinetic Mastery" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion Expanded" id="ID_KT_KTPE_CLASS_FEATURE_PSIONIC_TALENT_KINETIC_MASTERY">
            <supports>Kibbles Psionic Talent,Psionic Synthesis</supports>
            <requirements>ID_KT_KTPE_FEAT_PSIONIC_SYNTHESIS,ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE_TELEKINESIS_DISCIPLINE,ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE_PSYCHOKINETICS_DISCIPLINE</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Psionic Synthesis, Psychokinetics Discipline, Telekinesis Discipline</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Psionic Synthesis, Psychokinetics Discipline, Telekinesis Discipline</p>
                <p class="indent">Your ability to manipulate energy becomes a single blended prowess, freely swapping between manipulating force and energy. You can apply Telekinetic Force modifiers to Kinetic Blast and Elemental Blast modifiers to Telekinetic Force (though to do not gain any benefits from from a Specialization while doing so).</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can apply Telekinetic Force modifiers to Kinetic Blast and Elemental Blast modifiers to Telekinetic Force (though to do not gain any benefits from from a Specialization while doing so).</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Kinetic Storm" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion Expanded" id="ID_KT_KTPE_CLASS_FEATURE_PSIONIC_TALENT_KINETIC_STORM">
            <supports>Kibbles Psionic Talent,Psionic Synthesis</supports>
            <requirements>ID_KT_KTPE_FEAT_PSIONIC_SYNTHESIS,ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE_TELEKINESIS_DISCIPLINE,ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE_PSYCHOKINETICS_DISCIPLINE</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Psionic Synthesis, Psychokinetics Discipline, Telekinesis Discipline</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Psionic Synthesis, Psychokinetics Discipline, Telekinesis Discipline</p>
                <p class="indent">You as an action, you can expend 3 psi points to cast <i>fire cyclone</i>. If you have a psychokinetic specialization, it becomes the damage type of your specialization.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="3 psi points">
                <description>You can cast fire cyclone. If you have a psychokinetic specialization, it becomes the damage type of your specialization.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Physical Telekinesis" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion Expanded" id="ID_KT_KTPE_CLASS_FEATURE_PSIONIC_TALENT_PHYSICAL_TELEKINESIS">
            <supports>Kibbles Psionic Talent,Psionic Synthesis</supports>
            <requirements>ID_KT_KTPE_FEAT_PSIONIC_SYNTHESIS,ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE_ENHANCEMENT_DISCIPLINE,ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE_TELEKINESIS_DISCIPLINE</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Psionic Synthesis, Enhancement Discipline, Telekinesis Discipline</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Psionic Synthesis, Enhancement Discipline, Telekinesis Discipline</p>
                <p class="indent">When you use a Enhancing Surge to empower a creature, you can expend a psi point augment it with your Telekinesis to further assist them, optionally granting one of the following benefits:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>You can move the creature 10 feet (this movement does not provoke opportunity attacks).</li>
                    <li>You can telekinetically deflect the first weapon attack against them before the start of your next turn, giving that attack disadvantage.</li>
                    <li>You can telekinetically boost their next athletics check or weapon attack before the start of your next turn, granting that check or attack advantage.</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">Addititionally, while under the effect of Enhancing Surge, the amount you can lift, drag, or carry is doubled with assistance of your telekinesis, and you can apply Telekinetic Force modifiers to your weapon attacks.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1 psi point">
                <description>When you use a Enhancing Surge to empower a creature, you can expend a psi point augment it with your Telekinesis to further assist them, optionally granting one benefits. Addititionally, while under the effect of Enhancing Surge, the amount you can lift, drag, or carry is doubled with assistance of your telekinesis, and you can apply Telekinetic Force modifiers to your weapon attacks.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Planar Projections" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion Expanded" id="ID_KT_KTPE_CLASS_FEATURE_PSIONIC_TALENT_PLANAR_PROJECTIONS">
            <supports>Kibbles Psionic Talent,Psionic Synthesis</supports>
            <requirements>ID_KT_KTPE_FEAT_PSIONIC_SYNTHESIS,ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE_TRANSPOSITION_DISCIPLINE,ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE_PROJECTION_DISCIPLINE</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Psionic Synthesis, Projection Discipline, Transposition Discipline</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Psionic Synthesis, Projection Discipline, Transposition Discipline</p>
                <p class="indent">You gain the ability to project beings from other planes into partial reality as magical constructs. You learn the following spells and cast them as Alternate Effects of Projection, expending psi points as shown on the table below to cast them using your Psionics feature. You can cast them at higher levels be expending additional psi points.</p>
                <p class="indent">Unlike other spells cast by the Psionics feature, you need either material component of the spell, or a psionic crystal worth at least 100 gp x the number of psi points spent to cast the spell as the material component; the material component is not consumed by the casting of the spell. Additionally, any of the following spells that you are concentrating ends if you complete a short or long rest.</p>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Psi Points</td><td>Alternate Effect</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>2</td><td>summon beast</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3</td><td>summon fey</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>4</td><td>summon elemental</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5</td><td>summon aberration</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5</td><td>summon celestial</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>6</td><td>summon fiend</td></tr>
                </table>
                <div class="sidebar">
                    <h5 class="caption">Summon Spells</h5>
                    <p>The listed summoning spells can be found in Tasha’s Cauldron of Everything.</p>
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="2+ psi points">
                <description>You can cast specific summoning spells as Alternate Effects of your Projection by expending psi points. You need either material component of the spell, or a psionic crystal worth at least 100 gp x the number of psi points spent to cast the spell as the material component; the material component is not consumed by the casting of the spell. Additionally, any spells that you are concentrating ends if you complete a short or long rest.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Astral Swap" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion Expanded" id="ID_KT_KTPE_CLASS_FEATURE_PSIONIC_TALENT_ASTRAL_SWAP">
            <supports>Kibbles Psionic Talent,Psionic Synthesis</supports>
            <requirements>ID_KT_KTPE_FEAT_PSIONIC_SYNTHESIS,ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE_TRANSPOSITION_DISCIPLINE,ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE_PROJECTION_DISCIPLINE</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Psionic Synthesis, Projection Discipline, Transposition Discipline</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Psionic Synthesis, Projection Discipline, Transposition Discipline</p>
                <p class="indent">As a bonus action, you can Phase Rift to where your Astral Construct is; this movement counts as a Phase Rift, and you can apply modifiers to it as normal. Your Astral Construct is moved to where you started this movement along the Phase Rift; during the movement you can command your Astral Construct to attack a creature pases with its action.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>You can Phase Rift to where your Astral Construct is; this movement counts as a Phase Rift, and you can apply modifiers to it as normal.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Reality Warper" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion Expanded" id="ID_KT_KTPE_CLASS_FEATURE_PSIONIC_TALENT_REALITY_WARPER">
            <supports>Kibbles Psionic Talent,Psionic Synthesis</supports>
            <requirements>ID_KT_KTPE_FEAT_PSIONIC_SYNTHESIS,ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSIONIC_TALENT_MATTER_MADE_REAL,ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSIONIC_TALENT_MENTAL_IMAGE</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Psionic Synthesis, Matter Made Real, Mental Image</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Psionic Synthesis, Matter Made Real, Mental Image</p>
                <p class="indent">You can bring the illusions you make people see to life. When you are concentrating on an illusion spell, as a bonus action you can expend psi points during your turn you can bring aspects of the illusion into reality. For each psi point spent you can bring a 5-foot cube section of the illusion into reality until the start of your next turn, and it can have the following effects:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>If the effect would do damage, each 5-foot cube damage one target. That target must pass a Dexterity saving throw, or take damage equal to a number of d8 dice equal to the level of the spell.</li>
                    <li>If the effect would stop a creature, they cannot move through it. If the effect would restrain a creature, the that creature must pass a Dexterity saving throw or become restrained until the start of your next turn.</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">Each 5-foot cube can effect only one creature that is either within it or adjacent to it. The DM may allow grant it other effects as their discretion.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>When you are concentrating on an illusion spell, you can expend psi points during your turn you can bring aspects of the illusion into reality. For each psi point spent you can bring a 5-foot cube section of the illusion into reality until the start of your next turn.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Phantom Blade Barrage" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion Expanded" id="ID_KT_KTPE_CLASS_FEATURE_PSIONIC_TALENT_PHANTOM_BLADE_BARRAGE">
            <supports>Kibbles Psionic Talent,Psionic Synthesis</supports>
            <requirements>ID_KT_KTPE_FEAT_PSIONIC_SYNTHESIS,ID_KT_KTPE_CLASS_FEATURE_PSIONIC_TALENT_PROJECTED_WEAPONRY,ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSIONIC_TALENT_TELEKINETIC_WEAPONS</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Psionic Synthesis, Projected Weaponry, Telekinetic Weapons</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Psionic Synthesis, Projected Weaponry, Telekinetic Weapons</p>
                <p class="indent">You can create a weapon with Projected Weapon as part of making an attack with it using Telekinetic Weapons, allowing you to project as many weapons in this manner as you make attacks (no additional action required). When you use weapons created by Projected Weaponry as the projectiles for your Telekinetic Weapons, the range you can fling the weapons is doubled.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, if you expend 6 psi points on the Whirling modifier of Telekinetic Weapons, you can cast blade barrier instead of cloud of daggers, generating much larger number of ethereal blades as part of the casting.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can create a weapon with Projected Weapon as part of making an attack with it using Telekinetic Weapons, allowing you to project as many weapons in this manner as you make attacks (no additional action required).</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Parasitic Nightmare" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion Expanded" id="ID_KT_KTPE_CLASS_FEATURE_PSIONIC_TALENT_PARASITIC_NIGHTMARE">
            <supports>Kibbles Psionic Talent,Psionic Synthesis</supports>
            <requirements>ID_KT_KTPE_FEAT_PSIONIC_SYNTHESIS,ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE_TELEPATHY_DISCIPLINE,ID_KT_PSION_EXP_CLASS_FEATURE_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE_CONSUMPTION_DISCIPLINE</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Psionic Synthesis, Consumption Discipline, Telepathy Discipline</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Consumption Discipline, Telepathy Discipline</p>
                <p class="indent">You gain the ability to add Telepathic Intrusion modifiers to Mind Leech.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, when you deal psychic damage to a creature that is frightened of you, you can render yourself invisible to that creature until the start of your next turn; you can immediately (no action required) roll an Intelligence (Stealth) check affecting only creatures you are invisible from as a result of this talent.</p>
                <p class="indent">If you are hidden from a creature that is frightened of you, when it moves, you can use your reaction to teleport to an unoccupied space within 5 feet of that creature (at the completion of their movement).</p>
        <div class="sidebar">
            <h5 class="caption">Rules Interaction</h5>
            <p>The frightened condition impacts a creature while it can see the target it is frightened of. If you are invisible, it cannot see, and will not suffer the conditions of the frightened condition. You are essentially trading the frightened for them being unable to see you.</p>
        </div>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can add Telepathic Intrusion modifiers to Mind Leech. Additionally, when you deal psychic damage to a creature that is frightened of you, you can render yourself invisible to that creature until the start of your next turn. If you are hidden from a creature that is frightened of you, when it moves, you can use your reaction to teleport to an unoccupied space within 5 feet of that creature.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="The Void" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion Expanded" id="ID_KT_KTPE_CLASS_FEATURE_PSIONIC_TALENT_THE_VOID">
            <supports>Kibbles Psionic Talent,Psionic Synthesis</supports>
            <requirements>ID_KT_KTPE_FEAT_PSIONIC_SYNTHESIS,ID_KT_PSION_EXP_CLASS_FEATURE_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE_CONSUMPTION_DISCIPLINE,ID_KT_PSION_EXP_CLASS_FEATURE_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE_NULLIFICATION_DISCIPLINE</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Psionic Synthesis, Consumption Discipline, Nullification Discipline</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Consumption Discipline, Nullification Discipline</p>
                <p class="indent">You devour all supernatural effects near you. Whenever a creature (including yourself) within 5 feet of you takes damage from magical source, you can expend 1 or more psi points to use your reaction to reduce the damage taken by 1d8 per psi point spent. You can divide this amount between multiple creatures within range if they take damage at the same time.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, whenever you successfully cast <i>counterspell</i>, <i>dispel magic</i>, or <i>remove curse</i>, you regain hit points equal to the level of spell stopped or ended.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Whenever a creature (including yourself) within 5 feet of you takes damage from magical source, you can expend 1 or more psi points to use your reaction to reduce the damage taken by 1d8 per psi point spent. You can divide this amount between multiple creatures within range if they take damage at the same time. Additionally, whenever you successfully cast counterspell, dispel magic, or remove curse, you regain hit points equal to the level of spell stopped or ended.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Element Eater" type="Class Feature" source="Kibbles’ Psion Expanded" id="ID_KT_KTPE_CLASS_FEATURE_PSIONIC_TALENT_ELEMENT_EATER">
            <supports>Kibbles Psionic Talent,Psionic Synthesis</supports>
            <requirements>ID_KT_KTPE_FEAT_PSIONIC_SYNTHESIS,ID_KT_PSION_EXP_CLASS_FEATURE_PSIONIC_DISCIPLINE_CONSUMPTION_DISCIPLINE,ID_KT_KTPE_ARCHETYPE_PSION_ELEMENTAL_MIND</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Psionic Synthesis, Elemental Mind, Consumption Discipline</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Elemental Mind, Consumption Discipline</p>
                <p class="indent">Your mind is merged with your elemental power, and it is life and sustainence for you, integrating with your powers of consumption, granting you the following benefits:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>When you cast <i>absorb elements</i> the damage bonus can applied to your Mind Leech power as bonus psychic damage.</li>
                    <li>When a creature with resistance or immunity to Acid, Cold, Fire, Lightning, or Thunder damage fails a saving throw against your Mind Leech power, you gain resistance to the damage type it has resistance or immunity to (if the creature has multiple resistances or immunities to those damage types, you gain one of your choice).</li>
                    <li>You can using the Living Power modifiers Forming or Reaching to turn Mind Leech into a melee or ranged spell attack, as per those modifiers; you cannot add any Modifier that requires the target to fail a saving throw when using it this way.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you cast absorb elements the damage bonus can applied to your Mind Leech power as bonus psychic damage. When a creature with resistance or immunity to Acid, Cold, Fire, Lightning, or Thunder damage fails a saving throw against your Mind Leech power, you gain resistance to the damage type it has resistance or immunity to. You can using the Living Power modifiers Forming or Reaching to turn Mind Leech into a melee or ranged spell attack, as per those modifiers; you cannot add any Modifier that requires the target to fail a saving throw when using it this way.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>


    <!-- Psionic Items -->
        <element name="Amplifying Crystal, Uncommon" type="Magic Item" source="Kibbles’ Psion Expanded" id="ID_source_abbreviation_MAGIC_ITEM_AMPLIFYING_CRYSTAL_UNCOMMON">
            <description>
                <p class="indent">While holding this crystal, you gain a +1 bonus to psionics attack rolls and to the psionic saving throw DCs of your psionic abilities. The bonus is determined by the crystal’s rarity</p>
                <p class="indent">In addition, when you use a psionic power, you can add 1 psi points; these points can only be used on psionic powers, but can exceed your normal psi limit. You can’t use this property again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
                <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
                <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
                <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
                <set name="attunement" addition="by a Psionic">true</set>
                <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
            </setters>
            <rules>
                <stat name="psi:limit" value="1" />
                <stat name="spellcasting:attack" value="1" />
                <stat name="spellcasting:dc" value="1" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Amplifying Crystal, Rare" type="Magic Item" source="Kibbles’ Psion Expanded" id="ID_source_abbreviation_MAGIC_ITEM_AMPLIFYING_CRYSTAL_RARE">
            <description>
                <p class="indent">While holding this crystal, you gain a +2 bonus to psionics attack rolls and to the psionic saving throw DCs of your psionic abilities. The bonus is determined by the crystal’s rarity</p>
                <p class="indent">In addition, when you use a psionic power, you can add 2 psi points; these points can only be used on psionic powers, but can exceed your normal psi limit. You can’t use this property again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
                <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
                <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
                <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
                <set name="attunement" addition="by a Psionic">true</set>
                <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
            </setters>
            <rules>
                <stat name="psi:limit" value="2" />
                <stat name="spellcasting:attack" value="2" />
                <stat name="spellcasting:dc" value="2" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Amplifying Crystal, Very Rare" type="Magic Item" source="Kibbles’ Psion Expanded" id="ID_source_abbreviation_MAGIC_ITEM_AMPLIFYING_CRYSTAL_VERYRARE">
            <description>
                <p class="indent">While holding this crystal, you gain a +3 bonus to psionics attack rolls and to the psionic saving throw DCs of your psionic abilities. The bonus is determined by the crystal’s rarity</p>
                <p class="indent">In addition, when you use a psionic power, you can add 3 psi points; these points can only be used on psionic powers, but can exceed your normal psi limit. You can’t use this property again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
                <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
                <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
                <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
                <set name="attunement" addition="by a Psionic">true</set>
                <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
            </setters>
            <rules>
                <stat name="psi:limit" value="3" />
                <stat name="spellcasting:attack" value="3" />
                <stat name="spellcasting:dc" value="3" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Focusing Crystal" type="Magic Item" source="Kibbles’ Psion Expanded" id="ID_source_abbreviation_MAGIC_ITEM_FOCUSING_CRYSTAL">
            <description>
                <p class="indent">While holding this crystal, you can use it to focus your mind, more perfectly opening your psionic senses. You can use this spell to cast clairvoyance without expending psi points. Once while the effect is active, you can use a Psionic ability (power, spell or talent) that does not deal damage on a creature within range of the sensor as if it was in range and sight of you. You can’t use this property again until you finish a long rest.</p>
                <p class="indent">At the start of your turn, you can focus this crystal (as if concentrating on a spell) and reduce your movement speed to zero. When you do so, until the end of your turn the range of all psionic abilities with a range other than touch are doubled.</p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
                <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
                <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
                <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
                <set name="attunement" addition="by a Psionic">true</set>
                <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
        <element name="Resonating Crystal" type="Magic Item" source="Kibbles’ Psion Expanded" id="ID_source_abbreviation_MAGIC_ITEM_RESONATING_CRYSTAL">
            <description>
                <p class="indent">This is a crystal that has been fundamentally warped by exposure to psionic powers. It now holds the perfect resonance to trap and hold psionic energy, though it does not naturally generate it.</p>
                <p class="indent">While holding this crystal, as an action you can imbue up to 4 psi points into it. While it is imbued it gives off 10 feet of bright light and 10 feet of dim light with a eerie purple hue.</p>
                <p class="indent">If it has one or more points imbued in it, as an action you can reclaim the psi points stored in it, regaining expended psi points from it up to your maximum psi points.</p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
                <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
                <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
                <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
                <set name="attunement" addition="by a Psionic">true</set>
                <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
        <element name="Psi Blade Crystal, Uncommon" type="Magic Item" source="Kibbles’ Psion Expanded" id="ID_source_abbreviation_MAGIC_ITEM_PSI_BLADE_CRYSTAL_UNCOMMON">
            <description>
                <p class="indent">Embedded in a ring, braclet, bladeless sword hilt, or similar item, this small gem seems to have minimal value to the casual observer, but has perfect psionic resonance.</p>
                <p class="indent">While carried by a Way of the Soul Knife Monk, that monk can use this crystal to focus a purer Soul Knife, adding +1 to attack and damage rolls with their Soul Knife.</p>
                <p class="indent">Some crystals come in various colors, and change the hue of your psi blade to match the color of the crystal.</p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
                <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
                <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
                <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
                <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
        <element name="Psi Blade Crystal, Rare" type="Magic Item" source="Kibbles’ Psion Expanded" id="ID_source_abbreviation_MAGIC_ITEM_PSI_BLADE_CRYSTAL_RARE">
            <description>
                <p class="indent">Embedded in a ring, braclet, bladeless sword hilt, or similar item, this small gem seems to have minimal value to the casual observer, but has perfect psionic resonance.</p>
                <p class="indent">While carried by a Way of the Soul Knife Monk, that monk can use this crystal to focus a purer Soul Knife, adding +2 to attack and damage rolls with their Soul Knife.</p>
                <p class="indent">Some crystals come in various colors, and change the hue of your psi blade to match the color of the crystal.</p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
                <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
                <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
                <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
                <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
        <element name="Psi Blade Crystal, Very Rare" type="Magic Item" source="Kibbles’ Psion Expanded" id="ID_source_abbreviation_MAGIC_ITEM_PSI_BLADE_CRYSTAL_VERYRARE">
            <description>
                <p class="indent">Embedded in a ring, braclet, bladeless sword hilt, or similar item, this small gem seems to have minimal value to the casual observer, but has perfect psionic resonance.</p>
                <p class="indent">While carried by a Way of the Soul Knife Monk, that monk can use this crystal to focus a purer Soul Knife, adding +3 to attack and damage rolls with their Soul Knife.</p>
                <p class="indent">Some crystals come in various colors, and change the hue of your psi blade to match the color of the crystal.</p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
                <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
                <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
                <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
                <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
        <element name="Purity of Mind" type="Magic Item" source="Kibbles’ Psion Expanded" id="ID_source_abbreviation_MAGIC_ITEM_PURITY_OF_MIND">
            <description>
                <p class="indent">A blindfold made of heavy silken cloth, it is emblazoned with strange patterns. When worn, you are lose any normal vision that relies on your eyes and are blinded but gain several benefits as your mind is cleared of visual distractions.</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>You gain a mindsight of 60 feet, allowing you to see creatures with an Intelligence of 6 or higher within range as if by blindsight. A creature you are unaware of can still be hidden from you.</li>
                    <li>You gain a blindsight of 10 feet. If you already have a blindsight, its range is increased by 10 feet.</li>
                    <li>You are immune to effects that require you to see the target or effect, even if they are within your mindsight or blindsight.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
                <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
                <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
                <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
                <set name="attunement" addition="by a Psionic">true</set>
                <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
            </setters>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_BLINDSIGHT" />
                <grant type="Vision" id="ID_KT_KTPE_VISION_MINDSIGHT" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Mindsight" type="Vision" source="Kibbles’ Psion Expanded" id="ID_KT_KTPE_VISION_MINDSIGHT">
                <description>
                    <p>You can see creatures with an Intelligence of 6 or higher within range as if by blindsight. A creature you are unaware of can still be hidden from you.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>You can see creatures with an Intelligence of 6 or higher within {{mindsight:range}} feet as if by blindsight. A creature you are unaware of can still be hidden from you.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="mindsight:range" value="60" bonus="base" />
                </rules>
            </element>
        <element name="Psionically Attuned Weapon" type="Magic Item" source="Kibbles’ Psion Expanded" id="ID_source_abbreviation_MAGIC_ITEM_PSIONICALLY_ATTUNED_WEAPON">
            <description>
                <p class="indent">This weapon is perfectly attuned to conducting psionic energy. While wielding it, you gain the Psionic Weapon talent, but it can only be used when targeting this weapon. When you use Psionic Weapon in this way, it requires only 1 psi point to activate.</p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
                <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
                <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
                <set name="type" addition="any melee">Weapon</set>
                <set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_MELEE</set>
                <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
                <set name="name-format">Psionically Attuned {{parent}}</set>
            </setters>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_KT_PSION_CLASS_FEATURE_PSIONIC_TALENT_PSIONIC_WEAPON" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Soul Shard" type="Magic Item" source="Kibbles’ Psion Expanded" id="ID_source_abbreviation_MAGIC_ITEM_SOUL_SHARD">
            <description>
                <p class="indent">A crystalized fragment of a dead psionic creature. How these form, few know. Many suspect dark secrets at their origin. These shards can be driven into the flesh of another psionic creature, dealing 1d4 piercing damage and 4d12 psychic damage and causing them to instantly become attuned to it. When you do so, you gain access to a Psionic Discipline that the creature it was formed from presumably had, along with one flaw formed from the fragment of their soul within the shard.</p>
                <p class="indent">When you find a soul shard, the DM can determine the Discipline it contains and the flaw it confers while attuned, you can roll on the following table to determine them.</p>
                <p class="indent">To unattune to it, must spend an action to try to rip it free. You must succeed a DC 15 Charsma saving throw. Each time you fail this this save, you take 4d12 psychic damage.</p>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>d6</td><td>Discipline</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1</td><td>Telekinesis</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>2</td><td>Telepathy</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3</td><td>Enhancement</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>4</td><td>Psychokinetics</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5</td><td>Transposition</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>6</td><td>Precognition</td></tr>
                </table>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>d6</td><td>Flaw</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1</td><td>Your anger grows harder to control, your eyes change color and start glowing when you become angry.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>2</td><td>You hear a faint screaming at all times. It sounds almost... familiar.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3</td><td>A strange swirling tattoo-like scar very slowly grows from where it pierces you that burns painfully.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>4</td><td>When you sleep, you have nightmares about another life filled with horror, fear and revulsion.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5</td><td>You cannot remember your own name, even when told.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>6</td><td>You grow small vestigial tentacles along your jawline like a strange beard after being attuned to it for 1d4 days.</td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
                <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
                <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
                <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
                <set name="attunement" addition="by a Psionic">true</set>
                <set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
            </setters>
        </element>

</elements>