<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>The Abhorrent</name>
        <author url="https://homebrewery.naturalcrit.com/share/BJXi89joF4">u/AinDaBrain</author>
        <update version="0.0.2">
            <file name="race-abhorrent.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/user/race-abhorrent.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Abhorrent" type="Race" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_RDDT_UA_RACE_ABHORRENT">
        <description>
            <p>In a similar manner of how Tieflings are related to fiends and Aasimar trace their lineage to celestials, Abhorrents are descendants of eldritch entities from the Outer Planes. These humanoids usually come about from pacts with these otherworldly entities, but a few are also sired from Star Spawn that morph themselves into a human-like appearance. Some warlocks even seek out this form in order to better channel their patron’s power, but most are just born into the world corrupted from their ancestors’ lineage. Regardless of how they came about, Abhorrents are usually seen as an ill omen, and, as such, are shunned from many societies.</p>
            <h4>UNNATURAL ORIGINS</h4>
            <p>Most Abhorrents have some kind of physical defect that betrays their heritage. Roll a d4 or choose one of the options below:</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d4</td><td>column2</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>You have an additional eye somewhere on your body, usually on a hand or near your other eyes. You cannot see anything through this eye, but it moves as if it is looking on its own.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>One or more of your phalanges (fingers and toes) have been replaced with a small tentacle. It can bend in any direction, but otherwise functions as the appendage it replaced.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>Your skin color is a shade such as pale green, blue, or purple.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>You have scales, similar to that of a fish, on a few patches of your skin.</td></tr>
            </table>
            <h4>ABHORRENT TRAITS</h4>
            <p>Abhorrents share certain traits due to their alien lineage.</p>
            <p>
                <span class="feature">Ability Score Increase.</span> Your Charisma score increases by 2.<br />
                <span class="feature">Age.</span> Abhorrents mature at the same rate as humans and live to a little over a century.<br />
                <span class="feature">Alien Intelligence.</span> You have resistance to psychic damage.<br />
                <span class="feature">Alignment.</span> Due to their varied lineage, Abhorrents can range anywhere from lawful to chaotic. They usually tend towards evil, though a few turn away from their malevolent ancestry and are of good alignment.<br />
                <span class="feature">Size.</span> Abhorrents are about the same size and build as humans. Your size is Medium.<br />
                <span class="feature">Speed.</span> Your base walking speed is 30 feet.<br />        
                <span class="feature">Subrace.</span> Four subraces of Abhorrents exist, each hailing from a different entity from the Outer Planes.<br />
            </p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="names" type="male"></set>
            <set name="names" type="female"></set>
            <set name="names" type="clan"></set>
            <set name="names-format">{{name}} {{clan}}</set>
            <set name="height" modifier="2d10">4’8"</set>
            <set name="weight" modifier="2d4">110 lb.</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet>
            <description>description</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="charisma" value="2" />
            <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_PSYCHIC" />
            <stat name="innate speed" value="30" bonus="base" />
            <grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_MEDIUM" />
            <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON" />
            <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_DEEP_SPEECH" />
            <select type="List" name="Abhorrent Defect">
                <item id="1">You have an additional eye somewhere on your body, usually on a hand or near your other eyes. You cannot see anything through this eye, but it moves as if it is looking on its own.</item>
                <item id="2">One or more of your phalanges (fingers and toes) have been replaced with a small tentacle. It can bend in any direction, but otherwise functions as the appendage it replaced.</item>
                <item id="3">Your skin color is a shade such as pale green, blue, or purple.</item>
                <item id="4">You have scales, similar to that of a fish, on a few patches of your skin.</item>
            </select>
            <select type="Sub Race" name="Abhorrent Subrace" supports="Abhorrent" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Child of Cthulhu" type="Sub Race" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_RDDT_UA_ABHORRENT_SUBRACE_CHILD_OF_CTHULHU">
        <supports>Abhorrent</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You are a descendant of Cthulhu, the Drowned God, a being that lurks beneath the sea in the city of R’lyeh. Because you are related to this alien being, you can influence the other’s minds with your own.</p>
            <p>
                <span class="feature">Ability Score Increase. </span>Your Wisdom score increases by 1.<br />
            </p>
            <div element="ID_RDDT_UA_ABHORRENT_WHISPERS_OF_THE_DEEP" />
            <div element="ID_RDDT_UA_ABHORRENT_LINKED_MINDS" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="wisdom" value="1" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RDDT_UA_ABHORRENT_WHISPERS_OF_THE_DEEP" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RDDT_UA_ABHORRENT_LINKED_MINDS" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Child of Tharizdun" type="Sub Race" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_RDDT_UA_ABHORRENT_SUBRACE_CHILD_OF_THARIZDUN">
        <supports>Abhorrent</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You are a descendant of Tharizdun, the Chained God, who was imprisoned millenia ago when it tried to destroy existence itself. Whether or not you follow in its footsteps, some of that destructive power still lurks within.</p>
            <p>
                <span class="feature">Ability Score Increase. </span>Your Strength score increases by 1.<br />
            </p>
            <div element="ID_RDDT_UA_ABHORRENT_WORLD_BREAKER" />
            <div element="ID_RDDT_UA_ABHORRENT_DEATHBRINGER_STANCE" level="3" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="strength" value="1" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RDDT_UA_ABHORRENT_WORLD_BREAKER" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RDDT_UA_ABHORRENT_DEATHBRINGER_STANCE" level="3" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Child of Hadar" type="Sub Race" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_RDDT_UA_ABHORRENT_SUBRACE_CHILD_OF_HADAR">
        <supports>Abhorrent</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You are a descendant of Hadar, the Ceaseless Hunger, a being that wishes to feed upon worlds in order to sate its insatiable appetite. As a descendant of this all-consuming being, you carry a portion of its otherworldly hunger.</p>
            <p>
                <span class="feature">Ability Score Increase. </span>Your Constitution score increases by 1.<br />
            </p>
            <div element="ID_RDDT_UA_ABHORRENT_THE_ETERNAL_HUNGER" />
            <div element="ID_RDDT_UA_ABHORRENT_SOUL_REND" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="constitution" value="1" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RDDT_UA_ABHORRENT_THE_ETERNAL_HUNGER" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RDDT_UA_ABHORRENT_SOUL_REND" level="3" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Child of Ilsensine" type="Sub Race" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_RDDT_UA_ABHORRENT_SUBRACE_CHILD_OF_ILSENSINE">
        <supports>Abhorrent</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You are a descendant of Ilsensine, a being that strives to enslave mortals and learn all there is to be know. As the patron deity of illithids and evil mind mages, it is known for its ever-expanding well of knowledge and for its ability to subjugate others to its will.</p>
            <p>
                <span class="feature">Ability Score Increase. </span>Your Intelligence score increases by 1.<br />
            </p>
            <div element="ID_RDDT_UA_ABHORRENT_SOOTHE_THE_MIND" />
            <div element="ID_RDDT_UA_ABHORRENT_OTHERWORLDLY_INTELLECT" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="intelligence" value="1" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RDDT_UA_ABHORRENT_SOOTHE_THE_MIND" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RDDT_UA_ABHORRENT_OTHERWORLDLY_INTELLECT" level="3" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Whispers of the Deep" type="Racial Trait" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_RDDT_UA_ABHORRENT_WHISPERS_OF_THE_DEEP">
        <description>
            <p>You know the spell <i>dissonant whispers</i> and can cast it once using this trait without using a spell slot. Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this spell. You regain the ability to cast it this way once you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can cast dissonant whispers without using a spell slot.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISSONANT_WHISPERS" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Linked Minds" type="Racial Trait" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_RDDT_UA_ABHORRENT_LINKED_MINDS">
        <description>
            <p>At the end of each long rest, you can choose up to five other creatures. While those creatures are within 30 feet of you, they can communicate telepathically with you and other linked creatures that are within range.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>At the end of each long rest, you can choose up to five other creatures. While those creatures are within 30 feet of you, they can communicate telepathically with you and other linked creatures that are within range.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    
    <element name="World Breaker" type="Racial Trait" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_RDDT_UA_ABHORRENT_WORLD_BREAKER">
        <description>
            <p>You know the spell <i>earth tremor</i> and can cast it once using this trait without using a spell slot. Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this spell. You regain the ability to cast it this way once you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>You can cast earth tremor without using a spell slot.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_EARTH_TREMOR" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Deathbringer Stance" type="Racial Trait" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_RDDT_UA_ABHORRENT_DEATHBRINGER_STANCE">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 3rd level, your relation to Tharizdun allows you to channel some of its destructive power. As a bonus action, you can unleash your innate destructive energy to cause yourself to be wreathed in eldritch power for one minute or until you end it as a bonus action. Once per turn while empowered this way, you can deal bonus thunder damage to one target when you damage it with a melee attack. This bonus damage is equal to half of your level + your Charisma modifier (minimum of one). Once you use this trait, you can’t use it again until you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Bonus Action">
            <description>You can wreathe yourself in eldritch power. Once per turn while empowered this way, you can deal {{deathbringer:level}} hit points bonus thunder damage to one target when you damage it with a melee attack.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="deathbringer:damage" value="1" bonus="damage" />
            <stat name="deathbringer:level" value="level:half" />
            <stat name="deathbringer:level" value="charisma:modifier" />
            <stat name="deathbringer:damage" value="deathbringer:level" bonus="damage" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    
    <element name="The Eternal Hunger" type="Racial Trait" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_RDDT_UA_ABHORRENT_THE_ETERNAL_HUNGER">
        <description>
            <p>ou know the spell <i>arms of Hadar</i> and can cast it once using this trait without using a spell slot. Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this spell. You regain the ability to cast it this way once you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>You can cast arms of Hadar without using a spell slot.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ARMS_OF_HADAR" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Soul Rend" type="Racial Trait" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_RDDT_UA_ABHORRENT_SOUL_REND">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 3rd level, your relation to Hadar allows you to channel some of its life ending power. When you damage a creature you can see within 120 feet of you and reduce its hit points to a number equal to or less than your level + your Charisma modifier (minimum of 5), you can cause it to drop to 0 hit points instead. This has no effect on constructs or undead. You can only use this trait once per turn. If you cast Arms of Hadar using The Eternal Hunger, you can choose to Soul Rend all creatures damaged, provided you haven’t already used this trait this turn.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Action">
            <description>When you damage a creature you can see within 120 feet of you and reduce its hit points to a number equal to or less than {{soul rend:limit}}, you can cause it to drop to 0 hit points instead. This has no effect on constructs or undead. You can only use this trait once per turn. If you cast Arms of Hadar using The Eternal Hunger, you can choose to Soul Rend all creatures damaged, provided you haven’t already used this trait this turn.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="soul rend:limit" value="5" bonus="limit" />
            <stat name="soul rend:level" value="level" />
            <stat name="soul rend:level" value="charisma:modifier" />
            <stat name="soul rend:limit" value="soul rend:level" bonus="limit" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Soothe the Mind" type="Racial Trait" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_RDDT_UA_ABHORRENT_SOOTHE_THE_MIND">
        <description>
            <p>You know the spell <i>charm person</i> and can cast it once using this trait without using a spell slot. Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this spell. You regain the ability to cast it this way once you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>You can cast charm person without using a spell slot.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CHARM_PERSON" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Otherworldly Intellect" type="Racial Trait" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_RDDT_UA_ABHORRENT_OTHERWORLDLY_INTELLECT">
        <description>
            <p>tarting at 3rd level, your relation to Ilsensine allows you to call upon its malign intellect, which carries a risk to one’s sanity. As an action, you can choose a creature within 60 feet of you and make a DC 10 Intelligence saving throw. On a failed save, you take 1d4 psychic damage which can’t be prevented in any way. On a success, you learn what the creature is, any vulnerabilities, resistances, or immunities that creature has, and you gain advantage on attack rolls against it until the end of your next turn. Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a short or a long rest. At your DM’s discretion, passing the saving throw could allow you to gain insight about an object you can see within range, or event that has happened in the past that you have at least heard about.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Short Rest">
            <description>You can choose a creature within 60 feet of you and make a DC 10 Intelligence saving throw. On a failed save, you take 1d4 psychic damage which can’t be prevented in any way. On a success, you learn what the creature is, any vulnerabilities, resistances, or immunities that creature has, and you gain advantage on attack rolls against it until the end of your next turn.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    
</elements>