<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Faerie</name>
        <author url="https://homebrewery.naturalcrit.com/share/SkQME8w6V" />
        <update version="0.0.3">
            <file name="race-faerie.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/races/race-faerie.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>

  <element name="Faerie" type="Race" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_RDDT_RACE_FAERIE">
      <description>
          <p>Faeries are creatures of the Feywild. They often appear human or elven in nature, many of them having red hair and green eyes. All faeries possess an innate gift for magic, which they call glamour. This glamour allows them to manipulate the sight of others. It can be used to hide their true selves or to cause some good-hearted mischief. While faeries are naturally the size of humans, they have the ability to temporarily shrink down in size, allowing them to get around unseen and to even fly around.</p>
          <h4>FAERIE TRAITS</h4>
          <p>Your faerie character possesses these traits.</p>
          <span class="feature">Ability Score Increase.</span> Your Charisma score increases by 2, and your Dexterity score increases by 1.
          <br />
          <span class="feature">Age.</span> Although faeries reach physical maturity at about the same age as humans, they can live up to 750 years old.
          <br />
          <span class="feature">Alignment.</span> Faeries are typically good in nature, sometimes causing some mischief. They often lean towards chaotic or neutral good, although it isn’t unheard of some faeries being evil.
          <br />
          <span class="feature">Size.</span> Faeries range from barely over 5 feet tall to well over 6 feet tall. Your size is Medium.
          <br />
          <span class="feature">Speed.</span> Your base walking speed is 30 feet.
          <br />
          <span class="feature">Glamour.</span> You know the *minor illusion* cantrip. When you reach 3rd level, you can cast the *disguise self* spell once with this trait and regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest. When you reach 5th level, you can cast the *invisibility* spell on yourself once with this trait and regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest. Charisma is your spellcasting ability for these spells.
          <br />
          <span class="feature">Fey Ancestry.</span> You have advantage on saving throws against being charmed and magic can’t put you to sleep.
          <br />
          <span class="feature">Fairy Form.</span> As an action, you can shrink yourself, and your equipment, down to a very small size. This transformation lasts for 10 minutes. While in fairy form, your size is tiny. You have a walking speed of 10 feet but sprout insect-like wings and gain a fly speed of 30 feet. You have advantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks and can attempt to hide even when you are obscured only by a creature that is at least one size larger than you. You can move through the space of any creature that is of a size larger than yours and can fit through spaces as small as 15 inches. However, you do not gain any benefits from armor or shields, you have disadvantage on Strength Checks and Strength Saving Throws, and your weapon attacks deal 1d4 less damage (this can\’t reduce the damage below 1). Once the 10 minutes are up, or you are reduced to 0 hit points, you revert to your original form, or you may also revert back early as an action. Once you use this trait, you cannot use it again until you finish a long rest.
          <br />
          <span class="feature">Language.</span> You can speak, read, and write Common and Sylvan.
      </description>
      <sheet display="false">
          <description />
      </sheet>
    <setters>
      <set name="names" type="male">Avon, Aodh, Cedar, Jeremy, Midnight, Moptop, Mitah, Willow, Tarragon, Flax, Nimbus, Echo, Cricket</set>
      <set name="names" type="female">April, Alina, Clover, Whirl, Petal, Celestia, Ivory, Selene, Corona, Thallia, Dahlia, Palmera, Mythia, Hiedra, Jessamine</set>
      <set name="names" type="clan">Shadowbay, Amaranthe, Cozymint, Mistythistle, Silverhill, Windybell, Glitterwing, Lightningfruit, Candlespeck, Vanillaspirit, Shimmerfig, Mangosong, Amberbutton, Sweetwhite</set>
      <set name="names-format">{{name}} {{clan}}</set>
      <set name="height" modifier="2d10">4’8"</set>
      <set name="weight" modifier="2d4">90 lb.</set>
    </setters>
    <rules>
      <stat name="charisma" value="2" />
      <stat name="dexterity" value="1" />
      <stat name="innate speed" value="30" bonus="base" />
      <grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_MEDIUM" />
      <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON" />
      <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_SYLVAN" />
      <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RDDT_RACIAL_TRAIT_FAERIE_GLAMOUR" />
      <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RDDT_RACIAL_TRAIT_FAERIE_FEY_ANCESTRY" />
      <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RDDT_RACIAL_TRAIT_FAERIE_FORM" />
    </rules>
  </element>

  <element name="Glamour" type="Racial Trait" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_RDDT_RACIAL_TRAIT_FAERIE_GLAMOUR">
    <supports />
    <requirements />
    <description>
      <p>You know the <i>minor illusion</i> cantrip. When you reach 3rd level, you can cast the <i>disguise self</i> spell once with this trait and regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest. When you reach 5th level, you can cast the <i>invisibility</i> spell on yourself once with this trait and regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest. Charisma is your spellcasting ability for these spells.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description level="1">You know the minor illusion cantrip.</description>
      <description level="3">You know the minor illusion cantrip and you can cast disguise self once per long rest.</description>
      <description level="5">You know the minor illusion cantrip and you can cast disguise self and invisibility on yourself once per long rest.</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules>
      <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MINOR_ILLUSION" level="1" />
      <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISGUISE_SELF" level="3" />
      <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INVISIBILITY" level="5" />
    </rules>
  </element>

  <element name="Fey Ancestry" type="Racial Trait" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_RDDT_RACIAL_TRAIT_FAERIE_FEY_ANCESTRY">
    <supports />
    <requirements />
    <description>
      <p>You have advantage on saving throws against being charmed and magic can’t put you to sleep.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>You have advantage on saving throws against being charmed and magic can’t put you to sleep.</description>
    </sheet>
  </element>

  <element name="Faerie Form" type="Racial Trait" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_RDDT_RACIAL_TRAIT_FAERIE_FORM">
    <supports />
    <requirements />
    <description>
      <p>As an action, you can shrink yourself, and your equipment, down to a very small size. This transformation lasts for 10 minutes. While in fairy form, your size is tiny. You have a walking speed of 10 feet but sprout insect-like wings and gain a fly speed of 30 feet. You have advantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks and can attempt to hide even when you are obscured only by a creature that is at least one size larger than you. You can move through the space of any creature that is of a size larger than yours and can fit through spaces as small as 15 inches. However, you do not gain any benefits from armor or shields, you have disadvantage on Strength Checks and Strength Saving Throws, and your weapon attacks deal 1d4 less damage (this can’t reduce the damage below 1). Once the 10 minutes are up, or you are reduced to 0 hit points, you revert to your original form, or you may also revert back early as an action. Once you use this trait, you cannot use it again until you finish a long rest.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
      <description>You can shrink yourself and your equipment into a tiny winged faerie form. Your walking speed is 10 feet but you gain a fly speed of 30 feet. You have advantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks and you can hide even when you are obscured by a creature only one size larger than you. You can fit through spaces as small as 15 inches. You lose all benefits of armor and shields, have disadvantage on Strength checks and saving throws and your weapon attacks do 1d4 less damage (minimum of 1). The transformation lasts 10 minutes or until you are reduced to 0 hit points.</description>
    </sheet>
  </element>
</elements>