<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
  <info>
    <name>Koradi</name>
    <description/>
    <author url="https://www.gmbinder.com/share/-LeSx_aycIgna2IBD5KK">@Ivy.Witchfire</author>
    <update version="0.18">
      <file name="race-koradi.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/user/race-koradi.xml" />
    </update>
  </info>

  <element name="Koradi" type="Race" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_RACE_KORADI">
    <description>
      <p class="flavor">ko-RAH-dee</p>
      <p>
        A hush falls over the deepest parts of the woods as a party of hunters tracks their unfortunate prey. Unbeknown to them, a slender olive-skinned humanoid crouches on a tree branch, entirely unnoticed She carefully plans her every move in order to remain undetected. Ears twitch and eyes squint as the koradi huntress slowly tracks behind the party, the hunters becoming the hunted. Her hand embraces the curves of the bow she made herself with a firm grip. It is well worn, but she knows it is reliable. As her feet weightlessly skim tree bark a foot knocks a loose branch, sending it tumbling down onto the carpeted floor. The hunters take notice and turn around to face her but before they can react she is long gone.
        <br />
        <span class="indent"/>
        The Koradi race is a secretive and protective one defined by the natural environment. Though they rarely interact with outsiders, they live in clan-like communities that share in a mutual relationships with the lands they call home.
      </p>
      <h4>EVOLVED PLANTFOLK</h4>
      <p>
        Though koradi are not plants themselves, their attunement with nature has given them biological traits similar to those of the plants they deem sacred. Koradi skin often takes earthen tones that deepens as they age to help them blend into the local lands. Eye colors vary greatly but are generally hazel or green in tint with an almond shaped iris. Their hair will range from common human tones to vibrant greens and whites. Those who are born with less exotic skin tones generally find an easier time assimilating with human society, though even the fairest skinned koradi will have a noticeable tint.
        <br />
        <span class="indent"/>
        However, the most distinguishable feature of koradi lies in their more naturalistic elements. Koradi from the deep woods will have bark like skin which resembles trees, while those from the swamp have amphibian-like skin. All koradi have various plant-like markings or growths over their body- sometimes symmetrical and sometimes not. These markings help the koradi blend in with the local lands and are used by outsiders to further differentiate them from one another. Koradi with the largest and most visible markings are held with the highest esteem among their community.
      </p>
      <h4>CLAN AND COMMUNITY</h4>
      <p>
        Koradi are an extremely resourceful folk who often create the tools they need from materials found in their homeland. As they will almost never purposely harm a plant or tree, they instead gather these materials from tree limbs that have fallen due to a storm or animals that perished due to natural causes. However, the bulk of their resource gathering comes from trading amongst their own clan and with neighboring koradi clans.
        <br />
        <span class="indent"/>
        These resourceful folk tend to organize themselves into clans that support and protect each individual member. Any materials or wealth they obtain are usually shared amongst their clan, though koradi will still keep personal belongings of high importance to themselves. Koradi clans often revolve themselves around one or two resources native to their homeland and will freely trade with other clans and the few creatures they trust, exchanging materials found in one region for those found in another.
      </p>
      <h4>NATURE’S WARDENS</h4>
      <p>
        As creatures who thrive and live off of the land, koradi have an obligation to protect their homes from anyone who seeks to cause harm to them. Hunters who (often unknowingly) stumble into a koradi clan’s territory must be extremely careful to avoid harming the environment so as to avoid being confronted by them. Harming a single koradi or sometimes even a single tree they hold sacred may cause the whole clan to turn against someone. On the other hand, koradi will guarantee safe passage through hazardous terrain to people who prove their alliance.
        <br />
        <span class="indent"/>
        Koradi are not greedy beings and will rarely perform tasks in exchange for money. They instead prefer to barter using goods and services. Because they often have to to share their lands with fey, they tend to have an instinctual trust for them- especially with dryads and other woodland protectors. Koradi will usually stay away from half-orcs and dwarves and will keep a close eye on humans, but a koradi will be quick to trust a gnome or an elf. Regardless of race however, a koradi hold a creature’s affinity (or lack of) towards nature above all else. It is for this reason that the only humans who have ever gained the trust of a koradi clan have been druids or hermits.
      </p>
      <h4>ARTFUL HUNTERS</h4>
      <p>
        Koradi are magical beings with a deep love for art, lore, and above all nature. Their equipment is expertly crafted from natural materials and is often expertly decorated with engravings and adornments. While many take up roles within their clan as dedicated farmers or healers, some will go on to train as silent trackers and warriors, perfecting their hunting and magical abilities in the process. Becoming a protector within your clan is viewed as a sign of great honor.
        <br />
        <span class="indent"/>
        Though few ever leave their clan and the local lands, the ones who leave the comfort of the woods may do so as a result of their natural curiosity, a desire for a better life, or sometimes even exile. They tend to put their skills to use in the outside world as sages, rangers, soldiers, herbalists, medicine men, and sometimes even adventurers.
      </p>
      <h4>KORADI NAMES</h4>
      <p>Koradi know each other primarily through their distinct markings and role within their clan. They usually only have a single name assigned to them by either their grandparents or the clan elder. Most koradi names are sylvan in nature and resemble those of elves, gnomes, and other fey. They lack a formal last name and instead use their clan name when required. Koradi clan names are more often than not based off of the materials and resources found within their territory.</p>
      <p>
        <span class="emphasis">Male Names:</span>
        Aldon, Alser, Bilmorn, Calwin, Darfin, Eldron, Erryn, Errick, Hagas, Klaern, Salen, Tanion, Valrick, Wirenth, Wrelin, Zaos
        <br />
        <span class="emphasis">Female Names:</span>
        Alimer, Arryn, Ava, Ellarian, Gaylia, Itariae, Lhuna, Naumys, Nuovis, Radelia, Sylmae, Teryani, Thalia, Yhendorn, Zentha
        <br />
        <span class="emphasis">Clan Names:</span>
        Alderwood, Amaranthe, Artemisia, Ashtree, Balsame, Calypto, Clove, Fennel, Helmlocke, Lily, Oaknut, Roselia, Spruce, Willow
      </p>
      <h4>KORADI TRAITS</h4>
      <p>Koradi are clever creatures who must also be hardy enough to survive in the wilderness. Your koradi character has the following traits in common with other koradi.</p>
      <p>
        <span class="feature">Ability Score Increase.</span>
        Your Wisdom score increases by 2, and your Constitution score increases by 1.
        <br />
        <span class="feature">Age.</span>
        Koradi age slightly slower than humans and reach maturity at 20 years of age. The oldest koradi can live up to 150 years.
        <br />
        <span class="feature">Alignment.</span>
        Koradi are incredibly respectful of their ancestors and rarely attack without reason, lending them towards a more lawful alignment. Evil aligned Koradi are few and far between as their interests lie in the preservation of their homes and society.
        <br />
        <span class="feature">Size.</span>
        Koradi are about the same size and build as humans. Your size is Medium.
        <br />
        <span class="feature">Speed.</span>
        Your base walking speed is 30 feet.
        <br />
        <span class="feature">Natural Camouflage.</span>
        You have advantage when trying to hide in densely foliaged areas such as swamps and forests and can try to hide in light foliage. You lose these benefits if you don medium or heavy armor.
        <br />
        <span class="feature">Verdant Being.</span>
        You know the
        <em>druidcraft</em>
        cantrip and can cast it at will. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for it.
        <br />
        <span class="feature">Folk Remedies.</span>
        You are proficient with herbalism kits.
        <br />
        <span class="feature">Languages.</span>
        You can speak, read, and write Common and one language known by the people your clan trades with, most often Sylvan, Gnomish, or Elvish.
        <br />
        <span class="feature">Subrace.</span>
        Koradi from different climates and regions tend to develop slightly different characteristics. The most common koradi come from either forested areas and are known as wildhearts, or from swampy regions and are known as mosshearts.
        <br />
      </p>
      <div element="ID_RACE_VARIANT_KORADI_VARIANT"/>
    </description>
    <sheet display="false" />
    <setters>
      <set name="names" type="male">Aldon, Alser, Bilmorn, Calwin, Darfin, Eldron, Erryn, Errick, Hagas, Klaern, Salen, Tanion, Valrick, Wirenth, Wrelin, Zaos</set>
      <set name="names" type="female">Alimer, Arryn, Ava, Ellarian, Gaylia, Itariae, Lhuna, Naumys, Nuovis, Radelia, Sylmae, Teryani, Thalia, Yhendorn, Zentha</set>
      <set name="names" type="clan">Alderwood, Amaranthe, Artemisia, Ashtree, Balsame, Calypto, Clove, Fennel, Helmlocke, Lily, Oaknut, Roselia, Spruce, Willow</set>
      <set name="names-format">{{name}} {{clan}}</set>
      <set name="height" modifier="2d10">4’8"</set>
      <set name="weight" modifier="2d4">110 lb.</set>
    </setters>
    <rules>
      <stat name="wisdom" value="2" />
      <stat name="constitution" value="1" />
      <stat name="innate speed" value="30" bonus="base" />
      <grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_MEDIUM" />
      <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON" />
      <select type="Language" name="Language (Koradi)" supports="Starting" />
      <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_NATURAL_CAMOUFLAGE" />
      <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_VERDANT_BEING" requirements="!ID_RACE_VARIANT_KORADI_VARIANT" />
      <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_FOLK_REMEDIES" />
      <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_KORADI_SUBRACE" />
      <select type="Race Variant" name="Koradi Variant" supports="Koradi" optional="true" />
    </rules>
  </element>

  <element name="Natural Camouflage" type="Racial Trait" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_NATURAL_CAMOUFLAGE">
    <supports />
    <requirements />
    <description>
      <p>You have advantage when trying to hide in densely foliaged areas such as swamps and forests and can try to hide in light foliage. You lose these benefits if you don medium or heavy armor.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>You have advantage when trying to hide in densely foliaged areas such as swamps and forests and can try to hide in light foliage. You lose these benefits if you don medium or heavy armor.</description>
    </sheet>
  </element>

  <element name="Verdant Being" type="Racial Trait" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_VERDANT_BEING">
    <supports />
    <requirements />
    <description>
      <p>
        You know the
        <em>druidcraft</em>
        cantrip and can cast it at will. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for it.
      </p>
    </description>
    <sheet display="false">
      <description>
        You know the
        <em>druidcraft</em>
        cantrip and can cast it at will. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for it.
      </description>
    </sheet>
    <rules>
      <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DRUIDCRAFT" />
    </rules>
  </element>

  <element name="Folk Remedies" type="Racial Trait" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_FOLK_REMEDIES">
    <supports />
    <requirements />
    <description>
      <p>You are proficient with herbalism kits.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet display="false"/>
    <rules>
      <select type="Proficiency" name="Folk Remedies" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_HERBALISM_KIT" />
    </rules>
  </element>

  <element name="Koradi Subrace" type="Racial Trait" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_KORADI_SUBRACE">
    <supports/>
    <requirements />
    <description>
      <p>Koradi from different climates and regions tend to develop slightly different characteristics. The most common koradi come from either forested areas and are known as wildhearts, or from swampy regions and are known as mosshearts.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet display="false"/>
    <rules>
      <select type="Sub Race" name="Koradi Subrace" supports="Koradi" />
    </rules>
  </element>

  <element name="Wildheart" type="Sub Race" source="GM Binder" id="ID_SUB_RACE_WILDHEART">
    <supports>Koradi</supports>
    <requirements />
    <description>
      <p>
        As a wildheart koradi, you come from a heavily forested region such as those found deep within the Feywild. You long for the untamed wilds–the places untouched by civilization, and your biology shows it.
        <br />
        <span class="indent"/>
        Wildhearts tend to have dark green or brown skin characterized by visible patches of rough, bark-like texture. Your skin is thicker than most other creatures’, resembling the bark on the trees from your homeland. As a wildheart you have the following traits.
      </p>
      <p>
        <span class="feature">Thick Hide.</span>
        Your skin has adapted to protect you without the need for cumbersome armor. You gain a +1 bonus to your AC while you are unarmored or lightly armored.
        <br />
        <span class="feature">Tree Climbers.</span> You have a climbing speed of 30 feet and you are not easily frightened by heights.
      </p>
    </description>
    <sheet display="false" />
    <setters />
    <rules>
      <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_KORADI_THICK_HIDE" />
      <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_KORADI_TREE_CLIMBERS" />
    </rules>
  </element>

  <element name="Thick Hide" type="Racial Trait" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_KORADI_THICK_HIDE">
    <supports />
    <requirements />
    <description>
      <p>Your skin has adapted to protect you without the need for cumbersome armor. You gain a +1 bonus to your AC while you are unarmored or lightly armored.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet display="false">
      <description>Your skin has adapted to protect you without the need for cumbersome armor. You gain a +1 bonus to your AC while you are unarmored or lightly armored.</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules>
      <stat name="ac:misc" value="1" equipped="[armor:none]" alt="Thick Hide" />
      <stat name="ac:misc" value="1" equipped="[armor:light]" alt="Thick Hide" />
    </rules>
  </element>

  <element name="Tree Climbers" type="Racial Trait" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_KORADI_TREE_CLIMBERS">
    <supports />
    <requirements />
    <description>
      <p>You have a climbing speed of 30 feet and you are not easily frightened by heights.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet display="false">
      <description>You have a climbing speed of 30 feet and you are not easily frightened by heights.</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules>
      <stat name="innate speed:climb" value="30" bonus="base" />
    </rules>
  </element>

  <element name="Mossheart" type="Sub Race" source="GM Binder" id="ID_SUB_RACE_MOSSHEART">
    <supports>Koradi</supports>
    <requirements />
    <description>
      <p>As a mossheart koradi, you are used to the damp soil and bogs of the dense swamps. You are extremely well versed in navigating the fast flowing rivers of the region and have adapted to a life surrounded by dangerous plants and creatures.<br /><span class="indent" />Mossheart skin tends to be slightly lighter, often with an olive or turquoise hue to it. Your skin is soft to the touch and shimmers slightly in the light as if it were perpetually damp. As a mossheart you have the following traits.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet display="false" />
    <setters />
    <rules>
      <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_KORADI_POISON_RESISTANCE" />
      <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_KORADI_BORN_SWIMMERS" />
    </rules>
  </element>

  <element name="Poison Resistance" type="Racial Trait" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_KORADI_POISON_RESISTANCE">
    <supports />
    <requirements />
    <description>
      <p>The deadly toxins in your natural environment have forced you to evolve a natural resistance against them. You have advantage on saving throws against poison, and gain resistance to poison damage.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>You have advantage on saving throws against poison, and gain resistance to poison damage.</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules>
		  <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_POISON" />
    </rules>
  </element>

  <element name="Born Swimmers" type="Racial Trait" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_KORADI_BORN_SWIMMERS">
    <supports />
    <requirements />
    <description>
      <p>You have a swimming speed of 30 feet and can hold your breath for up to 15 minutes.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>You have a swimming speed of 30 feet and can hold your breath for up to 15 minutes.</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules>
      <stat name="innate speed:swim" value="30" bonus="base" />
    </rules>
  </element>

  <element name="Winterborn" type="Sub Race" source="GM Binder" id="ID_SUB_RACE_WINTERBORN">
    <supports>Koradi</supports>
    <requirements />
    <description>
      <p>A special breed of koradi known as the winterborn exist in the tundras and evergreen forests of the world. Unlike koradi from the swamps and woods who create permament dwellings for themselves, winterborn rarely stay in one place for an extended period of time. The harsh cold and strong winds of such regions make farming extremely difficult, so winterborn instead migrate alongside the local animals.<br /><span class="indent" />Winterborn koradi have pine green or dusty brown skin tones with dark striations resembling pine needles. They will often decorate their thick, dread-like hair to resemble the native coniferous forests. As a winterborn koradi, you have the following traits.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet display="false" />
    <setters />
    <rules>
      <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_KORADI_ARCTIC_ACCLIMATION" />
      <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_KORADI_NOMADIC_PHYSIOLOGY" />
    </rules>
  </element>

  <element name="Arctic Acclimation" type="Racial Trait" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_KORADI_ARCTIC_ACCLIMATION">
    <supports />
    <requirements />
    <description>
      <p>You resist cold damage and the effects of cold climates.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>You resist cold damage and the effects of cold climates.</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules>
		  <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_COLD" />
    </rules>
  </element>

  <element name="Nomdadic Physiology" type="Racial Trait" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_KORADI_NOMADIC_PHYSIOLOGY">
    <supports />
    <requirements />
    <description>
      <p>Your body has evolved to allow you to travel across across vast swaths of frozen terrain. You can travel twice as far as a normal person without getting exhausted, and difficult terrain made of ice or snow does not slow your movement.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>You can travel twice as far as a normal person without getting exhausted, and difficult terrain made of ice or snow does not slow your movement.</description>
    </sheet>
  </element>

  <element name="Darkborn" type="Sub Race" source="GM Binder" id="ID_SUB_RACE_DARKBORN">
    <supports>Koradi</supports>
    <requirements />
    <description>
      <p>The rarest of the koradi race can be found deep inside caves or the underdark. Despite being surrounded by notoriously evil creatures, underdark koradi rarely have evil motivations. However, they are far more likely to attack in retaliation. These koradi especially rely upon their reclusive habits for self preservation and protection.<br /><span class="indent" />Your biology has shifted slightly to resemble the fungi of the underdark. Your skin tone ranges between shades of gray or purple and features prominent red or white spotting. As an underdark koradi you have the following traits.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet display="false" />
    <setters />
    <rules>
      <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_KORADI_TOXIC_TOUCH" />
      <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_KORADI_DARKVISION" />
    </rules>
  </element>

  <element name="Toxic Touch" type="Racial Trait" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_KORADI_TOXIC_TOUCH">
    <supports />
    <requirements />
    <description>
      <p>Your touch secretes a mild toxin that is harmful to most creatures. As your bonus action, you can force a creature grappling you, grappled by you, or otherwise in prolonged contact with you to make a Constitution saving throw (save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Constitution modifier). On a failed save the target becomes poisoned until the end of its next turn. You must then finish a short or long rest before you can use this ability again.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet usage="1/Short Rest" action="Bonus Action">
      <description>You can force a creature grappling you, grappled by your, or otherwise in prolonged contact with you to make a Constitution saving throw (save DC = {{darkborn:touch:savedc}}). On a failed save the target becomes poisioned until the end of its next turn.</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules>
      <stat name="darkborn:touch:savedc" value="8" />
      <stat name="darkborn:touch:savedc" value="constitution:modifer" />
      <stat name="darkborn:touch:savedc" value="proficiency" />
    </rules>
  </element>

  <element name="Darkvision" type="Racial Trait" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_KORADI_DARKVISION">
    <supports />
    <requirements />
    <description>
      <p>You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can’t discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet display="false">
      <description>You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can’t discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules>
      <grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_DARKVISION" />
    </rules>
  </element>

  <element name="Koradi Variant" type="Race Variant" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RACE_VARIANT_KORADI_VARIANT">
    <supports>Koradi</supports>
    <requirements />
    <description>
      <p>You can select the following trait in place of the koradi’s <em>verdant being</em> ability.<br /><span class="indent" /><span class="feature">Salutary of Nature.</span> You can cast the <em>goodberry</em> spell once using this trait and regain the ability to do so after a long rest. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for it.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet alt="Koradi" display="false"/>
    <rules>
      <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_SALUTARY_OF_NATURE" />
    </rules>
  </element>

  <element name="Salutary of Nature" type="Racial Trait" source="GM Binder" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_SALUTARY_OF_NATURE">
    <supports />
    <requirements />
    <description>
      <p>
        You can select the <em>salutary of nature</em> trait in place of the koradi’s <em>verdant being</em> ability.<br /><span class="indent"/>You can cast the <em>goodberry</em> spell once using this trait and regain the ability to do so after a long rest. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for it.
      </p>
    </description>
    <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
      <description>
        You can cast the <em>goodberry</em> spell once using this trait and regain the ability to do so after a long rest. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for it.
      </description>
    </sheet>
    <rules>
      <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GOODBERRY" />
    </rules>
  </element>

  <element name="Koradi Warrior Training" type="Feat" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_FEAT_KORADI_WARRIOR_TRAINING">
    <prerequisite>Koradi</prerequisite>
    <requirements>ID_GM_BINDER_RACE_KORADI</requirements>
    <description>
			<p><i>Prerequisite: Koradi</i></p>
      <p>You have undergone training in the weapons and tactics employed by your clan’s warriors. You gain the following traits.</p>
      <ul>
        <li>Increase your Dexterity score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</li>
        <li>You gain proficiency with blowguns, shortbows, and scimitars.</li>
        <li>Making a ranged attack from a concealed position using a blowgun, shortbow, or longbow does not immediately give away your position, though repeated attacks may.</li>
      </ul>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Making a ranged attack from a concealed position using a blowgun, shortbow, or longbow does not immediately give away your position, though repeated attacks may.</description>
    </sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="dexterity" value="1" />
      <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_BLOWGUN" />
      <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SHORTBOW" />
      <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_LONGBOW" />
		</rules>
  </element>

  <element name="Voice of the Wild" type="Feat" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_FEAT_VOICE_OF_THE_WILD">
    <prerequisite>Koradi</prerequisite>
    <requirements>ID_GM_BINDER_RACE_KORADI</requirements>
    <description>
			<p><i>Prerequisite: Koradi</i></p>
      <p>You have made a name for yourself amongst your clan due to your innate ability to communicate with nature’s creatures. You gain the following traits.</p>
      <ul>
        <li>You gain proficiency in the Animal Handling skill. If you’re already proficient in it, your proficiency bonus is doubled for any check you make with that skill.</li>
        <li>Beasts and sentient plants are able to understand your speech as if they shared a language with you. You do not necessarily understand them in return, though creatures that lack a language can express simple ideas through their body language. A creature’s ability to comprehend your messages and respond accordingly is limited by its intelligence and what it knows.</li>
      </ul>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Beasts and sentient plants are able to understand your speech as if they shared a language with you. You do not necessarily understand them in return, though creatures that lack a language can express simple ideas through their body language. A creature’s ability to comprehend your messages and respond accordingly is limited by its intelligence and what it knows.</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules>
            <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_OR_DOUBLE_ANIMALHANDLING" />
      <!--<stat name="animal handling:proficiency" value="proficiency" bonus="double" requirements="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ANIMALHANDLING"/>-->
    </rules>
  </element>

</elements>
