<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Living Doll Race</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="race-living-doll.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/races/race-living-doll.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="The Living Doll" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_PEDANTICPINEAPPLE_HOMEBREWERY_SOURCE_THE_LIVING_DOLL">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation">TLD</set>
            <set name="url">https://homebrewery.naturalcrit.com/share/DlyiDkJfi</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" abbreviation="PP" url="https://www.reddit.com/user/pedantic_pineapple/">u/pedantic_pineapple</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20200505</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Living Doll" type="Race" source="The Living Doll" id="ID_PP_TLD_RACE_LIVING_DOLL">
        <description>
            <p>Living dolls are a rare race of small humanoid constructs created by powerful beings from ordinary dolls. A few of these dolls have ended up independent in the material plane. Some who come across them, particularly the more magical inclined, are strucken with awe and curiosity. However, many are weary of them due to their artificial nature, with some cultures viewing them as being tied to evil or bad luck.</p>
            <h4>PRETTY LITTLE THINGS</h4>
            <p>Living dolls appear simply as dolls. They are small figures with the likeness of sightly humans. Living dolls are typically made from dolls of very high quality, posessing detail that one would almost never come across in any other dolls. Despite their comprehensive detail, they are still obviously recognizable as artificial. They possess large glass eyes similar to oversized marbles. These eyes are captivating, with their glossy appearance and vividly colored irises. However, they can appear cold to some, lacking the warmth possessed by the eyes of living creatures. Their skin color depends on the material they are made of, with porcelain and resin dolls being milky white colors while wooden dolls often have skin of the wood they are made from.</p>
            <h4>AN ARTIFICIAL BIRTH</h4>
            <p>Living dolls are created by binding souls to dolls, weaving the very essence of life into them. Living dolls can only be created by beings with god-like powers, such as lesser deities, archfey, or mortals on the level of chosen. The motivations behind their creation can differ, and are rarely known to the dolls themselves and other lesser beings. Legends recall some being created as friends of children using their dolls, but some of these tales end in the child’s disappearance.</p>
            <h4>LIVING DOLL NAMES</h4>
            <p>Living dolls are typically named by their creators. Archfey-made living dolls typically have elven names, while lesser deities use naming schemes that their followers do. Living dolls that come from chosen or similarly ascended mortal beings have names consistent with their creator’s race. These names are innately known to living dolls, even though they typically know nothing of their origin.</p>
            <h4>LIVING DOLL TRAITS</h4>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong> Your Charisma score increases by 2.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Age.</em></strong> You do not age, and are immortal. Dolls are typically made after the likeness of young adults, adolescents, or children.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Alignment.</em></strong> Living dolls are typically neutral or good in nature. They have childlike tendancies, tending towards chaotic alignments.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Size.</em></strong> Living dolls are around 1--2 feet tall. Your size is Tiny. In the process of soul-binding, dolls are filled with a heavy liquid metal. The weight of this liquid metal is 10 pounds.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Speed.</em></strong> Your base walking speed is 25 feet.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Natural Darkvision.</em></strong> With your glass eyes, you have superior darkvision in dark and dim conditions. You can see in dim light within 120 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. However, even in bright light, you cannot discern color, only shades of grey.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Improved Fighting.</em></strong> For the purposes of weapon handling and reach, you are treated as size Small. When making a melee attack against a creature from this distance, you appear to dash towards it with incredible speed before making the attack, and dash back to your original position afterwards. The dash itself cannot trigger any reactions, and does not take up any of your movement.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Child’s Play.</em></strong> You have advantage on all Charisma checks against children, with the exception of Intimidation.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Living Construct.</em></strong> Even though you were constructed, you are a living creature and can be targeted by spells that target living creatures. You are immune to disease, and have advantage on saving throws against being poisoned. You do not need to eat, drink, or breathe. You do not need to sleep, and magic cannot put you to sleep. Instead of sleeping, during a long rest you must spend at least 6 hours in an inactive, motionless state. This state does not render you unconscious, and you can hear but not see. The Medicine skill and healing kits do not work on you, but magical healing does. The Mending cantrip restores 1 hit point to you.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Ball Joints.</em></strong> You can move your body in ways that natural races cannot, such as bending your arms backwords or turning your head around.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Languages.</em></strong> You can speak, read, and write Common, as well as the language of your creator.</p>
            <p classs="indent"><strong><em>Subrace.</em> Due to the differences in how dolls may be made, there are three subraces of living doll. Choose one of these subraces.</strong></p>
        </description>
        <setters>
			<set name="height" modifier="2d8">0’10"</set>
			<set name="weight" modifier="1d4">10 lb.</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <stat name="charisma" value="2" />
            <grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_TINY" />
            <stat name="innate speed" value="25" bonus="base" />
            <grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_SUPERIORDARKVISION" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_PP_TLD_RACIAL_TRAIT_LIVING_DOLL_IMPROVED_FIGHTING" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_PP_TLD_RACIAL_TRAIT_LIVING_DOLL_CHILDS_PLAY" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_PP_TLD_RACIAL_TRAIT_LIVING_DOLL_LIVING_CONSTRUCT" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_PP_TLD_RACIAL_TRAIT_LIVING_DOLL_BALL_JOINTS" />
            <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON" />
            <select type="Language" name="Language, Living Doll" supports="Standard||Exotic" />
            <select type="Sub Race" name="Living Doll Construction" supports="Living Doll" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Improved Fighting" type="Racial Trait" source="The Living Doll" id="ID_PP_TLD_RACIAL_TRAIT_LIVING_DOLL_IMPROVED_FIGHTING">
            <description>
                <p>For the purposes of weapon handling and reach, you are treated as size Small. When making a melee attack against a creature from this distance, you appear to dash towards it with incredible speed before making the attack, and dash back to your original position afterwards. The dash itself cannot trigger any reactions, and does not take up any of your movement.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>For the purposes of weapon handling and reach, you are treated as size Small. When making a melee attack against a creature from this distance, you appear to dash towards it with incredible speed before making the attack, and dash back to your original position afterwards. The dash itself cannot trigger any reactions, and does not take up any of your movement.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Child’s Play" type="Racial Trait" source="The Living Doll" id="ID_PP_TLD_RACIAL_TRAIT_LIVING_DOLL_CHILDS_PLAY">
            <description>
                <p>You have advantage on all Charisma checks against children, with the exception of Intimidation.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You have advantage on all Charisma checks against children, with the exception of Intimidation.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Living Construct" type="Racial Trait" source="The Living Doll" id="ID_PP_TLD_RACIAL_TRAIT_LIVING_DOLL_LIVING_CONSTRUCT">
            <description>
                <p>Even though you were constructed, you are a living creature and can be targeted by spells that target living creatures. You are immune to disease, and have advantage on saving throws against being poisoned. You do not need to eat, drink, or breathe. You do not need to sleep, and magic cannot put you to sleep. Instead of sleeping, during a long rest you must spend at least 6 hours in an inactive, motionless state. This state does not render you unconscious, and you can hear but not see. The Medicine skill and healing kits do not work on you, but magical healing does. The <em>mending</em> cantrip restores 1 hit point to you.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You are immune to disease, and have advantage on saving throws against being poisoned. You do not need to eat, drink, or breathe. You do not need to sleep, and magic cannot put you to sleep. Instead of sleeping, during a long rest you must spend at least 6 hours in an inactive, motionless state. This state does not render you unconscious, and you can hear but not see. The Medicine skill and healing kits do not work on you, but magical healing does. The mending cantrip restores 1 hit point to you.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Ball Joints" type="Racial Trait" source="The Living Doll" id="ID_PP_TLD_RACIAL_TRAIT_LIVING_DOLL_BALL_JOINTS">
            <description>
                <p>You can move your body in ways that natural races cannot, such as bending your arms backwords or turning your head around.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>ou can move your body in ways that natural races cannot, such as bending your arms backwords or turning your head around.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    <element name="Resin" type="Sub Race" source="The Living Doll" id="ID_PP_TLD_SUBRACE_LIVING_DOLL_RESIN">
        <supports>Living Doll</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Living dolls are most commonly made from resin dolls, and resemble humans the closest. As a resin living doll, you are less vulnerable to physical damage, and therefore recieve a Constitution score increase.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong> Your Constitution score increases by 2.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Size.</em></strong> In addition to the weight of your internal liquid metal, you weigh an extra 4--5 pounds.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Camouflage.</em></strong> You have proficiency with Disguise Kits.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <stat name="constitution" value="2" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_DISGUISE_KIT" />
        </rules>
    </element>


    <element name="Porcelain" type="Sub Race" source="The Living Doll" id="ID_PP_TLD_SUBRACE_LIVING_DOLL_PORCELAIN">
        <supports>Living Doll</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Living dolls are sometimes made from porcelain dolls. As a porcelain living doll, your skin is thick but brittle.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong> Your Wisdom score increases by 1.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Size.</em></strong> In addition to the weight of your internal liquid metal, you weigh an extra 1--3 pounds.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Made of Porcelain.</em></strong> You have proficiency with Potter’s Tools.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Brittle Skin.</em></strong> Piercing damage against you is made with a 1d4 penalty, and bludgeoning damage against you is made with a 1d4 bonus.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Self Maintenance.</em></strong> You know the <em>mending</em> cantrip.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <stat name="wisdom" value="1" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_POTTERS_TOOLS" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_PP_TLD_RACIAL_TRAIT_LIVING_DOLL_PORCELAIN_BRITTLE_SKIN" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_PP_TLD_RACIAL_TRAIT_LIVING_DOLL_PORCELAIN_SELF_MAINTENANCE" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Brittle Skin" type="Racial Trait" source="The Living Doll" id="ID_PP_TLD_RACIAL_TRAIT_LIVING_DOLL_PORCELAIN_BRITTLE_SKIN">
            <description>
                <p>Piercing damage against you is made with a 1d4 penalty, and bludgeoning damage against you is made with a 1d4 bonus.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Piercing damage against you is made with a 1d4 penalty, and bludgeoning damage against you is made with a 1d4 bonus.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Self Maintenance" type="Racial Trait" source="The Living Doll" id="ID_PP_TLD_RACIAL_TRAIT_LIVING_DOLL_PORCELAIN_SELF_MAINTENANCE">
            <description>
                <p>You know the <em>mending</em> cantrip.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You know the mending cantrip.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MENDING" />
            </rules>
        </element>


    <element name="Wooden" type="Sub Race" source="The Living Doll" id="ID_PP_TLD_SUBRACE_LIVING_DOLL_WOODEN">
        <supports>Living Doll</supports>
        <description>
            <p>As a wooden living doll, you are made from carved wood. You are less likely to be pierced, but are more vulnerable to fire.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong> Your Strength score increases by 1.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Size.</em></strong> In addition to the weight of your internal liquid metal, you weigh an extra 0.5--1 pounds.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Carved from Wood.</em></strong> You have proficiency with Woodcarver’s Tools.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Wooden Body.</em></strong> Piercing damage against you is made with a 1d4 penalty, and fire damage against you is made with a 1d4 bonus.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <stat name="strength" value="1" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_WOODCARVERS_TOOLS" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_PP_TLD_RACIAL_TRAIT_LIVING_DOLL_WOODEN_WOODEN_BODY" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Wooden Body" type="Racial Trait" source="The Living Doll" id="ID_PP_TLD_RACIAL_TRAIT_LIVING_DOLL_WOODEN_WOODEN_BODY">
            <description>
                <p>Piercing damage against you is made with a 1d4 penalty, and fire damage against you is made with a 1d4 bonus.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Piercing damage against you is made with a 1d4 penalty, and fire damage against you is made with a 1d4 bonus.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

</elements>