<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Starborn Race</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="race-starborn.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/races/race-starborn.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="The Starborn" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_A2A3A2A3_GMBINDER_SOURCE_The Starborn">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation">TSR</set>
            <set name="url">https://www.gmbinder.com/share/-LtF5qVkO6ipq0bM3TOn</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" abbreviation="A2A3" url="https://www.reddit.com/user/a2a3a2a3">u/a2a3a2a3</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20200623</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Starborn" type="Race" source="The Starborn" id="ID_A2A3_TSR_RACE_STARBORN">
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">I ALWAYS THOUGHT HE WAS HUMAN. KIND BLOKE.</p>
            <p class="flavor">He lived up in the mountain, there, in that old house. Came down every now and then and watched us have a natter. Never much of a talker himself. Just sat there, watching us. But I remember his routine. Every night, I’d look out and see him walking on the edge of the mountain, no fear, gazing at the stars.</p>
            <p class="flavor" style="text-align:right;">—Dwarven warrior Tornaxe, remembering his old friend Maxal.</p>
            <p class="indent">The starborn are a people born from the cosmos. Mystery and travel is ingrained in their very soul, and they tend to seek it out.</p>
            <h4>SHAPED OF STARS</h4>
            <p>Starborn, in appearance, look like humans or elves with dark skin, and can generally pass themselves off as said species. However, on closer inspection, a viewer would observe a bluish or purple tinge, hinting at the starborn’s real self. Their eyes, too, are a mark of their species, and are often a pure shade of white, black, or yellow.</p>
            <p class="indent">When a starborn chooses, they may ignite their body, and a pattern of stars in the form of a constellation scatters across their body, shining light in all directions in an awe-inspiring reveal of their true nature.</p>
            <h4>MARKED BY THE STARS</h4>
            <p>The constellation a starborn is marked with symbolises innate abilities, and in societies comprised of starborn, often determines their role in their society. Starborn marked with the Beast will take on roles as warriors or builders, taking advantage of their natural strength. Those marked with the Hound, on the other hand, tend to work as guards and diplomats for their people, fiercely committed to helping their society thrive. Such starborn, born of others of their kind, are known as "innate" starborn.</p>
            <p class="indent">However, starborn are not always born in this way. Occasionally, magical power from the heavens themselves manifests in a human, elven, or occasionally triton child while it is still yet to be born, and are born into a society of their parents’ race. This child, known as a "bestowed" starborn, is more likely to branch off from the traditional roles assigned by other starborn. Starborn raised in a society of their kind, for this reason, tend to look down upon bestowed starborn as inferior and less rigidly bound by laws they consider to be the natural order of things.</p>
            <h4>WANDERERS IN THE DARK</h4>
            <p>Whether they are bestowed or innate, starborn share a continuous urge to travel. They often do so at night, being able to read the stars as well as any book. As such, many starborn - particularly bestowed - find their way towards a life of adventure, providing a way to follow their ideals while travelling around and discovering new places.</p>
            <p class="indent">When starborn stop somewhere, they’ll try and do so in a strange place, often as near to the stars as they can get - mountains, tall buildings and treehouses are popular locations. In a few locations, starborn have erected structures in such areas, to help others of their kind when they arrive in the area. But soon enough they’ll be moving on, following the call of the stars they’re formed of.</p>
            <h4>STARBORN NAMES</h4>
            <p>Innate starborn tend to take names similar to those of the culture nearest their people at the time, as a mark of their birthplace and a way to recall the location, due to their wandering lifestyle. Bestowed starborn tend to be given names as a child of the culture they are born into usually would.</p>
            <h4>STARBORN TRAITS</h4>
            <p>Your inherent strategy manifests itself in a variety of ways.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong> Your Dexterity score increases by 1.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Age.</em></strong> Starborn age similarly to humans, although begin to slow up at around 30. They live for around 150 years.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Alignment.</em></strong> Innate starborn are most often lawful, generally conforming to their societies’ restrictions on certain jobs for certain constellations. Bestowed starborn, on the other hand, are much more varied, and could be anywhere on the alignment spectrum.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Size.</em></strong> Starborn are about the same size as a human. Your size is Medium.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Speed.</em></strong> Your base walking speed is 30 feet.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Born to the Night.</em></strong> Starborn don’t often sleep. Instead, they gaze up into the night, observing the subtle movements and patterns in the heavens, for 5 hours a day. You are unaware of your surroundings beyond the sky in this state. After resting uninterrupted in this way, provided you can see the night sky, you gain the same benefit that a human does from 8 hours of sleep.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Read the Heavens.</em></strong> You have advantage on any ability checks made involving the stars, such as navigating by them or recalling the name of a specific constellation.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Starlight.</em></strong> As a bonus action, you can cause your body to flare up with starlight, revealing your true nature. While this is active, you shed bright light in a 20-foot radius and dim light for an additional 20 feet. This transformation lasts for 1 hour, or until you dismiss it as a bonus action.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Superior Darkvision.</em></strong> Used to navigating under the night sky, you can see well in darkness. You can see in dim light within 120 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can’t discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Languages.</em></strong> You can speak, read and write Common and Starborn. The starborn tongue has a mysterious tone to it, and is often used by mages when writing prophecies or other such mystical scriptures.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Subrace.</em></strong> The constellation a starborn is marked with determines its subrace. The following subraces detail generic constellations, which can be renamed according to the world you play in.</p>
            <div class="sidebar">
                <h5 class="caption">Constellations in Your World</h5>
                <p>The constellations the starborn subraces are based upon are intended to be as generic as possible to allow them to be used in a variety of settings. However, if any of them don’t fit your campaign, alter their name and perhaps even their role accordingly.</p>
            </div>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="names" type="male">Ander, Blath, Bran, Frath, Geth, Lander, Luth, Malcer, Stor, Taman, Urth</set>
            <set name="names" type="female">Amafrey, Betha, Cefrey, Kethra, Mara, Olga, Silifrey, Westra</set>
            <set name="names" type="surname">Brightwood, Helder, Hornraven, Lackman, Stormwind, Windrivver</set>
            <set name="names-format">{{name}} {{surname}}</set>
            <set name="height" modifier="2d10">4’8"</set>
            <set name="weight" modifier="2d4">110 lb.</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <stat name="dexterity" value="1" />
            <grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_MEDIUM" />
            <stat name="innate speed" value="30" bonus="base" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_A2A3_TSR_RACIAL_TRAIT_STARBORN_BORN_TO_THE_NIGHT" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_A2A3_TSR_RACIAL_TRAIT_STARBORN_READ_THE_HEAVENS" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_A2A3_TSR_RACIAL_TRAIT_STARBORN_STARLIGHT" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_A2A3_TSR_RACIAL_TRAIT_STARBORN_SUBRACE" />
            <grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_SUPERIORDARKVISION" />
            <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON" />
            <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_STARBORN" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Born to the Night" type="Racial Trait" source="The Starborn" id="ID_A2A3_TSR_RACIAL_TRAIT_STARBORN_BORN_TO_THE_NIGHT">
            <description>
                <p>Starborn don’t often sleep. Instead, they gaze up into the night, observing the subtle movements and patterns in the heavens, for 5 hours a day. You are unaware of your surroundings beyond the sky in this state. After resting uninterrupted in this way, provided you can see the night sky, you gain the same benefit that a human does from 8 hours of sleep.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can spend 5 hours gazing at the night sky to gain the same benefit as 8 hours of sleep. You are unaware of your surroundings beyond the sky in this state.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Read the Heavens" type="Racial Trait" source="The Starborn" id="ID_A2A3_TSR_RACIAL_TRAIT_STARBORN_READ_THE_HEAVENS">
            <description>
                <p>You have advantage on any ability checks made involving the stars, such as navigating by them or recalling the name of a specific constellation.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You have advantage on any ability checks made involving the stars, such as navigating by them or recalling the name of a specific constellation.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Starlight" type="Racial Trait" source="The Starborn" id="ID_A2A3_TSR_RACIAL_TRAIT_STARBORN_STARLIGHT">
            <description>
                <p>As a bonus action, you can cause your body to flare up with starlight, revealing your true nature. While this is active, you shed bright light in a 20-foot radius and dim light for an additional 20 feet. This transformation lasts for 1 hour, or until you dismiss it as a bonus action.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>You can cause your body to flare up with starlight for up to 1 hour or until you dismiss it as a bonus action. While this is active, you shed bright light in a 20-foot radius and dim light for an additional 20 feet.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Subrace" type="Racial Trait" source="The Starborn" id="ID_A2A3_TSR_RACIAL_TRAIT_STARBORN_SUBRACE">
            <description>
                <p>The constellation a starborn is marked with determines its subrace. The following subraces detail generic constellations, which can be renamed according to the world you play in.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Sub Race" name="Starborn Constellation" supports="Starborn Constellation" />
            </rules>
        </element>

    <element name="Beast" type="Sub Race" source="The Starborn" id="ID_A2A3_TSR_SUBRACE_STARBORN_BEAST">
        <supports>Starborn Constellation</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Beast starborn are larger, muscular starborn, able to take up roles as warriors when necessary, and carrying supplies for their people as they travel across the land in times of peace. When starborn occasionally construct a building, it is the Beast starborn who do the work.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong> Your Strength score increases by 2.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Powerful Build.</em></strong> You count as one size larger when determining your carrying capacity and the weight you can push, drag, or lift.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Beast’s Toughness.</em></strong> Your hit point maximum increases by 1, and it increases by 1 every time you gain a level.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <stat name="strength" value="2" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_A2A3_TSR_RACIAL_TRAIT_STARBORN_BEAST_POWERFUL_BUILD" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_A2A3_TSR_RACIAL_TRAIT_STARBORN_BEAST_BEASTS_TOUGHNESS" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Powerful Build" type="Racial Trait" source="The Starborn" id="ID_A2A3_TSR_RACIAL_TRAIT_STARBORN_BEAST_POWERFUL_BUILD">
            <description>
                <p>You count as one size larger when determining your carrying capacity and the weight you can push, drag, or lift.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You count as one size larger when determining your carrying capacity and the weight you can push, drag, or lift.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Beast’s Toughness" type="Racial Trait" source="The Starborn" id="ID_A2A3_TSR_RACIAL_TRAIT_STARBORN_BEAST_BEASTS_TOUGHNESS">
            <description>
                <p>Your hit point maximum increases by 1, and it increases by 1 every time you gain a level.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description>Your hit point maximum increases by 1, and it increases by 1 every time you gain a level.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="hp" value="level" />
            </rules>
        </element>

    <element name="Galaxy" type="Sub Race" source="The Starborn" id="ID_A2A3_TSR_SUBRACE_STARBORN_GALAXY">
        <supports>Starborn Constellation</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Galaxy starborn are some of the rarest and most mysterious of their kind. Rather than a ’constellation’ as such, their body is sprinkled with the pattern of distant stars in a stripe beyond the night sky. They tend to be blessed with knowledge beyond their years, and take up roles as navigators or witches within starborn society.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong> Your Intelligence or Wisdom score increases by 2.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Distant Knowledge.</em></strong> You know the dancing lights cantrip. When you reach 3rd level, you can cast the <em>dissonant whispers</em> spell once with this trait and regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest. When you reach 5th level, you can cast the <em>moonbeam</em> spell once with this trait and regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest. Whichever ability score you increased with the Galaxy subrace’s Ability Score Increase trait is your spellcasting ability for these spells. You can only cast these spells while using your Starlight feature.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <select type="Racial Trait" name="Ability Score Increase" supports="ID_A2A3_TSR_RACIAL_TRAIT_STARBORN_GALAXY_INTELLIGENCE|ID_A2A3_TSR_RACIAL_TRAIT_STARBORN_GALAXY_WISDOM" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_A2A3_TSR_RACIAL_TRAIT_STARBORN_GALAXY_DISTANT_KNOWLEDGE" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Intelligence" type="Racial Trait" source="The Starborn" id="ID_A2A3_TSR_RACIAL_TRAIT_STARBORN_GALAXY_INTELLIGENCE">
            <compendium display="false" />
            <description>
                <p></p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="Intelligence" value="2" />
                <stat name="distant-knowledge:ability" value="Intelligence" inline="true" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Wisdom" type="Racial Trait" source="The Starborn" id="ID_A2A3_TSR_RACIAL_TRAIT_STARBORN_GALAXY_WISDOM">
            <compendium display="false" />
            <description>
                <p></p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="Wisdom" value="2" />
                <stat name="distant-knowledge:ability" value="Wisdom" inline="true" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Distant Knowledge" type="Racial Trait" source="The Starborn" id="ID_A2A3_TSR_RACIAL_TRAIT_STARBORN_GALAXY_DISTANT_KNOWLEDGE">
            <description>
                <p>You know the dancing lights cantrip. When you reach 3rd level, you can cast the <em>dissonant whispers</em> spell once with this trait and regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest. When you reach 5th level, you can cast the <em>moonbeam</em> spell once with this trait and regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest. Whichever ability score you increased with the Galaxy subrace’s Ability Score Increase trait is your spellcasting ability for these spells. You can only cast these spells while using your Starlight feature.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You know the dancing lights cantrip.</description>
                <description level="3" usage="1/Long Rest">You know the dancing lights cantrip. Once per long rest, you can cast dissonant whispers. ({{distant-knowledge:ability}})</description>
                <description level="5" usage="1/Long Rest">You know the dancing lights cantrip. Once per long rest, you can cast dissonant whispers and moonbeam. ({{distant-knowledge:ability}})</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DANCING_LIGHTS" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISSONANT_WHISPERS" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MOONBEAM" level="3" />
            </rules>
        </element>

    <element name="Hound" type="Sub Race" source="The Starborn" id="ID_A2A3_TSR_SUBRACE_STARBORN_HOUND">
        <supports>Starborn Constellation</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Hound starborn are dedicated protectors, putting their life on the line for the sake of their friends and family. If you become friends with a hound starborn, you can count on them to protect you in even the most dangerous situations.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong> Your Strength and Charisma scores each increase by 1.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Friendly.</em></strong> You know the <em>friends</em> cantrip. Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this spell.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Loyal Guardian.</em></strong> As a reaction when a creature you can see within 60 feet is targeted by an attack, you can cause their AC to be increased by an amount equal to your level until the end of the attacker’s turn. After you use this ability, you can’t use it again until you complete a short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <stat name="strength" value="1" />
            <stat name="charisma" value="1" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_A2A3_TSR_RACIAL_TRAIT_STARBORN_HOUND_FRIENDLY" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_A2A3_TSR_RACIAL_TRAIT_STARBORN_HOUND_LOYAL_GUARDIAN" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Friendly" type="Racial Trait" source="The Starborn" id="ID_A2A3_TSR_RACIAL_TRAIT_STARBORN_HOUND_FRIENDLY">
            <description>
                <p>You know the <em>friends</em> cantrip. Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this spell.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You know the friends cantrip. Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this spell.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FRIENDS" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Loyal Guardian" type="Racial Trait" source="The Starborn" id="ID_A2A3_TSR_RACIAL_TRAIT_STARBORN_HOUND_LOYAL_GUARDIAN">
            <description>
                <p>As a reaction when a creature you can see within 60 feet is targeted by an attack, you can cause their AC to be increased by an amount equal to your level until the end of the attacker’s turn. After you use this ability, you can’t use it again until you complete a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Short Rest" action="Reaction">
                <description>When a creature you can see within 60 feet is targeted by an attack, you can cause their AC to be increased by {{level}} until the end of the attacker’s turn.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    <element name="Hunter" type="Sub Race" source="The Starborn" id="ID_A2A3_TSR_SUBRACE_STARBORN_HUNTER">
        <supports>Starborn Constellation</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Hunter starborn are the scouts and - well - hunters of their society, making use of their natural advantages to wield lightweight, ranged weapons with ease.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong> Your Dexterity and Wisdom scores each increase by 1.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Gifts of the Hunt.</em></strong> You know the <em>magic stone</em> cantrip. When you reach 3rd level, you can cast the <em>hunter’s mark</em> spell once with this trait and regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest. When you reach 5th level, you can cast the <em>cordon of arrows</em> spell once with this trait and regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for these spells.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <stat name="dexterity" value="1" />
            <stat name="wisdom" value="1" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_A2A3_TSR_RACIAL_TRAIT_STARBORN_HUNTER_GIFTS_OF_THE_HUNT" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Gifts of the Hunt" type="Racial Trait" source="The Starborn" id="ID_A2A3_TSR_RACIAL_TRAIT_STARBORN_HUNTER_GIFTS_OF_THE_HUNT">
            <description>
                <p>You know the <em>magic stone</em> cantrip. When you reach 3rd level, you can cast the <em>hunter’s mark</em> spell once with this trait and regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest. When you reach 5th level, you can cast the <em>cordon of arrows</em> spell once with this trait and regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for these spells.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You know the magic stone cantrip.</description>
                <description level="3" usage="1/Long Rest">You know the magic stone cantrip. Once per long rest, you can cast hunter’s mark. (Wisdom)</description>
                <description level="5" usage="1/Long Rest">You know the magic stone cantrip. Once per long rest, you can cast hunter’s mark and cordon of arrows. (Wisdom)</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGIC_STONE" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HUNTERS_MARK" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CORDON_OF_ARROWS" level="3" />
            </rules>
        </element>

    <element name="Sea Serpent" type="Sub Race" source="The Starborn" id="ID_A2A3_TSR_SUBRACE_STARBORN_SEA_SERPENT">
        <supports>Starborn Constellation</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Starborn marked with the Sea Serpent often form separate societies to the rest of their kind, preferring to live by or within the water. They often join societies of sea elves and tritons. Bestowed starborn of this constellation tend to be born from members of these species.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong> Your Constitution and Wisdom scores each increase by 1.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Amphibious.</em></strong> You can breathe air and water.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Serpent’s Bite.</em></strong> You know the ray of frost cantrip, although you can only cast it while using your Starlight feature. When you do, the serpent on your body appears to come to life and bite your target. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for this spell.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Swim Speed.</em></strong> You have a swimming speed of 30 feet.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <stat name="constitution" value="1" />
            <stat name="wisdom" value="1" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_A2A3_TSR_RACIAL_TRAIT_STARBORN_SEA_SERPENT_AMPHIBIOUS" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_A2A3_TSR_RACIAL_TRAIT_STARBORN_SEA_SERPENT_SERPENTS_BITE" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_A2A3_TSR_RACIAL_TRAIT_STARBORN_SEA_SERPENT_SWIM_SPEED" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Amphibious" type="Racial Trait" source="The Starborn" id="ID_A2A3_TSR_RACIAL_TRAIT_STARBORN_SEA_SERPENT_AMPHIBIOUS">
            <description>
                <p>You can breathe air and water.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can breathe air and water.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Serpent’s Bite" type="Racial Trait" source="The Starborn" id="ID_A2A3_TSR_RACIAL_TRAIT_STARBORN_SEA_SERPENT_SERPENTS_BITE">
            <description>
                <p>You know the ray of frost cantrip, although you can only cast it while using your Starlight feature. When you do, the serpent on your body appears to come to life and bite your target. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for this spell.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You know the ray of frost cantrip, although you can only cast it while using your Starlight feature. When you do, the serpent on your body appears to come to life and bite your target. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for this spell.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RAY_OF_FROST" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Swim Speed" type="Racial Trait" source="The Starborn" id="ID_A2A3_TSR_RACIAL_TRAIT_STARBORN_SEA_SERPENT_SWIM_SPEED">
            <description>
                <p>You have a swimming speed of 30 feet.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="innate speed:swim" value="30" bonus="base" />
            </rules>
        </element>

    <element name="Steed" type="Sub Race" source="The Starborn" id="ID_A2A3_TSR_SUBRACE_STARBORN_STEED">
        <supports>Starborn Constellation</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Steed starborn are naturally good with animals. They tend to livestock that their communities bring with them, and when they need to fight, they tend to ride into battle on top of the creature their constellation symbolises.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong> Your Wisdom score increases by 2.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Animal Affinity.</em></strong> You have proficiency in the Animal Handling skill.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Starry Steed.</em></strong> When you reach 3rd level, you can cast the find steed spell as an action once with this trait, and regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest. When you do so, the duration becomes 1 hour. You can only cast this spell while using your Starlight feature. When you do, the stars on your body spring off and form themselves into the steed they represent.</p>
            <p class="indent">During the duration, you cannot use your starlight feature and are no longer under the effect of it. However, the steed sheds bright light in a 20-foot radius and dim light for an additional 20 feet.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <stat name="wisdom" value="2" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_A2A3_TSR_RACIAL_TRAIT_STARBORN_STEED_ANIMAL_AFFINITY" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_A2A3_TSR_RACIAL_TRAIT_STARBORN_STEED_STARRY_STEED" level="3" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Animal Affinity" type="Racial Trait" source="The Starborn" id="ID_A2A3_TSR_RACIAL_TRAIT_STARBORN_STEED_ANIMAL_AFFINITY">
            <description>
                <p>You have proficiency in the Animal Handling skill.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description>You have proficiency in the Animal Handling skill.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ANIMALHANDLING" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Starry Steed" type="Racial Trait" source="The Starborn" id="ID_A2A3_TSR_RACIAL_TRAIT_STARBORN_STEED_STARRY_STEED">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 3rd level, you can cast the find steed spell as an action once with this trait, and regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest. When you do so, the duration becomes 1 hour. You can only cast this spell while using your Starlight feature. When you do, the stars on your body spring off and form themselves into the steed they represent.</p>
                <p class="indent">During the duration, you cannot use your Starlight feature and are no longer under the effect of it. However, the steed sheds bright light in a 20-foot radius and dim light for an additional 20 feet.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You can cast the find steed with a 1-hour duragion while using your Starlight feature. When you do, the stars on your body spring off and form themselves into the steed they represent. During the duration, you cannot use your Starlight feature and are no longer under the effect of it. However, the steed sheds bright light in a 20-foot radius and dim light for an additional 20 feet.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIND_STEED" level="3" />
            </rules>
        </element>

    <element name="Tool" type="Sub Race" source="The Starborn" id="ID_A2A3_TSR_SUBRACE_STARBORN_TOOL">
        <supports>Starborn Constellation</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Starborn marked with the tool are practical folk. They form the smiths, farmers, and artisans of their communities. They may not be doing the work people remember, but they are truly the backbone of starborn society. And they’re content with knowing that.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong> Your Dexterity and Charisma scores each increase by 1.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Natural at Your Trade.</em></strong> You have proficiency with one tool, one skill, and one weapon of your choice, and learn one language of your choice.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <stat name="dexterity" value="1" />
            <stat name="charisma" value="1" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_A2A3_TSR_RACIAL_TRAIT_STARBORN_TOOL_NATURAL_AT_YOUR_TRADE" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Natural at Your Trade" type="Racial Trait" source="The Starborn" id="ID_A2A3_TSR_RACIAL_TRAIT_STARBORN_TOOL_NATURAL_AT_YOUR_TRADE">
            <description>
                <p>You have proficiency with one tool, one skill, and one weapon of your choice, and learn one language of your choice.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Proficiency" name="Tool Proficiency, Starborn" supports="Tool" />
                <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency, Starborn" supports="Skill" />
                <select type="Proficiency" name="Weapon Proficiency, Starborn" supports="Weapon" />
            </rules>
        </element>


    <element name="Starborn" type="Language" source="The Starborn" id="ID_LANGUAGE_STARBORN">
        <description>
            <p>Typically spoken by Starborn. The starborn tongue has a mysterious tone to it, and is often used by mages when writing prophecies or other such mystical scriptures.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="exotic">true</set>
            <set name="speakers">Starborn</set>
            <set name="script">Starborn</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
</elements>