<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Faeryshin Race</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="race-faeryshin.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/races/race-faeryshin.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Faeryshin Race" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_DEATHMONKEY_RDDTUA_SOURCE_FAERYSHIN_RACE">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation"></set>
            <set name="url">https://drive.google.com/file/d/1uX9NfC8CimSxFSVQJT5uCO2avgoaYa_h/view</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" abbreviation="DM" url="https://www.reddit.com/user/DeathIVIonkey/">u/DeathIVIonky</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20200530</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Faeryshin" type="Race" source="Faeryshin Race" id="ID_DM_FAERYSHIN_RACE_FAERYSHIN">
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">“Look, it’s easy to outsmart a werewolf or a vampire," Jace said. "They’re no smarter than anyone else. But faeries live for hundreds ofyears and they’re as cunning as snakes. They don’t lie, but they love to engage in creative truth-telling. They’ll find out whatever it is you want most in the world and give it to you—with a sting in the tail ofthe gift that will make you regret you ever wanted it in the first place."</p>
            <p class="indent flavor">He sighed. "They’re not really about helping people. More about harm disguised as help.”</p>
            <p class="flavor" style="text-align: right;">—Cassandra Clare, -City ofAshes</p>
            <p class="indent">Tall tales and legends always make Faeries out to be such cunning tricksters, flitting about and protecting children - always the eager sideckick. That’s what everyone expects the first time they lay eyes on a Faerishyn, What they never expect is a creature more surly than a drunken dwarf after losing a bar fight. You might mistake them for a short elf or a tall gnome at first glance if it weren’t for the wings.</p>
            <h4>A PEOPLE DISPLACED</h4>
            <p>Tirnanoc is a small archipelago far in the open ocean, separated by tide and time. The ancestral home of the Faerishyn lies at a point where the veil between the prime material plane and the Feywild thins and intermingles. For all of their recorded history, the Faerishyn were content and prosperous.</p>
            <p class="indent">Basajuan Riyal, human explorer, “discovered” Tirnanoc. His first landing was met with naive curiosity by the Faeryshin, and his eyes widened at the exotic and unknown kingdom of Tirnanoc. The Faerishyn soon found that they’re trust was severely misaligned. Once Riyal and his explorer’s saw the troves ofmaterial resources that could be found on the islands of Tirnanoc, the humans were quick to return for the plunder.</p>
            <p class="indent">Less than 500 years, not even a single Elven or Faerishyn generation, have passed since the discovery of the Faerishyn island of Tirnanoc. For Humans, the discovery has become ancient history, passed from generation to generation 5 times over. For the Faerishyn, they witnessed the raising of their homeland by the ravages of war first hand. They are refugees and veterans of a war that the other side doesn’t even remember winning. This contradiction has festered in the hearts of the Faerishyn</p>
            <h4>THE COMING REBELLION</h4>
            <p>Years of fighting the humans for their land and the humans fighting for superiority of Tirnanoc ravaged the landscape. The mass mining ofmineralized destabilized the island structure which has sunk beneath the waves following a volcanic eruption.</p>
            <p class="indent">Most Faerishyn were brought to the “civilised” world as slaves to whatever human had laid claim to the areas that they happened to live. The end result here, because of their extended lifespan, is that they are often passed down through a household for generations.</p>
            <p class="indent">The younger Faerishyn have begun to rebel. They escape, join insurgent groups, and, try to enjoy the little freedoms that they have (or help others still held captive.</p>
            <h4>FADING POWERS</h4>
            <p>Time and the loss of their homeland has taken its toll on the Faerishyn. Some say Tirnanoc’s intermingled relationship with the feywild empowers the Faerishyn with magic, and without it, their strength is fading. In the Tirnanese wars, humans won through sheer force of numbers. Most books say that every Faeriehyn was as powerful as 10 men.</p>
            <p class="indent">Now, they’ve lost the ability to fly. Their wings now cosmetic for most, with the strongest only able to muster the ability to hover in place or extend a jump. They maintain some of their innate magic, but as the memory of their lands fade, so to does their connection to magic. There are still some Faerishyn with the gift, and other Faerishyn cling to them as their race’s last hope of freedom.</p>
            <h4>A LONGING FOR HOME</h4>
            <p>Faerishyn no longer have their homeland. When they do gain their freedom (however it is achieved) They are often filled with a purpose for the remainder of their lives. Were you set free by a gracious owner or did you escape a ruthless abuser? Is anyone trying to return your former owner? Were you born free? There will be people in every town who look down on you, call you racist names, act openly hostile toward you, or even report you to authorities.</p>
            <p class="indent">Suspicion, caution, and an overabundance of paranoia have made some Faerishyn into hermits, while others are brazen and dare someone to pick a fight with them. How you play this race will depend on how you answer several of these questions.</p>
            <h4>FAERISHYN NAMES</h4>
            <p>Each Faerishyn has two names: their first name and their clan name, which is often named for the region of Tirnanoc that their family originated. First name’s are often chosen from plants or minerals in the area.</p>
            <p><strong>Male Names:</strong> Acacia, Aurum, Ash, Birch, Carnelian, Ebony, Feu, Jasper, Kino, Malachite, Niobium, Onyx, Schist, Roche</p>
            <p><strong>Female Names:</strong> Cascade, Imogen, Iridium, Ivory, Ivy, Laurite, Meadow, Ochre, Opal, Piety, Ruby, Ruthenium, Satine, Sapphire, Tourmaline, Vignette, Willow</p>
            <p><strong>Clan Names:</strong> Bloodwood, Bogstench, Breakshore, Briarrock, Creekside, Floodplanes, Heartwood, Hilltop, Larou, Rosethorn, Saltmarsh, Stonemoss, Thornbrook, Wetlands</p>
            <h4>FAERISHYN TRAITS</h4>
            <p>Faerishyn share a number of innate abilities in common with each other.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong> Your Wisdom score increases. By 2, and your Dexterity score increases by 1.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Age.</em></strong> Faerishyn mature at the same rate humans do, and most are expected to settle down into an adult life by around age 40 - 50. They can live 350 to almost 500 years.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Alignment.</em></strong> Faerishyn tend to be chaotic or neutral in their view of society, and can run the gamut of moralities.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Size.</em></strong> Faerishyn stand between 4 and 5 feet tall and have slight or waifish builds. . Your size is Medium. Here’s how to determine your height and weight randomly, starting with rolling a size modifier:</p>
            <p class="indent"><em>Height modifier</em> = 2d4</p>
            <p class="indent"><em>Height</em> = 3 feet + 8 inches + your height modifier in inches</p>
            <p class="indent"><em>Weight in pounds</em> = 80 + (1d4 × your size modifier)</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Speed.</em></strong> Your base walking speed is 25 feet.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Darkvision.</em></strong> You have superior vision in dark and dim conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can’t discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Innate Spellcasting.</em></strong> You know the <em>druidcraft</em> cantrip. Starting at 3rd level, you can also cast <em>fortune’s favor</em> with this trait. Once you cast it, you can’t do so again until you finish a long rest. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for these spells.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Magic Resistance.</em></strong> You have advantage on saving throws against spells and other magical effects.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Wings.</em></strong> Your wings can not support flight, and do not grant you a fly speed. You may use them to slow your fall, however. To represent your wing’s abilities, you can castA feather fall an unlimited number of times with this trait, but you can target only yourself with it.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Languages.</em></strong> You can speak, read, and write common, and Sylvan.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <setters>
            <set name="names" type="male">male</set>
            <set name="names" type="female">female</set>
            <set name="names" type="clan">custom</set>
            <set name="names-format">{{name}} {{clan}}</set>
			<set name="height" modifier="2d4">3’8"</set>
			<set name="weight" modifier="1d4">80 lb.</set>
        </setters>
        <rules>
            <stat name="wisdom" value="2" />
            <stat name="dexterity" value="1" />
            <grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_MEDIUM" />
            <stat name="innate speed" value="25" bonus="base" />
            <grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_DARKVISION" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_DM_FAERYSHIN_RACIAL_TRAIT_INNATE_SPELLCASTING" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_DM_FAERYSHIN_RACIAL_TRAIT_MAGIC_RESISTANCE" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_DM_FAERYSHIN_RACIAL_TRAIT_WINGS" />
            <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON" />
            <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_SYLVAN" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Innate Spellcasting" type="Racial Trait" source="Faeryshin Race" id="ID_DM_FAERYSHIN_RACIAL_TRAIT_INNATE_SPELLCASTING">
            <description>
                <p>You know the <em>druidcraft</em> cantrip. Starting at 3rd level, you can also cast <em>fortune’s favor</em> with this trait. Once you cast it, you can’t do so again until you finish a long rest. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for these spells.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You know the druidcraft cantrip. (Wisdom)</description>
                <description level="3" usage="1/Long Rest">You know the druidcraft cantrip. You can cast fortune’s favor once. (Wisdom)</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DRUIDCRAFT" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_WOTC_EGTW_SPELL_FORTUNES_FAVOR" level="3" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Magic Resistance" type="Racial Trait" source="Faeryshin Race" id="ID_DM_FAERYSHIN_RACIAL_TRAIT_MAGIC_RESISTANCE">
            <description>
                <p>You have advantage on saving throws against spells and other magical effects.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You have advantage on saving throws against spells and other magical effects.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Wings" type="Racial Trait" source="Faeryshin Race" id="ID_DM_FAERYSHIN_RACIAL_TRAIT_WINGS">
            <description>
                <p>Your wings can not support flight, and do not grant you a fly speed. You may use them to slow your fall, however. To represent your wing’s abilities, you can cast <em>feather fall</em> an unlimited number of times with this trait, but you can target only yourself with it.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You may use your wings to slow your fall. To represent your wing’s abilities, you can cast feather fall an unlimited number of times with this trait, but you can target only yourself with it.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FEATHER_FALL" />
            </rules>
        </element>
    
</elements>