<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Vulpes</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="race-vulpe.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/races/race-vulpe.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Vulpes" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_RAINJUNKIE_GMBINDER_SOURCE_VULPES">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation">VULPES</set>
            <set name="url">https://www.gmbinder.com/share/-LIH1wSAHKusRQBT34sC</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" abbreviation="RJ" url="https://www.gmbinder.com/profile/rain-junkie">Rain-Junkie</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20200906</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Vulpes" type="Race" source="Vulpes" id="ID_RJ_VULPES_RACE_VULPES">
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">The elf cocked a delicate eyebrow as he watched the strange fox-man work. He called himself a ’vulpes’ and had said his name was Jupiter, although in all his years, Carric had never heard of such a race. Regardless, the Carric detected no transmutation or illusion magic altering or obscuring the vulpes’ true form, so he continued to watch him inscribe intricate arcane runes into the floor of the cavern. Despite his reservations, even Carric had to admit that Jupiter’s line work, especially considering the complexity of the runes he was inscribing, put a lot of old elven wizards he knew to shame.</p>
            <p>The vulpes are crafty and sly, masters of magic who can augment their magical knowledge with a variety of skills and abilities. No one knows quite where the vulpes herald from, and while they’ve intergrated into cities and towns across the material plane, many suspect they trace their origins to one of the outer planes, or the astral sea. Not even the vulpes know their true origin, but they tirelessly hone their magical abilties and skills to take on the challenges that face them in their lives.</p>
            <p class="indent">Almost all vulpes have fur that ranges from sandy brown to bright orange, with a few having fur that’s anywhere between black or white. A vulpes with black, grey, or white fur is often seen as an omen by most, believed to either be destined for greatness or doom.</p>
            <p class="indent">Each vulpes is able to command magic from a young age, seeming to know a specific arcane spell. This spell is often reflective of the vulpes’ personality, with more manipulative vulpes being able to cast charm person or disguise self, while more destructive vulpes are able to cast chromatic orb or thunderwave.</p>
            <h5>VULPES NAMES</h5>
            <p>Vulpes will often have a name based on the culture they grew up in; vulpes born in elven society might have an elven name, for example. Others, however, will take on a distinct vulpes name, embracing their heritage and sense of self (as much as vulpes already do). Vulpes names don’t differentiate between male and female. Vulpes don’t often adopt last names, and if taken, will often be reflective of the culture they grew up in.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b>Vulpes Names:</b> Anthe, Callisto, Fenrir, Io, Kalkye, Lysithia, Oberon, Sao, Stebos, Surtur, Sycorax, Taygete, Tethys, Thrymr, Umbriel, Ymir</p>
            <h4>Vulpe Traits</h4>
            <p>As a vulpes, you have certain traits in common with other vulpes.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong> Your Intelligence score increases by 2, and one other ability score increases by 1.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Age.</em></strong> Vulpes have lengthy lifespans, often living till the age of 300. They mature at the same rate as humans, though, reaching adulthood by the age of 20.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Alignment.</em></strong> Any, though Vulpes tend toward chaotic alignments.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Size.</em></strong> Vulpes stand around 5 feet tall, and weigh between 80 and 120 pounds. Your size is Medium.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Speed.</em></strong> Your base walking speed is 30 feet.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Darkvision.</em></strong> You have a fox’s keen senses, especially in the dark. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can’t discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Breadth of Knowledge.</em></strong> You can recognize and name any language you hear spoken or see in writing, even if you aren’t fluent in it.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Master Magician.</em></strong> You learn the prestidigitation cantrip, and the total number of its non-instantaneous effects you can have at once is increased by an amount equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of 1).</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Sly Tactics.</em></strong> You can make your initiative equal to the initiative of a willing creature within 60 feet of you after you roll but before combat begins.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you use this trait, you can’t use it again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Vague Arcana.</em></strong> Choose one 1st-level spell from the wizard spell list. You can cast that spell with this trait, using Intelligence as your spellcasting ability for it. Once you cast the spell, you can’t cast it again with this trait until you finish a long rest.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Languages.</em></strong> You can speak, read, and write Common and two other languages of your choice. Due to their skill with magic, vulpes will often know exotic languages such as Abyssal, Draconic, or Infernal.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="names" type="custom">Anthe, Callisto, Fenrir, Io, Kalkye, Lysithia, Oberon, Sao, Stebos, Surtur, Sycorax, Taygete, Tethys, Thrymr, Umbriel, Ymir</set>
            <set name="names-format">{{custom}}</set>
			<set name="height" modifier="2d6">4’8"</set>
			<set name="weight" modifier="1d6">75 lb.</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <stat name="Intelligence" value="2" />
			<select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Vulpes" supports="ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_STRENGTH|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_DEXTERITY|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_CONSTITUTION|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_WISDOM|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_CHARISMA" />
            <grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_MEDIUM" />
            <stat name="innate speed" value="30" bonus="base" />
            <grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_DARKVISION" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RJ_VULPES_RACIAL_TRAIT_VULPES_BREADTH_OF_KNOWLEDGE" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RJ_VULPES_RACIAL_TRAIT_VULPES_MASTER_MAGICIAN" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RJ_VULPES_RACIAL_TRAIT_VULPES_SLY_TACTICS" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RJ_VULPES_RACIAL_TRAIT_VULPES_VAGUE_ARCANA" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Breadth of Knowledge" type="Racial Trait" source="Vulpes" id="ID_RJ_VULPES_RACIAL_TRAIT_VULPES_BREADTH_OF_KNOWLEDGE">
            <description>
                <p>You can recognize and name any language you hear spoken or see in writing, even if you aren’t fluent in it.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can recognize and name any language you hear spoken or see in writing, even if you aren’t fluent in it.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Master Magician" type="Racial Trait" source="Vulpes" id="ID_RJ_VULPES_RACIAL_TRAIT_VULPES_MASTER_MAGICIAN">
            <description>
                <p>You learn the prestidigitation cantrip, and the total number of its non-instantaneous effects you can have at once is increased by an amount equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of 1).</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you cast prestidigiation, the total number of its non-instantaneous effects you can have at once is increased by {{master-magician:effects}}.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="master-magician:effects" value="1" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="master-magician:effects" value="intelligence:modifier" bonus="base" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PRESTIDIGITATION" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Sly Tactics" type="Racial Trait" source="Vulpes" id="ID_RJ_VULPES_RACIAL_TRAIT_VULPES_SLY_TACTICS">
            <description>
                <p>You can make your initiative equal to the initiative of a willing creature within 60 feet of you after you roll but before combat begins.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this trait, you can’t use it again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You can make your initiative equal to the initiative of a willing creature within 60 feet of you after you roll but before combat begins.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Vague Arcana" type="Racial Trait" source="Vulpes" id="ID_RJ_VULPES_RACIAL_TRAIT_VULPES_VAGUE_ARCANA">
            <description>
                <p>Choose one 1st-level spell from the wizard spell list. You can cast that spell with this trait, using Intelligence as your spellcasting ability for it. Once you cast the spell, you can’t cast it again with this trait until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You can cast your selected wizard spell once, using Intelligence as your spellcasting ability.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Spell" name="Vague Arcana, Vulpes" supports="Wizard,1" />
            </rules>
        </element>

</elements>