<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Sylvicine Race</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="race-sylvicine.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/races/race-sylvicine.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="The Sylvicine" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_GFP_GFP_SOURCE_THE_SYLVICINE">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation"></set>
            <set name="url">https://drive.google.com/file/d/1d2F6JtowIS6nGzzTagcNutT_u7p5Appf/view</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" abbreviation="GFP" url="https://www.genfantasypress.com/">Genuine Fantasy Press</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">true</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20200228</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Sylvicine" type="Race" source="The Sylvicine" id="ID_GFP_SYLVICINE_RACE_SYLVICINE">
        <description>
            <p>Cousins to the fey and faeries, the sylvicine are a humanoid race that walks the borderline between nature and civilization. The average sylvicine is about eight inches tall, with the gossamer wings of a dragonfly or a butterfly, and has sharp features and pointed ears. Their eyes, skin, and hair comes in a rainbow of shades and colors, often corresponding with the pattern of their wings.</p>
            <p class="indent">Sylvicine are clever and industrious, creating cunning devices and tiny, marvelous things. They possess the unique magical ability to instantly change size, though most can’t become larger than a human child. They are shockingly quick and are fierce when provoked, but almost all lack the mischievous nature of their fey cousins.</p>
            <p class="indent">The sylvicine are a short-lived race, rarely surviving past 50 years of age, but since they are born fully-formed and only show signs of their years in the final decade, they are able to live full, robust lives. Their short lifespans and immediate maturity gives lends them to be less patient than their elvish and fey cousins, particularly in times of conflict.</p>
            <p class="indent">Their societies are usually peaceful, dwelling near forests, jungles, mountains, coastlines, and deserts. Their ability to change size, coupled with their innate efficiency, allows them to easily dwell near or within other societies, though they rarely choose to. Culturally, they lean towards representative democracy to ensure that the needs of each variety are met and respected.</p>
            <h4>BORN OF SEASONS</h4>
            <p>The sylvicine come in four varieties, each corresponding with a season and a phase of the moon, and so they are revered by the Seekers of the Cycle for their connection to these celestial patterns. A sylvicine’s coloration and temperament are directly related to the time of year that they are born, but they are not born in the conventional sense.</p>
            <p class="indent">When a sylvicine dies and is buried in the ground, a tree will sprout from the place of its death, fueled with the departing life essence of the deceased. One year and one day after the burial, the tree will have become large and full to bloom, but in addition to flowers, it will bear several sylvicine, fully formed. Each will be a reflection of the original sylvicine that died, inheriting a fragment of the memories and personality of the first, but still a unique individual in their own right. All can speak immediately, and possess knowledge of how the original lived and died, often leading to terrible vengeance in the event of foul play or standing grudges against those that mistreated their progenitor. Burning the corpse of a sylvicine is viewed as the worst possible crime in their society, and is punished accordingly.</p>
            <p class="indent">The season that a sylvicine is born directly influences their personality, talents, and coloration, in addition to the memories and patters of their forebear, leading to the riot of colors and temperaments found among this race. Thankfully, siblings are usually born at the same time, leading to relative harmony among their family.</p>
            <h4>BOLD SPRING</h4>
            <p>Spring sylvicine, associated with the waxing moon, are commonly green and blue and yellow, with splashes of violet. Their wings are often wide and conventionally-shaped, with patterns like the segments of a growing leaf. They are bold and curious, driven to adventure, and are often seen as rash and naive by their kin. This boldness most often drives them to visit the towns and cities of the larger races, though they are also surprisingly respectful of personal boundaries and the limitations of others. Outside their own societies, they are commonly couriers, messengers, inventors, explorers, way-finders, guides, and herbalists.</p>
            <p class="indent">In sylvicine cities, “springlys” are more commonly viewed as the irresponsible type, and are consequentially placed into roles where they’re watched over by their more conventional kin. When they do rise to positions of authority, it is by learning the right moments to seek change, and to temper their often extraordinary expectations.</p>
            <h4>COOL SUMMER</h4>
            <p>Summer sylvicine, associated with the full moon, are color by contrast, with bright golden yellows and deep blacks, fierce purples and calm blues, or overwhelming greens and illustrious silvers. Their wings are long, thin, and wispy, frequently with small ribbons trailing from the ends. They are calm and aristocratic, prone to philosophy and recollection rather than action. This calm exterior contrasts sharply with their ambitious demeanor, for each and every one of them adores being the center of attention. Of the four varieties, they are the most prone to experiencing what they call “artistic differences” from their siblings, and when they journey outside sylvicine society, it is most often to seek a place where they can hog the spotlight. As such, they are drawn to places where artistry, performance, and expressions of intellectual beauty are relatively rare, that they might be the first to harness that untapped audience. Uplifting those poor souls is the sworn duty of a summer sylvicine, in their minds, and they are more than happy to do so. Their calm natures allow them to keep their more unusual artistic visions in check, for the most part, and it often aids them in the political sphere.</p>
            <p class="indent">In sylvicine society, the “summerlys” are often the most active in the fields of education and politics, seeing themselves as bringers of knowledge and instructors in the proper way of things. Of course, being only a quarter of their race, they trend towards more subtle methods of accruing influence, though they’re rarely malicious about it. Instead, each firmly believes that their way is best, and will peacefully push for that task to be achieved, until it eventually is in a way that they’ll get credit for.</p>
            <h4>CLEVER AUTUMN</h4>
            <p>Autumn sylvicine, associated with the waning moon, are commonly the colors of fallen leaves, with oranges, reds, browns, and yellows in abundance, with occasional patterns of vibrant pink or shining blue. Their wings are especially irregular and large, with odd whirling patterns and curious curves. Autumn sylvicine are straightforward and frank, dedicated and industrious. They are particularly revered for their ingenuity and ability to iterate on existing designs and processes, and for their valor in battle. When war comes to the doorstep of this peaceful race, the autumns are often the first to take the field. They are viewed as the backbone of sylvicine society, and are well-respected by the springlys for their decisiveness, the summerlys for their loyalty, and the winterlys for their candor. As a consequence, they rarely leave their homelands unless driven by a particularly strong motive, but when they do leave, they often take work as mercenaries, scouts, machinists, scribes, and craftspeople.</p>
            <p class="indent">Autumn sylvicine are also those greatest affected by their progenitor’s personalities, so while they have a well-earned reputation, that stereotype does not always apply as fully as some might assume. “Autumnlys” that came from springlys are often some of the bravest warriors and brashest fighters, blessed with a certain strategic cunning. Those from summerlys make excellent managers and organizers, being well suited to help others rise to the occasion. Autumnlys from winter sylvicine often lean more towards the arts of scholarship and magic than their contemporaries, though the study of the arcane is not unusual to any.</p>
            <h4>QUIET WINTER</h4>
            <p>The winter sylvicine, associated with the new moon, possess colorations that are common amongst the darker months. Vibrant, pale whites and deep, luxurious blacks blend with icy blues, shining silvers, and patterns of royal purple. Their wings and long, thin, and sharp, like icicles in from a branch, and their faces are particularly pointed. They are reserved, cautious, and secretive, especially when outside their homelands. This hesitation is contradicted by their shocking inquisitiveness and penchant for pointed questions, for it is not uncommon for one to remain silent until demanding to know a particularly personal bit of information or an extremely unusual fact regarding a given story or situation.</p>
            <p class="indent">Winter sylvicine are warmer and friendlier towards those they trust and know well, but to those they are unfamiliar with, they often are as harsh as a mountain breeze. Many are particularly studious of the arcane, expanding upon their knowledge by hunting down scraps of lost lore, or visiting the libraries and arcaneries of the larger races. They care less for courtesy than the others, and view the springlys as pointlessly hesitant when it comes to the property or secrets of those they do not know. Despite this, most that venture into the world are revered for their magical discoveries and unique perspectives.</p>
            <p class="indent">Among the sylvicine, “winterlys” are have an unusual reputation. Their secretive nature puts them on the outskirts of their society more often than not, but their inquisitiveness and expertise often push them to the forefront of many intellectual pursuits, and their affinity for magic is very well-respected. Unfortunately, their secrecy also creates an undercurrent of a particularly fearsome reputation; one that winterlys quietly approve of. Legends of winterly assassins, spies, and arcanists disposing of interlopers or intruders into the lands of this diminutive race are often well-founded.</p>
            <h4>CALL TO ADVENTURE</h4>
            <p>Sylvicine that venture forth from their societies to see the world often have a personal stake in things. Among the springlys, that calling is simply personal rebellion against a mundane existence. For summerlys, it’s a desire to share knowledge and seek fame. For autumnlys, material gain or a sense of duty are the most common reasons to depart, while winterlys seek to expand their studies with the limited time allotted to them in their short lifespans.</p>
            <h4>SYLVICINE NAMES</h4>
            <p>Sylvicine are born fully mature, and are named by their siblings upon their emergence from their birth tree. They take their progenitor’s personal name as a surname, to identify their siblings, but are otherwise named in accordance with their own individual appearances, personalties, and similarly appropriate circumstances. Some request to be named after certain things they see or remember, but their siblings have the ultimate choice.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Spring Names.</strong> April, Dewdrop, Sunbeam, Petal, Rose, Thorn, Creek, Wave, Blossom, Oak, Day</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Summer Names.</strong> Moonlight, Firesong, Violet, Bumble, Flutterwing, Luna, Somber, Sunflower</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Autumn Names.</strong> Pumpkin, Rake, Breeze, Anna, Durvan, Dire, Harvest, Keeper, Might, Sunset, Dawn</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Winter Names.</strong> Quiet, Whisper, Soft, Sharp, Darkness, Grim, Tact, Curious, Silent, Cunning, Veil</p>
            <h4>Sylvicine Traits</h4>
            <p>As a sylvicine, you gain the following racial traits:</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong> Sylvicine are cunning and extremely quick. Choose either Dexterity or Intelligence. Your chosen ability increases by 2, and the other increases by 1.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Age.</em></strong> Sylvicine are born fully formed and mature, but live only about 50 years, showing signs of age only in the last decade.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Alignment.</em></strong> Sylvicine society is relatively peaceful and benevolent, for the most part, though each individual is born under very different circumstances.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Size.</em></strong> Sylvicine are naturally between 6-9 inches tall. Your size is Tiny.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Speed.</em></strong> Your walking speed is 30.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Fey Ancestry.</em></strong> You have advantage on saving throws against being charmed, and magic can’t put you to sleep.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Fluttering Wings.</em></strong> As a sylvicine, you possess gossamer wings that allow you to fly a short distance into the air. While you are Tiny, you can use these wings to fly up to 10 feet into the air above a solid or liquid surface, and they grant you a flying speed of 35 feet. While Tiny, when you fly over a drop, you safely descend at a rate of 60 feet per round until you are no more than 10 feet above the lower surface. At any size, you can ignore the first 15 feet of distance fallen when calculating falling damage.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Size Shifting.</em></strong> Your innate magic allows you to instantly grow larger. At any time during your turn, you can choose to increase your size to become Small, or return to being Tiny. When you do, your dimensions multiply by four, and your weight multiplies by eight. Your equipment changes size along with you when you grow or shrink, and remains equally effective regardless of your changed size. If an object leaves your possession, it returns to normal size at the end of that turn. While you are Small or larger, your base walking speed increases to 35 feet. You can’t use this trait while you are grappled, restrained, or unable to take actions.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Languages.</em></strong> Sylvicine are born knowing the common tongue and Elvish, the language of their cousins.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <setters>
            <set name="names" type="male"></set>
            <set name="names" type="female"></set>
            <set name="names-format">{{name}}</set>
			<set name="height" modifier="1d4">5"</set>
			<set name="weight" modifier="1d4">10 lb.</set>
        </setters>
        <rules>
            <select type="Racial Trait" name="Ability Score Increase" supports="Sylvicine" />
            <grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_TINY" />
            <stat name="innate speeed" value="30" />
			<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON" />
			<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_ELVISH" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_GFP_SYLVICINE_RACIAL_TRAIT_SYLVICINE_FEY_ANCESTRY" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_GFP_SYLVICINE_RACIAL_TRAIT_SYLVICINE_FLUTTERING_WINGS" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_GFP_SYLVICINE_RACIAL_TRAIT_SYLVICINE_SIZE_SHIFTING" />
			<select type="Sub Race" name="Sylvicine Subrace" supports="Sylvicine" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Dexterity +2, Intelligence +1" type="Racial Trait" source="The Sylvicine" id="ID_GFP_SYLVICINE_RACIAL_TRAIT_SYLVICINE_DEXTERITY_EMPHASIS">
            <description>
                <p>Your Dexterity increases by 2 and your Intelligence increases by 1.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false" />
            <rules>
                <stat name="dexterity" value="2" />
                <stat name="intelligence" value="1" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Intelligence +2, Dexterity +1" type="Racial Trait" source="The Sylvicine" id="ID_GFP_SYLVICINE_RACIAL_TRAIT_SYLVICINE_INTELLIGENCE_EMPHASIS">
            <description>
                <p>You Intelligence increases by 2 and your Dexterity increases by 1.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false" />
            <rules>
                <stat name="intelligence" value="2" />
                <stat name="dexterity" value="1" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Fey Ancestry" type="Racial Trait" source="The Sylvicine" id="ID_GFP_SYLVICINE_RACIAL_TRAIT_SYLVICINE_FEY_ANCESTRY">
            <description>
                <p>You have advantage on saving throws against being charmed, and magic can’t put you to sleep.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You have advantage on saving throws against being charmed, and magic can’t put you to sleep.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Fluttering Wings" type="Racial Trait" source="The Sylvicine" id="ID_GFP_SYLVICINE_RACIAL_TRAIT_SYLVICINE_FLUTTERING_WINGS">
            <description>
                <p>As a sylvicine, you possess gossamer wings that allow you to fly a short distance into the air. While you are Tiny, you can use these wings to fly up to 10 feet into the air above a solid or liquid surface, and they grant you a flying speed of 35 feet. While Tiny, when you fly over a drop, you safely descend at a rate of 60 feet per round until you are no more than 10 feet above the lower surface. At any size, you can ignore the first 15 feet of distance fallen when calculating falling damage.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>While you are Tiny, you can use these wings to fly up to 10 feet into the air above a solid or liquid surface, and they grant you a flying speed of 35 feet. While Tiny, when you fly over a drop, you safely descend at a rate of 60 feet per round until you are no more than 10 feet above the lower surface. At any size, you can ignore the first 15 feet of distance fallen when calculating falling damage.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="innate speed:fly" value="35" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Size Shifting" type="Racial Trait" source="The Sylvicine" id="ID_GFP_SYLVICINE_RACIAL_TRAIT_SYLVICINE_SIZE_SHIFTING">
            <description>
                <p>Your innate magic allows you to instantly grow larger. At any time during your turn, you can choose to increase your size to become Small, or return to being Tiny. When you do, your dimensions multiply by four, and your weight multiplies by eight. Your equipment changes size along with you when you grow or shrink, and remains equally effective regardless of your changed size. If an object leaves your possession, it returns to normal size at the end of that turn. While you are Small or larger, your base walking speed increases to 35 feet. You can’t use this trait while you are grappled, restrained, or unable to take actions.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>At any time during your turn, you can choose to increase your size to become Small, or return to being Tiny. When you do, your dimensions multiply by four, and your weight multiplies by eight. Your equipment changes size along with you when you grow or shrink, and remains equally effective regardless of your changed size. If an object leaves your possession, it returns to normal size at the end of that turn. While you are Small or larger, your base walking speed increases to 35 feet. You can’t use this trait while you are grappled, restrained, or unable to take actions.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>


	<element name="Spring Sylvicine" type="Sub Race" source="The Sylvicine" id="ID_GFP_SYLVICINE_SUB_RACE_SYLVICINE_SPRING">
		<supports>Sylvicine</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Spring sylvicine are born during the season of growth and change, though on rare occasion are born during other months when the moon is waxing full. Their skin, hair, eyes, and wings are usually blue, green, yellow, brown, or some combination therein. They are the boldest of their kind, and make for excellent adventurers.</p>
            <h5>Spring Sylvicine Traits</h5>
            <p>As a spring sylvicine, you gain the following additional traits.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Bold.</em></strong> You gain advantage on saving throws against effects that would cause you to be frightened.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Inventive.</em></strong> You can take the Use an Object action using your bonus action during each of your turns.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Respectful.</em></strong> When making a Persuasion check while interacting with a creature, when you would fail the check, you can choose to use this feature to backpedal. When you do, treat your request as though you hadn’t made it. For example, if you asked a monarch for a favor and they would be offended by your failed request, using this trait would cause them to simply ignore the request instead.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you use this trait, you can’t do so again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<setters>
            <set name="names" type="male">Dewdrop, Sunbeam, Petal, Thorn, Creek, Wave, Oak, Day</set>
            <set name="names" type="female">April, Dewdrop, Sunbeam, Petal, Rose, Creek, Wave, Blossom, Day</set>
            <set name="names-format">{{name}}</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_GFP_SYLVICINE_RACIAL_TRAIT_SPRING_BOLD" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_GFP_SYLVICINE_RACIAL_TRAIT_SPRING_INVENTIVE" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_GFP_SYLVICINE_RACIAL_TRAIT_SPRING_RESPECTFUL" />
		</rules>
	</element>
        <element name="Bold" type="Racial Trait" source="The Sylvicine" id="ID_GFP_SYLVICINE_RACIAL_TRAIT_SPRING_BOLD">
            <description>
                <p>You gain advantage on saving throws against effects that would cause you to be frightened.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You have advantage on saving throws against effects that would cause you to be frightened.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Inventive" type="Racial Trait" source="The Sylvicine" id="ID_GFP_SYLVICINE_RACIAL_TRAIT_SPRING_INVENTIVE">
            <description>
                <p>You can take the Use an Object action using your bonus action during each of your turns.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>You can take the Use an Object action using your bonus action during each of your turns.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Respectful" type="Racial Trait" source="The Sylvicine" id="ID_GFP_SYLVICINE_RACIAL_TRAIT_SPRING_RESPECTFUL">
            <description>
                <p>When making a Persuasion check while interacting with a creature, when you would fail the check, you can choose to use this feature to backpedal. When you do, treat your request as though you hadn’t made it. For example, if you asked a monarch for a favor and they would be offended by your failed request, using this trait would cause them to simply ignore the request instead.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this trait, you can’t do so again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
                <description>When making a Persuasion check while interacting with a creature, when you would fail the check, you can choose to use this feature to backpedal. When you do, treat your request as though you hadn’t made it.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>


	<element name="Summer Sylvicine" type="Sub Race" source="The Sylvicine" id="ID_GFP_SYLVICINE_SUB_RACE_SYLVICINE_SUMMER">
		<supports>Sylvicine</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Summer sylvicine are born during the season of fruition and life, though on rare occasion are born during other months when the moon is entirely full. Their colors trend towards contrast, with dark blacks and bright golds, strong oranges and subtle blues, or striking reds and greens. They are calm and collected, but ambitious and vain, and often make for brilliant instructors.</p>
            <h5>Summer Sylvicine Traits</h5>
            <p>As a summer sylvicine, you gain the following additional traits.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Inspired Example.</em></strong> When you make an ability check and succeed, you can choose to grant a friendly creature that can hear you advantage on their next ability check made to accomplish the same objective in the same manner.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Smart Performance.</em></strong> You have proficiency in the Performance skill, and you can use your Intelligence modifier in place of your Charisma modifier when making Charisma (Performance) checks.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Polite Society.</em></strong> You have advantage on Insight checks made to discern the emotional states of other creatures.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<setters>
            <set name="names" type="male">Firesong, Bumble, Flutterwing, Somber, Sunflower</set>
            <set name="names" type="female">Moonlight, Firesong, Violet, Bumble, Flutterwing, Luna, Sunflower</set>
            <set name="names-format">{{name}}</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_GFP_SYLVICINE_RACIAL_TRAIT_SUMMER_INSPIRED_EXAMPLE" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_GFP_SYLVICINE_RACIAL_TRAIT_SUMMER_SMART_PERFORMANCE" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_GFP_SYLVICINE_RACIAL_TRAIT_SUMMER_POLITE_SOCIETY" />
		</rules>
	</element> 	
        <element name="Inspired Example" type="Racial Trait" source="The Sylvicine" id="ID_GFP_SYLVICINE_RACIAL_TRAIT_SUMMER_INSPIRED_EXAMPLE">
            <description>
                <p>When you make an ability check and succeed, you can choose to grant a friendly creature that can hear you advantage on their next ability check made to accomplish the same objective in the same manner.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you make an ability check and succeed, you can choose to grant a friendly creature that can hear you advantage on their next ability check made to accomplish the same objective in the same manner.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Smart Performance" type="Racial Trait" source="The Sylvicine" id="ID_GFP_SYLVICINE_RACIAL_TRAIT_SUMMER_SMART_PERFORMANCE">
            <description>
                <p>You have proficiency in the Performance skill, and you can use your Intelligence modifier in place of your Charisma modifier when making Charisma (Performance) checks.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can use your Intelligence modifier in place of your Charisma modifier when making Performance checks.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERFORMANCE" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Polite Society" type="Racial Trait" source="The Sylvicine" id="ID_GFP_SYLVICINE_RACIAL_TRAIT_SUMMER_POLITE_SOCIETY">
            <description>
                <p>You have advantage on Insight checks made to discern the emotional states of other creatures.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You have advantage on Insight checks made to discern the emotional states of other creatures.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>


	<element name="Autumn Sylvicine" type="Sub Race" source="The Sylvicine" id="ID_GFP_SYLVICINE_SUB_RACE_SYLVICINE_AUTUMN">
		<supports>Sylvicine</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Autumn sylvicine are born during the season of harvest and decline, though on rare occasion are born during other months when the moon is waning. Their colors trend towards those of the falling leaves, with golds, oranges, browns, and maroons in abundance. They are straightforward, clever, and industrious, and make for excellent warriors and soldiers.</p>
            <h5>Autumn Sylvicine Traits</h5>
            <p>As an autumn sylvicine, you gain the following additional traits.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Ingenious Armament.</em></strong> You gain proficiency with improvised weapons, and you can add the finesse property to improvised weapons you wield.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>To The Point.</em></strong> When you make an ability check with advantage, you can choose to roll a single d20 instead of two and add a +4 bonus to the roll result.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Candor.</em></strong> You can choose to tell the truth even when an effect, spell, or other mental compulsion would cause you to speak a lie.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<setters>
            <set name="names" type="male">Pumpkin, Rake, Breeze, Durvan, Dire, Harvest, Keeper, Might, Sunset, </set>
            <set name="names" type="female">Pumpkin, Breeze, Anna, Dire, Harvest, Keeper, Sunset, Dawn</set>
            <set name="names-format">{{name}}</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_GFP_SYLVICINE_RACIAL_TRAIT_AUTUMN_INGENIOUS_ARMAMENT" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_GFP_SYLVICINE_RACIAL_TRAIT_AUTUMN_TO_THE_POINT" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_GFP_SYLVICINE_RACIAL_TRAIT_AUTUMN_CANDOR" />
		</rules>
	</element> 	
        <element name="Ingenious Armament" type="Racial Trait" source="The Sylvicine" id="ID_GFP_SYLVICINE_RACIAL_TRAIT_AUTUMN_INGENIOUS_ARMAMENT">
            <description>
                <p>You gain proficiency with improvised weapons, and you can add the finesse property to improvised weapons you wield.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You have proficiency with improvised weapons, and you can add the finesse property to improvised weapons you wield.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="To The Point" type="Racial Trait" source="The Sylvicine" id="ID_GFP_SYLVICINE_RACIAL_TRAIT_AUTUMN_TO_THE_POINT">
            <description>
                <p>When you make an ability check with advantage, you can choose to roll a single d20 instead of two and add a +4 bonus to the roll result.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you make an ability check with advantage, you can choose to roll a single d20 instead of two and add a +4 bonus to the roll result.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Candor" type="Racial Trait" source="The Sylvicine" id="ID_GFP_SYLVICINE_RACIAL_TRAIT_AUTUMN_CANDOR">
            <description>
                <p>You can choose to tell the truth even when an effect, spell, or other mental compulsion would cause you to speak a lie.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can choose to tell the truth even when an effect, spell, or other mental compulsion would cause you to speak a lie.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>


	<element name="Winter Sylvicine" type="Sub Race" source="The Sylvicine" id="ID_GFP_SYLVICINE_SUB_RACE_SYLVICINE_WINTER">
		<supports>Sylvicine</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Winter sylvicine are born during the season of death and endings, though on rare occasion are born during other months when the moon is entirely unseen. They are garbed in blacks and whites, silvers and grays, purples, and icy blue. They are secretive, cunning, and gifted in the arcane arts.</p>
            <h5>Winter Sylvicine Traits</h5>
            <p>As a winter sylvicine, you gain the following additional traits.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Cantrips.</em></strong> You know two cantrips of your choosing from the wizard spell list. Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for these cantrips.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Secretive.</em></strong> When a creature attempts to read your mind, you are aware of its attempt, and you gain advantage on ability checks and saving throws to resist the attempt.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<setters>
            <set name="names" type="male">Quiet, Whisper, Sharp, Darkness, Grim, Tact, Curious, Silent, Cunning</set>
            <set name="names" type="female">Quiet, Whisper, Soft, Sharp, Tact, Curious, Silent, Veil</set>
            <set name="names-format">{{name}}</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_GFP_SYLVICINE_RACIAL_TRAIT_WINTER_CANTRIPS" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_GFP_SYLVICINE_RACIAL_TRAIT_WINTER_SECRETIVE" />
		</rules>
	</element> 	
        <element name="Cantrips" type="Racial Trait" source="The Sylvicine" id="ID_GFP_SYLVICINE_RACIAL_TRAIT_WINTER_CANTRIPS">
            <description>
                <p>You know two cantrips of your choosing from the wizard spell list. Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for these cantrips.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You know two cantrips of your choosing from the wizard spell list. Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for these cantrips.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Winter Sylvicine)" number="2" supports="Wizard,0" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Secretive" type="Racial Trait" source="The Sylvicine" id="ID_GFP_SYLVICINE_RACIAL_TRAIT_WINTER_SECRETIVE">
            <description>
                <p>When a creature attempts to read your mind, you are aware of its attempt, and you gain advantage on ability checks and saving throws to resist the attempt.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When a creature attempts to read your mind, you are aware of its attempt, and you gain advantage on ability checks and saving throws to resist the attempt.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>


</elements>