<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Nymphling Race</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="race-nymphling.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/races/race-nymphling.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="The Nymphling Race" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_VOLOTHAMP_GMBINDER_SOURCE_NYMPHLING_RACE">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation"></set>
            <set name="url">https://www.gmbinder.com/share/-M4dNGXFlkBi1OPjuUDX</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" url="https://www.gmbinder.com/profile/volothamp">Volothamp</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20200501</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Nymph" type="Race" source="The Nymphling Race" id="ID_VOLOTHAMP_NYMPHLING_RACE_NYMPH">
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Fine kid, I’ll tell you a story. Long ago, when I was your age, I was prancing around in the forest. After a while, I found my self in a clearing. I grew suddenly tired so I lay against a tree. Before I knew it, I was blinking awake and it was sunset, and standing in front of me was a woman. Her skin was tinted green; her hair was messy and filled with leaves. She spoke to me in a language I didn’t understand. I tried to respond but the words would not leave my mouth. She smiled, turned, and left. I saw her walk into a tree across the clearing. She just melded with it. Ever since that day I knew the trees were alive. Remember that kid, it’s the greatest lesson I’ve ever learned.</p>
            <p style="text-align: right;">—Jeff the Carpenter, speaking to his grandson</p>
            <p>Nymphlings are descendants of nature spirits. They have inherited their ancestors’ ability to meld with certain aspects of nature. They often seem out of touch with the world because they spend so much time communing with the flora and fauna of the wild. Many archdruids are weaker nymphs whose ancestry is so diluted that they have lost most of their fey connection.</p>
            <h4>REFLECTIONS OF NATURE</h4>
            <p>The nymphs of long ago were descended from powerful gods of nature. When they were born they divided themselves among different parts of the world. The common folk worshiped them almost as much as they worshiped their actual gods.</p>
            <p class="indent">The nymphs presided over various phenomena, from springs, to clouds, trees, meadows, caverns, and beaches, or even the stars. And, just like their predecessors, their personalities often reflect the part of nature their spirit is connected to. Oreads are often strong, calm, and cold; dryads are sturdy, rough, and wise; naiads are quick, flighty, and charming.</p>
            <p class="indent">When creating a nymph character consider your adventurer’s relationships with nature. Do they try to repress their strange abilities, or do they show them off to impress others? Are they adventuring to escape their past, or to find it? Do they have connections to other nymphs, or are they alone and trying to figure out why they are the way they are?</p>
            <h4>BORN WITH POWER</h4>
            <p>Many nymphs have innate sorcerous abilities that are related to their spiritual phenomenon. Aurae can speak to the wind, commanding it to follow their will; asteriae can create light like a star; nereids can speak to sea creatures and bend them to their command. These powers shape how a nymph will choose a profession in the real world. Perhaps the nereids lean towards fishing because they can command the fish to flow into their net. Or maybe a dryad would be sought by a king to help a forest from being poisoned.</p>
            <p class="indent">The nymphs are not only born with magical powers but often also political power. Nymphs are often born into noble families because kings and noblemen would try to satisfy them to bring good luck upon their kingdom. Additionally, on their travels, adventurers often come upon nymphs during quests.</p>
            <h4>NYMPH NAMES</h4>
            <p>The names of the nymph are usually reflective of the part of nature they are connected to. Sometimes nymphs also have normal names that they put at the start of their name to keep their nymph nature secret (eg. Andy Willow). However, more often than not, they only have one name.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Nymph Names:</strong> Juniper, Aella, Anemone, Thunder, Stone, Peak, Oak, Zephyr, Ash, Onyx, Summit, Crack, Crag, Bubble, Brook, Bambi, Mull.</p>
            <div ref="sidebar">
                <h5 class="caption">Optional Restriction: Females Only</h5>
                <p>In many myths and legends, nymphs were minor female only goddesses. In some games the DM may restrict you to only be able to play this race if your character is female.</p>
            </div>
            <h4>Nymph Traits</h4>
            <p>Your nymph character has the following traits.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong> Your Wisdom score is increased by 2.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Age.</em></strong> Nymphs are created through natural magic, and are born fully grown. There has not been a documented nymph who has died of old age.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Alignment.</em></strong> Nymphs often don’t like to conform to society; they value freedom and diversity, so they tend to lean towards chaos. However, it is just as likely to find an evil nymph as a good one.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Size.</em></strong> Due to the reflective nature of the nymphs, they can range from barely 5 feet to well over 6 feet tall. Your size is Medium.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Speed.</em></strong> Your walking speed is 30 feet.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Fey Ancestry.</em></strong> You have advantage on saving throws against being charmed, and magic can’t put you to sleep.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Languages.</em></strong> You can speak, read, and write Common and Sylvan.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Subrace.</em></strong> The part of nature that your spirit connects to can shape a nymph’s body and soul. The four major subraces of nymph include: dryads, oreads, aurae, and water nymphs. There are multiple types of water nymphs, such as nereids and naiads. This document also includes asteriae, lampads, and maenads in addition to the other nymph subraces to choose from.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <setters>
            <set name="names" type="male">male</set>
            <set name="names" type="female">female</set>
            <set name="names-format">{{name}}</set>
            <set name="height" modifier="2d10">4'8"</set>
            <set name="weight" modifier="2d4">90 lb.</set>
        </setters>>
        <rules>
            <stat name="wisdom" value="2" />
            <grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_MEDIUM" />
            <stat name="innate speed" value="30" bonus="base"/>
            <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON" />
            <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_SYLVAN" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_VOLOTHAMP_NYMPHLING_RACIAL_TRAIT_NYMPH_FEY_ANCESTRY" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_VOLOTHAMP_NYMPHLING_RACIAL_TRAIT_NYMPH_SUBRACE" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Fey Ancestry" type="Racial Trait" source="The Nymphling Race" id="ID_VOLOTHAMP_NYMPHLING_RACIAL_TRAIT_NYMPH_FEY_ANCESTRY">
            <description>
                <p>You have advantage on saving throws against being charmed, and magic can’t put you to sleep.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You have advantage on saving throws against being charmed, and magic can’t put you to sleep.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Subrace" type="Racial Trait" source="The Nymphling Race" id="ID_VOLOTHAMP_NYMPHLING_RACIAL_TRAIT_NYMPH_SUBRACE">
            <description>
                <p>The part of nature that your spirit connects to can shape a nymph’s body and soul. The four major subraces of nymph include: dryads, oreads, aurae, and water nymphs. There are multiple types of water nymphs, such as nereids and naiads. This document also includes asteriae, lampads, and maenads in addition to the other nymph subraces to choose from.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            <select type="Sub Race" name="Nymph Subrace" supports="Nymphling" />
            </rules>
        </element>
    
    <element name="Asteria" type="Sub Race" source="The Nymphling Race" id="ID_VOLOTHAMP_NYMPHLING_SUBRACE_NYMPH_ASTERIA">
        <supports>Nymphling</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Asteriae are descendants of the gods and goddesses of the constellations. Most asteriae are connected to a random star in the sky, but some of the more powerful ones may be connected to part of a constellation. Asteriae are often bright, happy, and willing to help others. They are like tiny lights in the middle of the darkness.</p>
            <p class="indent">The appearance of star nymphs varies, but they almost always stand out. The most striking thing about them is their eyes, glossy and without pupils and either silver or black.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Ability Score Increase.</strong> Your Charisma score is increased by 1.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Darkvision.</strong> You have superior vision in dark and dim conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can’t discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Starry Eyes.</strong> Your heritage makes you want to be friends with everyone. You have proficiency in either the Persuasion or Performance skill (your choice).</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Light Bringer.</strong> You know the dancing lights cantrip. When you reach 3rd level, you can cast the faerie fire spell, and upon reaching 5th level, you can cast the moonbeam spell. Once you cast a spell with this trait, you cannot do so again until you finish a long rest. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for these spells.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="charisma" value="1" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_VOLOTHAMP_NYMPHLING_RACIAL_TRAIT_ASTERIA_DARKVISION" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_VOLOTHAMP_NYMPHLING_RACIAL_TRAIT_ASTERIA_STARRY_EYES" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_VOLOTHAMP_NYMPHLING_RACIAL_TRAIT_ASTERIA_LIGHT_BRINGER" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Darkvision" type="Racial Trait" source="The Nymphling Race" id="ID_VOLOTHAMP_NYMPHLING_RACIAL_TRAIT_ASTERIA_DARKVISION">
            <description>
                <p>You have superior vision in dark and dim conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can’t discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can’t discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_DARKVISION" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Starry Eyes" type="Racial Trait" source="The Nymphling Race" id="ID_VOLOTHAMP_NYMPHLING_RACIAL_TRAIT_ASTERIA_STARRY_EYES">
            <description>
                <p>Your heritage makes you want to be friends with everyone. You have proficiency in either the Persuasion or Performance skill (your choice).</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency, Asteria" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERSUASION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERFORMANCE" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Light Bringer" type="Racial Trait" source="The Nymphling Race" id="ID_VOLOTHAMP_NYMPHLING_RACIAL_TRAIT_ASTERIA_LIGHT_BRINGER">
            <description>
                <p>You know the <em>dancing lights</em> cantrip. When you reach 3rd level, you can cast the <em>faerie fire</em> spell, and upon reaching 5th level, you can cast the <em>moonbeam</em> spell. Once you cast a spell with this trait, you cannot do so again until you finish a long rest. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for these spells.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You know the dancing lights cantrip. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability.</description>
                <description usage="1/Long Rest" level="3">You know the dancing lights cantrip. You can cast faerie fire. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability.</description>
                <description usage="1/Long Rest" level="5">You know the dancing lights cantrip. You can cast faerie fire and moonbeam once each. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DANCING_LIGHTS" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FAERIE_FIRE" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MOONBEAM" level="5" />
            </rules>
        </element>

    
    <element name="Aurae" type="Sub Race" source="The Nymphling Race" id="ID_VOLOTHAMP_NYMPHLING_SUBRACE_NYMPH_AURAE">
        <supports>Nymphling</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The descendants of the wind gods are quick and light. Aurae are speedy creatures, as fast as the wind and just as quicktongued.</p>
            <p class="indent">The windborn often have fair skin and hair of all kinds. Windborn are very fidgety for they all contain the energy of the wind inside of them.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Ability Score Increase.</strong> Your Dexterity score is increased by 1.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Fleet of Foot.</strong> Your base walking speed increases to 35 feet.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Leap of the Wind.</strong> Your jump distance is doubled. In addition, you can choose to use your Dexterity score instead of your Strength score when determining how far you can jump.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Light as Air.</strong> You are permanently under the effects of the feather fall spell.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Windcutting Tongue.</strong> The winds inside you don’t just make you move quicker, it makes you talk quicker. You gain proficiency in the Deception and Persuasion skills.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="dexterity" value="1" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_VOLOTHAMP_NYMPHLING_RACIAL_TRAIT_AURAE_FLEET_OF_FOOT" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_VOLOTHAMP_NYMPHLING_RACIAL_TRAIT_AURAE_LEAP_OF_THE_WIND" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_VOLOTHAMP_NYMPHLING_RACIAL_TRAIT_AURAE_LIGHT_AS_AIR" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_VOLOTHAMP_NYMPHLING_RACIAL_TRAIT_AURAE_WINDCUTTING_TONGUE" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Fleet of Foot" type="Racial Trait" source="The Nymphling Race" id="ID_VOLOTHAMP_NYMPHLING_RACIAL_TRAIT_AURAE_FLEET_OF_FOOT">
            <description>
                <p>Your base walking speed increases to 35 feet.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="innate speed:misc" value="5" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Leap of the Wind" type="Racial Trait" source="The Nymphling Race" id="ID_VOLOTHAMP_NYMPHLING_RACIAL_TRAIT_AURAE_LEAP_OF_THE_WIND">
            <description>
                <p>Your jump distance is doubled. In addition, you can choose to use your Dexterity score instead of your Strength score when determining how far you can jump.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Your jump distance is doubled. In addition, you can choose to use your Dexterity score instead of your Strength score when determining how far you can jump.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Light as Air" type="Racial Trait" source="The Nymphling Race" id="ID_VOLOTHAMP_NYMPHLING_RACIAL_TRAIT_AURAE_LIGHT_AS_AIR">
            <description>
                <p>You are permanently under the effects of the <em>feather fall</em> spell.</p>
                <div class="reference">
                    <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_FEATHER_FALL" />
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You are permanently under the effects of the feather fall spell.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FEATHER_FALL" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Windcutting Tongue" type="Racial Trait" source="The Nymphling Race" id="ID_VOLOTHAMP_NYMPHLING_RACIAL_TRAIT_AURAE_WINDCUTTING_TONGUE">
            <description>
                <p>The winds inside you don’t just make you move quicker, it makes you talk quicker. You gain proficiency in the Deception and Persuasion skills.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_DECEPTION" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERSUASION" />
            </rules>
        </element>

    
    <element name="Dryad" type="Sub Race" source="The Nymphling Race" id="ID_VOLOTHAMP_NYMPHLING_SUBRACE_NYMPH_DRYAD">
        <supports>Nymphling</supports>
        <description>
            <p>As a dryad, progeny of the ancient trees, you have an innate connecting to the flora and fauna of the world. Some dryads are like willows, their opinions bend and flow with the wind. On the other hand, some are like oaks, strong and unchanging in their decisions.</p>
            <p class="indent">Typically, dryads have dark brown or green hair and dark skin, sometimes tinted green. Their bodies often have bark growing on pieces or even large portions skin.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Ability Score Increase.</strong> Your Strength score is increased by 1.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Speak with Plants.</strong> You can speak with plants as if you shared a language, and have advantage on checks to influence them.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Nature's Path.</strong> You learn the druidcraft cantrip. Once you reach 3rd level you can cast the barkskin spell once with this trait, requiring no material components or concentration. You regain all uses of this trait when you finish a long rest.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Lesser Tree Stride.</strong> On your turn, you can spend 10 feet of your movement to step magically into one living tree within your reach and emerge in an unoccupied space within 5 feet from a second living tree within 40 feet of the first tree. Both trees must be at least one size larger than you. This movement does not provoke opportunity attacks. You may use this ability once and regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="strength" value="1" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_VOLOTHAMP_NYMPHLING_RACIAL_TRAIT_DRYAD_SPEAK_WITH_PLANTS" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="S_PATH" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_VOLOTHAMP_NYMPHLING_RACIAL_TRAIT_DRYAD_LESSER_TREE_STRIDE" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Speak with Plants" type="Racial Trait" source="The Nymphling Race" id="ID_VOLOTHAMP_NYMPHLING_RACIAL_TRAIT_DRYAD_SPEAK_WITH_PLANTS">
            <description>
                <p>You can speak with plants as if you shared a language, and have advantage on checks to influence them.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can speak with plants as if you shared a language, and have advantage on checks to influence them.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Nature's Path" type="Racial Trait" source="The Nymphling Race" id="ID_VOLOTHAMP_NYMPHLING_RACIAL_TRAIT_DRYAD_NATURE'S_PATH">
            <description>
                <p>You learn the <em>druidcraft</em> cantrip. Once you reach 3rd level you can cast the <em>barkskin</em> spell once with this trait, requiring no material components or concentration. You regain all uses of this trait when you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You know the druidcraft cantrip.</description>
                <description level="3" usage="1/Long Rest">You know the druidcraft cantrip. You can cast the barkskin spell once with this trait, requiring no material components or concentration.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DRUIDCRAFT" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BARKSKIN" level="3" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Lesser Tree Stride" type="Racial Trait" source="The Nymphling Race" id="ID_VOLOTHAMP_NYMPHLING_RACIAL_TRAIT_DRYAD_LESSER_TREE_STRIDE">
            <description>
                <p>On your turn, you can spend 10 feet of your movement to step magically into one living tree within your reach and emerge in an unoccupied space within 5 feet from a second living tree within 40 feet of the first tree. Both trees must be at least one size larger than you. This movement does not provoke opportunity attacks. You may use this ability once and regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>On your turn, you can spend 10 feet of your movement to step magically into one living tree within your reach and emerge in an unoccupied space within 5 feet from a second living tree within 40 feet of the first tree. Both trees must be at least one size larger than you. This movement does not provoke opportunity attacks.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    
    <element name="Lampad" type="Sub Race" source="The Nymphling Race" id="ID_VOLOTHAMP_NYMPHLING_SUBRACE_NYMPH_LAMPAD">
        <supports>Nymphling</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Spirits of the afterlife, lampads are creatures of the dark and descendants of gods of death. Lampads have a ghostly connection to the prime material and seem to be in both planes at once sometimes.</p>
            <p class="indent">Lampads often appear with ghostly pale skin and grey and black hair. Their eyes seem almost lifeless most of the time and appear to gaze into the souls of regular people.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Ability Score Increase.</strong> Your Constitution or Charisma score is increased by 1.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Foot in the Styx.</strong> You have resistance to necrotic damage.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Phase from Death.</strong> When you are reduced to 0 hit points but not killed outright, you can drop to 1 hit point instead. You can’t use this feature again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Soul from Hades.</strong> You know the chill touch cantrip. When you reach 3rd level, you can cast the blur spell once with this trait, and regain the ability to do so after finishing a long rest. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for these spells.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
			<select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Ability Score Increase, Lampad" supports="ID_INTERNAL_ASI_CONSTITUTION|ID_INTERNAL_ASI_CHARISMA" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_VOLOTHAMP_NYMPHLING_RACIAL_TRAIT_LAMPAD_FOOT_IN_THE_STYX" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_VOLOTHAMP_NYMPHLING_RACIAL_TRAIT_LAMPAD_PHASE_FROM_DEATH" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_VOLOTHAMP_NYMPHLING_RACIAL_TRAIT_LAMPAD_SOUL_FROM_HADES" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Foot in the Styx" type="Racial Trait" source="The Nymphling Race" id="ID_VOLOTHAMP_NYMPHLING_RACIAL_TRAIT_LAMPAD_FOOT_IN_THE_STYX">
            <description>
                <p>You have resistance to necrotic damage.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_NECROTIC" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Phase from Death" type="Racial Trait" source="The Nymphling Race" id="ID_VOLOTHAMP_NYMPHLING_RACIAL_TRAIT_LAMPAD_PHASE_FROM_DEATH">
            <description>
                <p>When you are reduced to 0 hit points but not killed outright, you can drop to 1 hit point instead. You can’t use this feature again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>When you are reduced to 0 hit points but not killed outright, you can drop to 1 hit point instead.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Soul from Hades" type="Racial Trait" source="The Nymphling Race" id="ID_VOLOTHAMP_NYMPHLING_RACIAL_TRAIT_LAMPAD_SOUL_FROM_HADES">
            <description>
                <p>You know the chill touch cantrip. When you reach 3rd level, you can cast the blur spell once with this trait, and regain the ability to do so after finishing a long rest. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for these spells.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You know the chill touch cantrip. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability.</description>
                <description level="3" usage="1/Long Rest">You know the chill touch cantrip. You can cast the blur spell once with this trait. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CHILL_TOUCH" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLUR" level="3" />
            </rules>
        </element>

    
    <element name="Maenad" type="Sub Race" source="The Nymphling Race" id="ID_VOLOTHAMP_NYMPHLING_SUBRACE_NYMPH_MAENAD">
        <supports>Nymphling</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Maenads are descendants of the followers of gods of madness and wine. The ancestors of maenads were likely part of the inner circle of a cult of one of these gods and were affected by ancient, magical rituals.</p>
            <p class="indent">These slightly crazy creatures often appear as normal people. However, upon closer inspection, they have some strange features. Their pupils are slits, their eyes are bloodshot, their mouths are a little more red than usual, and they have pointed fangs.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Ability Score Increase.</strong> Your Constitution score increases by 1.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Accustomed to Alchohol.</strong> You have been fed wine from birth, and are used to its effects. You have resistance to poison damage, and have advantage on saving throws against being poisoned.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Dancer.</strong> Your ancestors were amazing dancers. You gain proficiency in the Performance skill.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Fangs.</strong> You have strange, sharp fangs which are natural weapons, that you can use to make unarmed strikes. If you hit with it, you deal piercing damage equal to 1d4 + your Strength modifier, instead of the bludgeoning damage normal for an unarmed strike.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Ferocious Rush.</strong> As a bonus action, you can move up to your speed toward an enemy of your choice that you can see or hear. You must end this move closer to the enemy than you started.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="constitution" value="1" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_VOLOTHAMP_NYMPHLING_RACIAL_TRAIT_MAENAD_ACCUSTOMED_TO_ALCHOHOL" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_VOLOTHAMP_NYMPHLING_RACIAL_TRAIT_MAENAD_DANCER" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_VOLOTHAMP_NYMPHLING_RACIAL_TRAIT_MAENAD_FANGS" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_VOLOTHAMP_NYMPHLING_RACIAL_TRAIT_MAENAD_FEROCIOUS_RUSH" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Accustomed to Alchohol" type="Racial Trait" source="The Nymphling Race" id="ID_VOLOTHAMP_NYMPHLING_RACIAL_TRAIT_MAENAD_ACCUSTOMED_TO_ALCHOHOL">
            <description>
                <p>You have been fed wine from birth, and are used to its effects. You have resistance to poison damage, and have advantage on saving throws against being poisoned.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You have advantage on saving throws against being poisoned.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_POISON" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Dancer" type="Racial Trait" source="The Nymphling Race" id="ID_VOLOTHAMP_NYMPHLING_RACIAL_TRAIT_MAENAD_DANCER">
            <description>
                <p>Your ancestors were amazing dancers. You gain proficiency in the Performance skill.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERFORMANCE" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Fangs" type="Racial Trait" source="The Nymphling Race" id="ID_VOLOTHAMP_NYMPHLING_RACIAL_TRAIT_MAENAD_FANGS">
            <description>
                <p>You have strange, sharp fangs which are natural weapons, that you can use to make unarmed strikes. If you hit with it, you deal piercing damage equal to 1d4 + your Strength modifier, instead of the bludgeoning damage normal for an unarmed strike.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You have fangs which are natural weapons, that you can use to make unarmed strikes. If you hit, you deal  to 1d4 + {{strength:modifier}} piercing damage.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Ferocious Rush" type="Racial Trait" source="The Nymphling Race" id="ID_VOLOTHAMP_NYMPHLING_RACIAL_TRAIT_MAENAD_FEROCIOUS_RUSH">
            <description>
                <p>As a bonus action, you can move up to your speed toward an enemy of your choice that you can see or hear. You must end this move closer to the enemy than you started.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>You can move up to your speed toward an enemy of your choice that you can see or hear. You must end this move closer to the enemy than you started.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    
    <element name="Oread" type="Sub Race" source="The Nymphling Race" id="ID_VOLOTHAMP_NYMPHLING_SUBRACE_NYMPH_OREAD">
        <supports>Nymphling</supports>
        <description>
            <p>As strong and sturdy offspring of the ancient gods, Hecaterides, oreads relate to the unmovable strength of boulders, the icy coldness of summits, and the unrelenting power of rock slides.</p>
            <p class="indent">Oreads have rough, light skin and dark hair. Even when cut and bruised, they don’t bleed very much.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Ability Score Increase.</strong> Your Strength or Constitution score is increased by 1.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Rough Skin.</strong> Your rough, stony skin is harder to break through. While you are not wearing armor, your AC equals 13 + your Dexterity modifier.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Zenith Borne.</strong> As your ancestors stayed up high in the mountains, you have resistance to cold damage.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Earth Strider.</strong> You have a climb speed of 30 feet.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
			<select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Ability Score Increase, Lampad" supports="ID_INTERNAL_ASI_CONSTITUTION|ID_INTERNAL_ASI_STRENGTH" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_VOLOTHAMP_NYMPHLING_RACIAL_TRAIT_OREAD_ROUGH_SKIN" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_VOLOTHAMP_NYMPHLING_RACIAL_TRAIT_OREAD_ZENITH_BORNE" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_VOLOTHAMP_NYMPHLING_RACIAL_TRAIT_OREAD_EARTH_STRIDER" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Rough Skin" type="Racial Trait" source="The Nymphling Race" id="ID_VOLOTHAMP_NYMPHLING_RACIAL_TRAIT_OREAD_ROUGH_SKIN">
            <description>
                <p>Your rough, stony skin is harder to break through. While you are not wearing armor, your AC equals 13 + your Dexterity modifier.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="ac:rough skin oread:base" value="13" />
                <stat name="ac:rough skin oread:dexterity" value="dexterity:modifier" />
                <stat name="ac:rough skin oread" value="ac:rough skin oread:base" />
                <stat name="ac:rough skin oread" value="ac:rough skin oread:dexterity" />
                <stat name="ac:calculation" value="ac:rough skin oread" bonus="calculation" equipped="[armor:none]" alt="Rough Skin (Oread)" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Zenith Borne" type="Racial Trait" source="The Nymphling Race" id="ID_VOLOTHAMP_NYMPHLING_RACIAL_TRAIT_OREAD_ZENITH_BORNE">
            <description>
                <p>As your ancestors stayed up high in the mountains, you have resistance to cold damage.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_COLD" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Earth Strider" type="Racial Trait" source="The Nymphling Race" id="ID_VOLOTHAMP_NYMPHLING_RACIAL_TRAIT_OREAD_EARTH_STRIDER">
            <description>
                <p>You have a climb speed of 30 feet.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="speed:climb" value="speed" bonus="base" />
            </rules>
        </element>

    
    <element name="Water Nymph" type="Sub Race" source="The Nymphling Race" id="ID_VOLOTHAMP_NYMPHLING_SUBRACE_NYMPH_WATER_NYMPH">
        <supports>Nymphling</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Descendants of the naiads and nereids, water nymphs have either a love of the sea or of rivers. This is what divides them into two categories: nereids and naiads. Nereids connect strongly with the salty waters of the deep sea, while naiads are as quick and bubbly as a fast-flowing stream.</p>
            <p class="indent">Water nymphs often have pale or light blue skin and silver or blue hair. Sometimes their hair floats as if the water nymphs were underwater.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Ability Score Increase.</strong> Your Dexterity or Charisma score increases by 1.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Child of the Current.</strong> You have a swimming speed of 30 feet and you can breathe both air and water.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Bubble Speech.</strong> You can speak to any creature that has an innate swimming speed as if you shared a language.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Mask of the Sea.</strong> Your ability to merge with the water makes you hard to see. While you are submerged in water you can attempt to hide even without cover and have advantage on all Dexterity (Stealth) checks to do so.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
			<select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Ability Score Increase, Lampad" supports="ID_INTERNAL_ASI_DEXTERITY|ID_INTERNAL_ASI_CHARISMA" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_VOLOTHAMP_NYMPHLING_RACIAL_TRAIT_WATER_NYMPH_CHILD_OF_THE_CURRENT" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_VOLOTHAMP_NYMPHLING_RACIAL_TRAIT_WATER_NYMPH_BUBBLE_SPEECH" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_VOLOTHAMP_NYMPHLING_RACIAL_TRAIT_WATER_NYMPH_MASK_OF_THE_SEA" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Child of the Current" type="Racial Trait" source="The Nymphling Race" id="ID_VOLOTHAMP_NYMPHLING_RACIAL_TRAIT_WATER_NYMPH_CHILD_OF_THE_CURRENT">
            <description>
                <p>You have a swimming speed of 30 feet and you can breathe both air and water.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can breathe both air and water.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="speed:swim" value="30" bonus="base" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Bubble Speech" type="Racial Trait" source="The Nymphling Race" id="ID_VOLOTHAMP_NYMPHLING_RACIAL_TRAIT_WATER_NYMPH_BUBBLE_SPEECH">
            <description>
                <p>You can speak to any creature that has an innate swimming speed as if you shared a language.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can speak to any creature that has an innate swimming speed as if you shared a language.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Mask of the Sea" type="Racial Trait" source="The Nymphling Race" id="ID_VOLOTHAMP_NYMPHLING_RACIAL_TRAIT_WATER_NYMPH_MASK_OF_THE_SEA">
            <description>
                <p>Your ability to merge with the water makes you hard to see. While you are submerged in water you can attempt to hide even without cover and have advantage on all Dexterity (Stealth) checks to do so.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>While you are submerged in water you can attempt to hide even without cover and have advantage on all Stealth checks to do so.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    
</elements>