<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Sarsidhe Race</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="race-sarsidhe.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/races/race-sarsidhe.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="The Sarsidhe" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_ALLIEDSALAD_HOMEBREWERY_SOURCE_The Sarsidhe">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation"></set>
            <set name="url">https://homebrewery.naturalcrit.com/share/S1mb9iDdRE</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" abbreviation="AS" url="https://www.reddit.com/user/AlliedSalad/">u/AlliedSalad</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20200501</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Sarsidhe" type="Race" source="The Sarsidge" id="ID_AS_SARSIDHE_RACE_SARSIDHE">
        <description>
            <p>Dwelling in reclusive burrows in the Feywild, or in the deepest reaches of the wilds of the Material Plane, the Sarsidhe are lighthearted and mischievous. They delight in cultivating and safeguarding the beauty of nature.</p>
            <h4>FAERIE FOLK</h4>
            <p>Though all sarsidhe appear as small, winged humanoids, they are otherwise wildly varied. Some have human-like skin and hair; others may be green or bark-like, with mossy hair; and yet others will have bright, vibrant coloring. Some may have small horns or antlers, some may have antennae, and some may have neither. Their wings are similarly varied, with translucent, dragonfly-like wings being the most common; followed by moth or butterfly-like wings; and on very rare occasion, hummingbird wings.</p>
            <p class="indent">Though diminutive by humanoid standards, the sarsidhe are the largest of the faerie, and consider themselves the chiefest of their kin. In truth, other faeriekind are more accepting of the sarsidhe than of outsiders or intruders to their woods, but still prefer to keep their secrets to themselves.</p>
            <h4>GARDENERS AND CARETAKERS</h4>
            <p>The Sarsidhe make their homes in comfortable burrows, either in a suitable earthen mound, or in the hollow or roots of large trees. A tree that becomes home to a Sarsidhe burrow is never harmed by this; on the contrary, the faeries will help the tree to thrive, resulting in an almost symbiotic relationship. Sarsidhe are lovers of natural beauty, and will tend and care for all plant life near their homes. They are especially fond of flowering plants, and will help these species to proliferate and fill the area with their color and aroma.</p>
            <p class="indent">Any big folk who happen to wander into a Sarsidhe’s glade would hardly guess it to be inhabited. Though the area is certain to be lush and vibrant, it will also be wild and thick with growth, perhaps proving difficult for flightless creatures to navigate. Any doors or entrances to the faerie burrows are certain to be expertly hidden, all but impossible to find unless the Sarsidhe wish it to be.</p>
            <h4>Sarsidhe Traits</h4>
            <p>Your Sarsidhe character has the following traits.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong> Your Strength score is reduced by 2, your Dexterity score increases by 2, and your Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma score increases by 1.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Age.</em></strong> Sarsidhe reach maturity at about 8 years of age, and live an average of 35 years.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Alignment.</em></strong> Sarsidhe tend toward chaotic good. While they have a strong mischievous streak, they also have an instinctive desire to nurture and safeguard life.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Size.</em></strong> Sarsidhe typically range between 2 and 2 ½ feet in height. They are extremely light, even for their small size, typically weighing around only 20 pounds. Your size is small. Equipment made in your size weighs half its standard weight.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Speed.</em></strong> You have a base walking speed of 25 feet. You have a flying speed of 35 feet. You cannot fly while encumbered or while wearing heavy armor.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Darkvision.</em></strong> Accustomed to dense forest and moonlit nights, you have superior vision in dark and dim conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can’t discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Thrumming Wings.</em></strong> Your wings produce an audible thrumming or fluttering sound while in use. While flying, you cannot be hidden from creatures within 60 feet of you that can hear you.</p>
            <p class="indent">Any armor or other clothing you wear must be made or modified to accomodate your wings. Magical armor which can change its size to fit its wearer may also be able to adjust itself to allow for your wings, at your DM’s discretion.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Faeriekind.</em></strong> Your creature type is fey, rather than humanoid.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Languages.</em></strong> You can speak, read, and write Common and Sylvan.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Faerie Magic.</em></strong> You know the <em>druidcraft</em> cantrip.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Live to the Fullest.</em></strong> You are resistant to being aged by any means other than the natural passage of time. If subjected to any spell or other effect which would alter your physical age, the number of years your age would change is halved.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <stat name="strength" value="-2" />
            <stat name="dexterity" value="2" />
			<select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Ability Score Increase, Veditnal" supports="ID_INTERNAL_ASI_INTELLIGENCE|ID_INTERNAL_ASI_WISDOM|ID_INTERNAL_ASI_CHARISMA" />
			<grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_SMALL" />
            <stat name="innate speed" value="25" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="innate speed:fly" value="35" bonus="base" />
            <grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_DARKVISION" />
            <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON" />
            <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_SYLVAN" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_AS_SARSIDHE_RACIAL_TRAIT_SARSIDHE_THRUMMING_WINGS" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_AS_SARSIDHE_RACIAL_TRAIT_SARSIDHE_FAERIEKIND" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_AS_SARSIDHE_RACIAL_TRAIT_SARSIDHE_LIVE_TO_THE_FULLEST" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Thrumming Wings" type="Racial Trait" source="The Sarsidhe" id="ID_AS_SARSIDHE_RACIAL_TRAIT_SARSIDHE_THRUMMING_WINGS">
            <description>
                <p>Your wings produce an audible thrumming or fluttering sound while in use. While flying, you cannot be hidden from creatures within 60 feet of you that can hear you.</p>
                <p class="indent">Any armor or other clothing you wear must be made or modified to accomodate your wings. Magical armor which can change its size to fit its wearer may also be able to adjust itself to allow for your wings, at your DM’s discretion.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>While flying, you cannot be hidden from creatures within 60 feet of you that can hear you.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Faeriekind" type="Racial Trait" source="The Sarsidhe" id="ID_AS_SARSIDHE_RACIAL_TRAIT_SARSIDHE_FAERIEKIND">
            <description>
                <p>Your creature type is fey, rather than humanoid.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Your creature type is fey, rather than humanoid.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Faerie Magic" type="Racial Trait" source="The Sarsidhe" id="ID_AS_SARSIDHE_RACIAL_TRAIT_SARSIDHE_FAERIE_MAGIC">
            <description>
                <p>You know the <em>druidcraft</em> cantrip.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You know the druidcraft cantrip.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DRUIDCRAFT" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Live to the Fullest" type="Racial Trait" source="The Sarsidhe" id="ID_AS_SARSIDHE_RACIAL_TRAIT_SARSIDHE_LIVE_TO_THE_FULLEST">
            <description>
                <p>You are resistant to being aged by any means other than the natural passage of time. If subjected to any spell or other effect which would alter your physical age, the number of years your age would change is halved.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You are resistant to being aged by any means other than the natural passage of time. If subjected to any spell or other effect which would alter your physical age, the number of years your age would change is halved.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
</elements>