<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Backgrounds from Kibbles’ Artificer Extended Toolbox</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="backgrounds.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/kibblestasty/artificer-extended-toolbox/backgrounds.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Apothecary" type="Background" source="Kibbles’ Artificer Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KAET_BACKGROUND_APOTHECARY">
        <description>
            <p>You were a mixer of potions, master of the subtle art of producing potent magical effects from the right distilations. Hailing from the largest cities or the smallest villages, an apothecary's work is always in demand, though many that would demand it do not fully appreciate the care that goes into making a potion safe and effective.</p>
            <p class="indent"></p>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Skill Proficiencies:</strong> Nature, Medicine</li>
                <li><strong>Tool Proficiencies:</strong> Alchemist's supplies, Herbalism Kit.</li>
                <li><strong>Equipment:</strong> A minor healing potion, a set of Alchemy Supplies, an Herbalism Kit, and a set of common clothes.</li>
            </ul>
            <div element="ID_KT_KAET_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_HERBLORE" />
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="short">Nature, Medicine, Alchemist's supplies, Herbalism Kit</set>
        </setters>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_KT_KAET_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_HERBLORE" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_OPTIONAL_BACKGROUND_FEATURE"/>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_NATURE" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_MEDICINE" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_ALCHEMISTS_SUPPLIES" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_HERBALISM_KIT" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Feature: Herblore" type="Background Feature" source="Kibbles’ Artificer Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KAET_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_HERBLORE">
        <description>
            <p>You know what the potions people drink are actually made of. Whenever traveling at half speed or less through wilderness or camping in wilderness, you can acquire 10 gold pieces a day worth of potion reagents. These can be used against the next potion you craft.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet alt="Herblore">
            <description>Whenever traveling at half speed or less through wilderness or camping in wilderness, you can acquire 10 gold pieces a day worth of potion reagents.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Engineer" type="Background" source="Kibbles’ Artificer Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KAET_BACKGROUND_ENGINEER">
        <description>
            <p>Scholars and Academics are great, but many a kingdom has needed those of the more intellectual bent to put their intellect to more practical uses - designing everything from siege equipment to bridges.</p>
            <p class="indent">While construction may or may not have used magic here and there, at the end of the day something built without an engineer's oversight is much more likely to fall back down when it is needed most.</p>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Skill Proficiencies:</strong> Investigation, Nature</li>
                <li><strong>Tool Proficiencies:</strong> Carpenter's Tools, Mason's Tools</li>
                <li><strong>Equipment:</strong> A bottle of black ink, a quill, a small knife, the blue prints to the last project you were working on, a set of common clothes, and a belt pouch containing 10 gp.</li>
            </ul>
            <div element="ID_KT_KAET_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_BLUEPRINTS" />
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="short">Investigation, Nature, Carpenter's Tools, Mason's Tools</set>
        </setters>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_KT_KAET_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_BLUEPRINTS" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_OPTIONAL_BACKGROUND_FEATURE"/>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INVESTIGATION" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_NATURE" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_CARPENTERS_TOOLS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_MASONS_TOOLS" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Feature: Blueprints" type="Background Feature" source="Kibbles’ Artificer Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KAET_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_BLUEPRINTS">
        <description>
            <p>Given a little time to plan, you can produce blueprints or schematics for bridges, siege equipment, buildings, dams, or any other common feat of engineering that anyone proficient with the necessary artisan tools required to could follow to craft the outlined construction given the time and resources. Buildings more fantastical in nature may still be within your grasp to plan with skill appropriate skill checks at the DMs discretion.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet alt="Blueprints">
            <description>You can produce blueprints or schematics for bridges, siege equipment, buildings, dams, or any other common feat of engineering that anyone proficient with the necessary artisan tools required to could follow to craft the outlined construction given the time and resources.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Tinkerer" type="Background" source="Kibbles’ Artificer Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KAET_BACKGROUND_TINKERER">
        <description>
            <p>Falling somewhere between a merchant, sage, and - if you ask some villagers - a vagabond, a Tinkerer wonders from town to town bringing a cart (or sometimes just a donkey) of knick-nacks and knowhow. While not always welcomed with open arms, they can be life line of the smallest and most widely flung towns, as no route is too odd and winding for them to wander. Tinkerers may be wanderers by nature, but what opens doors is their useful knack for being able to fix problems with a dash of knowhow and ingenuity.</p>
            <p class="indent"></p>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Skill Proficiencies:</strong> Insight, Nature</li>
                <li><strong>Tool Proficiencies:</strong> Tinker's Tools</li>
                <li><strong>Languages:</strong> One language of your choice.</li>
                <li><strong>Equipment:</strong> A set of Tinker's Tools, a set of traveler's clothes, a set of saddle bags, and a pack horse.</li>
            </ul>
            <div element="ID_KT_KAET_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_KNOW_HOW" />
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="short">Insight, Nature, Tinker's Tools, 1 language</set>
        </setters>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_KT_KAET_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_KNOW_HOW" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_OPTIONAL_BACKGROUND_FEATURE"/>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_NATURE" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_TINKERS_TOOLS" />
            <select type="Language" name="Language, Tinkerer" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Feature: Know-How" type="Background Feature" source="Kibbles’ Artificer Extended Toolbox" id="ID_KT_KAET_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_KNOW_HOW">
        <description>
            <p>You've been around the block, and fixed more than one problem you had no business fixing with some application of ingenuity. When you need to construct or fix an item, you can often tinker up a replacement part from an alternate source. Any item that you could craft with Tinker's Tools for less then 50gp pieces, you can craft for free with miscellaneousness knick knacks. At the DM's discretion, this feature may help with larger crafting pieces as appropriate</p>
        </description>
        <sheet alt="Know-How">
            <description>When you need to construct or fix an item, you can often tinker up a replacement part from an alternate source. Any item that you could craft with Tinker's Tools for less then 50gp pieces, you can craft for free with miscellaneousness knick knacks.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    
</elements>