<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Channeler Class</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="class-channeler.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aurorabuilder/elements/master/class-channeler.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Channeler" type="Class" source="source" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_CHANNELER">
        <description>
            <p>Channelers are not trained, they are born. At times, the psychic fabric of the multiverse touches individuals in such a way that they are changed – awakened to unbridled mental powers that they never knew existed. As such, channelers must learn to shackle their newfound powers lest these powers consume them.</p>
            <p class="indent">How such psychic or spiritual forces determine how channelers are altered depends upon their natures. In some cases these forces bring channelers closer to death or the spiritual realm. In other cases, it alters their bodies or brings their minds to different states of cognition.</p>
            <h4>SELF RELIANT</h4>
            <p>The core challenge faced by channelers is dealing with the expression of their psychic abilities. The psionic awakening changes their perspectives of the world, often replacing their concept of normal. Channelers must learn to deal with these new paradigms and embrace these inner changes.</p>
            <p class="indent">Often misunderstood and feared, channelers are driven away from societies and must learn to face the world on their own. It is common that they find strength and companionship in others who travel the lands as they exert growing control over their power. Adventuring provides a natural outlet for channelers to master their powers to the benefit of their friends and allies.</p>
            <h4>CREATING A CHANNELER</h4>
            <p>The most important decisions to make for your channeler are how your character received its powers and what shape those powers take. Were you touched by spiritual forces that left you able to see the dead? Was your body changed in a way that it became malleable to your will? Can you tap into the Weave with your mind and shape it? You need to decide your psionic expression as that determines what powers you can use and the nature of your channeler.</p>
            <p class="indent">Next you want to decide how your channeler became an adventurer. Did you join a group to find safety or to gain camaraderie? How do you approach people you know or don’t know about your powers? Are you afraid of what you are or of what you could do if you ever let go? Do you seek to seal away your power or have you decided that you need to bridle and command it?</p>
            <h5>QUICK BUILD</h5>
            <p>You can make a channeler quickly by following these suggestions. First, determine you psionic expression (Medium, Metamorph, or Shaper). Second, your highest ability score should be the manifesting ability for the expression (Charisma for Medium, Constitution for Metamorph, or Intelligence for Shaper), followed by Wisdom. Third choose the hermit background. Lastly, choose the spectral armament power and the following power for your expression: precognition (Medium), elastic body (Metamorph), or singularity (Shaper).</p>
            <h2>CLASS FEATURES</h2>
            <p>As an channeler, you gain the following class features.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">HIT POINTS</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Hit Dice:</strong> 1d8 per channeler level</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at 1st Level:</strong> 8 + your Constitution modifier</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at Higher Levels:</strong> 1d8 (or 5) + your Constitution modifier per channeler level after 1st</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">PROFICIENCIES</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled mb">
                <li><strong>Armor:</strong> Light armor</li>
                <li><strong>Weapons:</strong> Simple weapons, rapiers, scimitars, short swords</li>
                <li><strong>Tools:</strong> Fortune telling tools</li>
            </ul>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Saving Throws:</strong> Wisdom, Charisma</li>
                <li><strong>Skills:</strong> two from Arcana, Deception, History, Insight, Investigation, Medicine, Perception, and Performance</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">EQUIPMENT</h5>
            <p>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>(a) a light crossbow and 20 bolts or (b) any simple weapon</li>
                <li>(a) a scimitar or (b) a simple weapon</li>
                <li>(a) a scholar’s pack or (b) an explorer’s pack padded armor and fortune telling tools</li>
            </ul>
            <p>If you forgo this starting equipment, as well as the items offered by your background, you start with 5d4 x 10 gp to buy your equipment.</p>
        <!-- class table here -->
            <h5 class="caption">THE CHANNELER</h5>
            <table class="class-features">
                <thead>
                    <tr><td class="col-5">Level</td><td class="col-10">Proficiency Bonus</td><td class="col-60 left">Features</td><td class="col-10">Powers Known</td><td class="col-10">Power Points</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td> 1st</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Power Manifestation, Psionic Expression</td><td>1</td><td>1</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 2nd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Psychic Burst (1d4)</td><td>2</td><td>3</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 3rd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Preternatural Awareness</td><td>2</td><td>5</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 4th</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>2</td><td>7</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 5th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">—</td><td>3</td><td>10</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 6th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Psychic Burst (1d6)</td><td>3</td><td>13</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 7th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Psionic Expression feature</td><td>4</td><td>16</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 8th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>4</td><td>20</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 9th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">—</td><td>5</td><td>24</td></tr>
                <tr><td>10th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Psychic Burst (1d8)</td><td>5</td><td>28</td></tr>
                <tr><td>11th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Psionic Expression feature</td><td>5</td><td>30</td></tr>
                <tr><td>12th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>5</td><td>33</td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Psionic Potency</td><td>5</td><td>36</td></tr>
                <tr><td>14th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Psychic Burst (1d10)</td><td>5</td><td>39</td></tr>
                <tr><td>15th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">—</td><td>6</td><td>41</td></tr>
                <tr><td>16th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>6</td><td>43</td></tr>
                <tr><td>17th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Psionic Expression feature</td><td>6</td><td>45</td></tr>
                <tr><td>18th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Psychic Burst (1d12)</td><td>6</td><td>47</td></tr>
                <tr><td>19th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>6</td><td>51</td></tr>
                <tr><td>20th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Power Incarnate</td><td>6</td><td>55</td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_CHANNELER_POWER_MANIFESTATION" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_CHANNELER_PSIONIC_EXPRESSION" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_CHANNELER_PSYCHIC_BURST" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_CHANNELER_PRETERNATURAL_AWARENESS" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_CHANNELER_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_CHANNELER_PSIONIC_POTENTCY" />
            <div element="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_CHANNELER_POWER_INCARNATE" />
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="hd">d8</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_RAPIER" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SCIMITAR" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SHORTSWORD" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_FORTUNE_TELLING_TOOLS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_WISDOM" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CHARISMA" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_CHANNELER_POWER_MANIFESTATION" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_CHANNELER_PSIONIC_EXPRESSION" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_CHANNELER_PSYCHIC_BURST" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_CHANNELER_PRETERNATURAL_AWARENESS" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_CHANNELER_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" level="4" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_CHANNELER_PSIONIC_POTENTCY" level="13" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_CHANNELER_POWER_INCARNATE" level="20" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Power Manifestation" type="Class Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_CHANNELER_POWER_MANIFESTATION">
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">1st-level channeler feature</p>
                <p>You were altered through psychic means, enabling you to call upon psionic powers. See chapter 2 for the general rules of power manifesting and for the channeler power list.</p>
                <h4>Powers Known</h4>
                <p>You know one power of your choice from the channeler power list. Your expression will grant you additional powers.</p>
                <p class="indent">The Powers Known column of the Channeler table shows when you learn more channeler powers of your choice. When you gain a level in this class, you can choose one of the powers you know and replace it with another power from the channeler power list or one from your Psionic Expression’s power list.</p>
                <h4>Power Points</h4>
                <p>The Channeler table shows how many power points you have to augment your channeler powers. When you manifest a power, you can expend power points to enhance the power. You can expend a number of power points no greater than your channeler level on a single power manifestation. You regain all expended power points when you finish a short or long rest.</p>
                <p class="indent">Psionic powers differ from spells in that powers can have different expressions when augmented by power points. These different expressions have a similar theme, but the scope and scale can change. For example, the suspension power includes expressions that can affect single targets or an area with different measures of control.</p>
                <h4>Manifesting Ability</h4>
                <p>Your manifesting ability is determined by your Psionic Expression feature.</p>
                <p class="indent">You use the appropriate ability whenever a power refers to your manifesting ability. In addition, you use the appropriate ability modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a channeler power you manifest and when making an attack roll with one.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You have {{channeler:powerpoints}} Power Points.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="1" level="1" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="2" level="2" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="2" level="3" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="2" level="4" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="3" level="5" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="3" level="6" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="3" level="7" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="4" level="8" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="4" level="9" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="4" level="10" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="2" level="11" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="3" level="13" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="3" level="14" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="3" level="12" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="2" level="15" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="2" level="16" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="2" level="17" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="2" level="18" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="4" level="19" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="4" level="20" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Psionic Expression" type="Class Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_CHANNELER_PSIONIC_EXPRESSION">
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">1st-level channeler feature</p>
                <p>When a channeler’s powers awaken they fall under one theme. When you create a channeler, choose a Psionic Expression. Perhaps the channeler feels close to the realm of spirits and to lost souls trapped in the world, taking on the expression of the medium. Another channeler may find its physical form is malleable to its will, becoming a metamorph. The shaper is a channeler who can summon spontaneous energies with but a thought.</p>
                <p>Each channeler is different, and when the channeler’s psychic power became awakened, certain traits emerged. This is your Psionic Expression which determines what sorts of powers and features you possess.</p>
                <p class="indent">Your psionic expression determines what powers you may possess and grants additional features at 1st, 7th, 11th, and 17th level.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false" />
            <rules>
                <select type="Archetype" name="Psionic Expression" supports="Psionic Expression" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Psychic Burst" type="Class Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_CHANNELER_PSYCHIC_BURST">
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">2nd-level channeler feature</p>
                <p>You can muster your shackled psionic energy. This unshackled energy is represented by your Psychic Burst die, which is a d4. You gain a number of Psychic Burst dice equal to your proficiency bonus.</p>
                <p class="indent">When you manifest a channeler power, you can spend one of your Psychic Burst dice. You gain a number of temporary power points equal to the result of the die roll. You can use these points to augment your power, and when you do so you can augment the power up to 2 points above your channeler level. For example, if you are 2nd level and manifest energy blast and use one Psychic Burst die which results in a 3, you can augment the power with up to 4 power points, using all 3 power points from the Psychic Burst die and one from your power point reserve.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can only spend one Psychic Burst die each turn. You don’t have to spend all your temporary power points on the same power, but only the first power you manifest after invoking this feature can be manifest with power points above your level in this class. All unspent power points gained from your Psychic Burst die are lost at the start of your next turn.</p>
                <p class="indent">As you gain levels in this class, the size of your Psychic Burst die increases: at 5th level (d6), 10th level (d8), 14th level (d10), and 18th level (d12). You regain all expended Psychic Burst dice when you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="{{proficiency}} Burst Dice/Long Rest">
                <description>When you manifest a channeler power, you can spend one of your Psychic Burst dice. You gain d{{psychicburst:die}} temporary power points. You can use these points to augment your power up to {{busrtdice:max}} points total. You can only spend one Psychic Burst die each turn. You don’t have to spend all your temporary power points on the same power, but only the first power you manifest after invoking this feature can be manifest with power points above your level in this class. All unspent power points gained from your Psychic Burst die are lost at the start of your next turn.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="psychicburst:die" value="4" bonus="base" level="2" />
                <stat name="psychicburst:die" value="2" level="5" />
                <stat name="psychicburst:die" value="2" level="10" />
                <stat name="psychicburst:die" value="2" level="14" />
                <stat name="psychicburst:die" value="2" level="18" />
                <stat name="busrtdice:max" value="level:channeler" />
                <stat name="busrtdice:max" value="2" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Preternatural Awareness" type="Class Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_CHANNELER_PRETERNATURAL_AWARENESS">
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">3rd-level channeler feature</p>
                <p>Your intuition supersedes your intellect, alerting you to close-by danger. When you spend a Psychic Burst die you increase your AC by 2 until the start of your next turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you spend a Psychic Burst die you increase your AC by 2 until the start of your next turn.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules />
        </element>
        <element name="Ability Score Improvement" type="Class Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_CHANNELER_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT">
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">4th-level channeler feature</p>
                <p>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false" />
            <rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Channeler 4)" supports="Improvement Option,Channeler,4" level="4" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Channeler 8)" supports="Improvement Option,Channeler,8" level="8" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Channeler 12)" supports="Improvement Option,Channeler,12" level="12" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Channeler 16)" supports="Improvement Option,Channeler,16" level="16" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Channeler 19)" supports="Improvement Option,Channeler,19" level="19" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Psionic Potentcy" type="Class Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_CHANNELER_PSIONIC_POTENTCY">
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">13th-level channeler feature</p>
                <p>Whenever you augment a power with more power points than your level in this class through your Psychic Burst feature, you increase your power save DC or power attack modifier for that power by 2</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Power Incarnate" type="Class Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_CLASS_FEATURE_CHANNELER_POWER_INCARNATE">
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">20th-level channeler feature</p>
                <p>You increase your manifesting ability (Charisma, Constitution, or Intelligence) by 4, and your maximum for that score is now 24.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>


	<element name="Medium" type="Archetype" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_CHANNELER_MEDIUM">
		<supports>Psionic Expression</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When you were born, or perhaps as a result of some trauma you experienced, a part of your soul entered the spiritual realm. To you, the lost souls of the dead and free-floating spirits became just more travelers along the roads you walk.</p>
			<div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MEDIUM_EXPRESSION_OF_SPIRIT" />
			<div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MEDIUM_SPIRIT_VISION" />
			<div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MEDIUM_SPIRITUAL_ATTUNEMENT" />
			<div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MEDIUM_BANISH_SPIRITS" />
			<div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MEDIUM_PERSONA_WARD" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MEDIUM_EXPRESSION_OF_SPIRIT" level="1" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MEDIUM_SPIRIT_VISION" level="1" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MEDIUM_SPIRITUAL_ATTUNEMENT" level="7" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MEDIUM_BANISH_SPIRITS" level="11" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MEDIUM_PERSONA_WARD" level="17" />
		</rules>
	</element>
		<element name="Expression of Spirit" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MEDIUM_EXPRESSION_OF_SPIRIT">
			<description>
				<p class="flavor">1st-level Medium feature</p>
				<p>Your inner soul empowers your psychic abilities. Your manifesting ability is Charisma. You use your Charisma whenever a power refers to your manifesting ability. In addition, you use your Charisma modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a channeler power you manifest and when making an attack roll with one.</p>
				<p style="align-text: center;"><b>Power Save DC</b> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier</p>
				<p style="align-text: center;"><b>Power attack modifier</b> = your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier</p>
				<p class="indent">When you gain a new channeler power, you may select a power from the channeler power list or the following powers: apopsi, dimensional disassociation, extrasensory perception, hypercognition, id insinuation, mind probe, muddle, precognition, psychometry, puppetry, and telekinetic grasp.</p>
				<p class="indent">At 1st level, you can select one of the powers above and add it to the list of powers you know. At 12th level, you may add another power from the list above.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet display="false" />
            <spellcasting name="Channeler" ability="Charisma" prepare="false">
                <list>TC Psionic Power,(Channeler||Medium)</list>
            </spellcasting>
			<rules>
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="1" level="1" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="2" level="2" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="2" level="3" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="2" level="4" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="3" level="5" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="3" level="6" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="3" level="7" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="4" level="8" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="4" level="9" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="4" level="10" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="2" level="11" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="3" level="13" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="3" level="14" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="3" level="12" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="2" level="15" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="2" level="16" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="2" level="17" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="2" level="18" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="4" level="19" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="4" level="20" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Psionic Power, Channeler" supports="$(spellcasting:list)" spellcasting="Channeler" level="1" number="2" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Psionic Power, Medium" supports="TC Psionic Power,Medium" spellcasting="Channeler" level="1" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Psionic Power, Channeler" supports="$(spellcasting:list)" spellcasting="Channeler" level="2" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Psionic Power, Channeler" supports="$(spellcasting:list)" spellcasting="Channeler" level="3" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Psionic Power, Channeler" supports="$(spellcasting:list)" spellcasting="Channeler" level="5" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Psionic Power, Channeler" supports="$(spellcasting:list)" spellcasting="Channeler" level="9" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Psionic Power, Medium" supports="TC Psionic Power,Medium" spellcasting="Channeler" level="12" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Psionic Power, Channeler" supports="$(spellcasting:list)" spellcasting="Channeler" level="13" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Psionic Power, Channeler" supports="$(spellcasting:list)" spellcasting="Channeler" level="17" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Spirit Vision" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MEDIUM_SPIRIT_VISION">
			<description>
				<p class="flavor">1st-level Medium feature</p>
				<p>You are attuned to the spirit realm. Whenever you are within 30 feet of a Spiritfont you are aware of its presence.</p>
				<p class="indent">As an action, you can concentrate to perceive the spirit realm and auras. While you concentrate you have aurasight and can perceive the Ethereal Plane within 60 feet of you. When you peer into the Ethereal Plane, you can manifest telepathy powers against targets on the Ethereal Plane, but can’t concentrate to maintain them while concentrating on your Spirit Vision feature.</p>
				<p class="indent">You can maintain this sight for a number of rounds equal to your levels in this class. While you use your Spirit Vision feature, you have the psionic focused condition.</p>
				<p class="indent">As long as you maintain this sight, you gain a +2 bonus on saving throws and Intelligence (Investigation) checks against illusions of any sort.</p>
				<p class="indent">When you reach 7th level, your vision allows you to perceive the presence of a spirit possessing a creature or object. If a creature is possessed by the spirit, the spirit makes a Charisma saving throw against your power save DC. If successful, you are unable to detect its presence.</p>
				<p class="indent">You can call upon your Spirit Vision feature a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus. You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet action="Action" usage="{{proficiency}}/Long Rest">
				<description>While you concentrate you have aurasight and can perceive the Ethereal Plane within 60 feet of you for up to {{level:channeler}} rounds. When you peer into the Ethereal Plane, you can manifest telepathy powers against targets on the Ethereal Plane, but can’t concentrate to maintain them while concentrating on this feature. While you use your Spirit Vision feature, you have the psionic focused condition and you gain a +2 bonus on saving throws and Intelligence (Investigation) checks against illusions of any sort.</description>
				<description level="7">While you concentrate you have aurasight and can perceive the Ethereal Plane within 60 feet of you for up to {{level:channeler}} rounds. When you peer into the Ethereal Plane, you can manifest telepathy powers against targets on the Ethereal Plane, but can’t concentrate to maintain them while concentrating on this feature. While you use your Spirit Vision feature, you have the psionic focused condition and you gain a +2 bonus on saving throws and Intelligence (Investigation) checks against illusions of any sort. Your vision allows you to perceive the presence of a spirit possessing a creature or object. If a creature is possessed by the spirit, the spirit makes a Charisma saving throw against your power save DC. If successful, you are unable to detect its presence.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <grant type="Vision" id="ID_TC_PSHB_VISION_SPIRITFONT_SENSE" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Spiritual Attunement" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MEDIUM_SPIRITUAL_ATTUNEMENT">
			<description>
				<p class="flavor">7th-level Medium feature</p>
				<p>Due to your closeness to the spirit realm, you can no longer be aged through supernatural means.</p>
				<p class="indent">Additionally, your psionic powers reach beyond the material world, striking a creature’s spirit as well as its body or mind, granting you the following benefits.</p>
				<ul>
					<li>You can target creatures and objects on both the Ethereal Plane and the Material Plane with your powers while on one of the planes. You must be aware of a creature to target it specifically, but area of effect powers will strike each target on the other place where it overlaps the one you're on.</li>
					<li>Whenever you deal damage to a creature with a psionic power, you increase the damage dealt by your proficiency bonus. A creature can only take this bonus damage once each round.</li>
					<li>Psionic powers you manifest against a celestial, elemental, fey, fiend, or undead ignore psychic and bludgeoning damage resistance.</li>
					<li>Telepathy powers you manifest against a celestial, elemental, fey, fiend, or undead ignore immunity to the following conditions: frightened, paralyzed, stunned, and unsettled.</li>
					<li>If you hit a creature with a psionic power while using your Spirit Vision feature, you can maintain Spirit Vision alongside the power as part of the same concentration. Spirit Vision ends when it normally would, regardless if this would happen before or after the power ends.</li>
				</ul>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description>You can target creatures and objects on both the Ethereal Plane and the Material Plane with your powers while on one of the planes. Your psionic powers deal an additional {{proficiency}} damage (1/round). Psionic powers and telepathy powers ignore certain damage resistance and condition immunities. If you hit a creature with a psionic power while using your Spirit Vision feature, you can maintain Spirit Vision alongside the power as part of the same concentration.
                You can no longer be aged through supernatural means.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Banish Spirits" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MEDIUM_BANISH_SPIRITS">
			<description>
				<p class="flavor">11th-level Medium feature</p>
				<p>As an action you can channel your inner strength to drive away spirits. You can attempt to do so twice. At 16th level you can Banish Spirits three times. You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</p>
				<p class="indent">The effect of Banish Spirits requires a saving throw. When you use this ability, the DC equals your power save DC.</p>
				<p class="indent">One celestial, elemental, fey, fiend, or undead that you can see within 30 feet of you must make a Wisdom saving throw. If the creature fails the saving throw, it is turned for 1 minute or until it takes any damage.</p>
				<p class="indent">A turned creature must spend its turns trying to move as far from you as it can, and it can’t willingly move to a space within 30 feet of you. It also can’t take reactions. For its actions, it can only use the Dash action or try to escape from an effect that prevents it from moving. If there’s nowhere to move, the creature can use the Dodge action.</p>
				<p class="indent">Weaker creatures, at your decision, can be either destroyed (if undead), banished to their home plane (if celestial, elemental, or fiend), or driven away (if fey) if they fail their saving throw. If the challenge rating of the creature is equal or less than the threshold shown on the Banish Spirits table, it suffers the effect. Banished celestials, elementals, and fiends can't return to the Material Plane for 24 hours, provided they have the means to do so. Fey that are driven away must flee one mile away from the location and can’t return for one month.</p>
				<h5 class="caption">Banish Spirits</h5>
				<table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Medium Level</td><td>Banishes or Destroys Creatures of CR…</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>10th</td><td>1 or lower</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>11th</td><td>2 or lower</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>14th</td><td>3 or lower</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>17th</td><td>4 or lower</td></tr>
				</table>
				<p>The Banish Spirits feature can be used on a creature or object to drive out a creature possessing it. When you do so, you become locked in a battle of wills with the possessor for up to 1 minute. Each round, the possessor must make a Wisdom saving throw against your power save DC. If the possessor fails three saving throws, it is forcibly removed from the host and is stunned until the end of its next turn. It can’t attempt to repossess the host again for 24 hours. If the possessor fails less than three saves, it remains within its host and is immune to your further attempts to remove it for 24 hours.</p>
				<p class="indent">You can also use this feature to render a spiritfont whose center is within 5 feet of you dormant. The spiritfont must succeed on an Intensity saving throw against your power save DC or it becomes dormant for a number of hours equal to your proficiency bonus.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet action="Action" usage="{{banishspirits:usage}}/Long Rest">
				<description>One celestial, elemental, fey, fiend, or undead that you can see within 30 feet of you must make a Wisdom saving throw. If the creature fails the saving throw, it is turned for 1 minute or until it takes any damage. Creatures of CR {{banishspirits:cr}} or lower are banished or destroyed. The Banish Spirits feature can be used on a creature or object to drive out a creature possessing it.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <stat name="banishspirits:usage" value="2" level="11" />
                <stat name="banishspirits:usage" value="1" level="16" />
                <stat name="banishspirits:cr" value="1" level="10" />
                <stat name="banishspirits:cr" value="1" level="11" />
                <stat name="banishspirits:cr" value="1" level="14" />
                <stat name="banishspirits:cr" value="1" level="17" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Persona Ward" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MEDIUM_PERSONA_WARD">
			<description>
				<p class="flavor">17th-level Medium feature</p>
				<p>You have advantage on Wisdom and Charisma saving throws and you are immune to charm effects.</p>
				<p class="indent">You are immediately aware of the perpetrator of a charm, curse, or possession attempt against you, knowing its exact location and identity. Whenever a creature attempts to possess you, you can spend a Psychic Burst die to forcibly expel it. The creature takes force damage equal to five rolls of your Psychic Burst die and is stunned until the end of its next turn. If you are possessed, you can spend a Psychic Burst die to make a new saving throw on your turn even when you're not in control, adding the number rolled to your save. A creature isn’t damaged or stunned in this case.</p>
				<p class="indent">Additionally, when using your Spirit Vision feature, you see creatures for what they truly are and can see the true form of a shapechanger or one which has had its form changed through some means.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description>You have advantage on Wisdom and Charisma saving throws and you are immune to charm effects. You are immediately aware of the perpetrator of a charm, curse, or possession attempt against you, knowing its exact location and identity. Whenever a creature attempts to possess you, you can spend a Psychic Burst die; it takes 5d{{psychicburst:die}} psychic damage and is stunned until the end of its next turn.
                If you are possessed, you can spend a Psychic Burst die to make a new saving throw on your turn even when you're not in control, adding the number rolled to your save.
                When using your Spirit Vision feature, you see creatures for what they truly are and can see the true form of a shapechanger or one which has had its form changed through some means.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
			</rules>
		</element>


	<element name="Metamorph" type="Archetype" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_CHANNELER_METAMORPH">
		<supports>Psionic Expression</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Flesh and bone are malleable forms to be sculpted and shaped to your will. You transcend the limits of biology, able to meld objects to your body. You can grow bone or reform your flesh using your Metaform feature.</p>
			<div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_METAMORPH_MORPHIC_POWER" />
			<div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_METAMORPH_METAFORM" />
			<div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_METAMORPH_UNARMORED_DEFENSE" />
			<div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_METAMORPH_BODY_MELD" />
			<div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_METAMORPH_ROBUST_FORM" />
			<div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_METAMORPH_WAR_FORM" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_METAMORPH_MORPHIC_POWER" level="1" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_METAMORPH_METAFORM" level="1" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_METAMORPH_UNARMORED_DEFENSE" level="1" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_METAMORPH_BODY_MELD" level="7" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_METAMORPH_ROBUST_FORM" level="11" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_METAMORPH_WAR_FORM" level="17" />
		</rules>
	</element>
		<element name="Morphic Power" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_METAMORPH_MORPHIC_POWER">
			<description>
				<p class="flavor">1st-level Metamorph feature</p>
				<p>You warp flesh and bone through your psychic ability. Your manifesting ability is Constitution. You use your Constitution whenever a power refers to your manifesting ability. In addition, you use your Constitution modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a channeler power you manifest and when making an attack roll with one.</p>
				<p style="align-text: center;"><b>Power Save DC</b> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Constitution modifier</p>
				<p style="align-text: center;"><b>Power attack modifier</b> = your proficiency bonus + your Constitution modifier</p>
				<p class="indent">When you gain a new channeler power, you may select a power from the channeler power list or the following powers: accelerated healing, biomorphic skin, chameleon, decay, elastic body, energy cloak, living weapon, martial insight, molecular agitation, size alteration, and speed of thought.</p>
				<p class="indent">At 1st level, you can select one of the powers above and add it to the list of powers you know. At 12th level, you may add another power from the list above.</p>
			</description>
            <spellcasting name="Channeler" ability="Constitution" prepare="false">
                <list>TC Psionic Power,(Channeler||Metamorph)</list>
            </spellcasting>
			<sheet>
				<description></description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="1" level="1" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="2" level="2" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="2" level="3" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="2" level="4" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="3" level="5" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="3" level="6" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="3" level="7" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="4" level="8" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="4" level="9" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="4" level="10" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="2" level="11" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="3" level="13" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="3" level="14" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="3" level="12" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="2" level="15" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="2" level="16" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="2" level="17" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="2" level="18" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="4" level="19" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="4" level="20" />
                <stat name="spellcasting:dc:con" value="spellcasting:dc" />
                <stat name="spellcasting:dc:con" value="constitution:modifier" bonus="ability" />
                <stat name="spellcasting:attack:con" value="spellcasting:attack" />
                <stat name="spellcasting:attack:con" value="constitution:modifier" bonus="ability" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Psionic Power, Channeler" supports="$(spellcasting:list)" spellcasting="Channeler" level="1" number="2" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Psionic Power, Medium" supports="TC Psionic Power,Metamorph" spellcasting="Channeler" level="1" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Psionic Power, Channeler" supports="$(spellcasting:list)" spellcasting="Channeler" level="2" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Psionic Power, Channeler" supports="$(spellcasting:list)" spellcasting="Channeler" level="3" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Psionic Power, Channeler" supports="$(spellcasting:list)" spellcasting="Channeler" level="5" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Psionic Power, Channeler" supports="$(spellcasting:list)" spellcasting="Channeler" level="9" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Psionic Power, Medium" supports="TC Psionic Power,Metamorph" spellcasting="Channeler" level="12" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Psionic Power, Channeler" supports="$(spellcasting:list)" spellcasting="Channeler" level="13" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Psionic Power, Channeler" supports="$(spellcasting:list)" spellcasting="Channeler" level="17" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Metaform" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_METAMORPH_METAFORM">
			<description>
				<p class="flavor">1st-level Metamorph feature</p>
				<p>As a bonus action, you can alter your physical form, adopting a trait from the Metaform Table. You are proficient with attack forms granted by a trait and use your Strength modifier on attack and damage rolls with weapon attacks granted by your metaform traits. Additionally, when you enter your metaform, you gain a number of temporary hit points equal to four times your level in this class. These hit points remain until you finish a long rest, enter your metaform again, or are depleted through damage. You can remain in your metaform for 10 minutes.</p>
				<p class="indent">While in your metaform, you can take a bonus action to adopt a second trait, or use your action to replace one trait you’ve adopted with a different trait. When you reach certain levels in this class, you can adopt additional traits: at 7th level (three traits), at 11th level (four traits), and at 17th level (five traits). You can spend one Psychic Burst die to manifest all traits you are capable of at once with your bonus action. You don’t gain temporary power points from the Psychic Burst die when it’s spent this way.</p>
				<p class="indent">When a metaform trait requires a target to make a saving throw, the save DC is equal to your power save DC.</p>
				<p class="indent">You can take on trivial, cosmetic changes in your metaform as you will, such as growing body hair or scaly skin, red eyes, or nightmarish features, for instance.</p>
				<p class="indent">Starting at 5th level, you gain the Multiattack action while in your metaform and your metaform trait attacks count as magical for the purpose of overcoming damage resistance and immunity. You can make two attacks using your metaform traits, or one attack with a metaform trait and one attack with a weapon. Metaform attacks can only be used once per limb, such that you can only make one bite attack, but could make two claw attacks. You can make an additional attack with a metaform trait (three attacks) when you reach 17th level in this class.</p>
				<p class="indent">Once you enter your metaform, you can’t do so again until you finish a short or long rest unless you enter it by spending a Psychic Burst die. When you reach 11th level, you can enter your metaform twice between rests.</p>
				<h5 class="caption">Metaform Table</h5>
				<table>
					<thead>
						<tr><td>Level</td><td>Trait</td><td>Effects</td></tr>
					</thead>
					<tr><td>1st</td><td>Amphibious</td><td>You can freely breathe air and water and gain a swimming speed equal to your walking speed.</td></tr>
					<tr><td></td><td>Darkvision</td><td>You gain darkvision up to 60 ft.</td></tr>
					<tr><td></td><td>Endurance</td><td>You increase your Constitution score to 16 if it’s not already higher, ignore the effects of exhaustion, and make Constitution ability checks with advantage.</td></tr>
					<tr><td></td><td>Fangs</td><td>You grow long fangs allowing you to make a bite attack that deals 1d8 piercing damage. When you score a critical hit with this attack, it deals an extra die of damage.</td></tr>
					<tr><td></td><td>Muscle Mass</td><td>You increase your Strength score to 16 if it’s not already higher and make Strength ability checks with advantage.</td></tr>
					<tr><td></td><td>Oily Skin</td><td>You become slippery. Opponents are at disadvantage on grappling checks against you and can’t grapple you on a hit with an attack without a grapple check.</td></tr>
					<tr><td></td><td>Reflexes</td><td>You increase your Dexterity score to 16 if it’s not already higher and make Dexterity ability checks with advantage.</td></tr>
					<tr><td></td><td>Sharp Nails</td><td>Each of your hands grows claws that deal 1d6 slashing damage. When you hit a target with this attack, you can take a bonus action to make an additional attack against the same target.</td></tr>
					<tr><td></td><td>Spines</td><td>You grow spines from your body that deal 2d4 piercing damage at the start your turn to a creature that you have grappled or been grappled by.</td></tr>
					<tr><td></td><td>Web Walk</td><td>You ignore movement restrictions caused by webbing. You also gain a climbing speed equal to your walking speed and can move along walls and ceilings using only your feet.</td></tr>
					<tr><td>5th</td><td>Blindsight</td><td>You gain blindsight up to 60 ft.</td></tr>
					<tr><td></td><td>Blood Siphon</td><td>Once each turn when you hit a creature with a metaform trait attack, you regain hit points equal to half the damage dealt.</td></tr>
					<tr><td></td><td>Enhanced Sight</td><td>You grow multiple eyes allowing you to see in any direction, gaining advantage on saving throws vs. blindness and on Perception checks. Foes gain no benefit from having an ally within 5 feet of you.</td></tr>
					<tr><td></td><td>Horns</td><td>You grow large horns allowing you to make a gore attack that deals 2d4 piercing damage. If you move at least 10 feet straight toward a target and hit with your gore attack on the same turn, the target takes an extra 2d4 piercing damage and you can attempt to shove it, pushing it up to 10 feet away and knocking prone on a success.</td></tr>
					<tr><td></td><td>Tentacle Arm</td><td>You transform one of your limbs into a tentacle that deals 1d6 bludgeoning damage and when it hits an opponent your size or smaller, you can initiate a grapple that restrains the creature if you win an opposed grapple check. Tentacles have the finesse property.</td></tr>
					<tr><td></td><td>Thick Skin</td><td>You increase your AC by 2 when not wearing armor.</td></tr>
					<tr><td></td><td>Venomous Attack</td><td>Once each round, when you hit a creature with a metaform trait, an unarmed strike, or a natural weapon it takes an extra 1d6 poison damage and must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or become poisoned for 1 minute.</td></tr>
					<tr><td></td><td>Web Spit</td><td>As an action you can spit webbing as a ranged weapon attack with range 30/90 ft. A Large or smaller creature hit by this web is restrained. As an action it can attempt a DC 10 + your Constitution modifier Strength check to break free. The webbing can also be destroyed, having AC 10, 5 + twice your Constitution bonus hit points, vulnerability to fire damage, and immunity to bludgeoning, poison, and psychic damage.</td></tr>
					<tr><td>11th</td><td>Paralytic Attack</td><td>Once each round, when you hit a creature with a metaform trait, an unarmed strike, or a natural weapon it takes an extra 1d6 necrotic damage and must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or become poisoned for to 1 minute. Until the poison ends, the target is paralyzed. The target can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending this poison effect on itself if it succeeds.</td></tr>
					<tr><td></td><td>Pincers</td><td>You grow pincers on any arm or tentacle you possess. Pincers deal 2d4 piercing damage and you can attempt to grapple a creature of your size or smaller on a hit. A grappled creature is restrained. During your turn you can deal 2d4 piercing damage to a grappled creature by taking a bonus action.</td></tr>
					<tr><td></td><td>Serpent Form</td><td>You replace your legs with a long serpent tail and trunk. You can make a constrict attack that deals 2d6 bludgeoning damage on a hit, and can attempt to grapple it. Until the grapple ends the target is restrained. You also can’t be knocked prone and make opposed checks to be shoved with advantage.</td></tr>
					<tr><td></td><td>Tail Spikes</td><td>You grow a tail filled with dozens of needle-like spikes. You can shoot these spikes by making a ranged weapon attack with range 100/200 ft. On a hit the target takes 1d8 piercing damage. When making a Multiattack, you can use this trait to attack more than once.</td></tr>
					<tr><td></td><td>Wings</td><td>You grow wings, gaining a flying speed of 60 ft.</td></tr>
					<tr><td>17th</td><td>Acidic Breath</td><td>As an action you can expel acid in a 15-foot cone. Each creature within the cone must make a Dexterity saving throw, taking 6d6 acid damage on a failed save or half as much damage on a successful one.</td></tr>
					<tr><td></td><td>Amorphous Form</td><td>You gain the Amorphous trait, allowing you to move through a space as narrow as 1 inch wide without squeezing.</td></tr>
					<tr><td></td><td>Extra Arms</td><td>You grow two extra arms identical to your normal arms (or you grow humanoid arms if you don’t normally possess arms). The arms can wield weapons or make unarmed strikes. When you take the Attack action, you can use a bonus action to make up to two offhand attacks. You can alternately wield two 2-handed weapons and use a bonus action to make an offhand attack with one of them.</td></tr>
				</table>
				<h5 class="caption">Other Options</h5>
				<p>You aren’t limited to the options from the Metaform table. For instance you could grow a sharp beak instead of fangs and deal the same piercing damage, or you could create a myriad of gaping maws along an arm in place of claws. Metaform is intended to allow the metamorph the ability to create a thematic form.</p>
				<p class="indent">The DM can develop and approve additional metaform options that fit within the scope of the framework presented below and that don’t duplicate psionic powers.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet action="Bonus Action">
				<description>You can adopt a trait from the Metaform Table. You gain {{metaform:temp-hp}} hit points. While in your metaform, you can take a bonus action to adopt a second trait, or use your action to replace one trait. You can spend one Psychic Burst die to manifest all traits you are capable of at once with your bonus action. You don’t gain temporary power points from the Psychic Burst die when it’s spent this way.</description>
				<description level="7">You can adopt a trait from the Metaform Table. You gain {{metaform:temp-hp}} hit points. While in your metaform, each round, you can take a bonus action to adopt adopt an additional trait (up to three total), or use your action to replace one trait. You can spend one Psychic Burst die to manifest all traits you are capable of at once with your bonus action. You don’t gain temporary power points from the Psychic Burst die when it’s spent this way.</description>
				<description level="11">You can adopt a trait from the Metaform Table. You gain {{metaform:temp-hp}} hit points. While in your metaform, each round, you can take a bonus action to adopt adopt an additional trait (up to four total), or use your action to replace one trait. You can spend one Psychic Burst die to manifest all traits you are capable of at once with your bonus action. You don’t gain temporary power points from the Psychic Burst die when it’s spent this way.</description>
				<description level="17">You can adopt a trait from the Metaform Table. You gain {{metaform:temp-hp}} hit points. While in your metaform, each round, you can take a bonus action to adopt an additional trait (up to five total), or use your action to replace one trait. You can spend one Psychic Burst die to manifest all traits you are capable of at once with your bonus action. You don’t gain temporary power points from the Psychic Burst die when it’s spent this way.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <stat name="metaform:temp-hp" value="level:channeler" />
                <stat name="metaform:temp-hp" value="level:channeler" />
                <stat name="metaform:temp-hp" value="level:channeler" />
                <stat name="metaform:temp-hp" value="level:channeler" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Unarmored Defense" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_METAMORPH_UNARMORED_DEFENSE">
			<description>
				<p class="flavor">1st-level Metamorph feature</p>
				<p>While you are not wearing armor, your Armor Class equals 10 + your Dexterity modifier + your Constitution modifier.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet display="false">
                <description>While you are wearing no armor, your AC equals {{ac:unarmored defense metamorph}}.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <stat name="ac:unarmored defense metamorph:base" value="10" />
                <stat name="ac:unarmored defense metamorph:dexterity" value="dexterity:modifier" />
                <stat name="ac:unarmored defense metamorph:intelligence" value="intelligence:modifier" />
                <stat name="ac:unarmored defense metamorph" value="ac:unarmored defense metamorph:base" />
                <stat name="ac:unarmored defense metamorph" value="ac:unarmored defense metamorph:dexterity" />
                <stat name="ac:unarmored defense metamorph" value="ac:unarmored defense metamorph:intelligence" />
                <stat name="ac:calculation" value="ac:unarmored defense metamorph" bonus="calculation" equipped="[armor:none]" alt="Unarmored Defense (Metamorph)" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Body Meld" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_METAMORPH_BODY_MELD">
			<description>
				<p class="flavor">7th-level Metamorph feature</p>
				<p>You can absorb small objects into your body. You can’t absorb more than one fourth of your mass. Items absorbed by you don’t function as a worn item would, for example, you can’t benefit from a ring of protection while it’s melded into your body. You can absorb any suitable object as a bonus action.</p>
				<p class="indent">You can also use a bonus action to immediately bring any absorbed item to hand, or even don it. For example, you could have boots of elvenkind absorbed, and with your bonus action retrieve and don them. You can absorb one object and retrieve one object as part of the same bonus action.</p>
				<p class="indent">You can also partially absorb weapons or makeshift-implements to act as weapons, grafting them to your limbs. These grafted weapons function as normal weapons of their type, but grafted weapons can’t be disarmed. You are proficient with any grafted weapon. A grafted weapon is considered magical so long as it remains grafted to you.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet action="Bonus Action">
				<description>You can absorb small objects into your body. You can also use a bonus action to immediately bring any absorbed item to hand, or even don it.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Robust Form" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_METAMORPH_ROBUST_FORM">
			<description>
				<p class="flavor">11th-level Metamorph feature</p>
				<p>You gain proficiency in Strength and Constitution saving throws. In addition, at the start of your turn you can revert to your normal form if you are polymorphed or petrified, but can't take a bonus action during this turn. If you were in your metaform before being afflicted, you revert to your metaform instead.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description>At the start of your turn you can revert to your normal form if you are polymorphed or petrified, but can't take a bonus action during this turn. If you were in your metaform before being afflicted, you revert to your metaform instead.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_STRENGTH" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CONSTITUTION" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="War Form" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_METAMORPH_WAR_FORM">
			<description>
				<p class="flavor">17th-level Metamorph feature</p>
				<p>While in your metaform, you gain a +2 bonus to Strength, to a maximum of 22, and you have advantage on Strength and Constitution ability checks while in it.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description>While in your metaform, you gain a +2 bonus to Strength, to a maximum of 22, and you have advantage on Strength and Constitution ability checks while in it.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
			</rules>
		</element>


	<element name="Shaper" type="Archetype" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_CHANNELER_SHAPER">
		<supports>Psionic Expression</supports>
		<description>
			<p>A shaper reaches into the very fabric of reality and bends it to the shaper’s will. A shaper can bring ectoplasm from the Astral Plane and fashion it into a construct or even tap into the Weave and duplicate certain spells. A shaper is direct, focusing on powers that accomplish the shaper’s goals quickly.</p>
			<div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHAPER_SHAPE_REALITY" />
			<div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHAPER_ASTRAL_TRICK" />
			<div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHAPER_MANIFEST_MAGIC" />
			<div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHAPER_SCULPT_EXPRESIONS" />
			<div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHAPER_PSYCHIC_RESIDUE" />
			<div element="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHAPER_ECTOPLASMIC_SHIELD" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHAPER_SHAPE_REALITY" level="1" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHAPER_ASTRAL_TRICK" level="1" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHAPER_MANIFEST_MAGIC" level="7" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHAPER_SCULPT_EXPRESIONS" level="7" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHAPER_PSYCHIC_RESIDUE" level="11" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHAPER_ECTOPLASMIC_SHIELD" level="17" />
		</rules>
	</element>
		<element name="Shape Reality" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHAPER_SHAPE_REALITY">
			<description>
				<p class="flavor">1st-level Shaper feature</p>
				<p>Through calculation and logic, you craft psionic energies. Your manifesting ability is Intelligence. You use your Intelligence whenever a power refers to your manifesting ability. In addition, you use your Intelligence modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a channeler power you manifest and when making an attack roll with one.</p>
				<p style="align-text: center;"><b>Power Save DC</b> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier</p>
				<p style="align-text: center;"><b>Power attack modifier</b> = your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier</p>
				<p class="indent">When you gain a new channeler power, you may select a power from the channeler power list or the following powers: animate electricity, dimensional breach, energy storm, harmonics, hydrokinesis, psionic blast, shadow shape, singularity, spatial void, and tremor.</p>
				<p class="indent">At 1st level, you add astral construct and can select one of the powers above and add it to the list of powers you know. At 12th level, you may add another power from the list above.</p>
			</description>
            <spellcasting name="Channeler" ability="Intelligence" prepare="false">
                <list>Channeler</list>
            </spellcasting>
			<sheet display="false" />
			<rules>
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="1" level="1" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="2" level="2" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="2" level="3" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="2" level="4" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="3" level="5" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="3" level="6" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="3" level="7" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="4" level="8" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="4" level="9" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="4" level="10" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="2" level="11" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="3" level="13" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="3" level="14" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="3" level="12" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="2" level="15" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="2" level="16" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="2" level="17" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="2" level="18" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="4" level="19" />
                <stat name="channeler:powerpoints" value="4" level="20" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Psionic Power, Channeler" supports="$(spellcasting:list)" spellcasting="Channeler" level="1" number="2" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Psionic Power, Medium" supports="TC Psionic Power,Shaper" spellcasting="Channeler" level="1" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Psionic Power, Channeler" supports="$(spellcasting:list)" spellcasting="Channeler" level="2" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Psionic Power, Channeler" supports="$(spellcasting:list)" spellcasting="Channeler" level="3" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Psionic Power, Channeler" supports="$(spellcasting:list)" spellcasting="Channeler" level="5" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Psionic Power, Channeler" supports="$(spellcasting:list)" spellcasting="Channeler" level="9" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Psionic Power, Medium" supports="TC Psionic Power,Shaper" spellcasting="Channeler" level="12" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Psionic Power, Channeler" supports="$(spellcasting:list)" spellcasting="Channeler" level="13" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Psionic Power, Channeler" supports="$(spellcasting:list)" spellcasting="Channeler" level="17" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Astral Trick" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHAPER_ASTRAL_TRICK">
			<description>
				<p class="flavor">1st-level Shaper feature</p>
				<p>You may select one cantrip from the sorcerer spell list which you manifest as a psionic power. The cantrip no longer has any components, instead it gains the psychic and either the glow or beam visual detections. Any duration greater than 1 round requires maintenance with the same timeframe as the spell’s duration. All other details of the cantrip are the same. Each cantrip gained through this feature counts as a channeler power for you.</p>
				<p class="indent">Starting at 2nd level, after using this feature, you can take a bonus action and spend a Psychic Burst die to manifest a special version of astral construct. You can only spend power points gained from the Psychic Burst die to augment the power when manifesting it this way, but you don’t need to maintain it, and it will last 1 hour, until it is reduced to 0 hit points, or you manifest astral trick again.</p>
				<p class="indent">When you reach 7th level, you may select a second cantrip from the sorcerer spell list, modified the same way as above. You gain additional converted cantrips at 11th level (third cantrip), and 17th level (fourth cantrip). Whenever you learn a new cantrip, you can replace a cantrip you know from this class with another cantrip from the sorcerer spell list.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet action="Bonus Action">
				<description>You spend a Psychic Burst die to augment your Astral Trick cantrips when manifesting it this way, but you don’t need to maintain it, and it will last 1 hour, until it is reduced to 0 hit points, or you manifest astral trick again.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <select type="Spell" name="Astral Trick" supports="Sorcerer,0" spellcasting="Channeler" level="1" allowReplace="true"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Astral Trick" supports="Sorcerer,0" spellcasting="Channeler" level="7" allowReplace="true"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Astral Trick" supports="Sorcerer,0" spellcasting="Channeler" level="11" allowReplace="true"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Astral Trick" supports="Sorcerer,0" spellcasting="Channeler" level="17" allowReplace="true"/>
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Manifest Magic" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHAPER_MANIFEST_MAGIC">
			<description>
				<p class="flavor">7th-level Shaper feature</p>
				<p>You may use your power points to manifest instantaneous evocation spells from the sorcerer spell list. You must use a number of power points equal to two times the spell’s level. If a spell allows using a higher level slot, you may expend additional power points to do so. Increasing a spell’s level requires 2 power points per higher slot level. For example, if you manifest a fireball spell using 8 power points, you deal 9d6 fire damage. You can’t manifest spells over 6th level, nor can you spend more power points than your channeler level.</p>
				<p class="indent">Spells you can manifest are shown on the Shaper Manifested Spells table. You don’t require spell components when manifesting evocation spells. Instead, they are manifested with psychic, gesture, and visual detections. Each spell is in the Player’s Handbook, unless it has an asterisk, in which case it is in Xanathar’s Guide to Everything. A manifested spell is considered a spell effect and can be countered by counterspell and similar effects.</p>
				<p class="indent">You use your power save DC and power attack modifier when you manifest spells through this feature. To manifest a spell, it must be a sorcerer spell from the evocation school with instantaneous duration and use a spell slot level no higher than 1/3 your level in this class.</p>
				<h5 class="caption">Shaper Manifested Spells</h5>
				<table>
					<thead>
                        <tr><td>Spell Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
					</thead>
					<tr><td>1st</td><td><em>burning hands, chaos bolt*, chromatic orb, earth tremor*, magic missile, thunder wave</em></td></tr>
					<tr><td>2nd</td><td><em>Aganazzar’s scorcher*, scorching ray, shatter, Snilloc’s snowball swarm*</em></td></tr>
					<tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>fireball , lightning bolt</em></td></tr>
					<tr><td>4th</td><td><em>ice storm, vitriolic sphere*</em></td></tr>
					<tr><td>5th</td><td><em>cone of cold</em></td></tr>
					<tr><td>6th</td><td><em>chain lightning, Otiluke’s freezing sphere</em></td></tr>
				</table>
			</description>
            <spellcasting name="Astral Tricks" ability="Intelligence" prepare="false">
                <list>Astral Trick</list>
            </spellcasting>
			<sheet>
				<description>You may use your power points to manifest Astral Tricks for 2 power points per spell level. If a spell allows using a higher level slot, you may expend additional power points to do so. Increasing a spell’s level requires 2 power points per higher slot level.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BURNING_HANDS" spellcasting="Astral Tricks" level="7" requirements="[channeler:powerpoints:2]" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_CHAOS_BOLT" spellcasting="Astral Tricks" level="7" requirements="[channeler:powerpoints:2]" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CHROMATIC_ORB" spellcasting="Astral Tricks" level="7" requirements="[channeler:powerpoints:2]" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_EARTH_TREMOR" spellcasting="Astral Tricks" level="7" requirements="[channeler:powerpoints:2]" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGIC_MISSILE" spellcasting="Astral Tricks" level="7" requirements="[channeler:powerpoints:2]" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_THUNDER_WAVE" spellcasting="Astral Tricks" level="7" requirements="[channeler:powerpoints:2]" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_AGANAZZARS_SCORCHER" spellcasting="Astral Tricks" level="7" requirements="[channeler:powerpoints:4]" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SCORCHING_RAY" spellcasting="Astral Tricks" level="7" requirements="[channeler:powerpoints:4]" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHATTER" spellcasting="Astral Tricks" level="7" requirements="[channeler:powerpoints:4]" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SNILLOCS_SNOWBALL_SWARM" spellcasting="Astral Tricks" level="7" requirements="[channeler:powerpoints:4]" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIREBALL" spellcasting="Astral Tricks" level="7" requirements="[channeler:powerpoints:6]" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LIGHTNING_BOLT" spellcasting="Astral Tricks" level="7" requirements="[channeler:powerpoints:6]" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ICE_STORM" spellcasting="Astral Tricks" level="7" requirements="[channeler:powerpoints:8]" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_VITRIOLIC_SPHERE" spellcasting="Astral Tricks" level="7" requirements="[channeler:powerpoints:8]" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONE_OF_COLD" spellcasting="Astral Tricks" level="7" requirements="[channeler:powerpoints:10]" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CHAIN_LIGHTNING" spellcasting="Astral Tricks" level="7" requirements="[channeler:powerpoints:12]" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_OTILUKES_FREEZING_SPHERE" spellcasting="Astral Tricks" level="7" requirements="[channeler:powerpoints:12]" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Sculpt Expresions" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHAPER_SCULPT_EXPRESIONS">
			<description>
				<p class="flavor">7th-level Shaper feature</p>
				<p>Through split-second calculation, you can shape your psionic powers. Whenever you manifest a power or a spell that affects other creatures that you can see, you can choose a number of them equal to 1 + your Intelligence modifier. The chosen creatures automatically succeed on their saving throws against the power or spell, and they take no damage if they would normally take half damage on a successful save.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet>
				<description>Whenever you manifest a power or a spell that affects other creatures that you can see, you can choose up to {{sculptexpressions:max}} creatures. The chosen creatures automatically succeed on their saving throws against the power or spell, and they take no damage if they would normally take half damage on a successful save.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <stat name="sculptexpressions:max" value="intelligence:modifier" />
                <stat name="sculptexpressions:max" value="1" />
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Psychic Residue" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHAPER_PSYCHIC_RESIDUE">
			<description>
				<p class="flavor">11th-level Shaper feature</p>
				<p>Manifestations which tap magical forces leave psychic residue. After using Astral Trick to manifest a cantrip or Manifest Magic to manifest an evocation spell, you can use your reaction to regain a Psychic Burst die.</p>
				<p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet usage="1/Short Rest" action="Reaction">
				<description>After using Astral Trick to manifest a cantrip or Manifest Magic to manifest an evocation spell, you can use your reaction to regain a Psychic Burst die.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
			</rules>
		</element>
		<element name="Ectoplasmic Shield" type="Archetype Feature" source="source" id="ID_author_source_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHAPER_ECTOPLASMIC_SHIELD">
			<description>
				<p class="flavor">17th-level Shaper feature</p>
				<p>When you are hit by or fail a saving throw against a spell or power that deals damage, you can use your reaction to erect a shield of ectoplasm that can absorb damage equal to twice your level in this class. You can empower your shield by spending power points, increasing the absorption by 5 points per power point you spend, but you can’t spend more power points than your channeler level.</p>
				<p class="indent">The shield remains in place until the end of your next turn and will continue to absorb damage from spells or powers which damage you that you choose. If your shield completely negates a spell’s damage or a power’s damage, you can choose to drop your shield and regain one Psychic Burst die.</p>
				<p class="indent">You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum once). You regain all expended uses of this feature when you finish a long rest.</p>
			</description>
			<sheet action="Reaction" usage="{{int-mod:min-one}}/Long Rest">
				<description>When you are hit by or fail a saving throw against a spell or power that deals damage, you can erect a shield that absorbs {{ectoplasmicshield:hp}} hit points damage. You can increase the amount by 5 hit points for each power point you spend (max: {{level:channeler}}) to augment it. The shield remains until the end of your next turn and absorb damage from spells or powers that you choose. If your shield completely negates a spell’s damage or a power’s damage, you can choose to drop your shield and regain one Psychic Burst die.</description>
			</sheet>
			<rules>
                <stat name="ectoplasmicshield:hp" value="level:channeler" />
                <stat name="ectoplasmicshield:hp" value="level:channeler" />
			</rules>
		</element>


    <!-- Skill Proficiencies -->
        <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_DECEPTION" />
        <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_HISTORY" />
        <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT" />
        <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INVESTIGATION" />
        <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_MEDICINE" />
        <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION" />
        <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERFORMANCE" />

    <!-- Channeler Psionic Powers -->
        <append id="ID_TC_PSHB_PSIONIC_POWER_ADAPTABILITY">
            <supports>Channeler</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_TC_PSHB_PSIONIC_POWER_BASTION_OF_THOUGHT">
            <supports>Channeler</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_TC_PSHB_PSIONIC_POWER_CONTROL_LIGHT">
            <supports>Channeler</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_TC_PSHB_PSIONIC_POWER_DEFLECTION">
            <supports>Channeler</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_TC_PSHB_PSIONIC_POWER_DIMENSIONAL_DISASSOCIATION">
            <supports>Channeler</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_TC_PSHB_PSIONIC_POWER_DISLOCATION">
            <supports>Channeler</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_TC_PSHB_PSIONIC_POWER_DISSONANT_DESTINY">
            <supports>Channeler</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_TC_PSHB_PSIONIC_POWER_ECTOPLASMIC_CREATION">
            <supports>Channeler</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_TC_PSHB_PSIONIC_POWER_EGO_WHIP">
            <supports>Channeler</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_TC_PSHB_PSIONIC_POWER_ENERGY_BLAST">
            <supports>Channeler</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_TC_PSHB_PSIONIC_POWER_FORETHOUGHT">
            <supports>Channeler</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_TC_PSHB_PSIONIC_POWER_INERTIAL_BARRIER">
            <supports>Channeler</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_TC_PSHB_PSIONIC_POWER_MENTAL_BARRIER">
            <supports>Channeler</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_TC_PSHB_PSIONIC_POWER_MIND_SPEAR">
            <supports>Channeler</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_TC_PSHB_PSIONIC_POWER_MIND_TAP">
            <supports>Channeler</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_TC_PSHB_PSIONIC_POWER_PSYCHIC_CRUSH">
            <supports>Channeler</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_TC_PSHB_PSIONIC_POWER_PSYCHIC_STATIC">
            <supports>Channeler</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_TC_PSHB_PSIONIC_POWER_REMOTE_SIGHT">
            <supports>Channeler</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_TC_PSHB_PSIONIC_POWER_SAP_VITALITY">
            <supports>Channeler</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_TC_PSHB_PSIONIC_POWER_SPECTRAL_ARMAMENT">
            <supports>Channeler</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_TC_PSHB_PSIONIC_POWER_SUSPENSION">
            <supports>Channeler</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_TC_PSHB_PSIONIC_POWER_TELEKINETIC_FLIGHT">
            <supports>Channeler</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_TC_PSHB_PSIONIC_POWER_TELEMPATHIC_PROJECTION">
            <supports>Channeler</supports>
        </append>

    <!-- Medium Psionic Powers -->
        <append id="ID_TC_PSHB_PSIONIC_POWER_APOPSI">
            <supports>Medium</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_TC_PSHB_PSIONIC_POWER_DIMENSIONAL_DISASSOCIATION">
            <supports>Medium</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_TC_PSHB_PSIONIC_POWER_EXTRASENSORY_PERCEPTION">
            <supports>Medium</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_TC_PSHB_PSIONIC_POWER_HYPERCOGNITION">
            <supports>Medium</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_TC_PSHB_PSIONIC_POWER_ID_INSINUATION">
            <supports>Medium</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_TC_PSHB_PSIONIC_POWER_MIND_PROBE">
            <supports>Medium</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_TC_PSHB_PSIONIC_POWER_MUDDLE">
            <supports>Medium</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_TC_PSHB_PSIONIC_POWER_PRECOGNITION">
            <supports>Medium</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_TC_PSHB_PSIONIC_POWER_PSYCHOMETRY">
            <supports>Medium</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_TC_PSHB_PSIONIC_POWER_PUPPETRY">
            <supports>Medium</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_TC_PSHB_PSIONIC_POWER_TELEKINETIC_GRASP">
            <supports>Medium</supports>
        </append>

    <!-- Metamorph Psionic Powers -->
        <append id="ID_TC_PSHB_PSIONIC_POWER_ACCELERATED_HEALING">
            <supports>Metamorph</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_TC_PSHB_PSIONIC_POWER_BIOMORPHIC_SKIN">
            <supports>Metamorph</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_TC_PSHB_PSIONIC_POWER_CHAMELEON">
            <supports>Metamorph</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_TC_PSHB_PSIONIC_POWER_DECAY">
            <supports>Metamorph</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_TC_PSHB_PSIONIC_POWER_ELASTIC_BODY">
            <supports>Metamorph</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_TC_PSHB_PSIONIC_POWER_ENERGY_CLOAK">
            <supports>Metamorph</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_TC_PSHB_PSIONIC_POWER_LIVING_WEAPON">
            <supports>Metamorph</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_TC_PSHB_PSIONIC_POWER_MARTIAL_INSIGHT">
            <supports>Metamorph</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_TC_PSHB_PSIONIC_POWER_MOLECULAR_AGITATION">
            <supports>Metamorph</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_TC_PSHB_PSIONIC_POWER_SIZE_ALTERATION">
            <supports>Metamorph</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_TC_PSHB_PSIONIC_POWER_SPEED_OF_THOUGHT">
            <supports>Metamorph</supports>
        </append>

    <!-- Shaper Psionic Powers -->
        <append id="ID_TC_PSHB_PSIONIC_POWER_ANIMATE_ELECTRICITY">
            <supports>Shaper</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_TC_PSHB_PSIONIC_POWER_DIMENSIONAL_BREACH">
            <supports>Shaper</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_TC_PSHB_PSIONIC_POWER_ENERGY_STORM">
            <supports>Shaper</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_TC_PSHB_PSIONIC_POWER_HARMONICS">
            <supports>Shaper</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_TC_PSHB_PSIONIC_POWER_HYDROKINESIS">
            <supports>Shaper</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_TC_PSHB_PSIONIC_POWER_PSIONIC_BLAST">
            <supports>Shaper</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_TC_PSHB_PSIONIC_POWER_SHADOW_SHAPE">
            <supports>Shaper</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_TC_PSHB_PSIONIC_POWER_SINGULARITY">
            <supports>Shaper</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_TC_PSHB_PSIONIC_POWER_SPATIAL_VOID">
            <supports>Shaper</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_TC_PSHB_PSIONIC_POWER_TREMOR">
            <supports>Shaper</supports>
        </append>

</elements>