<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Omega Warlock</name>
        <update version="0.0.2">
            <file name="class-omega-warlock.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/user/omega-warlock/class-omega-warlock.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>

    <element name="Omega Warlock" type="Source" source="Omega Warlock Compendium" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_SOURCE_OMEGA_WARLOCK_COMPENDIUM">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation">OWC</set>
            <set name="url">https://drive.google.com/file/d/1FEQQjQVgDub_b2B_pxhEIKgUGvX2s7pS/view</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" url="https://www.reddit.com/user/swecky">u/SwEcky</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20190521</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
  <!-- Omega Warlock -->    
    <element name="Omega Warlock" type="Class" source="Omega Warlock Compendium" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_OMEGA_WARLOCK">
        <description>
            <p>With a quasit sitting on his shoulder, a young elf in golden robes smiles warmly, weaving a magical charm into his honeyed words and bending the palace sentinel to his will.</p>
            <p class="indent">As flames spring to life in her hands, a wizened human whispers the secret name of her demonic patron, infusing her spell with abyssal powers.</p>
            <p class="indent">Shifting his gaze between a battered tome and the odd alignment of the stars overhead, a wild-eyed tiefling chants the mystic ritual that will open a doorway to a distant world.</p>
            <p class="indent">Warlocks are seekers of the knowledge that lies hidden in the fabric of the multiverse. Through pacts made with mysterious beings of supernatural power, warlocks unlock magical effects both subtle and spectacular. Drawing on the ancient knowledge of beings such as fey nobles, demons, devils, hags, and alien entities of the Far Realm, warlocks piece together arcane secrets to bolster their own power.</p>
            <h4>SWORN AND BEHOLDEN</h4>
            <p>A warlock is defined by a pact with an otherworldly being. Sometimes the relationship between warlock and patron is like that of a cleric and a deity, though the beings that serve as patrons for warlocks are not gods. A warlock might lead a cult dedicated to a demon prince, an archdevil, or an utterly alien entity—beings not typically served by clerics. More often, though, the arrangement is similar to that between a master and an apprentice. The warlock learns and grows in power, at the cost of occasional services performed on the patron’s behalf.</p>
            <p class="indent">The magic bestowed on a warlock ranges from minor but lasting alterations to the warlock’s being (such as the ability to see in darkness or to read any language) to access to powerful spells. Unlike bookish wizards, warlocks supplement their magic with some facility at hand-to-hand combat. They are comfortable in light armor and know how to use simple weapons.</p>
            <h4>DELVERS INTO SECRETS</h4>
            <p>Warlocks are driven by an insatiable need for knowledge and power, which compels them into their pacts and shapes their lives. This thirst drives warlocks into their pacts and shapes their later careers as well.</p>
            <p class="indent">Stories of warlocks binding themselves to fiends are widely known. But many warlocks serve patrons that are not fiendish. Sometimes a traveler in the wilds comes to a strangely beautiful tower, meets its fey lord or lady, and stumbles into a pact without being fully aware of it. And sometimes, while poring over tomes of forbidden lore, a brilliant but crazed student’s mind is opened to realities beyond the material world and to the alien beings that dwell in the outer void.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once a pact is made, a warlock’s thirst for knowledge and power can’t be slaked with mere study and research. No one makes a pact with such a mighty patron if he or she doesn’t intend to use the power thus gained. Rather, the vast majority of warlocks spend their days in active pursuit of their goals, which typically means some kind of adventuring. Furthermore, the demands of their patrons drive warlocks toward adventure.</p>
            <h4>CREATING A WARLOCK</h4>
            <p>As you make your warlock character, spend some time thinking about your patron and the obligations that your pact imposes upon you. What led you to make the pact, and how did you make contact with your patron? Were you seduced into summoning a devil, or did you seek out the ritual that would allow you to make contact with an alien elder god? Did you search for your patron, or did your patron find and choose you? Do you chafe under the obligations of your pact or serve joyfully in anticipation of the rewards promised to you? Work with your DM to determine how big a part your pact will play in your character’s adventuring career. Your patron’s demands might drive you into adventures, or they might consist entirely of small favors you can do between adventures.</p>
            <p class="indent">What kind of relationship do you have with your patron? Is it friendly, antagonistic, uneasy, or romantic? How important does your patron consider you to be? What part do you play in your patron’s plans? Do you know other servants of your patron?</p>
            <p class="indent">How does your patron communicate with you? If you have a chained companion, it might occasionally speak with your patron’s voice. Some warlocks find messages from their patrons etched on trees, mingled among tea leaves, or adrift in the clouds — messages that only the warlock can see. Other warlocks converse with their patrons in dreams or waking visions, or deal only with intermediaries.</p>
            <h5>QUICK BUILD</h5>
            <p>You can make a warlock quickly by following these suggestions. First, Intelligence should be your highest ability score, followed by Constitution. Second, choose the charlatan background. Third, choose the <i>thaumaturgy</i> and <i>chill touch</i> cantrips, along with the 1st-level spells <i>charm person</i> and <i>armor of Agathys</i>.</p>
            <h2>CLASS FEATURES</h2>
            <p>As warlock, you gain the following class features.</p>
            <h5>HIT POINTS</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Hit Dice:</strong> 1d8 per class level</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at 1st Level:</strong> 8 + your Constitution modifier</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at Higher Levels:</strong> 1d8 (or 5) + your Constitution modifier per class level after 1st</li>
            </ul>
            <h5>PROFICIENCIES</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Armor:</strong> Light armor</li>
                <li><strong>Weapons:</strong> Simple weapons</li>
                <li><strong>Tools:</strong> None</li>
            </ul>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Saving Throws:</strong> Intelligence, Wisdom</li>
                <li><strong>Skills:</strong> Choose two skills from Arcana, Deception, History, Intimidation, Investigation, Nature, and Religion</li>
            </ul>
            <h5>EQUIPMENT</h5>
            <p>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>(a) a light crossbow and 20 bolts or (b) any simple weapon</li>
                <li>(a) a component pouch or (b) an arcane focus</li>
                <li>(a) a scholar’s pack or (b) a dungeoneer’s pack</li>
                <li>Leather armor, any simple weapon, and two daggers</li>
            </ul>
            <div element="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OMEGA_WARLOCK_OTHERWORLDLY_PATRON" />
            <div element="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OMEGA_WARLOCK_PACT_BOON" />
            <div element="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OMEGA_WARLOCK_PACT_MAGIC" />
            <div element="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OMEGA_WARLOCK_ELDRITCH_INVOCATIONS" />
            <div element="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OMEGA_WARLOCK_HEX" />
            <div element="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OMEGA_WARLOCK_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" />
            <div element="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OMEGA_WARLOCK_MYSTIC_ARCANUM" />
            <div element="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OMEGA_WARLOCK_ELDRITCH_MASTER" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description>description</description>
        </sheet>
        <setters>
            <set name="short">A wielder of magic that is derived from a bargain with an extraplanar entity.</set>
            <set name="hd">d8</set>
        </setters>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" requirements="!ID_WOTC_PHB_MULTICLASS_WARLOCK" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" requirements="!ID_WOTC_PHB_MULTICLASS_WARLOCK" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_INTELLIGENCE" requirements="!ID_WOTC_PHB_MULTICLASS_WARLOCK" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_WISDOM" requirements="!ID_WOTC_PHB_MULTICLASS_WARLOCK" />
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency (Warlock)" supports="Skill,Warlock" number="2" requirements="!ID_WOTC_PHB_MULTICLASS_WARLOCK"/>

            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OMEGA_WARLOCK_OTHERWORLDLY_PATRON" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OMEGA_WARLOCK_PACT_BOON" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OMEGA_WARLOCK_PACT_MAGIC" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OMEGA_WARLOCK_ELDRITCH_INVOCATIONS" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OMEGA_WARLOCK_HEX" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OMEGA_WARLOCK_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" level="4" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OMEGA_WARLOCK_MYSTIC_ARCANUM" level="11" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OMEGA_WARLOCK_ELDRITCH_MASTER" level="20" />

        </rules>
    </element>
  <!-- Class Features -->
        <element name="Otherworldly Patron" type="Class Feature" source="Omega Warlock Compendium" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OMEGA_WARLOCK_OTHERWORLDLY_PATRON">
            <description>
                <p>At 1st level, you have struck a bargain with an otherworldly being of your choice, alls detailed at the end of the class description. Your choice grants you features at 1st level and again at 6th, 10th, and 14th level. Those features include an expanded spell list.</p>
                <h5>BESTOWED SPELLS</h5>
                <p>Each patron has a list of associated spells-its bestowed spells. You gain access to these spells at the levels specified in the patron description. Once you gain a bestowed spell, you always know it, and it doesn’t count against the number of spells you know.</p>
                <p class="indent">If you gain a spell that doesn’t appear on the warlock spell list, the spell is nonetheless a warlock spell for you.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Archetype" name="Otherworldly Patron" supports="Omega Warlock Otherworldly Patron" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Pact Boon" type="Class Feature" source="Omega Warlock Compendium" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OMEGA_WARLOCK_PACT_BOON">
            <description>
                <p>Additionally at 1st level, you have received a boon from your Otherworldly Patron as part of the pact you made each detailed at the end of the class description. This Boon also grants you additional features at 3rd, 5th, 9th, and 18th level.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Pact Boon" supports="Omega Warlock Pact Boon" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Pact Magic" type="Class Feature" source="Omega Warlock Compendium" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OMEGA_WARLOCK_PACT_MAGIC">
            <description>
                <p>Your arcane research and the magic bestowed on you by your patron have given you facility with spells. See Spells Rules for the general rules of spellcasting and the Spells Listing for the warlock spell list.</p>
                <h5>CANTRIPS</h5>
                <p>You know two cantrips of your choice from the warlock spell list. You learn additional warlock cantrips of your choice at higher levels, as shown in the Cantrips Known column of the Warlock table.</p>
                <h5>SPELL SLOTS</h5>
                <p>The Warlock table shows how many spell slots you have. The table also shows what the level of those slots is; all of your spell slots are the same level. To cast one of your warlock spells of 1st level or higher, you must expend a spell slot. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a short or long rest.</p>
                <p class="indent">For example, when you are 5th level, you have two 3rd-level spell slots. To cast the 1st-level spell witch bolt, you must spend one of those slots, and you cast it as a 3rd-level spell.</p>
                <h5>SPELLS KNOWN OF 1ST LEVEL AND HIGHER</h5>
                <p>At 1st level, you know two 1st-level spells of your choice from the warlock spell list.</p>
                <p class="indent">The Spells Known column of the Warlock table shows when you learn more warlock spells of your choice of 1st level and higher. A spell you choose must be of a level no higher than what’s shown in the table’s Slot Level column for your level. When you reach 6th level, for example, you learn a new warlock spell, which can be 1st, 2nd, or 3rd level.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, when you gain a level in this class, you can choose one of the warlock spells you know and replace it with another spell from the warlock spell list, which also must be of a level for which you have spell slots.</p>
                <h5>SPELLCASTING ABILITY</h5>
                <p>Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for your warlock spells, so you use your Intelligence whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Intelligence modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a warlock spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Spell save DC</b> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Spell attack modifier</b> = your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier</p>
                <h5>SPELLCASTING FOCUS</h5>
                <p>You can use an arcane focus as a spellcasting focus for your warlock spells.</p>
            </description>
            <spellcasting name="Omega Warlock" ability="Intelligence" prepare="false">
                <list>Warlock</list>
            </spellcasting>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="omega warlock:spellcasting:slots:count" value="1" level="1"/>
                <stat name="omega warlock:spellcasting:slots:count" value="1" level="2"/>
                <stat name="omega warlock:spellcasting:slots:count" value="1" level="11"/>
                <stat name="omega warlock:spellcasting:slots:count" value="1" level="17"/>

                <stat name="omega warlock:spellcasting:slot" value="1" level="1" />
                <stat name="omega warlock:spellcasting:slot" value="1" level="3" />
                <stat name="omega warlock:spellcasting:slot" value="1" level="5" />
                <stat name="omega warlock:spellcasting:slot" value="1" level="7" />
                <stat name="omega warlock:spellcasting:slot" value="1" level="9" />
                
                <!-- negative count to remove slots -->
                <stat name="omega warlock:spellcasting:slots:1" value="omega warlock:spellcasting:slots:count" level="1" />
                <stat name="omega warlock:spellcasting:slots:1" value="-omega warlock:spellcasting:slots:count" level="3" />
                <stat name="omega warlock:spellcasting:slots:2" value="omega warlock:spellcasting:slots:count" level="3" />
                <stat name="omega warlock:spellcasting:slots:2" value="-omega warlock:spellcasting:slots:count" level="5" />
                <stat name="omega warlock:spellcasting:slots:3" value="omega warlock:spellcasting:slots:count" level="5" />
                <stat name="omega warlock:spellcasting:slots:3" value="-omega warlock:spellcasting:slots:count" level="7" />
                <stat name="omega warlock:spellcasting:slots:4" value="omega warlock:spellcasting:slots:count" level="7" />
                <stat name="omega warlock:spellcasting:slots:4" value="-omega warlock:spellcasting:slots:count" level="9" />
                <stat name="omega warlock:spellcasting:slots:5" value="omega warlock:spellcasting:slots:count" level="9" />

                <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Omega Warlock)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),0" spellcasting="Omega Warlock" level="1" number="2" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Omega Warlock)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),0" spellcasting="Omega Warlock" level="4" number="1" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Omega Warlock)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),0" spellcasting="Omega Warlock" level="10" number="1" />

                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Omega Warlock)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="1" number="2" spellcasting="Omega Warlock"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Omega Warlock)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="2" spellcasting="Omega Warlock"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Omega Warlock)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="3" spellcasting="Omega Warlock"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Omega Warlock)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="4" spellcasting="Omega Warlock"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Omega Warlock)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="5" spellcasting="Omega Warlock"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Omega Warlock)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="6" spellcasting="Omega Warlock"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Omega Warlock)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="7" spellcasting="Omega Warlock"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Omega Warlock)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="8" spellcasting="Omega Warlock"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Omega Warlock)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="9" spellcasting="Omega Warlock"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Omega Warlock)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="11" spellcasting="Omega Warlock"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Omega Warlock)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="13" spellcasting="Omega Warlock"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Omega Warlock)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="15" spellcasting="Omega Warlock"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Omega Warlock)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="17" spellcasting="Omega Warlock"/>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Omega Warlock)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="19" spellcasting="Omega Warlock"/>

            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Eldritch Invocations" type="Class Feature" source="Omega Warlock Compendium" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OMEGA_WARLOCK_ELDRITCH_INVOCATIONS">
            <description>
                <p>In your study of occult lore, you have unearthed eldritch invocations, fragments of forbidden knowledge that imbue you with an abiding magical ability.</p>
                <p class="indent">At 2nd level, you gain one eldritch invocation of your choice. Your invocation options are detailed at the end of the document. When you gain certain warlock levels, you gain additional invocations of your choice, as shown in the Invocations Known column of the Warlock table.</p>
                <p class="indent">To swap an Invocation you must come to an understanding with your patron, something which might require completing a task for your patron.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Eldritch Invocation (Level 2)" supports="Omega Warlock Eldritch Invocation" level="2" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Eldritch Invocation (Level 7)" supports="Omega Warlock Eldritch Invocation" level="7" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Eldritch Invocation (Level 12)" supports="Omega Warlock Eldritch Invocation" level="12" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Eldritch Invocation (Level 17)" supports="Omega Warlock Eldritch Invocation" level="17" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Hex" type="Class Feature" source="Omega Warlock Compendium" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OMEGA_WARLOCK_HEX">
            <description>
                <p>At 2nd level, you hinder your enemies with mere words. Using a bonus action, you can expend a spell slot to hex a target within 90 feet for 1 minute.</p>
                <p class="indent">Until the hex ends, you deal an extra 1d6 necrotic damage to the target whenever you hit it with an attack. Also, choose one ability when you cast the target. The target has disadvantage on ability checks made with the chosen ability.</p>
                <p class="indent">If the target drops to 0 hit points before the hex ends, you can use a bonus action on a subsequent turn of yours to move the hex to a new creature.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can only have one target hexed active at a time and a <i>remove curse</i> cast on the target ends this effect early.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>You can expend a spell slot to hex a target within 90 feet for 1 minute. Until the hex ends, you deal an extra 1d6 necrotic damage to the target whenever you hit it with an attack. Also, choose one ability when you cast the target. The target has disadvantage on ability checks made with the chosen ability. If the target drops to 0 hit points before the hex ends, you can use a bonus action on a subsequent turn of yours to move the hex to a new creature.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Ability Score Improvement" type="Class Feature" source="Omega Warlock Compendium" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OMEGA_WARLOCK_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can forgo taking this feature to take a feat of your choice instead.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Omega Warlock 4)" supports="Improvement Option,Omega Warlock,4" level="4" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Omega Warlock 8)" supports="Improvement Option,Omega Warlock,8" level="8" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Omega Warlock 12)" supports="Improvement Option,Omega Warlock,12" level="12" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Omega Warlock 16)" supports="Improvement Option,Omega Warlock,16" level="16" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Omega Warlock 19)" supports="Improvement Option,Omega Warlock,19" level="19" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Mystic Arcanum" type="Class Feature" source="Omega Warlock Compendium" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OMEGA_WARLOCK_MYSTIC_ARCANUM">
            <description>
                <p>At 11th level, your patron bestows upon you a magical secret called an arcanum. Choose one 6th-level spell from the warlock spell list as this arcanum.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can cast your arcanum spell once without expending a spell slot. You must finish a long rest before you can do so again.</p>
                <p class="indent">At higher levels, you gain more warlock spells of your choice that can be cast in this way: one 7th-level spell at 13th level, one 8th-level spell at 15th level, and one 9th-level spell at 17th level. You regain all uses of your Mystic Arcanum when you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can cast your arcanum spell once without expending a spell slot. You must finish a long rest before you can do so again.</description>
                <description level="13">You can cast each of your arcanum spells once without expending a spell slot. You must finish a long rest before you can do so again.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Mystic Arcanum)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),6" spellcasting="Omega Warlock" known="true" level="11" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Mystic Arcanum)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),7" spellcasting="Omega Warlock" known="true" level="13" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Mystic Arcanum)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),8" spellcasting="Omega Warlock" known="true" level="15" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Spell (Mystic Arcanum)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),9" spellcasting="Omega Warlock" known="true" level="17" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Eldritch Master" type="Class Feature" source="Omega Warlock Compendium" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OMEGA_WARLOCK_ELDRITCH_MASTER">
            <description>
                <p>At 20th level, you can draw on your inner reserve of mystical power while entreating your patron to regain expended spell slots. You can spend 1 action to regain all your expended spell slots from your Pact Magic feature. Once you regain spell slots with this feature, you must finish a long rest before you can do so again.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You can spend 1 action to regain all your expended spell slots from your Pact Magic feature.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

  <!-- Pact Boons -->
   <!-- Pact of the Blade -->
    <element name="Pact of the Blade" type="Class Feature" source="Omega Warlock Compendium" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OW_PACT_OF_THE_BLADE">
        <supports>Omega Warlock Pact Boon</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The Pact of the Blade turns a warlock into an eldritch warrior, supplementing their magical prowess with martial skills. Warlocks who receive this boon are warriors of the occult. They may fight in their patron’s name, slaying those who would threaten or oppose them; or they may use their knowledge of the occult to attempt to stop the spread of its influence.</p>
            <div element="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OW_POTBLADE_PACT_WEAPON" />
            <div element="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OW_POTBLADE_WEAPON_BOND" />
            <div element="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OW_POTBLADE_THIRSTING_STRIKES" />
            <div element="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OW_POTBLADE_HEXBLADE" />
            <div element="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OW_POTBLADE_RUNEMARKED_BLADE" />
            <p class="flavor">If your patron is the Archfey, your weapon might be a slender blade wrapped in leafy vines. If your patron is the Great Old One, your weapon might be an ancient-looking spear, wilh a gemstone embedded in its head, carved to look like a terrible unblinking eye.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OW_POTBLADE_PACT_WEAPON" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OW_POTBLADE_WEAPON_BOND" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OW_POTBLADE_THIRSTING_STRIKES" level="5" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OW_POTBLADE_HEXBLADE" level="9" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OW_POTBLADE_RUNEMARKED_BLADE" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Pact Weapon" type="Class Feature" source="Omega Warlock Compendium" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OW_POTBLADE_PACT_WEAPON">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 1st level, you gain proficiency with medium armor, shields, and martial weapons.</p>
                <p class="indent">Also, you can transform up to two weapons (one can be a shield) into your Pact Weapons by performing a special ritual while you hold them. You perform the ritual over the course of 1 hour. You can’t affect an artifact or a sentient weapon in this way. The weapon ceases being your pact weapon if you die, if you perform the 1-hour ritual on a different weapon, or if you use a 1-hour ritual to break your bond to it.</p>
                <p class="indent">A Pact Weapon counts as a spellcasting focus and magical for the purpose of overcoming resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can transform up to two weapons (one can be a shield) into your Pact Weapons by performing a special ritual while you hold them. A Pact Weapon counts as a spellcasting focus and magical for the purpose of overcoming resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_MEDIUM_ARMOR" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_SHIELDS" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_MARTIAL_WEAPONS" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Weapon Bond" type="Class Feature" source="Omega Warlock Compendium" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OW_POTBLADE_WEAPON_BOND">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 3rd level, you can shunt your Pact Weapons into an extradimensional space (no action required), and you can make one or both reappear as an action.</p>
                <p class="indent">The weapons appear at your feet if they are in the extradimensional space when the bonds break.</p>
                <p class="indent">A Pact Weapon disappears into its extradimensional space if it is more than 5 feet away from you for 1 minute or more. It also disappears if you use this feature again or if you die.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can shunt your Pact Weapons into an extradimensional space (no action required), and you can make one or both reappear as an action.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Thirsting Strikes" type="Class Feature" source="Omega Warlock Compendium" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OW_POTBLADE_THIRSTING_STRIKES">
            <description>
                <p>At 5th level, you can attack with your pact weapon twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="extra attack:count" value="2" level="5" bonus="extra attack" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Hexblade" type="Class Feature" source="Omega Warlock Compendium" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OW_POTBLADE_HEXBLADE">
            <description>
                <p>At 9th level, when you hit a creature with your pact weapon, the creature takes extra necrotic damage equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum 1).</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, after you hit a creature with an attack, you can use or transfer your Hex ability on the target (no action required) and when a target is under the effect of your Hex ability, any weapon attack roll you make against the cursed target is a critical hit on a 19 or 20.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you hit a creature with your pact weapon, the creature takes {{hexblade:damage}} points extra necrotic damage. After you hit a creature with an attack, you can use or transfer your Hex ability on the target (no action required) and when a target is under the effect of your Hex ability, any weapon attack roll you make against the cursed target is a critical hit on a 19 or 20.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="hexblade:damage" value="1" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="hexblade:damage" value="intelligence:modifier" bonus="base" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Rune-marked Blade" type="Class Feature" source="Omega Warlock Compendium" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OW_POTBLADE_RUNEMARKED_BLADE">
            <description>
                <p>At 18th level, during your turn when you hit a creature with your pact weapon, you can use your bonus action to cast a Pact Magic spell with a casting time of 1 action.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>During your turn when you hit a creature with your pact weapon, you can use your bonus action to cast a Pact Magic spell with a casting time of 1 action.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

   <!-- Pact of the Chain -->
    <element name="Pact of the Chain" type="Class Feature" source="Omega Warlock Compendium" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OW_PACT_OF_THE_CHAIN">
        <supports>Omega Warlock Pact Boon</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The Pact of the Chain grants a warlock a servant—a creature in service of the otherworldly patron, tasked by the warlock’s benefactor with accompanying them on their adventures. Warlocks of this boon are commonly use their servant to spy on their foes or to obtain new perspectives. A patron may grant this boon to their warlock if they wish to bear firsthand witness to their exploits—or if they require an overseer to warn them of any attempts at betrayal.</p>
            <div element="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OW_POTCHAIN_CHAINED_COMPANION" />
            <div element="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OW_POTCHAIN_VOICE_OF_THE_CHAIN_MASTER" />
            <div element="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OW_POTCHAIN_HEX_BOUND" />
            <div element="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OW_POTCHAIN_CONDUIT_OF_THE_MASTER" />
            <div element="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OW_POTCHAIN_SUMMON_OF_THE_MASTER" />
            <p class="flavor">Your Chained Companion is an extension of your patron, a servant granted by the Archfey could be a mischievous sprite, the Demon Lord could have sent a lowly but power-hungry quasit to oversee that you not stray from your path, while the Undying might have given you a capable undead creature to help you gather information.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OW_POTCHAIN_CHAINED_COMPANION" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OW_POTCHAIN_VOICE_OF_THE_CHAIN_MASTER" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OW_POTCHAIN_HEX_BOUND" level="5" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OW_POTCHAIN_CONDUIT_OF_THE_MASTER" level="9" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OW_POTCHAIN_SUMMON_OF_THE_MASTER" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Chained Companion" type="Class Feature" source="Omega Warlock Compendium" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OW_POTCHAIN_CHAINED_COMPANION">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 1st level, you learn to summon a servant of your patron. The rules for creating a chained companion are at the end of this document. The Companion obeys your commands as best it can.</p>
                <p class="indent">If your companion is ever slain, the magical bond you share allows you to return it to life. With 1 hour of work and the expenditure of 15 gp per warlock level worth of rare incense, you call forth your Companion back from whichever plane it comes from. You can return it to life in this manner even if you do not possess any part of its body.</p>
                <h5>SERVANT’S BOND</h5>
                <p>Your Chained Companion gains a variety of benefits while it is accompanying you:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>It acts on your initiative, and you determine its actions, decisions, attitudes, and so on (no action required by you). If you are incapacitated or absent, your Companion acts on its own.</li>
                    <li>Your Chained Companion has abilities and game statistics determined in part by your level. Your Companion uses your proficiency bonus rather than its own.</li>
                    <li>Whenever you gain the Ability Score Improvement warlock class feature, your Companion’s abilities also improve. Your Companion can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or it can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. Your Companion can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Companion" name="Chained Companion" supports="Omega Warlock Companion" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Voice of the Chain Master" type="Class Feature" source="Omega Warlock Compendium" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OW_POTCHAIN_VOICE_OF_THE_CHAIN_MASTER">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 3rd level, while your Companion is on the same plane of existence, you can communicate with it telepathically. Additionally, as an action, you can see through your Companion’s eyes and hear what it hears until the start of your next turn, gaining the benefits of any special senses that the Companion has. During this time, you are deaf and blind with regard to your own senses. Lastly, while perceiving through your Companion’s senses, you can also speak through your servant in your own voice, even if it is normally incapable of speech.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>While your Companion is on the same plane of existence, you can communicate with it telepathically. Additionally, as an action, you can see through your Companion’s eyes and hear what it hears until the start of your next turn, gaining the benefits of any special senses that the Companion has. During this time, you are deaf and blind with regard to your own senses. Lastly, while perceiving through your Companion’s senses, you can also speak through your servant in your own voice, even if it is normally incapable of speech.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Hex Bound" type="Class Feature" source="Omega Warlock Compendium" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OW_POTCHAIN_HEX_BOUND">
            <description>
                <p>At 5th level, your Companion’s attacks counts as magical and it deals an additional 1d6 necrotic damage against a creature targeted by your Hex ability.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Your Companion’s attacks counts as magical and it deals an additional 1d6 necrotic damage against a creature targeted by your Hex ability.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Conduit of the Master" type="Class Feature" source="Omega Warlock Compendium" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OW_POTCHAIN_CONDUIT_OF_THE_MASTER">
            <description>
                <p>At 9th level, when you cast a spell, your Companion can deliver the spell as if it had cast the spell. Your Companion must be within 60 feet of you, and it must use its reaction to deliver the spell when you cast it. If the spell requires an attack roll, you use your attack modifier for the roll. If the spell has a range besides Touch, it is halved. If the spell has a range of Self, you can choose to target your Companion instead of yourself.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you cast a spell, your Companion can deliver the spell as if it had cast the spell. Your Companion must be within 60 feet of you, and it must use its reaction to deliver the spell when you cast it. If the spell requires an attack roll, you use your attack modifier for the roll. If the spell has a range besides Touch, it is halved. If the spell has a range of Self, you can choose to target your Companion instead of yourself.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Summon of the Master" type="Class Feature" source="Omega Warlock Compendium" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OW_POTCHAIN_SUMMON_OF_THE_MASTER">
            <description>
                <p>At 18th level, as a bonus action, you can target a creature under the effects of your Hex ability that you can see within 30 feet of you. This target must succeed on an Intelligence saving throw or be teleported to an unoccupied space that you can see within 5 feet of your familiar. The targeted creature has advantage on this saving throw if they would be teleported to a dangerous location, like the middle of a bonfire or over the edge of a cliff.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>You can target a creature under the effects of your Hex ability that you can see within 30 feet of you. This target must succeed on an Intelligence saving throw (save DC {{spellcasting:dc}}) or be teleported to an unoccupied space that you can see within 5 feet of your familiar. The targeted creature has advantage on this saving throw if they would be teleported to a dangerous location, like the middle of a bonfire or over the edge of a cliff.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

   <!-- Pact of the Tome -->
    <element name="Pact of the Tome" type="Class Feature" source="Omega Warlock Compendium" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OW_PACT_OF_THE_TOME">
        <supports>Omega Warlock Pact Boon</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The Pact of the Tome provides a warlock with a means of recording their spells and other pieces of arcane knowledge, allowing them to more easily catalogue their findings and spells. Warlocks who have such a book spend much of their time studying forbidden and long-forgotten lore in order to increase their knowledge and magical ability.</p>
            <div element="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OW_POTTOME_BOOK_OF_ERUDITION" />
            <div element="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OW_POTTOME_BOOK_OF_ANCIENT_SECRETS" />
            <div element="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OW_POTTOME_AGONIZING_INCANTATIONS" />
            <div element="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OW_POTTOME_LEDGER_OF_THE_DECEASED" />
            <div element="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OW_POTTOME_OCCULTISTS_TOME" />
            <p class="flavor">Your Book of Erudition might be a fine, gilt-edged tome gifted to you by the lordly Archfey. It could be a weighty tome bound in demon hide studded with iron, a gift of the Demon Lord, or it could be the tattered diary of a lunatic driven mad by contact with the Great Old One, that only your own burgeoning insanity allows you to understand.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OW_POTTOME_BOOK_OF_ERUDITION" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OW_POTTOME_BOOK_OF_ANCIENT_SECRETS" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OW_POTTOME_AGONIZING_INCANTATIONS" level="5" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OW_POTTOME_LEDGER_OF_THE_DECEASED" level="9" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OW_POTTOME_OCCULTISTS_TOME" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Book of Erudition" type="Class Feature" source="Omega Warlock Compendium" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OW_POTTOME_BOOK_OF_ERUDITION">
            <description>
                <p>At 1st level, your patron gives you a grimoire called a Book of Erudition. When you gain this feature, you gain the <i>eldritch blast</i> cantrip and two other cantrips of your choice. While the book is on your person, you can cast those cantrips at will. They don’t count against your number of cantrips known. If they don’t appear on the warlock spell list, they are nonetheless warlock spells for you.</p>
                <p class="indent">If you lose your Book of Erudition, you can perform a 1-hour ceremony to receive a replacement from your patron. This ceremony can be performed during a long rest, and it destroys the previous book. The book turns to ash when you die.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>While you have your Book of Erudition, you may cast eldritch blast and your Book of Erudition cantrips at will.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ELDRITCH_BLAST" spellcasting="Omega Warlock" known="true" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Book of Erudition)" number="2" spellcasting="Omega Warlock" known="true" supports="Warlock,0" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Book of Ancient Secrets" type="Class Feature" source="Omega Warlock Compendium" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OW_POTTOME_BOOK_OF_ANCIENT_SECRETS">
            <description>
                <p>At 3rd level, you can now inscribe magical rituals in your Book of Erudition. Choose two 1st-level spells that have the ritual tag from any class’s spell list. The spells appear in the book and don’t count against the number of spells you know. With your Book of Erudition in hand, you can cast the chosen spells as rituals. You can’t cast the spells except as rituals, unless you’ve learned them by some other means. You can also cast a warlock spell you know as a ritual if it has the ritual tag.</p>
                <p class="indent">On your adventures, you can add other ritual spells to your Book of Erudition. When you find such a spell, you can add it to the book if the spell’s level is equal to or less than half your warlock level (rounded up) and if you can spare the time to transcribe the spell. For each level of the spell, the transcription process takes 2 hours and costs 50 gp for the rare inks needed to inscribe it.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can now inscribe magical rituals in your Book of Erudition.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Spell" name="Ritual Spell (Book of Ancient Secrets)" number="2" supports="1,Ritual" spellcasting="Omega Warlock" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Agonizing Incantations" type="Class Feature" source="Omega Warlock Compendium" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OW_POTTOME_AGONIZING_INCANTATIONS">
            <description>
                <p>At 5th level, when you cast a damaging cantrip, add your Intelligence modifier to the damage it deals on a hit.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you cast a damaging cantrip, add {{intelligence:modifier}} to the damage it deals on a hit.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Ledger of the Deceased" type="Class Feature" source="Omega Warlock Compendium" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OW_POTTOME_LEDGER_OF_THE_DECEASED">
            <description>
                <p>At 9th level, your Book of Erudition is no longer destroyed when you die, and it can be used in place of your corpse to restore you to life.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, whenever a creature that you can see within 120 feet of you dies or you touch a corpse, you can choose to have their name be magically inscribed in your Book of Erudition. That creature’s corpse is always considered to be present and whole within your Book, creating a new copy of the body when needed. If your Book of Erudition is destroyed, all the names within are lost, even if the book is restored.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Your Book of Erudition is no longer destroyed when you die, and it can be used in place of your corpse to restore you to life.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Occultist’s Tome" type="Class Feature" source="Omega Warlock Compendium" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_CLASS_FEATURE_OW_POTTOME_OCCULTISTS_TOME">
            <description>
                <p>At 18th level, whenever you cast a cantrip on your turn, you can use your bonus action to cast a different cantrip.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>Whenever you cast a cantrip on your turn, you can use your bonus action to cast a different cantrip.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

</elements>