<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Grandmaester Omega Warlock Patron</name>
        <update version="0.0.3">
            <file name="omega-warlock-grandmaester.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/user/omega-warlock/omega-warlock-grandmaester.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="The Grandmaester" type="Archetype" source="Omega Warlock Compendium" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_ARCHETYPE_OMEGA_WARLOCK_OTHERWORLDLY_PATRON_GRANDMAESTER">
        <supports>Omega Warlock Otherworldly Patron</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You have made a pact with an archmagi, a creature that have an exceptional amount arcane knowledge. Often these beings desire only to expand their own power and influence, only using you as a pawn in its far larger scheme. Other times, they find the urge to take on an apprentice to continue their research in the case of an untimely death. Some are even unknowing that a lesser being is siphoning their power.</p>
            <div element="ID_SWECKY_OWC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OW_GRANDMAESTER_BESTOWED_SPELLS" />
            <div element="ID_SWECKY_OWC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OW_GRANDMAESTER_DAILY_ARCANA" />
            <div element="ID_SWECKY_OWC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OW_GRANDMAESTER_TEARING_THE_WEAVE" />
            <div element="ID_SWECKY_OWC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OW_GRANDMAESTER_ARCANE_NATURE" />
            <div element="ID_SWECKY_OWC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OW_GRANDMAESTER_THE_MAESTERS_FOCUS" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OW_GRANDMAESTER_BESTOWED_SPELLS" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OW_GRANDMAESTER_DAILY_ARCANA" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OW_GRANDMAESTER_TEARING_THE_WEAVE" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OW_GRANDMAESTER_ARCANE_NATURE" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OW_GRANDMAESTER_THE_MAESTERS_FOCUS" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Bestowed Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="Omega Warlock Compendium" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OW_GRANDMAESTER_BESTOWED_SPELLS">
            <description>
                <p>You gain bestowed spells at the warlock levels listed.</p>
                <h5>GRANDMAESTER BESTOWED SPELLS</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Warlock Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1st</td><td><i>explosion, magic missile</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td><i>mirror image, objectify</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><i>detect interference, dispel magic</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>7th</td><td><i>arcane eye, dimension door</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><i>Bigby’s hand, teleportation circle</i></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_RDDT_UA_OW_SPELL_EXPLOSION" level="1" spellcasting="Omega Warlock" known="true" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGIC_MISSILE" level="1" spellcasting="Omega Warlock" known="true" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MIRROR_IMAGE" level="3" spellcasting="Omega Warlock" known="true" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_RDDT_UA_OW_SPELL_OBJECTIFY" level="3" spellcasting="Omega Warlock" known="true" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_RDDT_UA_OW_SPELL_DETECT_INTERFERENCE" level="5" spellcasting="Omega Warlock" known="true" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISPEL_MAGIC" level="5" spellcasting="Omega Warlock" known="true" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ARCANE_EYE" level="7" spellcasting="Omega Warlock" known="true" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DIMENSION_DOOR" level="7" spellcasting="Omega Warlock" known="true" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BIGBYS_HAND" level="9" spellcasting="Omega Warlock" known="true" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TELEPORTATION_CIRCLE" level="9" spellcasting="Omega Warlock" known="true" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Daily Arcana" type="Archetype Feature" source="Omega Warlock Compendium" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OW_GRANDMAESTER_DAILY_ARCANA">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 1st level, your patron has taught you techniques for flexible spell preparation. When you finish a long rest, you can choose one of the warlock spells you know and replace it with another spell from the warlock spell list, which also must be of a level for which you have spell slots.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, you gain the <i>prestidigitation</i> cantrip.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you finish a long rest, you can choose one of the warlock spells you know and replace it with another spell from the warlock spell list, which also must be of a level for which you have spell slots.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PRESTIDIGITATION" spellcasting="omega warlock" known="true" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Tearing the Weave" type="Archetype Feature" source="Omega Warlock Compendium" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OW_GRANDMAESTER_TEARING_THE_WEAVE">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, you have been taught how to safely wrench your way through the weave. You can use an action to teleport yourself to an unoccupied space within 30 feet. Immediately after you reappear, a wave of arcane energy rushes out from your new position, and each creature within 5 feet of you must make a Strength saving throw. On a failure, each Medium or smaller creature is lifted 10 feet up in the air (if possible) where they are transfixed until the start of your next turn. While transfixed their movement speed is reduced to 0.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can bring along objects as long as their weight doesn’t exceed what you can carry.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Short Rest" action="Action">
                <description>You can teleport yourself to an unoccupied space within 30 feet. Immediately after you reappear, a wave of arcane energy rushes out from your new position, and each creature within 5 feet of you must make a Strength saving throw (save DC {{spellcasting:dc}}). On a failure, each Medium or smaller creature is lifted 10 feet up in the air (if possible) where they are transfixed until the start of your next turn. While transfixed their movement speed is reduced to 0. You can bring along objects as long as their weight doesn’t exceed what you can carry.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Arcane Nature" type="Archetype Feature" source="Omega Warlock Compendium" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OW_GRANDMAESTER_ARCANE_NATURE">
            <description>
                <p>At 10th level, you have become part of the magic you use. You gain resistance versus damage done by spells and you cannot lose concentration due to damage from spells.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You have resistance against damage done by spells and you cannot lose concentration due to damage from spells.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="The Maester’s Focus" type="Archetype Feature" source="Omega Warlock Compendium" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OW_GRANDMAESTER_THE_MAESTERS_FOCUS">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 14th level, you can temporarily shift part of the burden of spellcasting onto your patron, enabling you to transcend ordinary limitations. While you are concentrating on a warlock spell or a spell cast using an Eldritch Invocation you know, you can cast an additional warlock spell or a spell from an Eldritch Invocation you know that requires concentration and choose to maintain concentration on both spells simultaneously. If you are still maintaining concentration on both spells simultaneously after one minute, you must end your concentration on one of the spells. If you fail a Constitution saving throw to maintain concentration, you lose concentration on both spells.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you have used this feature, you must finish a long rest before you can use it again.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>While you are concentrating on a warlock spell or a spell cast using an Eldritch Invocation you know, you can cast an additional warlock spell or a spell from an Eldritch Invocation you know that requires concentration and choose to maintain concentration on both spells simultaneously. If you are still maintaining concentration on both spells simultaneously after one minute, you must end your concentration on one of the spells. If you fail a Constitution saving throw to maintain concentration, you lose concentration on both spells.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
</elements>