<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Great Old One Omega Warlock Patron</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="omega-warlock-great-old-one.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/user/omega-warlock/omega-warlock-great-old-one.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="The Great Old One" type="Archetype" source="Omega Warlock Compendium" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_ARCHETYPE_OMEGA_WARLOCK_OTHERWORLDLY_PATRON_">
        <supports>Omega Warlock Otherworldly Patron</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Your patron is a mysterious entity whose nature is utterly foreign to the fabric of reality. It might come from the Far Realm, the space beyond reality, or it could be one of the elder gods known only in legends. Its motives are incomprehensible to mortals, and its knowledge so immense and ancient that even the greatest libraries pale in comparison to the vast secrets it holds. The Great Old One might be unaware of your existence or entirely indifferent to you, but the secrets you have learned allow you to draw your magic from it.</p>
            <div element="ID_SWECKY_OWC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OW_GREAT_OLD_ONE_BESTOWED_SPELLS" />
            <div element="ID_SWECKY_OWC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OW_GREAT_OLD_ONE_AWAKENED_MIND" />
            <div element="ID_SWECKY_OWC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OW_GREAT_OLD_ONE_VISIONS_OF_HORROR" />
            <div element="ID_SWECKY_OWC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OW_GREAT_OLD_ONE_LABYRINTHINE_CONUNDRUM" />
            <div element="ID_SWECKY_OWC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OW_GREAT_OLD_ONE_CREATE_THRALL" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OW_GREAT_OLD_ONE_BESTOWED_SPELLS" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OW_GREAT_OLD_ONE_AWAKENED_MIND" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OW_GREAT_OLD_ONE_VISIONS_OF_HORROR" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OW_GREAT_OLD_ONE_LABYRINTHINE_CONUNDRUM" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OW_GREAT_OLD_ONE_CREATE_THRALL" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Bestowed Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="Omega Warlock Compendium" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OW_GREAT_OLD_ONE_BESTOWED_SPELLS">
            <description>
                <p>You gain bestowed spells at the warlock levels listed.</p>
                <h5>GREAT OLD ONE BESTOWED SPELLS</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Warlock Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1st</td><td><i>dissonant whispers, Tasha’s hideous laughter</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td><i>detect thoughts, phantasmal force</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><i>clairvoyance, sending</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>7th</td><td><i>Evard’s black tentacles, phantasmal killer</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><i>dominate person, telekinesis</i></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISSONANT_WHISPERS" level="1" spellcasting="Omega Warlock" known="true" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TASHAS_HIDEOUS_LAUGHTER" level="1" spellcasting="Omega Warlock" known="true" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_THOUGHTS" level="3" spellcasting="Omega Warlock" known="true" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PHANTASMAL_FORCE" level="3" spellcasting="Omega Warlock" known="true" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CLAIRVOYANCE" level="5" spellcasting="Omega Warlock" known="true" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SENDING" level="5" spellcasting="Omega Warlock" known="true" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_EVARDS_BLACK_TENTACLES" level="7" spellcasting="Omega Warlock" known="true" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PHANTASMAL_KILLER" level="7" spellcasting="Omega Warlock" known="true" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DOMINATE_PERSON" level="9" spellcasting="Omega Warlock" known="true" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TELEKINESIS" level="9" spellcasting="Omega Warlock" known="true" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Awakened Mind" type="Archetype Feature" source="Omega Warlock Compendium" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OW_GREAT_OLD_ONE_AWAKENED_MIND">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 1st level, your alien knowledge gives you the ability to touch the minds of other creatures. You can communicate telepathically with any creature you can see within 30 feet of you. You don't need to share a language with the creature for it to understand your telepathic utterances, but the creature must be able to understand at least one language.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can communicate telepathically with any creature you can see within 30 feet of you. You don't need to share a language with the creature for it to understand your telepathic utterances, but the creature must be able to understand at least one language.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_DEEP_SPEECH" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Visions of Horror" type="Archetype Feature" source="Omega Warlock Compendium" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OW_GREAT_OLD_ONE_VISIONS_OF_HORROR">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, you can flood the minds of those who assault you with terrifying, incomprehensible images from your patron's realm. When a creature within 60 feet damages you, you can use your reaction to force the creature to make an Intelligence saving throw against your warlock spell save DC. On a failed save, the creature takes psychic damage equal to 1d10 + half your warlock level and is frightened for 1 minute. A frightened creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on a success. On a successful save, the creature takes half as much damage and isn't frightened.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
                <description>When a creature within 60 feet damages you, you can use your reaction to force the creature to make an Intelligence saving throw (save DC {{spellcasting:dc}}). On a failed save, the creature takes 1d10 + {{level:omega warlock:half}} psychic damage and is frightened for 1 minute. A frightened creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on a success. On a successful save, the creature takes half as much damage and isn't frightened.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Labyrinthine Conundrum" type="Archetype Feature" source="Omega Warlock Compendium" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OW_GREAT_OLD_ONE_LABYRINTHINE_CONUNDRUM">
            <description>
                <p>At 10th level, the outer layers of your mind become alien in scope - becoming indecipherable to those who would plunder it, while revealing the true nature of the world around you. You are immune to any effect that would sense your emotions, read your thoughts, or determine you are lying, unless you allow it.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, you can use your action to open your mind to the truth of the world. For 10 minutes, you gain truesight out to 60 feet. Once you do so, you can't do so again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Short Rest" action="Action">
                <description>You can use your action to open your mind to the truth of the world. For 10 minutes, you gain truesight out to 60 feet. Additionally, you are immune to any effect that would sense your emotions, read your thoughts, or determine you are lying, unless you allow it.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Create Thrall" type="Archetype Feature" source="Omega Warlock Compendium" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OW_GREAT_OLD_ONE_CREATE_THRALL">
            <description>
                <p>At 14th level, you gain the ability to infect a humanoid’s mind with the alien magic of your patron. You can use your action to touch an incapacitated humanoid. That creature is then charmed by you until a remove curse spell of 5th level or higher is cast on it, the charmed condition is removed from it, or you use this feature again.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can communicate telepathically with the charmed creature as long as the two of you are on the same plane of existence. The charmed creature regards you as a trusted friend to be heeded and protected. Although the creature isn't under your control, it takes your requests or actions in the most favorable way it can.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>You can touch an incapacitated humanoid. That creature is then charmed by you until a remove curse spell of 5th level or higher is cast on it, the charmed condition is removed from it, or you use this feature again. You can communicate telepathically with the charmed creature as long as the two of you are on the same plane of existence. The charmed creature regards you as a trusted friend to be heeded and protected. Although the creature isn't under your control, it takes your requests or actions in the most favorable way it can.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
</elements>