<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Legion Omega Warlock Patron</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="omega-warlock-legion.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/user/omega-warlock/omega-warlock-legion.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="The Legion" type="Archetype" source="Omega Warlock Compendium" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_ARCHETYPE_OMEGA_WARLOCK_OTHERWORLDLY_PATRON_">
        <supports>Omega Warlock Otherworldly Patron</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You have made a pact with a legion, or more precisely, a legion has made a pact with you. In so doing these ten thousands souls grant you their power and experience of many lifetimes in exchange for being able to experience life once again through your eyes.</p>
            <p class="indent">These souls were once people and many different legions have different stories. One might have once been the citizens of a city that was destroyed by war or disaster. Others may be a various collection of people who refused to move on to the afterlife. Yet still others might be an army who seek vengeance against a particular enemy.</p>
            <div element="ID_SWECKY_OWC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OW_LEGION_BESTOWED_SPELLS" />
            <div element="ID_SWECKY_OWC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OW_LEGION_AURA_OF_THE_DEAD" />
            <div element="ID_SWECKY_OWC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OW_LEGION_COURT_OF_SOULS" />
            <div element="ID_SWECKY_OWC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OW_LEGION_SPECTRAL_SHROUD" />
            <div element="ID_SWECKY_OWC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OW_LEGION_LEGIONS_RALLY" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OW_LEGION_BESTOWED_SPELLS" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OW_LEGION_AURA_OF_THE_DEAD" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OW_LEGION_COURT_OF_SOULS" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OW_LEGION_SPECTRAL_SHROUD" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OW_LEGION_LEGIONS_RALLY" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Bestowed Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="Omega Warlock Compendium" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OW_LEGION_BESTOWED_SPELLS">
            <description>
                <p>You gain bestowed spells at the warlock levels listed.</p>
                <h5>LEGION BESTOWED SPELLS</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Warlock Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1st</td><td><i>inflict wounds, sanctuary</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td><i>blur, enhance ability</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td><i>bestow curse, phantom steed</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>7th</td><td><i>awareness, Mordenkainen's faithful hound</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><i>legend lore, skill empowerment</i></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INFLICT_WOUNDS" level="1" spellcasting="Omega Warlock" known="true" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SANCTUARY" level="1" spellcasting="Omega Warlock" known="true" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLUR" level="3" spellcasting="Omega Warlock" known="true" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENHANCE_ABILITY" level="3" spellcasting="Omega Warlock" known="true" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BESTOW_CURSE" level="5" spellcasting="Omega Warlock" known="true" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PHANTOM_STEED" level="5" spellcasting="Omega Warlock" known="true" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AWARENESS" level="7" spellcasting="Omega Warlock" known="true" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MORDKAINENS_FAITHFUL_HOUND" level="7" spellcasting="Omega Warlock" known="true" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LEGEND_LORE" level="9" spellcasting="Omega Warlock" known="true" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_SKILL_EMPOWERMENT" level="9" spellcasting="Omega Warlock" known="true" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Aura of the Dead" type="Archetype Feature" source="Omega Warlock Compendium" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OW_LEGION_AURA_OF_THE_DEAD">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 1st level, the souls of the legion can become partly corporeal within 10 feet of you. This causes the area to gain the following effects:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>You and allied creatures within your aura have advantage on death saving throws.</li>
                    <li>The area within the aura counts as difficult terrain for creatures of your choice.</li>
                    <li>You can cast spells that require a melee spell attack, or have a range of touch against any creature within, or adjacent to, your aura.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You and allied creatures within 10 feet have advantage on death saving throws. The area within 10 feet of you counts as difficult terrain for creatures of your choice. You can cast spells that require a melee spell attack or have a range of touch agains any creature within or adjacent to your aura (10 feet).</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Court of Souls" type="Archetype Feature" source="Omega Warlock Compendium" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OW_LEGION_COURT_OF_SOULS">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, the souls of the dead can keep your enemies at bay. You can use an action to force any number of creatures you choose within your aura to make a Strength saving throw. On a failed save they take cold damage equal to 1d6 + half your warlock level and are pushed to the closest available space outside of your aura and they cannot enter your aura again until the start of your next turn.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Short Rest" action="Action">
                <description>You can force any number of creatures you choose within your aura to make a Strength saving throw (save DC {{spellcasting:dc}}). On a failed save they 1d6 + {{level:omega warlock:half}} cold damage and are pushed to the closest available space outside of your aura and they cannot enter your aura again until the start of your next turn.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Spectral Shroud" type="Archetype Feature" source="Omega Warlock Compendium" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OW_LEGION_SPECTRAL_SHROUD">
            <description>
                <p>At 10th level, your own growing power gives the legion greater corporeal strength. While within your aura, you and creatures of your choice have resistance to necrotic and cold damage, and gain the benefits of half cover against ranged attacks made from outside the aura.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>While within your aura (10 feet), you and creatures of your choice have resistance to necrotic and cold damage, and gain the benefits of half cover against ranged attacks made from outside the aura.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Legion's Rally" type="Archetype Feature" source="Omega Warlock Compendium" id="ID_SWECKY_OWC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_OW_LEGION_LEGIONS_RALLY">
            <description>
                <p>At 14th level, you can use an action to call forth your legion to stand at your side in battle. Your aura now extends out to 30 feet for 1 minute, and you can choose up to six creatures that are within your aura. Those creatures gain temporary hit points equal to your warlock level. If a creature is unconscious, it is restored to consciousness with 1 hit point. The temporary hit points lasts for 1 minute.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>Your aura now extends out to 30 feet for 1 minute, and you can choose up to six creatures that are within your aura. Those creatures gain {{level:omega warlock}} temporary hit points. If a creature is unconscious, it is restored to consciousness with 1 hit point. The temporary hit points lasts for 1 minute.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
</elements>