<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Tome of Blood Magics Spells</name>
        <author url="https://homebrewery.naturalcrit.com/share/HJ5FlesyQ">Eliar’s Lost Arts</author>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="spells.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aurorabuilder/elements/master/spells.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    

    <element name="Bloodbridge" type="Spell" source="Tome of Blood Magics" id="ID_ELA_TOBM_SPELL_BLOODBRIDGE">
        <supports>Blood Mage</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You touch two creatures, drawing blood out of one (the "donor") and infusing it into the other (the "recipient"). An unwilling donor must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or take 2d4 necrotic damage. The recipient then gains a number of temporary hit points equal to half of the damage dealt this way unless either creature lacks blood (undead, constructs, plants, oozes, elementals, etc).</p>
            <p class="indent">This spell’s damage increases by 2d4 when you reach 5th level (4d4), 11th level (6d4), and 17th level (8d4).</p>
            <p class="flavor"><b>Source: </b>Edited from Wizard’s Spell Compendium</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">0</set>
            <set name="school">Necromancy</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">two golden needles</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Dictation" type="Spell" source="Tome of Blood Magics" id="ID_ELA_TOBM_SPELL_DICTATION">
        <supports>Blood Mage</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You enchant a pen or other writing instrument and it will begin to transcribe any words spoken in a language you know within 5 feet of it.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">0</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, 1 minute</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent"></set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Enemies" type="Spell" source="Tome of Blood Magics" id="ID_ELA_TOBM_SPELL_ENEMIES">
        <supports>Blood Mage</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Target creature must make a wisdom saving throw. On a failure, choose one of the following effects:</p>
            <p class="indent"> • It must immediately use it’s reaction to make an attack on a nearby creature that it considers an ally, and then the spell ends.</p>
            <p class="indent"> • It is convinced that another target creature is plotting against it and becomes unfriendly, or perhaps hostile toward that creature.</p>
            <p class="indent">When the spell ends, the creature realizes that you used magic to influence its mood. It gains advantage on all further saving throws caused by this spell for 24 hours and becomes hostile toward you. A creature prone to violence might attack you. Another creature might seek retribution in other ways (at the DM’s discretion), depending on the nature of your interaction with it.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">0</set>
            <set name="school">Enchantment</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a small doll</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Pain" type="Spell" source="Tome of Blood Magics" id="ID_ELA_TOBM_SPELL_PAIN">
        <supports>Blood Mage</supports>
        <description>
            <p>One creature you touch must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or be wracked by horrific pains. On a failed save, the creature has a -2 penalty on all attack rolls and ability checks. At the end of each of its turns, the creature may repeat the saving throw, ending the effect on a success.</p>
            <p class="indent">This spell’s penalty increases by -1 when you reach 5th level (-3), 11th level (-4), and 17th level (-5).</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">0</set>
            <set name="school">Necromancy</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent"></set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Redirect" type="Spell" source="Tome of Blood Magics" id="ID_ELA_TOBM_SPELL_REDIRECT">
        <supports>Blood Mage</supports>
        <description>
            <p>When a non-hostile creature that you can touch is targeted with a magical effect, you may use your reaction to change one of the targets of that spell to you instead.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">0</set>
            <set name="school">Abjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 reaction, which you can take when a creature within 5 feet of you is targeted with a magical effect.</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent"></set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Summoning" type="Spell" source="Tome of Blood Magics" id="ID_ELA_TOBM_SPELL_SUMMONING">
        <supports>Blood Mage</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You place a visible mark on an object that weigs no more than 5 lbs and fits in a 5 foot cube. As an action, you may summon that object to you, so long as it’s within 10 miles and not being worn or carried. After the marked object is summoned, after 48 hours have passed, or if you create the mark fades.</p>
            <p class="indent">This spell's weight limit is increased by 5 pounds, and the distance by 5 miles at 5th level (10 lbs, 15 miles), 11th level (15 lbs, 20 miles), and 17th level (20 lbs, 25 miles).</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">0</set>
            <set name="school">Conjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 action, or 1 reaction which you take at the start of combat</set>
            <set name="duration">48 hours</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">chalks worth 50gp</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Arcane Tether" type="Spell" source="Tome of Blood Magics" id="ID_ELA_TOBM_SPELL_ARCANE_TETHER">
        <supports>Blood Mage</supports>
        <description>
            <p>An ethereal chain springs from your hand and flies toward a creature you can see within range. That creature mus succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or take 1d8 force damage as the chain attaches itself to the creature’s chest and a point within 5 feet of that creature. The creature is anchored to that point, unable to move more than 5 feet away from it. As an action, a creature may attempt a Strength saving throw, breaking the chain on a success.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Conjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">1 minute</set>
            <set name="range">30 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">A needle and and pincushion</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Bloodbond" type="Spell" source="Tome of Blood Magics" id="ID_ELA_TOBM_SPELL_BLOODBOND">
        <supports>Blood Mage</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You link the health of two creatures. Choose one creature within 30 feet, and then another creature you touch. An unwilling creature must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or be linked to the other. Any damage taken by one creature is divided evenly (rounded up) between all linked creatures.</p>
            <p class="indent">At Higher Levels. When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, you may target one additional creature for each slot level above 1st up to a maximum of four. Additionally, if cast using a spell slot of 3rd level, the duration increases to 1 hour. If cast using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the duration increases to 8 hours.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Necromancy</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">10 minutes</set>
            <set name="range">30 feet, Touch</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">A length of red silk</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Shift" type="Spell" source="Tome of Blood Magics" id="ID_ELA_TOBM_SPELL_SHIFT">
        <supports>Blood Mage</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Make a melee spell attack. On hit, the target takes 5 (1d10) force damage and must succeed on a Charisma saving throw or be teleported up to 20 feet to an unoccupied space you can see.</p>
            <p class="indent">At Higher Levels. When cast using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the range the creature can be teleported is increased by 5 feet per spell slot level above the first.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Conjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent"></set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Stumble" type="Spell" source="Tome of Blood Magics" id="ID_ELA_TOBM_SPELL_STUMBLE">
        <supports>Blood Mage</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Whenever a creature within range begins its movement or moves within range, you may use your reaction to speak an ancient word of power. It must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or use its movement to move the opposite direction it intended and then fall to the ground prone. Creatures immune to being charmed are immune to this effect.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Enchantment</set>
            <set name="time">1 reaction, which you can take whenever a creature within range attempts to move, or a creature moves within range.</set>
            <set name="duration">1 round</set>
            <set name="range">20 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent"></set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Throw Voice" type="Spell" source="Tome of Blood Magics" id="ID_ELA_TOBM_SPELL_THROW_VOICE">
        <supports>Blood Mage</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You project your voice to any point you can see within range. As you cast the spell, speak up to 20 words to be thrown. You may choose to alter your voice so that it is loud and booming, gutteral and eldritch, etc. You may also choose to imitate a creature you have heard.</p>
            <p class="indent">A creature that uses its action to analyze the sound can determine that it is an illusion with a successful Investigation check against your spell save DC. If a creature discerns the illusion for what it is, the sound becomes muffled for that creature. If the spell is cast to imitate something, saving throws made by creatures familiar with the source you’re imitating are made with advantage.</p>
            <p class="flavor"><b>Source: </b>Edited from Wizard’s Spell Compendium</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Illusion</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="range">600 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent"></set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Animal Aspect" type="Spell" source="Tome of Blood Magics" id="ID_ELA_TOBM_SPELL_ANIMAL_ASPECT">
        <supports>Blood Mage</supports>
        <description>
            <p>As you cast this spell, choose a beast listed below. You alter your body by infusing it with bestial spirits. For the duration, you gain aspects of the chosen beast.</p>
            <p class="indent"> • Bear: you grow thick fur, gaining +2 to your AC.</p>
            <p class="indent"> • Cheetah: your legs lengthen and sprout spotted fur.  Your base speed increases by 10.</p>
            <p class="indent"> • Falcon: Your eyes grow larger and you grow feathers on your face. You gain advantage on perception checks. Additionally, attacking at long range does not impose disadvantage.</p>
            <p class="indent"> • Frog: your legs become elongated and muscular and mottled green. You gain advantage on Acrobatics and you can perform a long or high jump without a running start.</p>
            <p class="indent"> • Gorilla: your arms become long and strong and covered with dark hair. You gain a +1 bonus to your melee attack and damage rolls for the duration.</p>
            <p class="indent"> • Nightingale: your tongue narrows and you grow small feathers on your face and throat. You gain advantage on performance and deception checks to mimick another creature.</p>
            <p class="indent"> • Otter: your hands and feet become flat and webbed.  You gain a swim speed equal to your walking speed and can breathe underwater for the duration.</p>
            <p class="indent"> • Wolf: your face grows gray-brown fur and your mouth lengthens and fangs become more pronounced.  You gain advantage on survival checks to track other creatures, as well as perception checks that rely on smell. Additionally, your unarmed strike can be a bite attack that deals 1d6 piercing damage.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a piece of the animal in question</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Double Sight" type="Spell" source="Tome of Blood Magics" id="ID_ELA_TOBM_SPELL_DOUBLE_SIGHT">
        <supports>Blood Mage</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You touch a creature (the "recipient") and target another (the "donor"). An unwilling donor must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or become blind to their own senses for the duration. On a failed save, the recipient is able to see from the eyes of the donor and able to freely distinguish between the two eyesights. The donor may repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, or whenever it takes damage, ending the effect on a success.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Enchantment</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">concentration, up to 1 hour</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a pair of peeled grapes</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Nightscar" type="Spell" source="Tome of Blood Magics" id="ID_ELA_TOBM_SPELL_NIGHTSCAR">
        <supports>Blood Mage</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You place a magical mark on a creature which can only be seen by you and up to seven other individuals named by you when you cast the spell. It can also be seen by a creature able to see through invisibility. The mark remains on the target and visible to those who can see it no matter what efforts are made by that creature to hide the mark, including attempting to mask it with clothing, illusions, invisibility, or shapeshifting.</p>
            <p class="flavor"><b>Source: </b>Edited from Wizard’s Spell Compendium</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Illusion</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">1 week</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent"></set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Saving Grace" type="Spell" source="Tome of Blood Magics" id="ID_ELA_TOBM_SPELL_SAVING_GRACE">
        <supports>Blood Mage</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You leap to the air, flying toward a creature within range, taking their hand and shielding them. The creature gains 1d6 + your spellcasting ability modifier temporary hit points. Additionally, each other creature within 15 feet of your target must succeed on a Strength saving throw or be pushed back 15 feet.</p>
            <p class="indent">At Higher Levels: When cast using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the casting range increases by 15 feet and the creature gains 1d6 extra temporary hit points for each slot level above 3rd.</p>
            <p class="flavor"><b>Source: </b>Edited from /u/SwordMeow</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Abjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="range">30 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent"></set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Transposition" type="Spell" source="Tome of Blood Magics" id="ID_ELA_TOBM_SPELL_TRANSPOSITION">
        <supports>Blood Mage</supports>
        <description>
            <p>One creature within 60 feet that you can see and you magically switch positions. If the target is unwilling, it must succeed on a Charisma saving throw to resist the effect.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Conjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a pair of dice connected by twine</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Lifehunt Scythe" type="Spell" source="Tome of Blood Magics" id="ID_ELA_TOBM_SPELL_LIFEHUNT_SCYTHE">
        <supports>Blood Mage</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You create a spectral scythe that sweeps around you, dealing damage and healing you. All creatures within a 15 foot radius of you must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or take 2d10 necrotic and 2d10 cold damage, or half as much on a successful save. If a creature is damaged this way, you heal for half of the damage dealt to any single creature.</p>
            <p class="flavor"><b>Source: </b>Inspired by Dark Souls</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Necromancy</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="range">Self (15 foot radius)</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent"></set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Teleportation Aura" type="Spell" source="Tome of Blood Magics" id="ID_ELA_TOBM_SPELL_TELEPORTATION_AURA">
        <supports>Blood Mage</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Choose a point you can see within range. You and each creature within 10 feet of you is teleported to an unoccupied space within 10 feet of that point. Any unwilling creatures must succeed on a Charisma saving throw to resist the effect.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Conjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent"></set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Tidal Bomb" type="Spell" source="Tome of Blood Magics" id="ID_ELA_TOBM_SPELL_TIDAL_BOMB">
        <supports>Blood Mage</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You create a wave of tidal pressure that builds for a time and then explodes. Choose a 50 foot by 10 foot line, oriented as you choose centered on a point in range, or a 20 foot radius sphere. Whenever a creature enters this area for the first time or starts its turn there, it must make a Dexterity saving throw. A creature takes 2d8 cold damage on a failed save or half as much damage on a successful one. As a bonus action on any turn after the first turn you cast this spell, you may cause the area to explode in a wave of force. Each creature in the area must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or take 3d6 bludgeoning damage and 3d6 cold damage or half as much on a successful save. Then the spell ends.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Conjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="range">100 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent"></set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Bloodsworn Retribution" type="Spell" source="Tome of Blood Magics" id="ID_ELA_TOBM_SPELL_BLOODSWORN_RETRIBUTION">
        <supports>Blood Mage</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You speak an oath and shed your own blood, inflict 5, 10, or 20 points of damage to yourself and reducing your hit point total by that amount. Until the oath is completed or intentionally forsaken, you gain a bonus to all attack rolls, saving throws, and ability checks made while specifically and directly attempting to fulfill the oath (at the DM’s discretion). This bonus is equal to +1, +2, or +3 depending on the amount of hit points sacrificed. Additionally, you cannot recover the spell slot used to cast this spell until forsaking or completing the oath, at which point your hit point total is restored to normal as well.</p>
            <p class="flavor"><b>Source: </b>Edited from d20pfsrd.com</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">4</set>
            <set name="school">Necromancy</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="range">30 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a gold dagger worth at least 200gp</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Burning Blood" type="Spell" source="Tome of Blood Magics" id="ID_ELA_TOBM_SPELL_BURNING_BLOOD">
        <supports>Blood Mage</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You cause the open, bleeding wounds of a target you can see within range to burst into blood-red flame. If that creature is below it’s hit point maximum it must make a Constitution saving throw each round. The creature takes 2d6 fire damage and 1d6 necrotic damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. This spell ends after the target succeeds a saving throw three times.</p>
            <p class="indent">At Higher Levels. When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, the fire damage increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 4th.</p>
            <p class="flavor"><b>Source: </b>Edited from Wizard’s Spell Compendium</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">4</set>
            <set name="school">Necromancy</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">A drop of blood and a pinch of saltpeter</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Chilling Scythe" type="Spell" source="Tome of Blood Magics" id="ID_ELA_TOBM_SPELL_CHILLING_SCYTHE">
        <supports>Blood Mage</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You create an oversized but weightless scythe made of glowing, blue-black force. The scythe is considered to be a two-handed +1 magic weapon with which you are proficient. It deals 2d10 slashing damage + 1d8 cold damage on a hit and has the reach property.</p>
            <p class="indent">If you drop the weapon, it dissipates at the end of the turn. Thereafter, while the spell persists, you can use a bonus action to cause the sword to reappear in your hand.</p>
            <p class="flavor"><b>Source: </b>Edited from Priest's Spell Compendium</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">4</set>
            <set name="school">Necromancy</set>
            <set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
            <set name="duration">1 minute</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a gem-encrusted bone worth at least 250gp</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Blackflame Burst" type="Spell" source="Tome of Blood Magics" id="ID_ELA_TOBM_SPELL_BLACKFLAME_BURST">
        <supports>Blood Mage</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You channel a writhing mass of naturally opposed energies. For the duration, the energy grows stronger and becomes harder to contain. On any subsequent subsequent turn for the duration, you may use an action to cause the storm to disappear from your hands and reappear at a location you can see, where it bursts from the ground. Each creature in a 20-foot-radius sphere must make a Dexterity saving throw, taking 4d6 necrotic and 4d6 radiant damage on a failed save or half as much damage on a successful one. Then the spell ends. </p>
            <p class="indent">Alternatively, you may use a bonus action on each of your subsequent turns to channel more energy into the storm. Each time you do this, make a DC 13 Constitution saving throw. If you succeed, the spell is treated as though it were cast using a spell slot one level higher, up your highest level spell slot plus one. If you channel energy this way, you may not release the storm that turn.</p>
            <p class="indent">At Higher Levels. When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 6th level or higher, the radiant and necrotic damage both increase by 1d6 for each slot level above the 5th.</p>
            <p class="flavor">Inspired by /u/SwordMeow</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">5</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="range">300 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">A pinch of ash and sulfur</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Mindburn" type="Spell" source="Tome of Blood Magics" id="ID_ELA_TOBM_SPELL_MINDBURN">
        <supports>Blood Mage</supports>
        <description>
            <p>If target creature can cast spells, it must make a saving throw using its spellcasting modifier, depending on its spellcasting ability. On a failure, its highest-level spell slot is expended. For each level of that spell slot, that creature takes 1d8 psychic damage.</p>
            <p class="flavor"><b>Source: </b>Edited from Magic of Eberron</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">5</set>
            <set name="school">Enchantment</set>
            <set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a diamond worth at least 150 gp</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Rain of Blood" type="Spell" source="Tome of Blood Magics" id="ID_ELA_TOBM_SPELL_RAIN_OF_BLOOD">
        <supports>Blood Mage</supports>
        <description>
            <p>A storm of sticky, life-leeching, glowing red blood appears in a location you choose within range. The area of the storm consists of up to five 10-foot cubes, which you can arrange as you wish. Each cube must have at least once face adjacent to the face of another cube. If a creature moves into the spell’s area for the first time on a turn or starts its turn there, that creature takes 3d6 necrotic damage at the end of each of its turns for 1d4 rounds. This effect does not stack, though the creature must reroll the number of rounds and take the higher one.</p>
            <p class="flavor"><b>Source: </b>Wizard’s Spell Compendium</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">5</set>
            <set name="school">Necromancy</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="range">150 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a vial of blood</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Animate Blood" type="Spell" source="Tome of Blood Magics" id="ID_ELA_TOBM_SPELL_ANIMATE_BLOOD">
        <supports>Blood Mage</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You animate up to six drops of your own blood and turn them into inch-tall minions. Each droplet has the statistics found below. A droplet that moves more than 150 feet away from you becomes inert. You are mentally linked to each of the droplets and may issue them commands. A droplet without a command will remain inert. As an action, you may switch your perception to one of theirs in order to use their senses as your own. While doing so, you are blinded and deafened to your own surroundings. You may also use a bonus action to direct one of the droplets to attack, using your spell attack modifier. If the attack succeeds, the droplet deals 4d10 necrotic damage and then the spell ends on it.</p>
            <p class="flavor"><b>Source: </b>Wizard’s Spell Compendium</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">6</set>
            <set name="school">Necromancy</set>
            <set name="time">1 minute</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="range">150 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">up to 6 drops of your blood</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Nilspace Doorway" type="Spell" source="Tome of Blood Magics" id="ID_ELA_TOBM_SPELL_NILSPACE_DOORWAY">
        <supports>Blood Mage</supports>
        <description>
            <p>To cast this spell, you must first build a stone archway inscribed with arcane runes. The arch may be of any appearance and design of your choice. This archway does not have to be set up as part of a wall, although it can be. When you finish casting this spell, the door then permanently opens to an extradimensional space 40 feet wide × 60 feet long, with a 10 foot high ceiling. If you wish, you may alter its dimensions as long as it remains that size (the floor can take up no more than 2,400 square feet). Unless you take additional methods to hide and lock the doorway, anyone can use it and enter your space.</p>
            <p class="indent">The interior of this room is completely featureless, however you may furnish it as you wish. It will continuously provide fresh air and a temperature anywhere between 50° and 100° Fahrenheit.</p>
            <p class="indent">If you wish (and have the ability), you may add any of the following spells to the final result while preparing this spell: <em>alarm</em>, <em>continual flame</em>, <em>guards and wards</em>, <em>magic mouth</em>, <em>major image</em>, <em>minor illusion</em>, <em>silent image</em>, <em>unseen servant</em>, and other, similar spells of the DM’s discretion. Each spell increases the cost of the doorway by 100 gp + 50 gp per spell level, and increases the casting time by 1 hour, but causes those spells to be permanent. You are still bound by any limitations of those spells other than range. If an added spell is dispelled or suppressed, it will return to full strength the following day at dawn.</p>
            <p class="indent">Bringing an extradimensional item such as a <em>bag of holding</em> into this room suppresses the magical properties of the item until it exits the room.</p>
            <p class="flavor"><b>Source: </b>Edited from The Great Net Spellbook</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">6</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">5 hours</set>
            <set name="duration">Permanent</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a stone and iron doorway worth at least 2,000 gp</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Transfusion" type="Spell" source="Tome of Blood Magics" id="ID_ELA_TOBM_SPELL_TRANSFUSION">
        <supports>Blood Mage</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You attempt to siphon blood from nearby creatures. All creatures within 20 feet of you must succeed on a constitution saving throw or take 10d6 necrotic damage and you regain half that many hit points.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">6</set>
            <set name="school">Necromancy</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="range">Self (20 feet)</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent"></set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Ravenous Darkness" type="Spell" source="Tome of Blood Magics" id="ID_ELA_TOBM_SPELL_RAVENOUS_DARKNESS">
        <supports>Blood Mage</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Magical darkness spreads from a point you choose within range to fill a 50-foot-radius sphere for the duration, spreading around corners. A creature with darkvision can’t see through this darkness, and nonmagical light can’t illuminate it. Additionally, if any of this spell’s area overlaps with an area of light created by a spell of 6th level or lower, the created the light is dispelled.</p>
            <p class="indent">The area of darkness is filled with toothy, ravenous jaws that bite at anything in the area. It attacks using your spell attack modifier and may attack each creature other than you inside it once at the end of your turns; roll one attack with advantage, regardless of the number of creatures inside, and compare it to each creature’s AC individually. On hit, the target takes 3d8 slashing damage and its hit point maximum is reduced by that amount. This damage counts as magical for the purposes of calculating resistances and immunities.</p>
            <p class="indent">A creature other than you must make a dexterity saving throw, taking 6d6 (magical) slashing damage or half as much on a successful save, whenever it enters the area for the first time or ends its turn there, and its hit point maximum is reduced by that amount. If the creature’s hit point total is reduced to 0, the creature is eaten and disappears, dropping all magical items it was carrying. This reduction to a creature’s hit point maximum lasts until the creature finishes a long rest or until it is affected by a spell like <em>greater restoration</em>.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels</em></strong>: When you cast this spell with an 8th-level or higher spell slot, the attack damage increases by 1d8 per slot level above 7th.</p>
            <p class="flavor"><b>Source: </b>d20pfsrd.com</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">7</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="range">100 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a dozen teeth of various animals</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Omniscience" type="Spell" source="Tome of Blood Magics" id="ID_ELA_TOBM_SPELL_OMNISCIENCE">
        <supports>Blood Mage</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You channel divine knowledge directly into your mind. For the duration, you gain Truesight out to a range of 120 feet. Additionally, when you cast this spell roll ten d20s and record the results. For the duration, you may replace any ability check, attack roll, or saving throw a creature within range would roll with any number recorded. You must choose to do so before the roll, and each number may only be used once. Additionally, for the duration, whenever you would roll an Intelligence check, you may replace your die roll with a 20. Finally, you gain expertise in every tool and gain the ability to flawlessly speak and understand all languages.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">8</set>
            <set name="school">Divination</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">1 minute</set>
            <set name="range">120 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">golden tarot deck worth at least 1,000 gp, which this spell consumes</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Omnipresence" type="Spell" source="Tome of Blood Magics" id="ID_ELA_TOBM_SPELL_OMNIPRESENCE">
        <supports>Blood Mage</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Choose up to four creatures within 30 feet of you. Upon casting this spell, you permanently gain knowledge of the precise location of those creatures’ bodies, even if you are on separate planes of existance or if they’re hidden by a spell such Nondetection. This effect cannot be dispelled or detected by a spell of 8th level or lower.</p>
            <p class="indent">As an action, you may expend an 8th-level spell slot and another golden pin to teleport yourself to an unoccupied space within 30 feet of one of the marked creatures.</p>
            <p class="indent">If you cast this spell and mark new creatures, the old enchantments fade.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">8</set>
            <set name="school">Divination</set>
            <set name="time">1 hour</set>
            <set name="duration">Permanent</set>
            <set name="range">30 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">Up to four golden pins worth 1,000 gp each, which this spell consumes</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Conjure Colossus" type="Spell" source="Tome of Blood Magics" id="ID_ELA_TOBM_SPELL_CONJURE_COLOSSUS">
        <supports>Blood Mage</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The head, torso, and arms of a truly enormous, humanoid construct rises from the ground. It is easily 50 feet tall, lacks facial features, and is made of the same substance as the terrain it is summoned in.</p>
            <p class="indent">The creature is under your command. It rolls its own initiative. On each of your turns, you can use a bonus action to mentally command the creature if its within 1,000 feet of you. You decide what action the creature will take or you can issue a general command, such as to guard a particular chamber or corridor. If you issue no commands, the creature only defends itself against hostile creatures. Once given an order, the creature continues to follow it until its task is complete.</p>
            <p class="indent">You may use an action to cause the Colossus to retreat into the ground and emerge in another unoccupied space you can see within 1,000 feet.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">9</set>
            <set name="school">Conjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 10 minutes</set>
            <set name="range">300 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a diamond worth at least 500 gp, which the spell consumes, and a ball of clay</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Endure" type="Spell" source="Tome of Blood Magics" id="ID_ELA_TOBM_SPELL_ENDURE">
        <supports>Blood Mage</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You choose a spell that is affecting a creature you can touch, freezing it in time. Until you lose your concentration, that spell has a duration of 1 hour. If you maintain concentration for the full hour, the duration becomes 1 year, as an arcane tattoo inscribing the spell appears on the creature’s body. The tattoo fades if dispelled by a Dispel Magic spell of 9th-level or higher, or if the spell ends on the target in another way (for example, if a creature affected by Invisibility attacks, the spell ends and the tattoo fades).</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">9</set>
            <set name="school">Abjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 hour</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">A set of arcane inks worth 2,500 gp, which the spell consumes, and a platinum needle worth 5,000 gp</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Fury" type="Spell" source="Tome of Blood Magics" id="ID_ELA_TOBM_SPELL_FURY">
        <supports>Blood Mage</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Speaking a few ancient words to manipulate the fabric of universe, you unleash a pure, elemental force of destruction. You create a 15-foot sphere of hateful energy around you for up to 1 minute. All nonmagical structures and objects that aren’t being worn or carried that enter the sphere are instantly incinerated. </p>
            <p class="indent">Whenever a creature other than you enters the spell’s area for the first time on a turn or ends it’s turn there it must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, it takes 1d6 of all 13 damage types (Bludgeoning, Piercing, Slashing, Acid, Fire, Cold, Poison, Necrotic, Radiant, Lightning, Psychic, Thunder and Force), or half as much on a successful one.</p>
            <p class="indent">The ground beneath your feet becomes lifeless and acrid. Any water or plants that grow in that area for the next year becomes toxic. Any creature that drinks the affected water or eats any vegetation from  the area must make a Constitution saving  throw or become poisoned for 24 hours. Likewise, any creature that sleeps in an affected area must make a Constitution saving throw or become poisoned for 24 hours.</p>
            <p class="indent">After one year, the toxic effects begin to fade, disappearing completely over the next week.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">9</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="range">Self (15-foot sphere)</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent"></set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Illusionary Army" type="Spell" source="Tome of Blood Magics" id="ID_ELA_TOBM_SPELL_ILLUSIONARY_ARMY">
        <supports>Blood Mage</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You split your soul to create 10 semi-real illusionary duplicates that appear utterly indistinguishable from you. Your "prime body" disappears at the same time. The duplicates appear in unoccupied spaces you can see within 30 feet of you. Each illusion has your statistics, but will disappear upon taking damage. You have the senses of all illusions simultaneously and can easily differentiate between them. Each illusion moves on the same turn but collectively can  take only one action, one bonus action, and one reaction per round, as well as sharing your current spell slots. When there is only one illusion remaining, your real body replaces that remaining illusion and this spell ends. If the spell ends and there are two or more illusions remaining, you choose which one you replace.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">9</set>
            <set name="school">Illusion</set>
            <set name="time">1 minute</set>
            <set name="duration">6 hours</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a sapphire worth at least 1,000 gp, which the spell consumes</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Infuse Intellect" type="Spell" source="Tome of Blood Magics" id="ID_ELA_TOBM_SPELL_INFUSE_INTELLECT">
        <supports>Blood Mage</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You diffuse arcane power into your bloodstream, where it finds its way to your brain, increasing your thought capacity greatly for the duration and giving yourself the following properties:</p>
            <p class="indent">• Your Intelligence and Wisdom scores become 26 and you gain advantage on these saving throws and ability checks.</p>
            <p class="indent">None</p>
            <p class="indent">• Spells with a casting time of 1 action can be cast as a bonus action.</p>
            <p class="indent">None</p>
            <p class="indent">None</p>
            <p class="indent">When the spell ends, you must make a constitution saving throw. On a success, your movement speed is halved until you take a long rest and you must choose to take either an action or bonus action on each of your turns, but not both. On a failure, you fall unconscious for 1d4 hours or until damaged, and you recieve the above effects as though you succeeded on the save upon waking.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">9</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 10 minutes</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a sapphire worth at least 1,000 gp, which the spell consumes</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Omnipotence" type="Spell" source="Tome of Blood Magics" id="ID_ELA_TOBM_SPELL_OMNIPOTENCE">
        <supports>Blood Mage</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You temporarily ascend to near-godhood. For the duration, whenever you cast a spell using a spell slot 5th level or lower, it’s cast as though it used a 5th-level spell slot. When you cast a spell of 6th level or higher, it’s cast as though it used a 8th-level spell slot. These spells count as though they were cast with their lowest-level spell slot for the purposes of class abilities.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">9</set>
            <set name="school">Divination</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">1 minute</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent"></set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Steal Soul" type="Spell" source="Tome of Blood Magics" id="ID_ELA_TOBM_SPELL_STEAL_SOUL">
        <supports>Blood Mage</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You reach into a creature near death and steal their soul. If a creature has lost at least 100 hit points, they must make a charisma saving throw. On a failure, you pull out their soul and can enact one of the following effects:</p>
            <p class="indent">• Rend. You rip apart the creature's soul, destroying it and it's material body completely. The creature may not be returned to life by any means short of divine intervention or a Wish spell.</p>
            <p class="indent">• Seal. You seal the creature's soul in the diamond used to cast this spell. Each diamond may only be used to hold one soul, releasing the first creature trapped should another attempt to be sealed. A creature is trapped until the diamond is shattered. The diamond has an AC of 15 (natural armor) and 10 hit points. Light can pass through the gem normally (allowing the target to see out and other creatures to see in), but nothing else can pass through, even by means of teleportation or planar travel. While the soul is trapped, the body disappears, dropping everything it's wearing or carrying, but is recreated upon the soul's release.</p>
            <p class="indent">• Consume. You infuse yourself or another creature you can touch with the soul, restoring 10d4+10 hit points to that creature instantly and damaging the target by the same amount.</p>
            <p class="indent">• Twist. You twist the soul, and restore it to the creature. The creature falls unconscious for 1 round. Upon awakening it must succeed on a Charisma saving throw or it's alignment and morals change until the diamond used to cast this spell is shattered. The diamond has an AC of 15 (natural armor) and 10 hit points. For example, if the creature was lawful evil, it becomes chaotic good. If it was chaotic neutral, it becomes lawful neutral. If you try to cast this spell on a creature with a true neutral alignment, the diamond shatters and the spell fails.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">9</set>
            <set name="school">Necromancy</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Special</set>
            <set name="range">Touch</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a diamond, worth at least 2,500 gp</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Turn to Lightning" type="Spell" source="Tome of Blood Magics" id="ID_ELA_TOBM_SPELL_TURN_TO_LIGHTNING">
        <supports>Blood Mage</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You transform yourself into a bolt of lightning, enhancing your abilities for up to a minute and gaining the following properties:</p>
            <p class="indent">• Your dexterity score becomes 30 and you gain advantage on dexterity saving throws and ability checks.</p>
            <p class="indent">• Your speed becomes 0. Instead of moving normally, up to two times each turn, choose a point you can see within 60 feet to travel to near- instantaneously. If you would pass through a creature on your way to that point, it must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, it takes 8d10 lightning damage and can’t use reactions until your next turn, or half as much damage on a successful one. Creatures made of metal or wearing metal armor have disadvantage on this saving throw. A creature can only be damaged this way once each turn.</p>
            <p class="indent">• Your melee attacks deal an additional 2d10 lightning damage and are rolled with advantage.</p>
            <p class="indent">• You have immunity to lightning damage and the paralyzed condition.</p>
            <p class="indent">• You gain an additional action on each of your turns. That action can be used only to take the Attack (one weapon attack only), Dash, Disengage, Hide, or Use an Object action. </p>
            <p class="indent">When the spell ends, you must make a constitution saving throw. On a success, your movement speed is halved until you take a long rest and you must choose to take either an action or bonus action on each of your turns, but not both. On a failure, you fall unconscious for 1 hour or until damaged, and upon awakening you suffer the effects as though you succeeded on the save.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">9</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a crystal rod, worth at least 5,000 gp</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
</elements>