<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Psionics Divine Domain</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="cleric-psionics-domain.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/subclasses/cleric/cleric-psionics-domain.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Psionics Domain" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_BUNNYGEONMASTER_GM_BINDER_SOURCE_Psionics Domain">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation">CPD</set>
            <set name="url">https://www.gmbinder.com/share/-LUJ3u0sR02STNxS8PQF</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" abbreviation="BGM" url="https://www.reddit.com/u/BunnygeonMaster">u/BunnygeonMaster</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20200401</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Psionics Domain" type="Archetype" source="Psionics Domain" id="ID_BGM_CPD_ARCHETYPE_CLERIC_PSIONICS_DOMAIN">
        <supports>Divine Domain</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Psychic talents are uncommon in most worlds, but gods such as Sardior, Zuoken, and Ilsensine still manifest the powers of the Psionics Domain to diligent followers, invoking the innate magics of an unfettered intellect. The psionic gods have diverse focuses in their doctrine - some preach domination of the minds of others, while others uphold the nobility of striving to attain mental perfection - but all teach their clerics to incorporate psychic talent with their divine magic as dual spellcasters and psions.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">Psionic Domain Spells</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Cleric Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1st</td><td><em>cause fear, dissonant whispers</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>detect thoughts, phantasmal force</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>hypnotic pattern, sending</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>7th</td><td><em>confusion, dimension door</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>9th</td><td><em>synaptic static, Rary’s telepathic bond</em></td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_BGM_CPD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PSIONICS_PSYCHIC_FOCUS" />
            <div element="ID_BGM_CPD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PSIONICS_CD_ESCHEW_COMPONENTS" />
            <div element="ID_BGM_CPD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PSIONICS_CD_MIND_BLAST" />
            <div element="ID_BGM_CPD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PSIONICS_POTENT_SPELLCASTING" />
            <div element="ID_BGM_CPD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PSIONICS_BRAINSTEALER" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_CAUSE_FEAR" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="1" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISSONANT_WHISPERS" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="1" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_THOUGHTS" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="3" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PHANTASMAL_FORCE" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="3" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HYPNOTIC_PATTERN" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="5" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SENDING" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="5" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONFUSION" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="7" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DIMENSION_DOOR" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="7" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_SYNAPTIC_STATIC" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="9" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RARYS_TELEPATHIC_BOND" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" level="9" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_BGM_CPD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PSIONICS_PSYCHIC_FOCUS" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_BGM_CPD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PSIONICS_CD_ESCHEW_COMPONENTS" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_BGM_CPD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PSIONICS_CD_MIND_BLAST" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_BGM_CPD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PSIONICS_POTENT_SPELLCASTING" level="8" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_BGM_CPD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PSIONICS_BRAINSTEALER" level="17" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Psychic Focus" type="Archetype Feature" source="Psionics Domain" id="ID_BGM_CPD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PSIONICS_PSYCHIC_FOCUS">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning when you choose this domain at 1st level, you are able to maintain an elevated state of mind, activating benefits of your choice. Choose one of the following psychic focuses to maintain. The effect of the focus lasts until you finish a long rest, at which point you choose to either maintain the same focus or change to a different one.</p>
                <p class="indent">While you maintain a psychic focus, you gain the ability to cast an associated psionic cantrip*. This cantrip counts as a cleric cantrip for you, and it does not count against the number of cleric cantrips you know. These psionic cantrips are detailed at the end of this compendium.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Mentalist.</em></strong> You gain resistance to psychic damage and can cast the <em>mind meld</em> cantrip.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Glamour.</em></strong> You can cast <em>disguise self</em> without expending a spell slot and regain the ability to do so when you finish a short or long rest. Also, you can cast the <em>delusion</em> cantrip.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Hypnotist.</em></strong> You gain proficiency in your choice of either the Deception or Persuasion skills, and you can cast the <em>mystic charm</em> cantrip.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Kineticist.</em></strong> When you score a critical hit with a cleric spell attack, you can roll one of the spell’s damage dice one additional time and add it to the extra damage of the critical hit. You can cast the <em>energy beam</em> cantrip.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Transcendence.</em></strong> You don’t need to eat, breathe, or sleep. To gain the benefits of a long rest, you can spend 8 hours engaged in light activity, rather than sleeping during any of it. You can cast the <em>mystic grasp</em> cantrip.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Choose one of the following psychic focuses to maintain: Mentalist, Glamour, Hypnotist, Kineticist, or Transcendance. The effect of the focus lasts until you finish a long rest, at which point you choose to either maintain the same focus or change to a different one.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_KAMINEIGH_MMMOM_SPELL_MIND_MELD" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISGUISE_SELF" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_KAMINEIGH_MMMOM_SPELL_DELUSION" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_KAMINEIGH_MMMOM_SPELL_MYSTIC_CHARM" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_KAMINEIGH_MMMOM_SPELL_ENERGY_BEAM" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_KAMINEIGH_MMMOM_SPELL_MYSTIC_GRASP" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Channel Divinity: Eschew Components" type="Archetype Feature" source="Psionics Domain" id="ID_BGM_CPD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PSIONICS_CD_ESCHEW_COMPONENTS">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 2nd level, you can invoke your alien god to cast a spell using only the power of your mind. When you cast a cleric spell, you can use your Channel Divinity to cast it without any verbal, somatic, or material components that do not have a listed cost.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Channel Divinity" alt="Eschew Components">
                <description>When you cast a cleric spell, you can use your Channel Divinity to cast it without any verbal, somatic, or material components that do not have a listed cost.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Channel Divinity: Mind Blast" type="Archetype Feature" source="Psionics Domain" id="ID_BGM_CPD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PSIONICS_CD_MIND_BLAST">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 6th level, you can unleash a blast of psychic power using your Channel Divinity. As an action, choose one creature within 30 feet of you. That creature must make an Intelligence saving throw. On a failed save it takes 3d6 psychic damage and is stunned until the end of its next turn. On a successful save a creature takes half as much damage and is not stunned.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Channel Divinity" alt="Mind Blast" action="Action">
                <description>Choose one creature within 30 feet of you. That creature must make an Intelligence saving throw. On a failed save it takes 3d6 psychic damage and is stunned until the end of its next turn. On a successful save a creature takes half as much damage and is not stunned.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Potent Spellcasting" type="Archetype Feature" source="Psionics Domain" id="ID_BGM_CPD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PSIONICS_POTENT_SPELLCASTING">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 8th level, you add your Wisdom modifier to the damage you deal with any cleric cantrip.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You add {{wisdom:modifier}} to the damage you deal with any cleric cantrip.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Brainstealer" type="Archetype Feature" source="Psionics Domain" id="ID_BGM_CPD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PSIONICS_BRAINSTEALER">
            <description>
                <p>At 17th level, you learn the <em>feeblemind</em> spell, which counts as a Domain spell for you. Also, when a creature is stunned by your Mind Blast, it repeats the saving throw at the end of each of its turns. On a success, it is no longer stunned. On a failure, it remains stunned.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, when a creature is stunned by your Mind Blast feature, and you are within 5 feet of it and can touch it, you can use an action to attempt to annihilate its mind. If the creature has 100 hit points or fewer, it is immediately killed as you rend its intellect. If the creature has more than 100 hit points, it takes 10d10 psychic damage.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you attempt to annihilate a creature’s mind using this feature, you can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>When a creature is stunned by your Mind Blast, it repeats the saving throw at the end of each of its turns. On a success, it is no longer stunned. On a failure, it remains stunned. If you are within 5 feet of a stunned creature and can touch it, you can use an action to attempt to annihilate its mind. If the creature has 100 hit points or fewer, it is immediately killed as you rend its intellect. If the creature has more than 100 hit points, it takes 10d10 psychic damage.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FEEBLEMIND" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" />
            </rules>
        </element>
    
</elements>