<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Titan Class</name>
        <update version="0.0.2">
            <file name="class-titan.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/rain-junkie/class-titan.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Titan Class" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_RAINJUNKIE_GMBINDER_SOURCE_Titan Class">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation">TITAN</set>
            <set name="url">https://www.gmbinder.com/share/-LsgkLDLt4gE22QyAhPX</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" abbreviation="RJ" url="https://www.gmbinder.com/profile/rain-junkie">Rain-Junkie</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20200904</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Titan" type="Class" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_CLASS_TITAN">
        <description>
            <p>The tiefling’s dark plate armour clanks as she strides across the battlefield, her eyes forward and her glaive out, snow drifting around her. She cleaves through orc after orc, their lifeless corpses falling to the side, allowing her passage. With each step she takes, a burst of ice pulses through the ground, seeping into the nearby corpses. An orc chief in front of her lets out a battlecry and begins to charge forward. Smirking, she throws her hand out, and the corpses of the orcs shamble back to life under her command, rising to do battle for their new master.</p>
            <p class="indent">The human looks up from the field he’s tending, seeing his younger sister smiling as she plants some carrots, burying them in the soft soil. Beyond her, however, he sees a wolf begin to lunge, and with all of his being, he reaches out and bends the earth around her, using magic he had never known he’d had.</p>
            <p class="indent">Crushing the wyrmling’s skull beneath his boot, the dwarf turns to look over at the snarling red dragon. Rolling his shoulders and cracking his knuckles, the dwarf breaks out into a sprint towards the fiery beast as his allies continue to fight back the hoard of wyrmlings. Lightning begins to trail after him, and as he brings his fist forward, slamming the weight of his thunderous energy into the dragon, a loud crash fills the cavern, and lighting sparks off in all directions.</p>
            <p class="indent">Bringing his shield up to deflect another blow, the kobold spits out blood and lets out a vicious snarl. The goblins laugh an jeer as they gang up on the lone kobold, and dig into his armour with their shortswords and daggers. Letting out an anguished cry, the kobold’s eyes flash with a vibrant orange energy, and the goblins laughs quickly turn to cries of pain as they are consumed in a raging inferno of brilliant sunlight.</p>
            <p class="indent">All of these warriors are titans, people who are willing to die to protect those that can’t protect themselves. Imbued with powerful defensive magic, and branded with a powerful emblem, they dare to tread in the darkest of places, armed with the knowledge that they have already spat in the face of impossible odds.</p>
            <h4>A DEFINING MOMENT</h4>
            <p>Every titan is born of a defining moment, one where their convictions are truly tested. When someone commits themselves to protecting something, to the point that they’re willing to die for it, a magic is sparked inside of them that bursts forth like a explosion, allowing them to harness powerful abjuration magic that they can use to shield and protect others.</p>
            <p class="indent">For some titans, their defining moments involve self sacrifice, giving their lives in defence of their charges. Oftentimes, these titans are later reborn into their bodies, powerful entities that govern or observe such selfless deeds deeming them worthy enough to champion their cause in a new life. This second chance allows titans to think upon who they were in their past life, and forces them to consider their choices up unto the point of their sacrifice.</p>
            <h4>CHANNELED POWER</h4>
            <p>A titan can receive their magic from nearly any source. The most common are titans that received their magic from a god or patron, and either called out to them as they made their sacrifice, or were devouts during their life, and were especially chosen. These titans often adopt the Sunkeeper Code, since the brilliant light is reflective of their own desire to see good spread throughout the multiverse.</p>
            <p class="indent">Other titans are simply chosen by mere fate, and are just as likely to adopt one code over another. These titan’s are unsure of the origin of their powers, but are accepting and quick to learn, excited to put their new magic to the test.</p>
            <p class="indent">A titan’s magic is as flexible as it is strong, and it’s not uncommon for a titan to have their magic shift and change as they grow. Titans who begin their journey as Stormstrikers might shift to a Frostwarden, or those who take up the name of a Sunkeeper adjust their focus and instead embrace the enduring nature of Stonehearts.</p>
            <p class="indent">No matter how a titan receieved their magic, they are only able to wield it because of their strong protective spirit. Making the sacrifice that is required to become a titan is no easy feat, and not all who do so become titans. Some speculate their is an otherworldy force that hand picks titans from birth, and guides them into their defining moment. Others speculate that it’s simply chance, and that to be a titan, you must simply have a unique, powerful desire to protect those in need.</p>
            <h4>EMBLEMS AND CRESTS</h4>
            <p>To a titan, an emblem is more than a symbol or icon. It’s a visualisation of their very soul, an aspect of their personality and force of spirit that they use to identify themselves. When a titan is born of sacrifice, their crest is etched into their soul, marking them for all of time.</p>
            <p class="indent">When two titans with the same emblem meet, a bond is forged that is stronger than any other. These titans that bond under the same emblem are a whirlwind of destruction on the battlefield, and none can hope to break their near perfect defence.</p>
            <p class="indent">Unlike emblems, crests are personal touches that titans adopt to add to their emblem. Reflective of their codes, a crest isn’t as meaningful to a titan as their emblem, but is no less powerful. When adopting a crest, a titan will often mix its imagery with that of their emblem, creating something new and unique. A titan with the eagle emblem and the fire crest might fight with the fury of a phoenix, while one with the ram emblem and blizzard crest might fight with the power of an avalanche.</p>
            <h4>CREATING A TITAN</h4>
            <p>Because of your defining moment, powerful defensive magic is now yours to command. Titan’s bolster this magic with martial knowledge so be sure to consider how your titan character came to learn martial combat; perhaps they trained in a military academy before they where a solider, or took up learning it after their defining moment to further enhance their prowess on the battlefield.</p>
            <p class="indent">Furthermore, be sure to consider the right emblem for your titan. A titan’s emblem is meant to reflect a titan’s most core personality, so feel free to replace any animal associated with an emblem with another animal that you feel better reflects your character. The animals presented in the feature are merely suggestions, and you can easily replace the Elk emblem with something like a jaguar, the Ram emblem with a crocodile, or even the Lion emblem with a dragon. Work with your DM to come up with the best representation of your character.</p>
            <h5>QUICK BUILD</h5>
            <p class="indent">You can make a titan quickly by following these suggestions. First, put your highest ability score in Constitution, followed by Strength. Second, choose the folk hero or soldier background. Third, choose either the Elk, Lion, or Wolf emblem.</p>
            <h2>CLASS FEATURES</h2>
            <p>As an titan, you gain the following class features.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">HIT POINTS</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Hit Dice:</strong> 1d12 per titan level</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at 1st Level:</strong> 12 + your Constitution modifier</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at Higher Levels:</strong> 1d12 (or 7) + your Constitution modifier per titan level after 1st</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">PROFICIENCIES</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled mb">
                <li><strong>Armor:</strong> All armour, shields</li>
                <li><strong>Weapons:</strong> Simple weapons, martial weapons</li>
                <li><strong>Tools:</strong> None</li>
            </ul>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Saving Throws:</strong> Strength, Constitution</li>
                <li><strong>Skills:</strong> Choose two from Athletics, History, Insight, Intimidation, Perception, and Survival</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">EQUIPMENT</h5>
            <p>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>(a) one martial weapon and a shield or (c) two martial weapons</li>
                <li>(a) chain mail, (b) scale mail or (c) leather armour</li>
                <li>(a) a light crossbow and 20 bolts or (b) five javelins</li>
                <li>(a) a dungeoneer’s pack or (b) an explorer’s pack</li>
            </ul>
            <p class="indent">Alternatively, you may start with 5d4 × 10 gp to buy your own equipment.</p>
            <h5>MULTICLASSING</h5>
            <p class="indent"><b>Prerequisites.</b> To qualify for multiclassing into the titan class, you must meet these prerequisites: Strength and Constitution 13.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b>Proficiencies.</b> When you multiclass into the titan class, you gain the following proficiencies: Light armour, medium armour, shields, and simple weapons.</p>
        <!-- class table here -->
            <h5 class="caption">THE TITAN</h5>
            <table class="class-features">
                <thead>
                    <tr><td class="col-5">Level</td><td class="col-10">Proficiency Bonus</td><td class="col-60 left">Features</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td> 1st</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Valiant Defender, Titan’s Emblem</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 2nd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Defensive Bulwark, Fighting Style</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 3rd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Titan Code</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 4th</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 5th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Extra Attack</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 6th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Elemental Defender, Rapid Defence</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 7th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Titan Code feature</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 8th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 9th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Forceful Blockade (1d6)</td></tr>
                <tr><td>10th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Expansive Defence</td></tr>
                <tr><td>11th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Titan Code feature</td></tr>
                <tr><td>12th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Forceful Blockade (2d6)</td></tr>
                <tr><td>14th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Unyielding Body</td></tr>
                <tr><td>15th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Titan Code feature</td></tr>
                <tr><td>16th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td></tr>
                <tr><td>17th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Forceful Blockade (3d6)</td></tr>
                <tr><td>18th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Titan Code feature</td></tr>
                <tr><td>19th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td></tr>
                <tr><td>20th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Last Stand</td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_RJ_TITAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TITAN_VALIANT_DEFENDER" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_TITAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TITAN_TITANS_EMBLEM" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_TITAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TITAN_DEFENSIVE_BULWARK" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_TITAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TITAN_FIGHTING_STYLE" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_TITAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TITAN_TITAN_CODE" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_TITAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TITAN_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_TITAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TITAN_EXTRA_ATTACK" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_TITAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TITAN_ELEMENTAL_DEFENDER" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_TITAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TITAN_RAPID_DEFENCE" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_TITAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TITAN_FORCEFUL_BLOCKADE" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_TITAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TITAN_EXPANSIVE_DEFENCE" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_TITAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TITAN_UNYIELDING_BODY" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_TITAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TITAN_LAST_STAND" />
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="hd">d12</set>
            <set name="short">A warrior that protects those that can’t protect themselves.</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_MEDIUM_ARMOR" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_HEAVY_ARMOR" requirements="!ID_RJ_TITAN_MULTICLASS_TITAN" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_SHIELDS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_MARTIAL_WEAPONS" requirements="!ID_RJ_TITAN_MULTICLASS_TITAN" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_STRENGTH" requirements="!ID_RJ_TITAN_MULTICLASS_TITAN" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CONSTITUTION" requirements="!ID_RJ_TITAN_MULTICLASS_TITAN" />
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency, Titan" supports="Skill,Titan" number="2" requirements="!ID_RJ_TITAN_MULTICLASS_TITAN" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TITAN_VALIANT_DEFENDER" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TITAN_TITANS_EMBLEM" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TITAN_DEFENSIVE_BULWARK" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TITAN_FIGHTING_STYLE" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TITAN_TITAN_CODE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TITAN_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" level="4" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TITAN_EXTRA_ATTACK" level="5" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TITAN_ELEMENTAL_DEFENDER" level="6" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TITAN_RAPID_DEFENCE" level="6" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TITAN_FORCEFUL_BLOCKADE" level="9" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TITAN_EXPANSIVE_DEFENCE" level="10" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TITAN_UNYIELDING_BODY" level="14" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TITAN_LAST_STAND" level="20" />
        </rules>
        <multiclass id="ID_RJ_TITAN_MULTICLASS_TITAN">
            <prerequisite>Strength and Constitution 13</prerequisite>
            <requirements>[str:13],[con:13]</requirements>
            <setters>
                <set name="multiclass proficiencies">When you multiclass into the titan class, you gain the following proficiencies: Light armour, medium armour, shields, and simple weapons.</set>
            </setters>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS" />
            </rules>
        </multiclass>
    </element>
        <element name="Valiant Defender" type="Class Feature" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TITAN_VALIANT_DEFENDER">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 1st level, you’re able to safeguard your allies with your magic. As a reaction when a creature within 5 feet of you takes bludgeoning, piercing or slashing damage from a source you can see, you can reach out towards them and take that damage instead of that creature taking it. The feature doesn’t transfer any other effects that might accompany the damage, and any damage you take this way is first reduced by an amount equal to 1d6 + half your titan level (rounded up). This damage can’t be further reduced by any other effects or resistances.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Reaction">
                <description>When a creature within 5 feet of you takes bludgeoning, piercing or slashing damage from a source you can see, you can reach out towards them and take that damage instead of that creature taking it. The feature doesn’t transfer any other effects that might accompany the damage, and any damage you take this way is first reduced by 1d6 + {{level:titan}}.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Titan’s Emblem" type="Class Feature" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TITAN_TITANS_EMBLEM">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 1st level, you can bear an emblem that reflects the most core aspect of your personality. This emblem grants you additional boons, which you wear on your person, either in the form of a tabbard, a cloak, or a shield design. Once you choose a titan’s emblem, you can’t choose another one.</p>
                <p class="indent">While you wear this emblem, you gain the benefits associated with it.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Eagle.</b> The eagle reflects splendor. Whenever you make a Charisma check, you can add a d4 to the result.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Elk.</b> The elk embodies agility. Your walking speed increases by 5 feet.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Hawk.</b> The hawk depicts perception. Whenever you make a Wisdom check, you can add a d4 to the result.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Lion.</b> The lion represents honor. You have advantage on saving throws against being frightened.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Ram.</b> The ram reflects resilience. When you roll initiative, you gain 2d4 temporary hit points.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Snake.</b> The snake depicts cunning. Whenever you make an Intelligence check, you can add a d4 to the result.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Wolf.</b> The wolf embodies vigilance. When you roll initiative, you can roll a d4 and add it to the result.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>While you wear this emblem, you gain the benefits associated with it.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Titan’s Emblem" supports="Titans Emblem" level="1" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Eagle" type="Class Feature" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TITANS_EMBLEM_EAGLE">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <supports>Titans Emblem</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>The eagle reflects splendor. Whenever you make a Charisma check, you can add a d4 to the result.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Titan’s Emblem">
                    <description>Whenever you make a Charisma check, you can add a d4 to the result.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Elk" type="Class Feature" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TITANS_EMBLEM_ELK">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <supports>Titans Emblem</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>The elk embodies agility. Your walking speed increases by 5 feet.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Titan’s Emblem">
                    <description>Your walking speed increases by 5 feet.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Hawk" type="Class Feature" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TITANS_EMBLEM_HAWK">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <supports>Titans Emblem</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>The hawk depicts perception. Whenever you make a Wisdom check, you can add a d4 to the result.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Titan’s Emblem">
                    <description>Whenever you make a Wisdom check, you can add a d4 to the result.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Lion" type="Class Feature" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TITANS_EMBLEM_LION">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <supports>Titans Emblem</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>The lion represents honor. You have advantage on saving throws against being frightened.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Titan’s Emblem">
                    <description>You have advantage on saving throws against being frightened.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Ram" type="Class Feature" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TITANS_EMBLEM_RAM">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <supports>Titans Emblem</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>The ram reflects resilience. When you roll initiative, you gain 2d4 temporary hit points.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Titan’s Emblem">
                    <description>When you roll initiative, you gain 2d4 temporary hit points.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Snake" type="Class Feature" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TITANS_EMBLEM_SNAKE">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <supports>Titans Emblem</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>The snake depicts cunning. Whenever you make an Intelligence check, you can add a d4 to the result.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Titan’s Emblem">
                    <description>Whenever you make an Intelligence check, you can add a d4 to the result.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Wolf" type="Class Feature" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TITANS_EMBLEM_WOLF">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <supports>Titans Emblem</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>The wolf embodies vigilance. When you roll initiative, you can roll a d4 and add it to the result.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Titan’s Emblem">
                    <description>When you roll initiative, you can roll a d4 and add it to the result.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
        <element name="Defensive Bulwark" type="Class Feature" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TITAN_DEFENSIVE_BULWARK">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 2nd level, you can create a defensive bulwark that allows you to better protect your allies from harm. As an action on your turn, you can create a bulwark that is a 10-foot radius sphere centered on you (but doesn’t move with you) that lasts for 1 minute, and appears as a transparent bubble of shimmering energy. As an action on your turn, you can move the bulwark to re-center on you. The bulwark has the following benefits:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>You don’t need to be within 5 feet of a creature to use your Valiant Defender feature, as long as you and the creature are both inside your bulwark.</li>
                    <li>Hostile creatures treat the inside of the bulwark as difficult terrain, and attack rolls they make while outside the bulwark can’t have advantage if their target is inside the bulwark.</li>
                    <li>When a creature is reduced to 0 hit points while inside your bulwark, you can have them drop to 1 hit point instead. That creature also gains temporary hit points equal to 1d12 + your titan level. Once you return a creature to 1 hit point this way, your bulwark ends.</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t do so again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description action="Action" usage="1/Short Rest">You can create a bulwark that is a {{defensive-bulwark:radius}}-foot radius sphere centered on you (but doesn’t move with you) that lasts for 1 minute. As an action on your turn, you can move the bulwark to re-center on you. The bulwark has the following benefits: You don’t need to be within 5 feet of a creature to use your Valiant Defender feature, as long as you and the creature are both inside your bulwark. Hostile creatures treat the inside of the bulwark as difficult terrain, and attack rolls they make while outside the bulwark can’t have advantage if their target is inside the bulwark. When a creature is reduced to 0 hit points while inside your bulwark, you can have them drop to 1 hit point instead. That creature also gains 1d12 + {{level:titan}} temporary hit points. Once you return a creature to 1 hit point this way, your bulwark ends.</description>
                <description level="6" action="Bonus Action" usage="2/Short Rest">You can create a bulwark that is a {{defensive-bulwark:radius}}-foot radius sphere centered on you (but doesn’t move with you) that lasts for 1 minute. As an action on your turn, you can move the bulwark to re-center on you. The bulwark has the following benefits: You don’t need to be within 5 feet of a creature to use your Valiant Defender feature, as long as you and the creature are both inside your bulwark. Hostile creatures treat the inside of the bulwark as difficult terrain, and attack rolls they make while outside the bulwark can’t have advantage if their target is inside the bulwark. When a creature is reduced to 0 hit points while inside your bulwark, you can have them drop to 1 hit point instead. That creature also gains 1d12 + {{level:titan}} temporary hit points. Once you return a creature to 1 hit point this way, your bulwark ends.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="defensive-bulwark:radius" value="10" level="2" />
                <stat name="defensive-bulwark:radius" value="5" level="10" />
                <stat name="defensive-bulwark:radius" value="5" level="20" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Fighting Style" type="Class Feature" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TITAN_FIGHTING_STYLE">
            <description>
                <p>At 2nd level, you adopt a particular style of fighting as your specialty. Choose one of the following options. You can’t take the same Fighting Style option more than once, even if you get to choose again.</p>
                <h5>DEFENSE</h5>
                <p>While you’re wearing armor, you gain a +1 bonus to AC.</p>
                <h5>DUELLING</h5>
                <p>When you are wielding a melee weapon in one hand and no other weapons, you gain a +2 bonus to damage rolls with that weapon.</p>
                <h5>GREAT WEAPON FIGHTING</h5>
                <p>When you roll a 1 or 2 on a damage die for an attack you make with a melee weapon that you are wielding with two hands, you can reroll the die and must use the new roll. The weapon must have the two-handed or versatile property for you to gain this benefit.</p>
                <h5>TWO-WEAPON FIGHTING</h5>
                <p>When you engage in two-weapon fighting, you can add your ability modifier to the damage of the second attack.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Fighting Style, Titan" supports="Fighting Style, Titan" level="2" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Titan Code" type="Class Feature" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TITAN_TITAN_CODE">
            <description>
                <p>Different titans choose different codes, depending on their beliefs, personal fighting style, or aesthetics. The code a titan adopts isn’t as important to them as their emblem is, and a few titan’s have been known to change their code during their life, as their approach to battle and safeguarding their allies shifts.</p>
                <p class="indent">When you reach 3rd level, you take up a code that defines you as a titan. You can choose either Frostwarden, Stoneheart, Stormstriker or Sunkeeper; these codes are detailed at the end of the class description.</p>
                <p class="indent">Your choice grants you features at 3rd level and again at 7th, 11th, 15th, and 18th level. Those features include the code crests.</p>
                <h5>CODE CRESTS</h5>
                <p>Each code also has two crests, and you choose one when you gain this feature. You display your code crest in a similar fashion to your titan’s emblem. You can change your code crest whenever you gain a level in this class.</p>
                <h5>SAVING THROWS</h5>
                <p>Some of your subclass features require your target to make a saving throw to resist the feature’s effects. The saving throw DC is calculated as follows:</p>
                <p style="text-align: center;"><b>Titan Save DC</b> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Constitution modifier</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Archetype" name="Titan’s Code" supports="Titan Code" level="3" />
                <stat name="titan:save-dc" value="8" />
                <stat name="titan:save-dc" value="proficiency" />
                <stat name="titan:save-dc" value="constitution:modifier" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Ability Score Improvement" type="Class Feature" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TITAN_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Titan 4)" supports="Improvement Option,Titan,4" level="4" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Titan 8)" supports="Improvement Option,Titan,8" level="8" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Titan 12)" supports="Improvement Option,Titan,12" level="12" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Titan 16)" supports="Improvement Option,Titan,16" level="16" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Titan 19)" supports="Improvement Option,Titan,19" level="19" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Extra Attack" type="Class Feature" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TITAN_EXTRA_ATTACK">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 5th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="extra attack:count" value="2" level="5" bonus="extra attack" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Elemental Defender" type="Class Feature" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TITAN_ELEMENTAL_DEFENDER">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, you can shield your allies from the dangers of the elements. You can choose one of of the following damage types from this list: acid, cold, fire, lightning, and thunder. You can use your Valiant Defender to reduce the damage a creature takes when the damage it takes is one of your chosen damage types, in addition to bludgeoning, piercing, or slashing damage.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can choose one more damage type at 10th level, and another one at 14th level.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Elemental Defender" supports="Titan Elemental Defender" level="6" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Elemental Defender" supports="Titan Elemental Defender" level="10" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Elemental Defender" supports="Titan Elemental Defender" level="14" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Acid" type="Class Feature" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TITAN_ELEMENTAL_DEFENDER_ACID">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <supports>Titan Elemental Defender</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>You can use Valiant Defender to reduce acid damage.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>You can use Valiant Defender to reduce acid damage.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Cold" type="Class Feature" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TITAN_ELEMENTAL_DEFENDER_COLD">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <supports>Titan Elemental Defender</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>You can use Valiant Defender to reduce cold damage.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>You can use Valiant Defender to reduce cold damage.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Fire" type="Class Feature" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TITAN_ELEMENTAL_DEFENDER_FIRE">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <supports>Titan Elemental Defender</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>You can use Valiant Defender to reduce fire damage.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>You can use Valiant Defender to reduce fire damage.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Lightning" type="Class Feature" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TITAN_ELEMENTAL_DEFENDER_LIGHTNING">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <supports>Titan Elemental Defender</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>You can use Valiant Defender to reduce lightning damage.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>You can use Valiant Defender to reduce lightning damage.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Thunder" type="Class Feature" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TITAN_ELEMENTAL_DEFENDER_THUNDER">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <supports>Titan Elemental Defender</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>You can use Valiant Defender to reduce thunder damage.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>You can use Valiant Defender to reduce thunder damage.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
        <element name="Rapid Defence" type="Class Feature" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TITAN_RAPID_DEFENCE">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 6th level, you’re easily able to ready yourself for battle. You can use Defensive Bulwark twice before a rest, but you can only have one bulwark created at a time; if you create a second bulwark, the first one immediately vanishes.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, you can create a bulwark as a bonus action on your turn, rather than an action.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Forceful Blockade" type="Class Feature" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TITAN_FORCEFUL_BLOCKADE">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 9th level, you’re able to rebuke those who would dare harm your allies. When you use your Valiant Defender feature, you deal 1d6 force damage to the creature that attempted to damage your ally.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, when you reduce the damage dealt to 0 with your Valiant Defender feature, you use the highest number possible for each damage die. For example, instead of dealing 1d6 force damage, you instead deal 6.</p>
                <p class="indent">This force damage increases to 2d6 at 13th level and 3d6 at 17th level.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you use your Valiant Defender feature, you deal {{forceful-blockade:damage-dice}}d6 force damage to the creature that attempted to damage your ally. Additionally, when you reduce the damage dealt to 0 with your Valiant Defender feature, you use the highest number possible for each damage die.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="forceful-blockade:damage-dice" value="1" level="9" />
                <stat name="forceful-blockade:damage-dice" value="1" level="13" />
                <stat name="forceful-blockade:damage-dice" value="1" level="17" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Expansive Defence" type="Class Feature" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TITAN_EXPANSIVE_DEFENCE">
            <description>
                <p>At 10th level, your bulwark expands, allowing you to better protect those you care for. The radius of your bulwark increase by 5 feet, and by an additional 5 feet at 20th level.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Unyielding Body" type="Class Feature" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TITAN_UNYIELDING_BODY">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 14th level, your body can’t be broken. Your Strength score, Dexterity score, Constitution score, and your hit point maximum can’t be reduced.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, you have advantage on ability checks and saving throws to avoid being knocked prone, grappled, restrained, or otherwise moved against your will.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Your Strength score, Dexterity score, Constitution score, and your hit point maximum can’t be reduced. Additionally, you have advantage on ability checks and saving throws to avoid being knocked prone, grappled, restrained, or otherwise moved against your will.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Last Stand" type="Class Feature" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_CLASS_FEATURE_TITAN_LAST_STAND">
            <description>
                <p>At 20th level, you know that you can only stop fighting once your allies are safe. When you are reduced to 0 hit points, you can draw on your protective magic to allow you to return to battle. You regain all your hit points, and recover any expended uses of your class or subclass features. Any negative conditions that you’re under end, and if you’re prone, you stand up.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t do so again until 7 days have passed.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you are reduced to 0 hit points, you can draw on your protective magic to allow you to return to battle. You regain all your hit points, and recover any expended uses of your class or subclass features. Any negative conditions that you’re under end, and if you’re prone, you stand up. Once you use this feature, you can’t do so again until 7 days have passed.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

  <!-- Titan Codes -->
    <element name="Code of the Frostwarden" type="Archetype" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_CODE_OF_THE_FROSTWARDEN">
        <supports>Titan Code</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Frostwarden’s are as hard as ice, unmoving on the battlefield. No matter how the battle shifts and flows, a Frostwarden stands tall against it, knowing that if they don’t, no one will. They reach to darker magics to bolster their defensive capabilities, using necromancy and undead to further their cause. Other titans see Frostwardens as dark, and some believe they are something far from the noble name of titan. Frostwardens, however, know that any sacrifice is worth protecting those you love.</p>
            <div element="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FROSTWARDEN_CODE_CRESTS" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FROSTWARDEN_GLACIAL_SHROUD" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FROSTWARDEN_RISE_TO_BATTLE" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FROSTWARDEN_GRASP_OF_ICE" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FROSTWARDEN_DEATH_DEFIANT" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FROSTWARDEN_LEGION_OF_THE_FROSTWARDEN" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FROSTWARDEN_CODE_CRESTS" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FROSTWARDEN_GLACIAL_SHROUD" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FROSTWARDEN_RISE_TO_BATTLE" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FROSTWARDEN_GRASP_OF_ICE" level="11" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FROSTWARDEN_DEATH_DEFIANT" level="15" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FROSTWARDEN_LEGION_OF_THE_FROSTWARDEN" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Code Crests" type="Archetype Feature" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FROSTWARDEN_CODE_CRESTS">
            <description>
                <p>You gain access to the following additional crests:</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Blizzard.</b> The blizzard represents hardiness. Once per turn, you can give yourself advantage on a melee weapon attack you make against a creature who’s movement speed has been reduced or is 0.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Skull.</b> The skull represents death. While you’re below half your hit points maximum, you gain a number of temporary hit points equal to your Constitution modifier at the start of each of your turns.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Code Crest" allowReplace="true" supports="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FROSTWARDEN_CREST_BLIZZARD|ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FROSTWARDEN_CREST_SKULL" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Blizzard" type="Archetype Feature" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FROSTWARDEN_CREST_BLIZZARD">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>The blizzard represents hardiness. Once per turn, you can give yourself advantage on a melee weapon attack you make against a creature who’s movement speed has been reduced or is 0.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Code Crest">
                    <description>Once per turn, you can give yourself advantage on a melee weapon attack you make against a creature who’s movement speed has been reduced or is 0.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Skull" type="Archetype Feature" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FROSTWARDEN_CREST_SKULL">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>The skull represents death. While you’re below half your hit points maximum, you gain a number of temporary hit points equal to your Constitution modifier at the start of each of your turns.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Code Crest">
                    <description>While you’re below half your hit points maximum, you gain {{constitution:modifier}} temporary hit points at the start of each of your turns.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
        <element name="Glacial Shroud" type="Archetype Feature" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FROSTWARDEN_GLACIAL_SHROUD">
            <description>
                <p>Starting when you choose this code at 3rd level, dark ice twists inside your bulwark, shielding your allies from harm by covering them in frost. Your bulwark gains the following benefits:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>When an allied creature other than you starts its turn inside your bulwark, it gains 1d4 temporary hit points, which last until the start of its next turn. These temporary hit points increase to 1d6 at 5th level, 1d8 at 10th level, 1d10 at 15th level, and 1d12 at 20th level.</li>
                    <li>Allied creatures inside your bulwark have advantage on death saving throws.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Defensive Bulwark">
                <description>Your bulwark gains the following benefits: When an allied creature other than you starts its turn inside your bulwark, it gains 1d{{glacial-shroud:die-type}} temporary hit points, which last until the start of its next turn. Allied creatures inside your bulwark have advantage on death saving throws.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="glacial-shroud:die-type" value="4" bonus="base" level="3" />
                <stat name="glacial-shroud:die-type" value="6" bonus="base" level="5" />
                <stat name="glacial-shroud:die-type" value="8" bonus="base" level="10" />
                <stat name="glacial-shroud:die-type" value="10" bonus="base" level="15" />
                <stat name="glacial-shroud:die-type" value="12" bonus="base" level="20" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Rise to Battle" type="Archetype Feature" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FROSTWARDEN_RISE_TO_BATTLE">
            <description>
                <p>At 7th level, you gain the ability to imbue a corpse with your frost magic, bending it to your will. You can target a beast or humanoid corpse of a Small or larger creature that has been dead for no longer than a minute, using your bonus action to reanimate it, causing it to stand up immediately. The creature uses the skeleton stat block in the Monster Manual, except it has a number of hit points equal to your Constitution modifier + your titan level. It remains animated for 10 minutes, after which time it collapses and dies.</p>
                <p class="indent">In combat, the skeleton’s turn comes immediately after yours. It obeys your mental commands, and the only action it can take is the Attack action, making one attack. While in inside your bulwark, it gains a bonus to its AC and attack rolls equal to your Constitution modifier.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can use this feature once, and regain your use of it when you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="1/Short Rest">
                <description>You can target a beast or humanoid corpse of a Small or larger creature that has been dead for no longer than a minute, reanimating it, causing it to stand up immediately. The creature uses the skeleton stat block in the Monster Manual, except it has {{rise-to-battle:hp}} hit points</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="rise-to-battle:hp" value="constitution:modifier" />
                <stat name="rise-to-battle:hp" value="level:titan" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Grasp of Ice" type="Archetype Feature" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FROSTWARDEN_GRASP_OF_ICE">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 11th level, you can cause the frozen dead to reach up towards you foes. The first time you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack on your turn, it takes an additional 1d12 cold damage. Additionally, if it’s on the ground, frozen, skeletal hands burst forth and grab it in its space. It’s speed is reduced by 10 feet until the start of your next turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>The first time you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack on your turn, it takes an additional 1d12 cold damage. Additionally, if it’s on the ground, frozen, skeletal hands burst forth and grab it in its space. It’s speed is reduced by 10 feet until the start of your next turn.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Death Defiant" type="Archetype Feature" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FROSTWARDEN_DEATH_DEFIANT">
            <description>
                <p>At 15th level, you can place a protective blessing on a dying creature, in an attempt to help guide it back to the land of the living. As a bonus action, you can target a dying creature within 30 feet of you and bless it, which lasts until the creature becomes stable, regains hit points, or dies. You can’t target a stable creature with this ability. For the duration of the blessing, the creature is immune to all damage and gains a bonus to its death saving throws. This bonus is a d4.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You can target a dying creature within 30 feet of you and bless it, which lasts until the creature becomes stable, regains hit points, or dies. You can’t target a stable creature with this ability. For the duration of the blessing, the creature is immune to all damage and gains a 1d4 bonus to its death saving throws.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Legion of the Frostwarden" type="Archetype Feature" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FROSTWARDEN_LEGION_OF_THE_FROSTWARDEN">
            <description>
                <p>At 18th level, you can have the air around drop to a biting cold as spectral undead hover around you. As an action on your turn, you can undergo this transformation, which lasts for 1 minute or until you’re reduced to 0 hit points. While transformed, you gain the following benefits:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>You gain immunity to cold and necrotic damage.</li>
                    <li>You can command any skeleton under your control within 60 feet of you to move up to its speed and make a single weapon attack as a bonus action on your turn.</li>
                    <li>The first time you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack on your turn, spectral undead also strike out at the target. The creature takes an additional 1d12 cold damage and 1d12 necrotic damage.</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You can summon a spectral legion, which lasts for 1 minute or until you’re reduced to 0 hit points. You gain immunity to cold and necrotic damage. You can command any skeleton under your control within 60 feet of you to move up to its speed and make a single weapon attack as a bonus action on your turn. The first time you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack on your turn, spectral undead also strike out at the target. The creature takes an additional 1d12 cold damage and 1d12 necrotic damage.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    <element name="Code of the Stoneheart" type="Archetype" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_CODE_OF_THE_STONEHEART">
        <supports>Titan Code</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The Stoneheart are enduring and everlasting, and know that they must weather the storm so that they can resist what comes after it. Other titans believe that the Stonehearts aren’t adaptive, and are too focused on the future, but the Stoneheart know that looking forward doesn’t blind them to the present, but instead allows them to better protect the ones they love.</p>
            <div element="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STONEHEART_CODE_CRESTS" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STONEHEART_SHIFTING_EARTH" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STONEHEART_WOVEN_STONE" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STONEHEART_ROCKSLIDE" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STONEHEART_SLATE_SKIN" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STONEHEART_MARCH_OF_THE_STONEHEART" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STONEHEART_CODE_CRESTS" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STONEHEART_SHIFTING_EARTH" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STONEHEART_WOVEN_STONE" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STONEHEART_ROCKSLIDE" level="11" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STONEHEART_SLATE_SKIN" level="15" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STONEHEART_MARCH_OF_THE_STONEHEART" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Code Crests" type="Archetype Feature" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STONEHEART_CODE_CRESTS">
            <description>
                <p>You gain access to the following additional crests:</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Fissure.</b> The fissure represents power. The first time you hit a creature with a weapon attack on your turn, you can push them 5 feet in a direction of your choice.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Mountain.</b> The mountain represents strength. When you successfully shove a creature on your turn, that creature takes 1d6 bludgeoning damage.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Code Crest" allowReplace="true" supports="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STONEHEART_CREST_FISSURE|ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STONEHEART_CREST_MOUNTAIN" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Fissure" type="Archetype Feature" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STONEHEART_CREST_FISSURE">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>The fissure represents power. The first time you hit a creature with a weapon attack on your turn, you can push them 5 feet in a direction of your choice.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Code Crest">
                    <description>The first time you hit a creature with a weapon attack on your turn, you can push them 5 feet in a direction of your choice.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Mountain" type="Archetype Feature" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STONEHEART_CREST_MOUNTAIN">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>The mountain represents strength. When you successfully shove a creature on your turn, that creature takes 1d6 bludgeoning damage.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Code Crest">
                    <description>When you successfully shove a creature on your turn, that creature takes 1d6 bludgeoning damage.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
        <element name="Shifting Earth" type="Archetype Feature" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STONEHEART_SHIFTING_EARTH">
            <description>
                <p>Starting when you choose this code at 3rd level, the inside of your bulwark rumbles, beckoning the earth around you to heed your call. Your bulwark gains the following benefits:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>When a hostile creature starts its turn inside your bulwark, you can force them to make a Strength saving throw. On a failed save, you can push them up to 5 feet in a horizontal direction of your choice.</li>
                    <li>You can carve out natural stone and rock when you place your bulwark, causing walls, terrain, and objects to vanish. If your bulwark partially enters a wall, terrain, or an object, it carves out the section of it inside your bulwark. This doesn’t effect any terrain that is underneath you when you create the bulwark, and creates no instability in a structure surrounding it. When the terrain returns, any creatures or objects still in the opening created by the bulwark are safely ejected to the nearest unoccupied space.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Defensive Bulark">
                <description>Your bulwark gains the following benefits: When a hostile creature starts its turn inside your bulwark, you can force them to make a Strength saving throw (DC {{titan:save-dc}}). On a failed save, you can push them up to 5 feet in a horizontal direction of your choice. If your bulwark partially enters a wall, terrain, or an object, it carves out the section of it inside your bulwark.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Woven Stone" type="Archetype Feature" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STONEHEART_WOVEN_STONE">
            <description>
                <p>At 7th level, you’re able to tug at the earth, weaving it to your will. As an action on your turn, you can choose to either pull or push a wave of earth towards or away from you in a line 15-feet wide and 60 feet long, forcing each creature in the line to make a Strength saving throw.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Pull.</b> Creatures are pulled 20 feet directly towards you on a failed save, and only pulled half as far on a success.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Push.</b> Creatures are pushed 20 feet directly away from you on a failed save, and only pushed half as far on a success. A creature can’t be pushed beyond the end of the line.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can use this feature once, and regain your use of it when you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Short Rest">
                <description>You can choose to either pull or push a wave of earth towards or away from you in a line 15-feet wide and 60 feet long, forcing each creature in the line to make a Strength saving throw (DC {{titan:save-dc}}).</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Rockslide" type="Archetype Feature" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STONEHEART_ROCKSLIDE">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 11th level, your strikes reverberate with the power of the mountains, allowing you to topple the mightest of foes. The first time you hit a creature with a weapon attack on your turn, you deal an additional 1d8 bludgeoning damage. Additionally, the next attack roll that creature makes before the start of your next turn has disadvantage.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>The first time you hit a creature with a weapon attack on your turn, you deal an additional 1d8 bludgeoning damage. Additionally, the next attack roll that creature makes before the start of your next turn has disadvantage.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Slate Skin" type="Archetype Feature" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STONEHEART_SLATE_SKIN">
            <description>
                <p>At 15th level, your skin becomes as hard as rock, and allows you to resist the attacks of distant foes who can’t pierce it. When a non-magical ranged attack that targets you deals damage equal to or less than your Constitution modifier + half your titan level, it instead deals no damage.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When a non-magical ranged attack that targets you deals damage equal to or less {{slate-skin:damage}}, it instead deals no damage.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="slate-skin:damage" value="constitution:modifier" />
                <stat name="slate-skin:damage" value="level:titan:half" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="March of the Stoneheart" type="Archetype Feature" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STONEHEART_MARCH_OF_THE_STONEHEART">
            <description>
                <p>At 18th level, you’re able to have your body becomes as hard as slate and stone, and cause your soul to becomes as rugged and enduring as a mountain. As an action on your turn, you can undergo this transformation, which lasts for 1 minute or until you’re reduced to 0 hit points. While transformed, you gain the following benefits:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>You gain resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage.</li>
                    <li>At the start of each of your turns, you gain temporary hit points equal to half your titan level.</li>
                    <li>When you hit a creature with an attack, it must make a Strength saving throw or be knocked prone. If you hit a prone creature with an attack, it’s movement speed is halved the end of your next turn.</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You transform into a stone titan,which lasts for 1 minute or until you’re reduced to 0 hit points. You gain resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage. At the start of each of your turns, you gain {{level:titan:half}} temporary hit points. When you hit a creature with an attack, it must make a Strength saving throw (DC {{titan:save-dc}}) or be knocked prone. If you hit a prone creature with an attack, it’s movement speed is halved the end of your next turn.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    <element name="Code of the Stormstriker" type="Archetype" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_CODE_OF_THE_STORMSTRIKER">
        <supports>Titan Code</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Stormstrikers hit first and ask questions later. Living by the phrase "flow like lightning, strike like thunder", they use their quick reflexes to weave through combat. Other titans often see stormstrikers as too brash or aggressive, but stormstrikers know that when push comes to shove, someone has to punch first.</p>
            <div element="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STORMSTRIKER_CODE_CRESTS" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STORMSTRIKER_ROLLING_THUNDER" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STORMSTRIKER_CRASHING_LIGHTNING" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STORMSTRIKER_STORM_TRANCE" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STORMSTRIKER_LEAPING_LIGHTNING" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STORMSTRIKER_FEROCITY_OF_THE_STORMSTRIKER" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STORMSTRIKER_CODE_CRESTS" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STORMSTRIKER_ROLLING_THUNDER" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STORMSTRIKER_CRASHING_LIGHTNING" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STORMSTRIKER_STORM_TRANCE" level="11" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STORMSTRIKER_LEAPING_LIGHTNING" level="15" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STORMSTRIKER_FEROCITY_OF_THE_STORMSTRIKER" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Code Crests" type="Archetype Feature" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STORMSTRIKER_CODE_CRESTS">
            <description>
                <p>You gain access to the following additional crests:</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Lightning.</b> The lightning represents flow. When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can move up to 10 feet without provoking attacks of opportunity before or after you make your first attack as part of that action.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Thunder.</b> The thunder represents power. You can have your unarmed strikes deal 1d4 bludgeoning damage and 1d4 thunder damage. Once per turn when you hit a creature with an unarmed strike, you can daze it. The creature can’t take reactions until the start of its next turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Code Crest" allowReplace="true" supports="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STORMSTRIKER_CREST_LIGHTNING|ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STORMSTRIKER_CREST_THUNDER" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Lightning" type="Archetype Feature" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STORMSTRIKER_CREST_LIGHTNING">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>The lightning represents flow. When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can move up to 10 feet without provoking attacks of opportunity before or after you make your first attack as part of that action.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Code Crest">
                    <description>When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can move up to 10 feet without provoking attacks of opportunity before or after you make your first attack as part of that action.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Thunder" type="Archetype Feature" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STORMSTRIKER_CREST_THUNDER">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>The thunder represents power. You can have your unarmed strikes deal 1d4 bludgeoning damage and 1d4 thunder damage. Once per turn when you hit a creature with an unarmed strike, you can daze it. The creature can’t take reactions until the start of its next turn.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Code Crest">
                    <description>You can have your unarmed strikes deal 1d4 bludgeoning damage and 1d4 thunder damage. Once per turn when you hit a creature with an unarmed strike, you can daze it. The creature can’t take reactions until the start of its next turn.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
        <element name="Rolling Thunder" type="Archetype Feature" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STORMSTRIKER_ROLLING_THUNDER">
            <description>
                <p>Starting when you choose this code at 3rd level, your bulwark shifts around the battlefield as you do, allowing you to strike foe after foe. Your bulwark gains the following benefits:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>When you damage a creature on your turn while you’re inside the bulwark, you can use your bonus action to re-center your bulwark immediately after.</li>
                    <li>Hostile creatures inside your bulwark can’t benefit from advantage or any magical bonus to any Strength or Dexterity checks they make, as static electricity hinders their bodies.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Defensive Bulark">
                <description>Your bulwark gains the following benefits: When you damage a creature on your turn while you’re inside the bulwark, you can use your bonus action to re-center your bulwark immediately after. Hostile creatures inside your bulwark can’t benefit from advantage or any magical bonus to any Strength or Dexterity checks they make, as static electricity hinders their bodies.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Crashing Lightning" type="Archetype Feature" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STORMSTRIKER_CRASHING_LIGHTNING">
            <description>
                <p>At 7th level, you’re able to build up momentum, allowing you to deal devastating blows to your enemies. When you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can have that creature take an additional 3d4 lightning damage and must make a Strength saving throw or be knocked prone.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can use this feature once, and regain your use of it when you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
                <description>When you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can have that creature take an additional 3d4 lightning damage and must make a Strength saving throw (DC {{titan:save-dc}}) or be knocked prone.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Storm Trance" type="Archetype Feature" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STORMSTRIKER_STORM_TRANCE">
            <description>
                <p>At 11th level, you’re able blast your foes with lightning, even when your attack would normally miss. The first time you miss a creature you can see with a melee weapon attack on your turn, you can can have lightning arc towards them, causing them to take lightning damage equal to 1d4 + your Constitution modifier.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>The first time you miss a creature you can see with a melee weapon attack on your turn, you can can have lightning arc towards them, causing them to take 1d4 + {{constitution:modifier}} lightning damage.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Leaping Lightning" type="Archetype Feature" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STORMSTRIKER_LEAPING_LIGHTNING">
            <description>
                <p>At 15th level, bursts of storm energy allow you to leap into the air. When you take the Dash action on your turn, you gain a flying speed equal to your walking speed, which lasts until the end of the turn. You fall if you end your turn in the air and nothing else is holding you aloft.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you take the Dash action on your turn, you gain a {{speed}}-foot flying speed, which lasts until the end of the turn. You fall if you end your turn in the air and nothing else is holding you aloft.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Ferocity of the Stormstriker" type="Archetype Feature" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STORMSTRIKER_FEROCITY_OF_THE_STORMSTRIKER">
            <description>
                <p>At 18th level, you’re able to have lightning surge through your body, leaping to nearby foes. As an action on your turn, you can undergo this transformation, which lasts for 1 minute or until you’re reduced to 0 hit points. While transformed, you gain the following benefits:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>You gain immunity to lightning and thunder damage.</li>
                    <li>Your walking speed increases by 10 feet.</li>
                    <li>When you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack on your turn, creatures of your choice within 20 feet of the target take 1d4 lightning damage and 1d4 thunder damage.</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t do so again until you finish a long rest</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You can create a surge of lightning in your body, which lasts for 1 minute or until you’re reduced to 0 hit points. You gain immunity to lightning and thunder damage. Your walking speed increases by 10 feet. When you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack on your turn, creatures of your choice within 20 feet of the target take 1d4 lightning damage and 1d4 thunder damage.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    <element name="Code of the Sunkeeper" type="Archetype" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_CODE_OF_THE_SUNKEEPER">
        <supports>Titan Code</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Sunkeepers channel powerful solar magic to smite their foes. To Sunkeepers, good and evil is as clear and light and dark, and those who fall on the wrong side are quick to feel their wrath. Even though other titans believe Sunkeepers are too narrow in their ideas, no one can deny their prowess in battle.</p>
            <div element="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUNKEEPER_CODE_CRESTS" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUNKEEPER_BLAZING_BULWARK" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUNKEEPER_CHAINS_OF_CONQUEST" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUNKEEPER_RADIANT_FLASH" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUNKEEPER_SEARING_WILL" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUNKEEPER_WINGS_OF_THE_SUNKEEPER" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUNKEEPER_CODE_CRESTS" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUNKEEPER_BLAZING_BULWARK" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUNKEEPER_CHAINS_OF_CONQUEST" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUNKEEPER_RADIANT_FLASH" level="11" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUNKEEPER_SEARING_WILL" level="15" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUNKEEPER_WINGS_OF_THE_SUNKEEPER" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Code Crests" type="Archetype Feature" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUNKEEPER_CODE_CRESTS">
            <description>
                <p>You gain access to the following additional crests:</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Flame.</b> The flame represents destruction. Once per turn when you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack, you deal an additional 1d6 fire damage.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Sun.</b> The sun represents purity. You can take the Help action as a bonus action on your turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Code Crest" allowReplace="true" supports="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUNKEEPER_CREST_FLAME|ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUNKEEPER_CREST_SUN" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Flame" type="Archetype Feature" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUNKEEPER_CREST_FLAME">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>The flame represents destruction. Once per turn when you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack, you deal an additional 1d6 fire damage.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Code Crest">
                    <description>Once per turn when you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack, you deal an additional 1d6 fire damage.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Sun" type="Archetype Feature" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUNKEEPER_CREST_SUN">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>The sun represents purity. You can take the Help action as a bonus action on your turn.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Code Crest">
                    <description>You can take the Help action as a bonus action on your turn.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
        <element name="Blazing Bulwark" type="Archetype Feature" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUNKEEPER_BLAZING_BULWARK">
            <description>
                <p>Starting when you choose this code at 3rd level, the inside of your bulwark turns into a furnace to burn the strongest of foes. Your bulwark gains the following benefits:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>When a hostile creature enters your bulwark for the first time or starts its turn there, it takes 1d6 fire damage.</li>
                    <li>The area inside the bulwark is bright light, and can’t be dispelled by magical darkness. Hostile creatures can’t benefit from invisibility while inside your bulwark.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Defensive Bulark">
                <description>When a hostile creature enters your bulwark for the first time or starts its turn there, it takes 1d6 fire damage. The area inside the bulwark is bright light, and can’t be dispelled by magical darkness. Hostile creatures can’t benefit from invisibility while inside your bulwark.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Chains of Conquest" type="Archetype Feature" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUNKEEPER_CHAINS_OF_CONQUEST">
            <description>
                <p>At 7th level, you’re able to strike down a foe with hot-iron chains. As an action on your turn, you can choose a creature you can see within 60 feet of you. That creature must make a Strength saving throw as chains burst forth from the ground and ensare it. On a failed save, a creature takes 2d6 fire damage and 2d6 radiant damage and is restrained until the end of your next turn. If the creature is flying, it is pulled to the ground on a failed save (but doesn’t suffer any fall damage). On a successful save, a creature takes half as much damage and isn’t restrained.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can use this feature once, and regain your use of it when you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Short Rest">
                <description>You can choose a creature you can see within 60 feet of you. That creature must make a Strength saving throw (DC {{titan:save-dc}}) as chains burst forth from the ground and ensare it. On a failed save, a creature takes 2d6 fire damage and 2d6 radiant damage and is restrained until the end of your next turn. If the creature is flying, it is pulled to the ground on a failed save (but doesn’t suffer any fall damage). On a successful save, a creature takes half as much damage and isn’t restrained.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Radiant Flash" type="Archetype Feature" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUNKEEPER_RADIANT_FLASH">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 11th level, your magic shines with a brilliant light that sears your foes. The first time you hit a creature on your turn with a melee weapon attack, it glows with radiant light until the end of your turn. Attacks you make against a creature that glows with this light have advantage, and deal an additional 1d6 radiant damage.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>The first time you hit a creature on your turn with a melee weapon attack, it glows with radiant light until the end of your turn. Attacks you make against a creature that glows with this light have advantage, and deal an additional 1d6 radiant damage.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Searing Will" type="Archetype Feature" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUNKEEPER_SEARING_WILL">
            <description>
                <p>At 15th level, your drive to enforce your will is unmatched. You are immune to being charmed, and when you fail an Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma saving throw against a spell or magical effect, you can turn that failure into a success.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You are immune to being charmed, and when you fail an Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma saving throw against a spell or magical effect, you can turn that failure into a success.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Wings of the Sunkeeper" type="Archetype Feature" source="Titan Class" id="ID_RJ_TITAN_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUNKEEPER_WINGS_OF_THE_SUNKEEPER">
            <description>
                <p>At 18th level, you’re able to have radiant wings of pure sunlight shoot out from your back, and can conjure a blade of pure fire. As an action on your turn, you can undergo this transformation, which lasts for 1 minute or until you’re reduced to 0 hit points. While transformed, you gain the following benefits:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>You gain immunity to fire and radiant damage.</li>
                    <li>You gain a flying speed of 30 feet.</li>
                    <li>As an action on your turn, you can shoot a blast of sunfire from your flaming blade at a point you can see within 60 feet of you. Creatures of your choice within 10 feet of that point must make a Dexterity saving throw or take 2d6 fire damage and 2d6 radiant damage. On a successful save, a creature takes half as much damage.</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You manifest wings of pure sunlight for 1 minute or until you’re reduced to 0 hit points. You gain immunity to fire and radiant damage. You gain a flying speed of 30 feet. As an action on your turn, you can shoot a blast of sunfire from your flaming blade at a point you can see within 60 feet of you. Creatures of your choice within 10 feet of that point must make a Dexterity saving throw (DC {{titan:save-dc}}) or take 2d6 fire damage and 2d6 radiant damage. On a successful save, a creature takes half as much damage.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

  <!-- Titan Skills -->
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ATHLETICS">
        <supports>Titan</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_HISTORY">
        <supports>Titan</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT">
        <supports>Titan</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INTIMIDATION">
        <supports>Titan</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION">
        <supports>Titan</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SURVIVAL">
        <supports>Titan</supports>
    </append>

  <!-- Fighting Styles -->
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_DEFENSE">
        <supports>Titan</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_DUELING">
        <supports>Titan</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_GREAT_WEAPON_FIGHTING">
        <supports>Titan</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_TWOWEAPON_FIGHTING">
        <supports>Titan</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_MARINER">
        <supports>Titan</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_DEVIKYN_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTING_STYLE_DUAL_WIELDING">
        <supports>Titan</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_DEVIKYN_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTING_STYLE_PUGILISM">
        <supports>Titan</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_DEVIKYN_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTING_STYLE_SWITCH_FIGHTING">
        <supports>Titan</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_THEARENAGUY_RDDTUA_CLASS_FEATURE_SHIELD_BASHING">
        <supports>Titan</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_DD_RCRF_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTING_STYLE_DUALWIELDING">
        <supports>Titan</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_DD_RCRF_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTING_STYLE_GREAT_WEAPONS">
        <supports>Titan</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_DD_RCRF_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTING_STYLE_LIGHT_WEAPONS">
        <supports>Titan</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_UA20191104_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTING_STYLE_BLIND_FIGHTING">
        <supports>Titan</supports>
    </append>
</elements>