<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Exemplar v1</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="class-exemplar.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/rain-junkie/class-exemplar.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_RAINJUNKIE_GMBINDER_SOURCE_EXEMPLAR">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation">TEC</set>
            <set name="url">https://www.gmbinder.com/share/-MI8JifNZzzqC56i1sa8</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" abbreviation="RJ" url="https://www.gmbinder.com/profile/rain-junkie">Rain-Junkie</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20201227</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Exemplar" type="Class" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_EXEMPLAR">
        <description>
            <p>Raising his maul, the dwarf brings it crashing down onto the shambling skeleton before him. As the bones rattle onto the ground, the dwarf feels his shadow armor hum as more undead close in. The dwarf motions with his hands and unleashes a freezing wind into the undead horde, the ice and sleet stopping them in their tracks as onlooking soldiers shout and cheer.</p>
            <p class="indent">Knocking an arrow to their bow, a drow fires an arrow at a troglodyte lurking in the shadows before them. As the arrow hits, lightning erupts from the impact toward another troglodyte nearby. As the troglodytes screech in pain, the drow chuckles while ethereal wings sprout from their back that lift them soaring into the air.</p>
            <p class="indent">A human stares in awe at a massive statue of an ancient hero before kneeling in its presence, having journeyed far to see it in person. As she kneels, the human begin to feel a surge of magical power course through her body, the magic resembling that once wielded by the hero whose statue stands before her.</p>
            <p class="indent">These heroes are exemplars — individuals who aspire to be as mighty as the heroes of myth and legend. They channel the magical strength of aspects that represent different powers of the universe, wielding such powers as they draw closer to becoming legends themselves.</p>
            <h4>LEGEND IN THE MAKING</h4>
            <p>Exemplars strive to become legends in their own right, revering heroes, paragons, and ancient icons who came before them. Many who become exemplars begin with a humble origin, simply longing to one day be a hero. Others are descended from legendary figures and wish to carry on their legacy. Regardless of their origin, the drive to become something greater than themselves is at the heart of every exemplar.</p>
            <p class="indent">In their path to become a legend themselves, exemplars train in martial techniques, often focusing on specific weapons that grant them incredible skill in wielding them. They also draw upon aspects that represent different powers in the multiverse. These aspects can originate from divine, elemental, or otherworldly sources, and an exemplar can wield strands of their aspect’s power in ways that grant them special abilities, boons, and magical prowess.</p>
            <h4>HEROES OF THE WORLD</h4>
            <p>Driven by their desire to be like the legends of old, the life of an exemplar is one of adventure. An exemplar lives for ways to prove their worth and to be remembered for ages to come. Many seek out evil forces or mythical monsters to vanquish. Some seek to perform feats of strength or undertake ancient journeys that are dangerous to most mortals. Others still seek to embody the qualities of their most revered heroes, instilling upon themselves a code of honor that an exemplar will live to uphold till their final breath.</p>
            <p class="indent">Adventuring exemplars seek worthy challenges. The rumor of an ancient evil’s return, otherworldly forces tearing into the mortal realms, and braving a gauntlet none have ever returned from are but examples of the challenges that can entice an exemplar and call them to action. Exemplars long to be remembered and seek praise, respect, and admiration. Though there are many things that can make one a legend, few ever live to see themselves become one. It is this that drives an exemplar above all else — for to be remembered and be like a hero of old is the ultimate goal.</p>
            <h4>CREATING AN EXEMPLAR</h4>
            <p>The first thing you need to consider which combat form best suits your character. Every exemplar is trained with martial weapons, so be sure to work with your DM to figure out how your character became skilled in combat, and then choose a style of combat that best suits you and how you want to play.</p>
            <p class="indent">Additionally, while you don’t gain access to them at 1st level, begin to think about which aspects best suit your character, both in their personality and their fighting style. Your exemplar might be one that swaps between many aspects as it suits them day to day, or you might dedicate yourself to one, and only swap when you absolutely have too.</p>
            <h5>QUICK BUILD</h5>
            <p>You can make an exemplar quickly by following these suggestions. First, make either Strength or Dexterity your highest ability scores, depending on the kinds of weapons you plan to use, followed by the ability you choose as part of your Aspiring Legend feature. If you’re unsure, choose Charisma. Finally, choose the Folk Hero background.</p>
            <h2>CLASS FEATURES</h2>
            <p>As an exemplar, you gain the following class features.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">HIT POINTS</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Hit Dice:</strong> 1d10 per exemplar level</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at 1st Level:</strong> 10 + your Constitution modifier</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at Higher Levels:</strong> 1d10 (or 6) + your Constitution modifier per exemplar level after 1st</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">PROFICIENCIES</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled mb">
                <li><strong>Armor:</strong> Light armor, medium armor, shields</li>
                <li><strong>Weapons:</strong> Simple weapons, martial weapons</li>
                <li><strong>Tools:</strong> None</li>
            </ul>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Saving Throws:</strong> Strength, Dexterity</li>
                <li><strong>Skills:</strong> Choose two from Acrobatics, Athletics, Insight, Investigation, Perception, and Persuasion.</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">EQUIPMENT</h5>
            <p>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>(a) a martial weapon and a shield or (b) two martial weapons</li>
                <li>(a) studded leather armor or (b) scale mail</li>
                <li>(a) a longbow and 20 arrows or (b) five javelins</li>
                <li>(a) a explorer’s pack or (b) a dungeoneer’s pack</li>
            </ul>
            <p>Alternatively, you may start with 5d4 x 10 gp to buy your own equipment.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">THE EXEMPLAR</h5>
            <table class="class-features">
                <thead>
                    <tr><td class="col-5">Level</td><td class="col-10">Proficiency Bonus</td><td class="col-60 left">Features</td><td class="col-10">Boons Known</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td> 1st</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Aspiring Legend, Armed Defence, Combat Form</td><td>‒</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 2nd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Heroic Aspect</td><td>‒</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 3rd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Exalted Boons</td><td>1</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 4th</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>1</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 5th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Extra Attack</td><td>2</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 6th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Combat Form feature</td><td>2</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 7th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Heroic Feat</td><td>2</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 8th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>3</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 9th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">By Their Will</td><td>3</td></tr>
                <tr><td>10th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>3</td></tr>
                <tr><td>11th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Combat Form feature, Heroic Aspect increase</td><td>4</td></tr>
                <tr><td>12th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>4</td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Sublime Boons</td><td>4</td></tr>
                <tr><td>14th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Resolve</td><td>5</td></tr>
                <tr><td>15th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Realized Legend</td><td>5</td></tr>
                <tr><td>16th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>5</td></tr>
                <tr><td>17th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Combat Form feature</td><td>6</td></tr>
                <tr><td>18th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Sublime Boons increase</td><td>6</td></tr>
                <tr><td>19th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>6</td></tr>
                <tr><td>20th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Heroic Will</td><td>8</td></tr>
            </table>
            <h3>OPTIONAL RULE: MULTICLASSING</h3>
            <p><b><i>Prerequisites.</i></b> To qualify for multiclassing into the exemplar class, you must meet these prerequisites: Strength 13 and Dexterity 13.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Proficiencies.</i></b> When you multiclass into the exemplar class, you gain the following proficiencies: Light armor, medium armor, simple weapons, martial weapons.</p>
            <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXEMPLAR_ASPIRING_LEGEND" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXEMPLAR_ARMED_DEFENCE" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXEMPLAR_COMBAT_FORM" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXEMPLAR_HEROIC_ASPECT" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXEMPLAR_EXALTED_BOONS" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXEMPLAR_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXEMPLAR_EXTRA_ATTACK" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXEMPLAR_HEROIC_FEAT" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXEMPLAR_BY_THEIR_WILL" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXEMPLAR_SUBLIME_BOONS" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXEMPLAR_RESOLVE" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXEMPLAR_REALIZED_LEGEND" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXEMPLAR_HEROIC_WILL" />
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="hd">d10</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_MEDIUM_ARMOR" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_SHIELDS" requirements="!ID_RJ_TEC_MULTICLASS_EXEMPLAR" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_MARTIAL_WEAPONS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_STRENGTH" requirements="!ID_RJ_TEC_MULTICLASS_EXEMPLAR" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_DEXTERITY" requirements="!ID_RJ_TEC_MULTICLASS_EXEMPLAR" />
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency, Exemplar" number="2" supports="Skill, RJ Exemplar" requirements="!ID_RJ_TEC_MULTICLASS_EXEMPLAR" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXEMPLAR_ASPIRING_LEGEND" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXEMPLAR_ARMED_DEFENCE" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXEMPLAR_COMBAT_FORM" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXEMPLAR_HEROIC_ASPECT" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXEMPLAR_EXALTED_BOONS" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXEMPLAR_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" level="4" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXEMPLAR_EXTRA_ATTACK" level="5" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXEMPLAR_HEROIC_FEAT" level="7" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXEMPLAR_BY_THEIR_WILL" level="9" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXEMPLAR_SUBLIME_BOONS" level="13" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXEMPLAR_RESOLVE" level="14" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXEMPLAR_REALIZED_LEGEND" level="15" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXEMPLAR_HEROIC_WILL" level="20" />
        </rules>
        <multiclass id="ID_RJ_TEC_MULTICLASS_EXEMPLAR">
            <prerequisite>Strength 13 and Dexterity 13</prerequisite>
            <requirements>[str:13],[dex:13]</requirements>
            <setters>
                <set name="multiclass proficiencies">When you multiclass into the exemplar class, you gain the following proficiencies: Light armor, medium armor, simple weapons, martial weapons.</set>
            </setters>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS" />
            </rules>
        </multiclass>
    </element>
        <element name="Aspiring Legend" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXEMPLAR_ASPIRING_LEGEND">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 1st level, your legend has only just begun. Choose one of the following ability scores, which determines your exemplar ability modifier.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Intelligence.</b> Your exemplar ability modifier is Intelligence, as you study the deeds of heroes of old. You gain proficiency in the History skill, and learn one language of your choice.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Wisdom.</b> Your exemplar ability modifier is Wisdom, as you meditate on the actions of past legends. You gain proficiency in the Religion skill and one set of artisan tools of your choice.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Charisma.</b> Your exemplar ability modifier is Charisma, as you personify the heroics of legends past. You gain proficiency in the Performance skill and one musical instrument of your choice.</p>
                <p class="indent">You use your exemplar ability modifier as part of your class, subclass, and aspect features. In addition, you use your exemplar ability modifier when setting the saving throw DC for an exemplar feature you use.</p>
                <p style="text-align: center;"><b>Exemplar save DC</b> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your exemplar ability modifier</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false"/>
            <rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Exemplar Ability" supports="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXEMPLAR_ABILITY_MODIFIER_INTELLIGENCE|ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXEMPLAR_ABILITY_MODIFIER_WISDOM|ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXEMPLAR_ABILITY_MODIFIER_CHARISMA" level="1" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Intelligence" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXEMPLAR_ABILITY_MODIFIER_INTELLIGENCE">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>Your exemplar ability modifier is Intelligence, as you study the deeds of heroes of old. You gain proficiency in the History skill, and learn one language of your choice. You use your exemplar ability modifier as part of your class, subclass, and aspect features. In addition, you use your exemplar ability modifier when setting the saving throw DC for an exemplar feature you use.</p>
                    <p style="text-align: center;"><b>Exemplar save DC</b> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your intelligence modifier</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>Your exemplar ability modifier is Intelligence. Your exemplar save DC is {{exemplar-ability:modifier}}.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="exemplar-ability:modifier" value="intelligence:modifier" />
                    <stat name="exemplar:save-dc" value="8" />
                    <stat name="exemplar:save-dc" value="proficiency" />
                    <stat name="exemplar:save-dc" value="exemplar-ability:modifier" />
                    <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_HISTORY" />
                    <select type="Language" name="Language, Aspiring Legend" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Wisdom" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXEMPLAR_ABILITY_MODIFIER_WISDOM">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>Your exemplar ability modifier is Wisdom, as you meditate on the actions of past legends. You gain proficiency in the Religion skill and one set of artisan tools of your choice. You use your exemplar ability modifier as part of your class, subclass, and aspect features. In addition, you use your exemplar ability modifier when setting the saving throw DC for an exemplar feature you use.</p>
                    <p style="text-align: center;"><b>Exemplar save DC</b> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your wisdom modifier</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>Your exemplar ability modifier is Wisdom. Your exemplar save DC is {{exemplar-ability:modifier}}.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="exemplar-ability:modifier" value="wisdom:modifier" />
                    <stat name="exemplar:save-dc" value="8" />
                    <stat name="exemplar:save-dc" value="proficiency" />
                    <stat name="exemplar:save-dc" value="exemplar-ability:modifier" />
                    <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_RELIGION" />
                    <select type="Proficiency" name="Artisan Tool Proficiency, Aspiring Legend" supports="Artisan tools" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Charisma" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXEMPLAR_ABILITY_MODIFIER_CHARISMA">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>Your exemplar ability modifier is Charisma, as you personify the heroics of legends past. You gain proficiency in the Performance skill and one musical instrument of your choice. You use your exemplar ability modifier as part of your class, subclass, and aspect features. In addition, you use your exemplar ability modifier when setting the saving throw DC for an exemplar feature you use.</p>
                    <p style="text-align: center;"><b>Exemplar save DC</b> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your charisma modifier</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>Your exemplar ability modifier is Charisma. Your exemplar save DC is {{exemplar-ability:modifier}}.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="exemplar-ability:modifier" value="charisma:modifier" />
                    <stat name="exemplar:save-dc" value="8" />
                    <stat name="exemplar:save-dc" value="proficiency" />
                    <stat name="exemplar:save-dc" value="exemplar-ability:modifier" />
                    <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERFORMANCE" />
                    <select type="Proficiency" name="Musical Instrument Proficiency, Aspiring Legend" supports="Musical Instrument" />
                </rules>
            </element>
        <element name="Armed Defence" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXEMPLAR_ARMED_DEFENCE">
            <description>
                <p>At 1st level, your skill with your weapons allows you to use them to effortlessly parry strikes as you weave in and out of combat. While you’re holding a weapon and not wearing any armor, your Armor Class equals 10 + your Strength modifier + your Dexterity modifier. You can use a shield and still gain this benefit.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>While you’re holding a weapon and not wearing any armor, your base Armor Class is {{ac:armed defense exemplar}}.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="ac:armed defense exemplar:base" value="10" />
                <stat name="ac:armed defense exemplar:dexterity" value="dexterity:modifier" />
                <stat name="ac:armed defense exemplar:strength" value="strength:modifier" />
                <stat name="ac:armed defense exemplar" value="ac:armed defense exemplar:base" />
                <stat name="ac:armed defense exemplar" value="ac:armed defense exemplar:dexterity" />
                <stat name="ac:armed defense exemplar" value="ac:armed defense exemplar:strength" />
                <stat name="ac:calculation" value="ac:armed defense exemplar" bonus="calculation" equipped="[armor:none]" alt="Armed Defense (Barbarian)" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Combat Form" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXEMPLAR_COMBAT_FORM">
            <description>
                <p>Each exemplar takes on a combat form that defines how they fight. Crusaders march forth with weapons that allow them to make use of shields, or keep a hand free. Gladiators rush into battle with a war cry and a heavy weapon. A marksman skirts along the edges of the battlefield, with a bow or crossbow in hand, and a partisan moves in and out of combat as if dancing.</p>
                <p class="indent">At 1st level, you choose a combat form, which defines the kinds of weapons you fight with. Choose either the Crusader, Gladiator, Marksman, or Partisan, each of which are detailed at the end of the class description.</p>
                <p class="indent">Your choice grants you features at 1st level, and again at 6th level, 11th level, and 17th level.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false" />
            <rules>
                <select type="Archetype" name="Combat Form" supports="Exemplar Combat Form" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Heroic Aspect" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXEMPLAR_HEROIC_ASPECT">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 2nd level, you can adopt an aspect that empowers you. Each aspect is an embodyment of a source of power. Many gods, otherworldly beings, and arch-devils and demons consider at least one of these aspects as part of their sphere of influence.</p>
                <p class="indent">Each heroic aspect is embodiment of power, something that is familiar, real, and inspires awe and respect. As an exemplar, your legendary destiny allows you to channel these aspects to bolster your martial prowess, harnessing magic unfamiliar and strange to achieve your goals.</p>
                <p class="indent">Choose one heroic aspect, detailed at the end of the class description, that you adopt. When you finish a long rest, you can replace any aspect you’ve adopted with another aspect of your choice.</p>
                <p class="indent">When you reach 11th level in this class, you can adopt a second heroic aspect each time you finish a long rest.</p>
                <h5>WILLPOWER</h5>
                <p>Some of your aspect features are fueled by willpower, which is your determination in battle. You have 4 willpower, and you regain all expended willpower when you finish a long rest.</p>
                <h5>ASPECT RITE</h5>
                <p>Each heroic aspect has an associated Aspect Rite, which imbues you with a lasting power that embodies your adopted aspect. While you have adopted an aspect, you gain the benefits of its associated Aspect Rite.</p>
                <h5>RIGHTEOUS ACT</h5>
                <p>Each heroic aspect has a righteous act, a powerful ability that turns the tide of battle. You can use a righteous act you have access to by spending 2 willpower as an action on your turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="{{willpower:points}} willpower/{{willpower:reset}}">
                <description>When you finish a long rest, you can replace any aspect you’ve adopted with another aspect of your choice. You can use a righteous act you have access to by spending 2 willpower as an action on your turn.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Heroic Aspect" supports="Exemplar Heroic Aspect" level="2" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Heroic Aspect" supports="Exemplar Heroic Aspect" level="11" />
                <stat name="willpower:points" value="4" level="2" />
                <stat name="willpower:reset" inline="true" value="Long Rest" level="20" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Exalted Boons" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXEMPLAR_EXALTED_BOONS">
            <description>
                <p>At 3rd level, you can focus your aspect, refining your capabilities to suit your situation. You learn one exalted boon, which must be of an aspect you’ve adopted. Each of the exalted boons are listed below their associated aspect. When you gain certain exemplar levels, you can learn additional boons, as shown in the Boons Known column of the Exemplar table.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can change your known exalted boons when you finish a long rest, choosing from the boons available to you by your chosen aspects. If you adopt a new aspect when you finish a long rest, you must replace any boons you know with boons from an aspect you’re associated with.</p>
                <p class="indent">At 20th level, you gain access to every boon associated with each aspect you’ve adopted.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, when you use a boon, you can spend 1 willpower to empower the boon’s effects, granting it a bonus listed under each boon. You can only empower a boon this way once per turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can change your known exalted boons when you finish a long rest, choosing from the boons available to you by your chosen aspects. If you adopt a new aspect when you finish a long rest, you must replace any boons you know with boons from an aspect you’re associated with. Additionally, when you use a boon, you can spend 1 willpower to empower the boon’s effects, granting it a bonus listed under each boon. You can only empower a boon this way once per turn.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Exalted Boon" supports="Exemplar Exalted Boon" level="3" requirements="![level:exemplar:20]" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Exalted Boon" supports="Exemplar Exalted Boon" level="5" requirements="![level:exemplar:20]" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Exalted Boon" supports="Exemplar Exalted Boon" level="8" requirements="![level:exemplar:20]" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Exalted Boon" supports="Exemplar Exalted Boon" level="11" requirements="![level:exemplar:20]" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Exalted Boon" supports="Exemplar Exalted Boon" level="14" requirements="![level:exemplar:20]" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Exalted Boon" supports="Exemplar Exalted Boon" level="17" requirements="![level:exemplar:20]" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Ability Score Improvement" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXEMPLAR_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 10th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. You can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false" />
            <rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Exemplar 4)" supports="Improvement Option,Exemplar,4" level="4" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Exemplar 8)" supports="Improvement Option,Exemplar,8" level="8" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Exemplar 12)" supports="Improvement Option,Exemplar,12" level="12" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Exemplar 16)" supports="Improvement Option,Exemplar,16" level="16" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Exemplar 19)" supports="Improvement Option,Exemplar,19" level="19" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Extra Attack" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXEMPLAR_EXTRA_ATTACK">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 5th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="extra attack:count" value="2" level="5" bonus="extra attack" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Heroic Feat" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXEMPLAR_HEROIC_FEAT">
            <description>
                <p>At 7th level, when you make a saving throw or ability check using Strength or Dexterity, you can add both your Strength and Dexterity modifiers to it. You must do so before you roll.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t do so again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you make a saving throw or ability check using Strength or Dexterity, you can add both your Strength and Dexterity modifiers (+{{heroic-feat:save-bonus}}) to it. You must do so before you roll.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="heroic-feat:save-bonus" value="strength:modifier" level="7" />
                <stat name="heroic-feat:save-bonus" value="dexterity:modifier" level="7" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="By Their Will" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXEMPLAR_BY_THEIR_WILL">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 9th level, the willpower of ancient heroes is imbued within you, granting you the means to fight on. When you finish a short rest, you regain up to 2 expended willpower.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you finish a short rest, you regain up to 2 expended willpower.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Sublime Boons" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXEMPLAR_SUBLIME_BOONS">
            <description>
                <p>At 13th level, your ability to channel your aspect’s power allows you to take on sublime boons. When you finish a long rest, you can choose a single sublime boon, which must be of an aspect you’ve adopted. A sublime boon doesn’t count against the total number of boons you know.</p>
                <p class="indent">When you reach 18th level, you can adopt a second sublime boon each time you finish a long rest.</p>
                <h5>ABSOLUTE ZERO</h5>
                <p class="flavor">Requirements: Aspect of Winter</p>
                <p class="indent">Your very presence chills the air. Creatures of your choice treat any space within 10 feet of you as difficult terrain.</p>
                <h5>BLINDING FLARE</h5>
                <p class="flavor">Requirements: Aspect of Fire</p>
                <p class="indent">When you use your Wildfire rite on a creature, it must make a Constitution saving throw or become blinded until the start of their next turn.</p>
                <h5>BRIGHTEST LIGHT</h5>
                <p class="flavor">Requirements: Aspect of Light</p>
                <p class="indent">You inner light always guides you. You gain the benefits of your Guiding Light rite for each attack you make on your turn.</p>
                <h5>ENDURING BODY</h5>
                <p class="flavor">Requirements: Aspect of Death</p>
                <p class="indent">You’re able to rise above death. You regain hit points equal to 1d6 + your exemplar ability modifier if you end your turn in combat with fewer than half of your hit points remaining and you aren’t incapacitated.</p>
                <h5>LIGHTNING STORM</h5>
                <p class="flavor">Requirements: Aspect of the Storm</p>
                <p class="indent">Your lightning arcs across the battlefield as you effortlessly control it. When you use your Arcing Storm rite, the initial target of the attack also takes the rite’s damage. Additionally, you can have two lightning bolts arc from the initial target towards two different targets. The distance you can have the lightning arc increases by 15 feet.</p>
                <h5>TEMPEST’S WINGS</h5>
                <p class="flavor">Requirements: Aspect of Air</p>
                <p class="indent">You cause a large pair of magical wings sprout from your back, granting you a flying speed equal to half your current speed. You can create these wings as a bonus action on your turn. They last until you dismiss them (no action required).</p>
                <p class="indent">The wings you summon can take on an appearance of your choice, but appear somewhat translucent and obviously magical, and as such, don’t impede you or affect any armor you’re wearing.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you finish a long rest, you can choose a single sublime boon, which must be of an aspect you’ve adopted.</description>
                <description level="18">When you finish a long rest, you can choose two sublime boons, which must be of an aspect you’ve adopted.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Sublime Boon" supports="Exemplar Sublime Boon" level="13" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Sublime Boon" supports="Exemplar Sublime Boon" level="18" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Resolve" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXEMPLAR_RESOLVE">
            <description>
                <p>At 14th level, your force of will is undeniable. While under an effect that allows you to make a saving throw at the end of each of your turns, ending the effect on a success, you can instead make the saving throw at the start of each of your turns.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>While under an effect that allows you to make a saving throw at the end of each of your turns, ending the effect on a success, you can instead make the saving throw at the start of each of your turns.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Realized Legend" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXEMPLAR_REALIZED_LEGEND">
            <description>
                <p>At 15th level, your adventures have started to become legend. When you spend at least 3 days in a settlement, a number of commoners equal to your exemplar ability modifier approach you and offer to perform mundane tasks for you, but they do not fight for you, will not follow you into obviously dangerous areas, and will stop aiding you endanger or abuse them. They’ll also stop aiding you once you leave the settlement.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you spend at least 3 days in a settlement, {{exemplar-ability:modifier}} commoners approach you and offer to perform mundane tasks for you, but they do not fight for you, will not follow you into obviously dangerous areas, and will stop aiding you endanger or abuse them. They’ll also stop aiding you once you leave the settlement.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Heroic Will" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXEMPLAR_HEROIC_WILL">
            <description>
                <p>At 20th level, you have become legend. Your total willpower increases by 4 (to a total of 8), and you regain up to 4 expended willpower when you finish a short rest.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, when you make a weapon damage roll using Strength or Dexterity, you can add both your Strength and Dexterity modifiers to it.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="willpower:points" value="4" level="20" />
                <stat name="willpower:reset" inline="true" value="Short Rest" level="20" />
            </rules>
        </element>

        <element name="Crusader" type="Archetype" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_EXEMPLAR_CRUSADER">
            <supports>Exemplar Combat Form</supports>
            <description>
                <p>As a crusader, you fight with weapons such as longswords, battle axes, and spears, using them with skill and prowess. You fight best alongside others, and can easily parry, block, and dodge even the most dangerous blows.</p>
                <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CRUSADER_STAND_UNITED" />
                <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CRUSADER_PERFECT_DEFENSE" />
                <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CRUSADER_PERFECT_DEFENCE_IMPROVEMENT" />
                <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CRUSADER_THE_BEST_DEFENCE" />
                <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CRUSADER_CRUSADERS_STANCE" />
            </description>
            <sheet display="false" />
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CRUSADER_STAND_UNITED" level="1" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CRUSADER_PERFECT_DEFENSE" level="1" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CRUSADER_PERFECT_DEFENCE_IMPROVEMENT" level="6" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CRUSADER_THE_BEST_DEFENCE" level="11" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CRUSADER_CRUSADERS_STANCE" level="17" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Stand United" type="Archetype Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CRUSADER_STAND_UNITED">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 1st level, you have advantage on saving throws against being frightened while you’re within 5 feet of a friendly creature that isn’t incapacitated.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You have advantage on saving throws against being frightened while you’re within 5 feet of a friendly creature that isn’t incapacitated.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Perfect Defense" type="Archetype Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CRUSADER_PERFECT_DEFENSE">
            <description>
                <p>At 1st level, you can easily parry and block dangerous blows. When you’re hit by an attack while you’re wielding a melee weapon in one hand and no other weapons, you can enter a defensive stance as a reaction. Until the start of your next turn, you gain a bonus to your AC, including against the triggering attack. This bonus is equal to your exemplar ability modifier.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can use this feature a number of times equal to your exemplar ability modifier (minimum of 1), and regain all uses when you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Reaction" usage="{{exemplar-ability:modifier}}/Long Rest">
                <description>When you’re hit by an attack while you’re wielding a melee weapon in one hand and no other weapons, you can enter a defensive stance as a reaction. Until the start of your next turn, you gain +{{exemplar-ability:modifier}} bonus to your AC, including against the triggering attack.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Perfect Defence Improvement" type="Archetype Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CRUSADER_PERFECT_DEFENCE_IMPROVEMENT">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, you can choose one of the following features, which enhances your Perfect Defence feature.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Reverberating Bulwark.</b> Creatures that make attack rolls against you while you’re in your defensive stance take force damage equal to 1d4 + your exemplar ability modifier.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Penultimate Defence.</b> While in your defensive stance, you gain a bonus to any Dexterity saving throws you make equal to your exemplar ability modifier, and you can use your reaction to enter the defensive stance when you’re forced to make a Dexterity saving throw.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Perfect Defense Improvement" supports="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CRUSADER_PERFECT_DEFENCE_IMPROVEMENT_REVERBERATING_BULWARK|ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CRUSADER_PERFECT_DEFENCE_IMPROVEMENT_PENULTIMATE_DEFENCE" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Reverberating Bulwark" type="Archetype Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CRUSADER_PERFECT_DEFENCE_IMPROVEMENT_REVERBERATING_BULWARK">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>Creatures that make attack rolls against you while you’re in your defensive stance take force damage equal to 1d4 + your exemplar ability modifier.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Defensive Stance">
                    <description>Creatures that make attack rolls against you while you’re in your defensive stance take 1d4 + {{exemplar-ability:modifier}} force damage.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Penultimate Defence" type="Archetype Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CRUSADER_PERFECT_DEFENCE_IMPROVEMENT_PENULTIMATE_DEFENCE">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>While in your defensive stance, you gain a bonus to any Dexterity saving throws you make equal to your exemplar ability modifier, and you can use your reaction to enter the defensive stance when you’re forced to make a Dexterity saving throw.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Defensive Stance" action="Reaction">
                    <description>While in your defensive stance, you gain a +{{exemplar-ability:modifier}} bonus to any Dexterity saving throws you make, and you can use your reaction to enter the defensive stance when you’re forced to make a Dexterity saving throw.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
        <element name="The Best Defence" type="Archetype Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CRUSADER_THE_BEST_DEFENCE">
            <description>
                <p>At 11th level, once per turn when you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can have it take an additional 1d6 damage and become taunted until the start of your next turn.</p>
                <p class="indent">While taunted, the target has disadvantage on attack rolls against creatures other than you until it hits you with an attack.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Once per turn when you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can have it take an additional 1d6 damage and have disadvantage on attack rolls against creatures other than you until it hits you with an attack.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Crusader’s Stance" type="Archetype Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CRUSADER_CRUSADERS_STANCE">
            <description>
                <p>At 17th level, your opponents leave openings that you can easily take advantage of during battle. You can enter an aggressive stance as bonus action on your turn. While you’re in this stance and aren’t incapacitated, you can make a melee weapon attack against any creature that hits you with a melee attack (no action required).</p>
                <p class="indent">This stance lasts for 1 minute, or until you make five special attacks, at which point it ends. Once you enter this stance, you can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You can enter an aggressive stance. While you’re in this stance and aren’t incapacitated, you can make a melee weapon attack against any creature that hits you with a melee attack (no action required). This stance lasts for 1 minute, or until you make five special attacks, at which point it ends.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>

    <element name="Gladiator" type="Archetype" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_EXEMPLAR_GLADIATOR">
        <supports>Exemplar Combat Form</supports>
        <description>
            <p>As a gladiator, you fight with weapons such as glaives, mauls, and halberds, wielding them with a devastating brutality. You excel when up close with your foes, where your sheer strength allows you to overpower others.</p>
            <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GLADIATOR_GLORIOUS_SLAUGHTER" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GLADIATOR_DEVASTATING_SWING" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GLADIATOR_DEVASTATING_SWING_IMPROVEMENT" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GLADIATOR_EXECUTIONER" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GLADIATOR_GLADIATORS_CHALLENGE" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GLADIATOR_GLORIOUS_SLAUGHTER" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GLADIATOR_DEVASTATING_SWING" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GLADIATOR_DEVASTATING_SWING_IMPROVEMENT" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GLADIATOR_EXECUTIONER" level="11" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GLADIATOR_GLADIATORS_CHALLENGE" level="17" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Glorious Slaughter" type="Archetype Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GLADIATOR_GLORIOUS_SLAUGHTER">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 1st level, you have advantage on Charisma (Intimidation) checks against a creature that has seen you reduce another creature of at least CR 1/4 to 0 hit points within the past minute.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You have advantage on Intimidation checks against a creature that has seen you reduce another creature of at least CR 1/4 to 0 hit points within the past minute.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Devastating Swing" type="Archetype Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GLADIATOR_DEVASTATING_SWING">
            <description>
                <p>At 1st level, when you make an attack while wielding a melee weapon with the heavy property, you can declare a devastating swing. On a hit, the target takes additional damage equal to 1d12 + your exemplar ability modifier, and must make a Strength saving throw or be knocked prone.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can use this feature a number of times equal to your exemplar ability modifier (minimum of 1), and regain all uses when you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you make an attack while wielding a melee weapon with the heavy property, you can declare a devastating swing. On a hit, the target takes additional 1d12 + {{exemplar-ability:modifier}} damage, and must make a Strength saving throw (DC {{exemplar:save-dc}}) or be knocked prone.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Devastating Swing Improvement" type="Archetype Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GLADIATOR_DEVASTATING_SWING_IMPROVEMENT">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, you can choose one of the following features, which enhances your Devastating Swing feature.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Dizzying Swing.</b> On a failed the save, the creature is also stunned until the start of your next turn.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Sweeping Blow.</b> When you make a Devastating Swing, you can also have creatures of your choice within 5 feet of the target take damage equal to 1d6 + your exemplar ability modifier, the damage type of which is your weapon’s damage type.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Devastating Swing Improvement" supports="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GLADIATOR_DEVASTATING_SWING_IMPROVEMENT_DIZZYING_SWING|ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GLADIATOR_DEVASTATING_SWING_IMPROVEMENT_SWEEPING_BLOW" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Dizzying Swing" type="Archetype Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GLADIATOR_DEVASTATING_SWING_IMPROVEMENT_DIZZYING_SWING">
                <description>
                    <p>On a failed the save, the creature is also stunned until the start of your next turn.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Devastating Swing">
                    <description>On a failed the save, the creature is also stunned until the start of your next turn.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Sweeping Blow" type="Archetype Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GLADIATOR_DEVASTATING_SWING_IMPROVEMENT_SWEEPING_BLOW">
                <description>
                    <p>When you make a Devastating Swing, you can also have creatures of your choice within 5 feet of the target take damage equal to 1d6 + your exemplar ability modifier, the damage type of which is your weapon’s damage type.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Devastating Swing">
                    <description>When you make a Devastating Swing, you can also have creatures of your choice within 5 feet of the target take 1d6 + {{exemplar-ability:modifier}} damage of your weapon's type.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
        <element name="Executioner" type="Archetype Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GLADIATOR_EXECUTIONER">
            <description>
                <p>At 11th level, you thrive in battle while your opponent is weak. Once per turn when you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you deal an additional 1d8 damage to it. If the creature is below half it’s hit point maximum, you deal 1d12 damage to it instead.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Once per turn when you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you deal an additional 1d8 damage to it. If the creature is below half it’s hit point maximum, you deal 1d12 damage to it instead.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Gladiator’s Challenge" type="Archetype Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GLADIATOR_GLADIATORS_CHALLENGE">
            <description>
                <p>At 17th level, your strikes inspire challenge, goading your enemies to do battle with you in your arena. When you hit a creature with an attack while wielding a melee weapon with the heavy property, you can challenge them. A 20-foot radius sphere appears centered on that creature (but doesn’t move with it) and lasts for 1 minute, until you leave the sphere, or until the creature is reduced to 0 hit points. The edges of the sphere are formed out of specrtral soldiers, and if the challenged creature moves within 5 feet of the edge of the sphere on its turn or starts its turn there, it takes force damage equal to 1d12 + half your exemplar level. Only you and the challenged creature can see the soldiers, and the challenged creature can’t leave the sphere by any means. All teleportation attempts fail, and spells and abilities can’t move the creature outside the sphere, unless you cast them.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>When you hit a creature with an attack while wielding a melee weapon with the heavy property, you can challenge them. A 20-foot radius sphere appears centered on that creature. If the challenged creature moves within 5 feet of the edge of the sphere on its turn or starts its turn there, it takes 1d12 + {{level:exemplar:half}} force damage.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>

    <element name="Marksman" type="Archetype" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_EXEMPLAR_MARKSMAN">
        <supports>Exemplar Combat Form</supports>
        <description>
            <p>As a marksman, you fight with weapons such as bows and crossbows, striking with deadly precision. You’re patient with each and every shot, and know how to pierce even the most well defended foes.</p>
            <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MARKSMAN_ARCHERS_EYE" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MARKSMAN_PIERCING_SHOT" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MARKSMAN_PIERCING_SHOT_IMPROVEMENT" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MARKSMAN_DEADLY_PRECISION" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MARKSMAN_MARKSMANS_BARRAGE" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MARKSMAN_ARCHERS_EYE" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MARKSMAN_PIERCING_SHOT" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MARKSMAN_PIERCING_SHOT_IMPROVEMENT" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MARKSMAN_DEADLY_PRECISION" level="11" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MARKSMAN_MARKSMANS_BARRAGE" level="17" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Archer’s Eye" type="Archetype Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MARKSMAN_ARCHERS_EYE">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 1st level, few can escape your gaze. You gain a bonus to your passive Wisdom (Perception) score. This bonus is equal to your exemplar ability modifier.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="perception:passive" value="exemplar-ability:modifier" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Piercing Shot" type="Archetype Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MARKSMAN_PIERCING_SHOT">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 1st level, you can fire a piercing shot. When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can forgo a single attack as part of that action to make this special attack while you’re wielding a ranged weapon. Creatures in a line 60 feet long and 1-inch wide must make a Dexterity saving throw, taking piercing damage equal to 2d4 + your exemplar ability modifier on a failed save, or half as much on a success.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can use this feature a number of times equal to your exemplar ability modifier (minimum of 1), and regain all uses when you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="{{exemplar-ability:modifier}}/Long Rest">
                <description>When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can forgo a single attack as part of that action to make this special attack while you’re wielding a ranged weapon. Creatures in a line 60 feet long and 1-inch wide must make a Dexterity saving throw, taking 2d4 + {{exemplar-ability:modifier}} piercing damage equal to on a failed save, or half as much on a success.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Piercing Shot Improvement" type="Archetype Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MARKSMAN_PIERCING_SHOT_IMPROVEMENT">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, you can choose one of the following features, which enhances your Piercing Shot feature.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Magnum Shot.</b> Creatures that fail their saving throw against your Piercing Shot are pushed 20 feet directly away from you, and the creature closest to you in the line has disadvantage on the saving throw.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Split Shot.</b> You can fire three piercing shots as part of the attack, expending only one use of your Piercing Shot feature. A creature in the path of more than one arrow only takes damage from one.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Piercing Shot Improvement" supports="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MARKSMAN_PIERCING_SHOT_IMPROVEMENT_MAGNUM_SHOT|ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MARKSMAN_PIERCING_SHOT_IMPROVEMENT_SPLIT_SHOT" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Magnum Shot" type="Archetype Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MARKSMAN_PIERCING_SHOT_IMPROVEMENT_MAGNUM_SHOT">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>Creatures that fail their saving throw against your Piercing Shot are pushed 20 feet directly away from you, and the creature closest to you in the line has disadvantage on the saving throw.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>Creatures that fail their saving throw against your Piercing Shot are pushed 20 feet directly away from you, and the creature closest to you in the line has disadvantage on the saving throw.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Split Shot" type="Archetype Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MARKSMAN_PIERCING_SHOT_IMPROVEMENT_SPLIT_SHOT">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>You can fire three piercing shots as part of the attack, expending only one use of your Piercing Shot feature. A creature in the path of more than one arrow only takes damage from one.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>You can fire three piercing shots as part of the attack, expending only one use of your Piercing Shot feature. A creature in the path of more than one arrow only takes damage from one.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
        <element name="Deadly Precision" type="Archetype Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MARKSMAN_DEADLY_PRECISION">
            <description>
                <p>At 11th level, you can focus your shots, ruthlessly sizing up your foe as you take them down. Once per turn when you make a ranged attack roll, you can declare one of the following shots, aiming at a specific part of the creature. If a creature doesn’t posess the body part you declare, your attack gains no benefit.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Headshot.</b> On a hit, the attack deals an additional 1d10 piercing damage.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Bodyshot.</b> You can roll a d4 and add it to your attack roll.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Armshot.</b> On a hit, the target must make a Dexterity saving throw or drop one object of your choice that it’s carrying.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Legshot.</b> On a hit, the target must make a Strength saving throw or be knocked prone.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Once per turn when you make a ranged attack roll, you can aim at a specific part of the creature.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Marksman’s Barrage" type="Archetype Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MARKSMAN_MARKSMANS_BARRAGE">
            <description>
                <p>At 17th level, you can summon a swarm of spectral arrows to barrage your foes. When you roll initiative or as a bonus action on your turn, you can summon 10 magical arrows in your space that hover around you.</p>
                <p class="indent">Whenever you make a ranged weapon attack or use your Piercing Shot feature as part of the Attack action, you can have one of the arrows hovering around you shoot towards a creature you can see within 30 feet of your target. That creature takes 1d8 piercing damage.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature to summon the barrage of arrows, you can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>When you roll initiative or as a bonus action on your turn, you can summon 10 magical arrows in your space that hover around you. Whenever you make a ranged weapon attack or use your Piercing Shot feature as part of the Attack action, you can have one of the arrows hovering around you shoot towards a creature you can see within 30 feet of your target. That creature takes 1d8 piercing damage.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>

    <element name="Partisan" type="Archetype" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_EXEMPLAR_PARTISAN">
        <supports>Exemplar Combat Form</supports>
        <description>
            <p>As a partisan, you fight with weapons such as shortswords, daggers, and hand axes, allowing you to strike with speed. You attack fast and often, and dance across the battlefield with unmatched grace and elegance.</p>
            <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PARTISAN_DERVISHS_DANCE" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PARTISAN_STEEL_WHIRLWIND" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PARTISAN_STEEL_WHIRLWIND_IMPROVEMENT" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PARTISAN_RAPID_STRIKES" />
            <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PARTISAN_PARTISANS_SHROUD" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PARTISAN_DERVISHS_DANCE" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PARTISAN_STEEL_WHIRLWIND" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PARTISAN_STEEL_WHIRLWIND_IMPROVEMENT" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PARTISAN_RAPID_STRIKES" level="11" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PARTISAN_PARTISANS_SHROUD" level="17" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Dervish’s Dance" type="Archetype Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PARTISAN_DERVISHS_DANCE">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 1st level, when you engage in two-weapon fighting, you can make the off-hand attack as part of the Attack action, rather than as a bonus action. You can’t make a weapon attack using your bonus action and use this feature on the same turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you engage in two-weapon fighting, you can make the off-hand attack as part of the Attack action, rather than as a bonus action. You can’t make a weapon attack using your bonus action and use this feature on the same turn.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Steel Whirlwind" type="Archetype Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PARTISAN_STEEL_WHIRLWIND">
            <description>
                <p>At 1st level, you can whirl your weapons around you. When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can forgo a single attack as part of that action to make this special attack while you’re wielding a melee weapon in each hand. Creatures within 5 feet of you must make a Dexterity saving throw, taking slashing damage equal to 2d6 + your exemplar ability modifier on a failed save, or half as much on a success. This attack counts as a weapon attack with a light weapon for the purposes of two-weapon fighting.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can use this feature a number of times equal to your exemplar ability modifier (minimum of 1), and regain all uses when you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can forgo a single attack as part of that action to make this special attack while you’re wielding a melee weapon in each hand. Creatures within 5 feet of you must make a Dexterity saving throw (DC {{exemplar:save-dc}}), taking 2d6 + {{exemplar-ability:modifier}} slashing damage a failed save, or half as much on a success.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Steel Whirlwind Improvement" type="Archetype Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PARTISAN_STEEL_WHIRLWIND_IMPROVEMENT">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, you can choose one of the following features, which enhances your Steel Whirlwind feature.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Quicksilver Storm.</b> Your steel whirlwind affects creatures within 10 feet of you. Creatures within 5 feet of you when you use it take an additional 1d6 damage.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Shield of Blades.</b> Creatures that fail their saving throw have disadvantage on attack rolls against you until the start of your next turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Steel Whirlwind Improvement" supports="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PARTISAN_STEEL_WHIRLWIND_IMPROVEMENT_QUICKSILVER_STORM|ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PARTISAN_STEEL_WHIRLWIND_IMPROVEMENT_SHIELD_OF_BLADES" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Quicksilver Storm" type="Archetype Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PARTISAN_STEEL_WHIRLWIND_IMPROVEMENT_QUICKSILVER_STORM">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>Your steel whirlwind affects creatures within 10 feet of you. Creatures within 5 feet of you when you use it take an additional 1d6 damage.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Steel Whirlwind">
                    <description>Your steel whirlwind affects creatures within 10 feet of you. Creatures within 5 feet of you when you use it take an additional 1d6 damage.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Shield of Blades" type="Archetype Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PARTISAN_STEEL_WHIRLWIND_IMPROVEMENT_SHIELD_OF_BLADES">
                <compendium display="false" />
                <description>
                    <p>Creatures that fail their saving throw have disadvantage on attack rolls against you until the start of your next turn.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="Steel Whirlwind">
                    <description>Creatures that fail their saving throw have disadvantage on attack rolls against you until the start of your next turn.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
        <element name="Rapid Strikes" type="Archetype Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PARTISAN_RAPID_STRIKES">
            <description>
                <p>At 11th level, when you engage in two-weapon fighting, you can add your ability modifier to the damage of the second attack if you aren’t already.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you engage in two-weapon fighting, you can add your ability modifier to the damage of the second attack if you aren’t already.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Partisan’s Shroud" type="Archetype Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PARTISAN_PARTISANS_SHROUD">
            <description>
                <p>At 17th level, you can shroud yourself in a whirling storm of spectral blades. The first time you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack on your turn, these spectral blades whirl around you in a 5-foot radius. Each melee weapon attack you hit beyond the first on your turn increases the radius by 5 feet, to a maximum of 15 feet. The spectral blades vanish when you end your turn without attacking a creature.</p>
                <p class="indent">When a creature of your choice enters the area for the first time on its turn or starts it’s turn inside of it, it must make a Dexterity saving throw, taking slashing damage equal to 1d6 + your exemplar ability modifier on a failed save.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>The first time you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack on your turn, you summon spectral blades around you in a 5-foot radius. Each melee weapon attack you hit beyond the first on your turn increases the radius by 5 feet, to a maximum of 15 feet. The spectral blades vanish when you end your turn without attacking a creature. When a creature of your choice enters the area for the first time on its turn or starts it’s turn inside of it, it must make a Dexterity saving throw (DC {{exemplar:save-dc}}), taking 1d6 + {{exemplar:save-dc}} slashing damage.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>


        <element name="Aspect of Air" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXEMPLAR_ASPECT_OF_AIR">
            <supports>Exemplar Heroic Aspect</supports>
            <description>
                <p>The aspect of air embodies agility and fluidity. Those who adopt this aspect are nimble in battle as they weave between their foes, delivering a death as swift as they are.</p>
                <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_ASPECT_OF_AIR_ASPECT_RITE" />
                <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_ASPECT_OF_AIR_RIGHTEOUS_ACT" />
                <h5>ASPECT OF AIR: BOONS</h5>
                <p>The following boons are available to an exemplar who adopts the aspect of air.</p>
                <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_AIR_ACCELERATE" />
                <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_AIR_GALE_FORCE" />
                <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_AIR_LIGHT_FOOT" />
                <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_AIR_WIND_SPRINT" />
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_AIR_ACCELERATE" level="20" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_AIR_GALE_FORCE" level="20" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_AIR_LIGHT_FOOT" level="20" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_AIR_WIND_SPRINT" level="20" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Aspect Rite" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_ASPECT_OF_AIR_ASPECT_RITE">
                <description>
                    <p>You gain the following aspect rite, due to your connection to the aspect of air.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b>Wind Step.</b> Your speed increases by 10 feet, and opportunity attacks against you have disadvantage.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet alt="Wind Step">
                    <description>Opportunity attacks against you have disadvantage.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="speed:misc" value="10" bonus="aspect rite" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Righteous Act" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_ASPECT_OF_AIR_RIGHTEOUS_ACT">
                <description>
                    <p>You gain access to the following righteous act, due to your connection to the aspect of air.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b>Raging Tempest.</b> You call upon the aspect of air to throw those around you to their feet in awe of your glory as an action. Any number of creatures of your choice within 20 feet of you must make a Strength saving throw. Creatures that failed their saving throw are pushed up to 20 feet in a horizontal direction of your choice and are knocked prone. On a successful save, a creature can choose to either be pushed or be knocked prone.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="2 willpower" action="Action" alt="Raging Tempest">
                    <description>Any number of creatures of your choice within 20 feet of you must make a Strength saving throw (DC {{exemplar:save-dc}}) or be pushed up to 20 feet in a horizontal direction of your choice and are knocked prone. On a successful save, a creature can choose to either be pushed or be knocked prone.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Accelerate" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_AIR_ACCELERATE">
                <supports>Exemplar Exalted Boon</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>You can run while others crawl. You have advantage on initiative rolls, and when combat begins, your speed increases by 10 feet and you don’t provoke opportunity attacks until you take damage or until 1 minute passes.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b>Willpower.</b> When you roll initiative, you can spend 1 willpower to increase the bonus to your speed by an additional 10 feet.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>You have advantage on initiative rolls, and when combat begins, your speed increases by 10 feet and you don’t provoke opportunity attacks until you take damage or until 1 minute passes. When you roll initiative, you can spend 1 willpower to increase the bonus to your speed by an additional 10 feet.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Gale Force" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_AIR_GALE_FORCE">
                <supports>Exemplar Exalted Boon</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>When you make an opportunity attack against a creature, you can instead attempt to shove the creature.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b>Willpower.</b> You can spend 1 willpower when you shove a creature to grant yourself advantage on the Strength (Athletics) check.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>When you make an opportunity attack against a creature, you can instead attempt to shove the creature. You can spend 1 willpower when you shove a creature to grant yourself advantage on the Athletics check.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Light Foot" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_AIR_LIGHT_FOOT">
                <supports>Exemplar Exalted Boon</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>You gain a bonus to your Dexterity (Stealth) checks equal to your exemplar ability modifier, and you can’t trigger floor-based traps and mechanisms, such as tripwires, pressure plates, or pitfalls.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b>Willpower.</b> You can spend 1 willpower to take the Hide action as a bonus action on your turn.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>You gain a +{{exemplar-ability:modifier}} bonus to your Stealth checks and you can’t trigger floor-based traps and mechanisms, such as tripwires, pressure plates, or pitfalls. You can spend 1 willpower to take the Hide action as a bonus action on your turn.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Wind Sprint" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_AIR_WIND_SPRINT">
                <supports>Exemplar Exalted Boon</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>Your steps carry you far. When you take the Dash action, you can move an additional 15 feet if you only spend your movement on your turn moving in a straight line.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b>Willpower.</b> You can spend 1 willpower to take the Dash action as a bonus action on your turn.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>When you take the Dash action, you can move an additional 15 feet if you only spend your movement on your turn moving in a straight line. You can spend 1 willpower to take the Dash action as a bonus action on your turn.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>

        <element name="Aspect of Death" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXEMPLAR_ASPECT_OF_DEATH">
            <supports>Exemplar Heroic Aspect</supports>
            <description>
                <p>The aspect of death embodies resilience and hardship. Those who adopt this aspect are an unyielding force on the battlefield, wading through combat as they shrug off blow after blow.</p>
                <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_ASPECT_OF_DEATH_ASPECT_RITE" />
                <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_ASPECT_OF_DEATH_RIGHTEOUS_ACT" />
                <h5>ASPECT OF DEATH: BOONS</h5>
                <p>The following boons are available to an exemplar who adopts the aspect of death.</p>
                <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_DEATH_HANGMANS_NOOSE" />
                <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_DEATH_FOOT_IN_THE_GRAVE" />
                <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_DEATH_REJECT_DEATH" />
                <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_DEATH_UMBRAL_ARMOR" />
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_DEATH_HANGMANS_NOOSE" level="20" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_DEATH_FOOT_IN_THE_GRAVE" level="20" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_DEATH_REJECT_DEATH" level="20" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_DEATH_UMBRAL_ARMOR" level="20" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Aspect Rite" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_ASPECT_OF_DEATH_ASPECT_RITE">
                <description>
                    <p>You gain the following aspect rite, due to your connection to the aspect of death.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b>Soul Mark.</b> Once per turn when you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can mark it until the start of your next turn. The next time the marked creature deals damage to you, you can reduce that damage by an amount equal to your exemplar ability modifier. You can reduce damage this way once per mark.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet alt="Soul Mark">
                    <description>Once per turn when you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can mark it until the start of your next turn. The next time the marked creature deals damage to you, you can reduce that damage by {{exemplar-ability:modifier}}.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Righteous Act" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_ASPECT_OF_DEATH_RIGHTEOUS_ACT">
                <description>
                    <p>You gain access to the following righteous act, due to your connection to the aspect of death.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b>Soul Shield.</b> You can call upon the aspect of death to shroud you. As an action, you gain temporary hit points equal to 5 + twice your exemplar level, which last for 1 hour.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="2 willpower" action="Action" alt="Soul Shield">
                    <description>You gain {{soul-shield:temp-hp}} temporary hit points, which last for 1 hour.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="soul-shield:temp-hp" value="level:exemplar" />
                    <stat name="soul-shield:temp-hp" value="level:exemplar" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Hangman’s Noose" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_DEATH_HANGMANS_NOOSE">
                <supports>Exemplar Exalted Boon</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>You mark hangs over those close to death, stealing their vitality. If a creature is reduced to 0 hit points while it’s marked by your Aspect of Death feature, you gain temporary hit points equal to your proficiency bonus + your exemplar ability modifier, which last for 1 minute.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b>Willpower.</b> When you gain these temporary hit points, you can spend 1 willpower to teleport up to 15 feet to an unoccupied space that you can see.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>If a creature is reduced to 0 hit points while it’s marked by your Aspect of Death feature, you gain {{hangmans-noose:temp-hp}} temporary hit points, which last for 1 minute. When you gain these temporary hit points, you can spend 1 willpower to teleport up to 15 feet to an unoccupied space that you can see.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="hangmans-noose:temp-hp" value="proficiency" />
                    <stat name="hangmans-noose:temp-hp" value="exemplar-ability:modifier" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Foot in the Grave" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_DEATH_FOOT_IN_THE_GRAVE">
                <supports>Exemplar Exalted Boon</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>Your very essence is tied to death, granting you fortitude. Any critical hit against you becomes a normal hit. When a creature critically hits you, it takes necrotic damage equal to 1d6 + your exemplar ability modifier.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b>Willpower.</b> When you negate a critical hit, you can spend 1 willpower to reduce any damage you take from the attack to 0, and the attacker takes the full amount of damage it would have dealt to you (as if it critically hit you) as necrotic damage.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>Any critical hit against you becomes a normal hit. When a creature critically hits you, it takes 1d6 + {{exemplar-ability:modifier}} necrotic damage. When you negate a critical hit, you can spend 1 willpower to reduce any damage you take from the attack to 0, and the attacker takes the full amount of damage it would have dealt to you (as if it critically hit you) as necrotic damage.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Reject Death" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_DEATH_REJECT_DEATH">
                <supports>Exemplar Exalted Boon</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>When you’re reduced to 0 hit points as a result of taking damage, you can drop to 1 hit point instead. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b>Willpower.</b> You can spend 1 willpower when you use this boon to drop to a number of hit points equal to 5 + your examplar level.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                    <description>When you’re reduced to 0 hit points as a result of taking damage, you can drop to 1 hit point instead. You can spend 1 willpower when you use this boon to drop to {{reject-death:hp}} hit points.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="reject-death:hp" value="5" />
                    <stat name="reject-death:hp" value="level:exemplar" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Umbral Armor" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_DEATH_UMBRAL_ARMOR">
                <supports>Exemplar Exalted Boon</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>You can use your action to conjure and don a set of shadow armor. If you’re wearing armor when you use this feature, the shadows wrap around your armor, shrouding it in solid black. While wearing the armor, your AC equals 17 (your Dexterity modifier doesn’t affect this number), unless it would be higher. The shadowed armor disappears if you fall unconscious or if you use this feature again.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b>Willpower.</b> You can spend 1 willpower as a bonus action to bolster your armor for 1 minute. While the armor is bolstered and you take damage greater than 5 + half your exemplar level, you can reduce that damage by an amount equal to 5 + half your exemplar level. This effect then ends.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet action="Action">
                    <description>You can conjure and done a set of shadow armor. While wearing the armor, your AC equals 17 (your Dexterity modifier doesn’t affect this number), unless it would be higher. The shadowed armor disappears if you fall unconscious or if you use this feature again. You can spend 1 willpower as a bonus action to bolster your armor for 1 minute. While the armor is bolstered, you can reduce that damage by {{umbral-armor:reduction}}. This effect then ends.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="umbral-armor:reduction" value="5" />
                    <stat name="umbral-armor:reduction" value="level:exemplar:half" />
                </rules>
            </element>


        <element name="Aspect of Light" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXEMPLAR_ASPECT_OF_LIGHT">
            <supports>Exemplar Heroic Aspect</supports>
            <description>
                <p>The aspect of light embodies truth and compassion. Those who adopt this aspect are a force of precision, ensuring that both their own strikes, and those of their allies, land swift and true.</p>
                <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_ASPECT_OF_LIGHT_ASPECT_RITE" />
                <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_ASPECT_OF_LIGHT_RIGHTEOUS_ACT" />
                <h5>ASPECT OF LIGHT: BOONS</h5>
                <p class="indent">The following boons are available to an exemplar who adopts the aspect of light.</p>
                <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_BRILLIANT_GLEAM" />
                <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_HALO_OF_LIGHT" />
                <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_RADIANT_STRIKE" />
                <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_REACHING_LIGHT" />
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_BRILLIANT_GLEAM" level="20" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_HALO_OF_LIGHT" level="20" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_RADIANT_STRIKE" level="20" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_REACHING_LIGHT" level="20" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Aspect Rite" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_ASPECT_OF_LIGHT_ASPECT_RITE">
            <description>
                <p>You gain the following aspect rite, due to your connection to the aspect of light.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Guiding Light.</b> The first time you make a weapon attack on your turn, you gain a bonus to the attack roll. This bonus is equal to a d4.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet alt="Guiding Light">
                <description>The first time you make a weapon attack on your turn, you gain a +1d4 bonus to the attack roll.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Righteous Act" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_ASPECT_OF_LIGHT_RIGHTEOUS_ACT">
            <description>
                <p>You gain access to the following righteous act, due to your connection to the aspect of death.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Solar Ray.</b> You mark a creature within 60 feet of you with radiant light. At the end of that creature's next turn, a blast of light shoots down from the sky centered on that creature. The blast of light is a cylinder 20-feet wide and 10 miles high, and creatures of your choice in the blast must make a Constitution saving throw or become blinded for 1 minute. A blinded creature can repeat this saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on a success.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="2 willpower" action="Action" alt="Solar Ray">
                <description>You mark a creature within 60 feet of you with radiant light. At the end of that creature's next turn, a blast of light 20-feet wide and 10 miles high descends from the sky, and creatures of your choice in the blast must make a Constitution saving throw(DC {{exemplar:save-dc}}) or become blinded for 1 minute. A blinded creature can repeat this saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on a success.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Brilliant Gleam" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_BRILLIANT_GLEAM">
            <supports>Exemplar Exalted Boon</supports>
            <description>
                <p>When you make an attack roll against a creature with advantage and hit, you deal an additional 1d4 radiant damage.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Willpower.</b> You can spend 1 willpower when you take the Attack action, granting yourself advantage on weapon attacks you make until the end of the turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you make an attack roll against a creature with advantage and hit, you deal an additional 1d4 radiant damage. You can spend 1 willpower when you take the Attack action, granting yourself advantage on weapon attacks you make until the end of the turn.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Halo of Light" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_HALO_OF_LIGHT">
            <supports>Exemplar Exalted Boon</supports>
            <description>
                <p>You can summon a halo above your head as a bonus action, which lasts until you dismiss it (no action required). The halo sheds bright light in a 15-foot radius, and dim light for an additional 15 feet. Creatures of your choice have advantage on death saving throws while in the bright light shed by your halo.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Willpower.</b> You can spend 1 willpower as a bonus action while you have your halo of light to empower it. For 1 minute while empowered, the radius of bright and dim light shed by your halo is doubled, and if the light overlaps with an area of magical darkness, that area is lit for the duration.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>You can summon a halo above your head as a bonus action, which lasts until you dismiss it (no action required). The halo sheds bright light in a 15-foot radius, and dim light for an additional 15 feet. Creatures of your choice have advantage on death saving throws while in the bright light shed by your halo. You can spend 1 willpower as a bonus action while you have your halo of light to empower it. For 1 minute while empowered, the radius of bright and dim light shed by your halo is doubled, and if the light overlaps with an area of magical darkness, that area is lit for the duration.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Radiant Strike" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_RADIANT_STRIKE">
            <supports>Exemplar Exalted Boon</supports>
            <description>
                <p>Even your missed strikes still strike with the fury of light. Once per turn when you miss with a weapon attack, you can have the target of the attack take radiant damage equal to your exemplar ability modifier.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Willpower.</b> When you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can spend 1 willpower to deal an additional radiant damage equal to 1d6 + your exemplar ability modifier to it.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Once per turn when you miss with a weapon attack, you can have the target of the attack take radiant damage equal to your exemplar ability modifier. When you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can spend 1 willpower to deal an additional radiant damage equal to 1d6 + your exemplar ability modifier to it.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Reaching Light" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_REACHING_LIGHT">
            <supports>Exemplar Exalted Boon</supports>
            <description>
                <p>When you use the Help action to aid an ally in attacking a creature, the target of that attack can be within 30 feet of you, rather than within 5 feet of you, if the target can see you.</p>
                <p class="indent"><b>Willpower.</b> You can spend 1 willpower to take the Help action as a bonus action on your turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you use the Help action to aid an ally in attacking a creature, the target of that attack can be within 30 feet of you, rather than within 5 feet of you, if the target can see you. You can spend 1 willpower to take the Help action as a bonus action on your turn.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>

        
        <element name="Aspect of the Inferno" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXEMPLAR_ASPECT_OF_THE_INFERNO">
            <supports>Exemplar Heroic Aspect</supports>
            <description>
                <p>The aspect of the inferno represents ferocity and vengeance. Those who adopt this aspect are brutal on the battlefield, using their mastery of fire to punish those that dare face them.</p>
                <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_ASPECT_OF_THE_INFERNO_ASPECT_RITE" />
                <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_ASPECT_OF_THE_INFERNO_RIGHTEOUS_ACT" />
                <h5>ASPECT OF THE INFERNO: BOONS</h5>
                <p>The following boons are available to an exemplar who adopts the aspect of the inferno.</p>
                <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_THE_INFERNO_CLOAK_OF_EMBERS" />
                <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_THE_INFERNO_FIERY_CHARGE" />
                <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_THE_INFERNO_FLASHFIRE" />
                <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_THE_INFERNO_STOKE_THE_FLAMES" />
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_THE_INFERNO_CLOAK_OF_EMBERS" level="20" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_THE_INFERNO_FIERY_CHARGE" level="20" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_THE_INFERNO_FLASHFIRE" level="20" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_THE_INFERNO_STOKE_THE_FLAMES" level="20" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Aspect Rite" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_ASPECT_OF_THE_INFERNO_ASPECT_RITE">
                <description>
                    <p>You gain the following aspect rite, due to your connection to the aspect of the inferno.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b>Wildfire.</b> Whenever a creature within 30 feet of you hits you with an attack, you can use your reaction to deal 1d4 fire damage to it.</p>
                    <p class="indent">This damage increases to 1d6 at 5th level, 1d8 at 11th level, and 1d10 at 17th level.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet alt="Wildfire" action="Reaction">
                    <description>Whenever a creature within 30 feet of you hits you with an attack, you can use your reaction to deal 1d{{wildfire:die-type}} fire damage to it.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="wildfire:die-type" value="4" bonus="base" level="2" />
                    <stat name="wildfire:die-type" value="6" bonus="base" level="5" />
                    <stat name="wildfire:die-type" value="8" bonus="base" level="11" />
                    <stat name="wildfire:die-type" value="10" bonus="base" level="17" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Righteous Act" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_ASPECT_OF_THE_INFERNO_RIGHTEOUS_ACT">
                <description>
                    <p>You gain access to the following righteous act, due to your connection to the aspect of the inferno.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b>Vengeful Flare.</b> You can imbue yourself with the vengeful aspect of fire that burns inside you as an action. You enter a vengeful state for 1 minute, which grants you the following benefits:</p>
                    <ul>
                        <li>When you deal damage to a creature with your Wildfire rite, you can roll the damage twice and take the higher number.</li>
                        <li>Any damage you deal with your aspect features ignores resistance to fire damage.</li>
                        <li>When a creature hits you with an attack, you can move up to your speed as a reaction and make a weapon attack against it. This attack has advantage, and on a hit, you deal additional fire damage equal to 1d8 + twice your exemplar level. Your vengeful state then ends.</li>
                    </ul>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="2 willpower" action="Action" alt="Vengeful Flare">
                    <description>You enter a vengeful state for 1 minute, which grants you the following benefits: When you deal damage to a creature with your Wildfire rite, you can roll the damage twice and take the higher number. Any damage you deal with your aspect features ignores resistance to fire damage. When a creature hits you with an attack, you can move up to your speed as a reaction and make a weapon attack against it. This attack has advantage, and on a hit, you deal additional fire damage equal to 1d8 + twice your exemplar level. Your vengeful state then ends.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Cloak of Embers" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_THE_INFERNO_CLOAK_OF_EMBERS">
                <supports>Exemplar Exalted Boon</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>You can conjure a cloak made of smouldering embers. When you use your Wildfire rite, it deals additional fire damage equal to your exemplar ability modifier.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b>Willpower.</b> When you use your Wildfire rite, you can spend 1 willpower and have creatures of your choice within 10 feet of you other than the target of the rite take fire damage equal to your exemplar ability modifier.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>You can conjure a cloak made of smouldering embers. When you use your Wildfire rite, it deals additional fire damage equal to your exemplar ability modifier. When you use your Wildfire rite, you can spend 1 willpower and have creatures of your choice within 10 feet of you other than the target of the rite take fire damage equal to your exemplar ability modifier.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Fiery Charge" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_THE_INFERNO_FIERY_CHARGE">
                <supports>Exemplar Exalted Boon</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>As an action on your turn, you can charge forward in a line 5-feet wide. The length of the line is equal to half your walking speed. You keep charging until you impact a solid surface or a creature, or until you reach the end of the line. If you strike a creature, it must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, you strike the target and stop moving. When you strike something, whatever you strike takes fire damage equal to 2d8 + half your exemplar level.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b>Willpower.</b> When you strike a creature with your fiery charge, you can spend 1 willpower and push the creature up to 20 feet directly away from you. If the creature collides with terrain, and object, or another creature, it takes 1d8 bludgeoning damage.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet action="Action">
                    <description>You can charge forward in a line 5-feet wide and {{speed:half}} feet long. If you strike a creature, it must make a Dexterity saving throw (DC {{exemplar:Save-dc}}). On a failed save, you strike the target and stop moving. When you strike something, whatever you strike takes 2d8 + {{level:exemplar:half}} fire damage. When you strike a creature with your fiery charge, you can spend 1 willpower and push the creature up to 20 feet directly away from you. If the creature collides with terrain, and object, or another creature, it takes 1d8 bludgeoning damage.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Flashfire" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_THE_INFERNO_FLASHFIRE">
                <supports>Exemplar Exalted Boon</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>Once per turn when you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack, you can teleport to an unoccupied space within 5 feet of it that you can see.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b>Willpower.</b> When you teleport after hitting a creature with a melee weapon attack, you can spend 1 willpower an teleport to an unoccupied space within 15 feet of it.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>Once per turn when you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack, you can teleport to an unoccupied space within 5 feet of it that you can see. When you teleport after hitting a creature with a melee weapon attack, you can spend 1 willpower an teleport to an unoccupied space within 15 feet of it.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Stoke the Flames" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_THE_INFERNO_STOKE_THE_FLAMES">
                <supports>Exemplar Exalted Boon</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can ignite any weapons you’re holding, which become wreathed in flame until the end of your turn. While a weapon is wreathed in flame, attacks you make with it deal an additional 1d10 fire damage on hit. You can’t use this boon again until you finish a long rest.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b>Willpower.</b> You can spend 1 willpower when you ignite your weapons, granting yourself advantage on weapon attacks you make before the end of your turn.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                    <description>When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can ignite any weapons you’re holding. Attacks you make with it deal an additional 1d10 fire damage on hit. You can spend 1 willpower when you ignite your weapons, granting yourself advantage on weapon attacks you make before the end of your turn.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>

        <element name="Aspect of the Storm" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXEMPLAR_ASPECT_OF_THE_STORM">
            <supports>Exemplar Heroic Aspect</supports>
            <description>
                <p>The aspect of the storm embodies power and justice. Those who adopt this aspect strike true on the battlefield, landing blows as powerful as lightning bolts.</p>
                <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_ASPECT_OF_THE_STORM_ASPECT_RITE" />
                <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_ASPECT_OF_THE_STORM_RIGHTEOUS_ACT" />
                <h5>ASPECT OF THE STORM: BOONS</h5>
                <p>The following boons are available to an exemplar who adopts the aspect of the storm.</p>
                <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_THE_STORM_CLOUDSTRIKE" />
                <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_THE_STORM_DISTANT_STORM" />
                <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_THE_STORM_HIGH_VOLTAGE" />
                <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_THE_STORM_LIGHTNING_SURGE" />
            </description>
            <sheet display="false" />
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_THE_STORM_CLOUDSTRIKE" level="20" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_THE_STORM_DISTANT_STORM" level="20" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_THE_STORM_HIGH_VOLTAGE" level="20" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_THE_STORM_LIGHTNING_SURGE" level="20" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Aspect Rite" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_ASPECT_OF_THE_STORM_ASPECT_RITE">
                <description>
                    <p>You gain the following aspect rite, due to your connection to the aspect of the storm.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b>Arcing Storm.</b> Once per turn when you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can have lightning arc off it towards another creature within 15 feet of it. That creature takes 1d4 lightning damage.</p>
                    <p class="indent">This damage increases to 1d6 at 5th level, 1d8 at 11th level, and 1d10 at 17th level.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet alt="Arcing Storm">
                    <description>Once per turn when you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can have lightning arc off it towards another creature within 15 feet of it. That creature takes 1d{{arcing-storm:die-type}} lightning damage.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="arcing-storm:die-type" value="4" bonus="base" level="2" />
                    <stat name="arcing-storm:die-type" value="6" bonus="base" level="5" />
                    <stat name="arcing-storm:die-type" value="8" bonus="base" level="11" />
                    <stat name="arcing-storm:die-type" value="10" bonus="base" level="17" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Righteous Act" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_ASPECT_OF_THE_STORM_RIGHTEOUS_ACT">
                <description>
                    <p>You gain access to the following righteous act, due to your connection to the aspect of the storm.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b>Lightning Strike.</b> You can call down the fury of the storm as an action. Choose up to three points that you can see within 60 feet of you. Creatures within 5 feet of a point must make a Dexterity saving throw, taking lightning damage equal to 2d6 + your exemplar level on a failed save, and half as much damage on a success. A creature in the area of more than one lightning strike is affected only once.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="2 willpower" action="Action" alt="Lightning Strike">
                    <description>Choose up to three points that you can see within 60 feet of you. Creatures within 5 feet of a point must make a Dexterity saving throw (DC {{exemplar:save-dc}}), taking 2d6 + {{level:exemplar}} lightning damage on a failed save, and half as much damage on a success. A creature in the area of more than one lightning strike is affected only once.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Cloudstrike" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_THE_STORM_CLOUDSTRIKE">
                <supports>Exemplar Exalted Boon</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>Your accuracy calls lightning. Whenever you score a critical hit, you can have the target of the attack and creatures of your choice within 5 feet of it take 1d10 lightning damage.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b>Willpower.</b> When you score a critical hit, you can spend 1 willpower. Doing so increases the lightning damage by an amount equal to 1d10, and the cloudstrike effects creatures of your choice within 10 feet of the target.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>Whenever you score a critical hit, you can have the target of the attack and creatures of your choice within 5 feet of it take 1d10 lightning damage. When you score a critical hit, you can spend 1 willpower. Doing so increases the lightning damage by an amount equal to 1d10, and the cloudstrike effects creatures of your choice within 10 feet of the target.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Distant Storm" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_THE_STORM_DISTANT_STORM">
                <supports>Exemplar Exalted Boon</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>Once on each of your turns when you make a weapon attack, you can have your reach for that attack be 5 feet greater than normal if you make a melee weapon attack, or increase your weapon’s short range by 30 feet if you’re making a ranged weapon attack.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b>Willpower.</b> When you extend the reach or range of a weapon attack you make, you can spend 1 willpower to double the bonus reach or range of that attack, and have the attack deal lightning damage, instead of it’s usual damage type.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>Once on each of your turns when you make a weapon attack, you can have your reach for that attack be 5 feet greater than normal if you make a melee weapon attack, or increase your weapon’s short range by 30 feet if you’re making a ranged weapon attack. When you extend the reach or range of a weapon attack you make, you can spend 1 willpower to double the bonus reach or range of that attack, and have the attack deal lightning damage, instead of it’s usual damage type.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="High Voltage" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_THE_STORM_HIGH_VOLTAGE">
                <supports>Exemplar Exalted Boon</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>Lightning surges inside of you, awaiting an outlet. You gain a bonus to your initiative rolls equal to your exemplar ability modifier, and when you roll lightning damage during the first round of combat, you can roll the damage dice twice and take the higher result.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b>Willpower.</b> You can spend 1 willpower when you roll initiative as a reaction to choose two creatures you can see within the range of your Arcing Storm rite, dealing your arcing storm damage to each of those creatures.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>When you roll lightning damage during the first round of combat, you can roll the damage dice twice and take the higher result. You can spend 1 willpower when you roll initiative as a reaction to choose two creatures you can see within the range of your Arcing Storm rite, dealing your arcing storm damage to each of those creatures.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="initiative" value="exemplar-ability:modifier" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Lightning Surge" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_THE_STORM_LIGHTNING_SURGE">
                <supports>Exemplar Exalted Boon</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>Once per turn when you deal lightning damage to a creature with one of your exemplar features, you can cause another creature within 15 feet of the first creature to take half as much lightning damage.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b>Willpower.</b> You can spend 1 willpower to have the damage be equal to the original damage dealt, and have it bounce to an additional number of creatures equal to your exemplar ability modifier. A creature can’t take this damage more than once per turn, and it can’t bounce to the initial creature.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>Once per turn when you deal lightning damage to a creature with one of your exemplar features, you can cause another creature within 15 feet of the first creature to take half as much lightning damage. You can spend 1 willpower to have the damage be equal to the original damage dealt, and have it bounce to an additional {{exemplar-ability:modifier}} creatures. A creature can’t take this damage more than once per turn, and it can’t bounce to the initial creature.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>

        <element name="Aspect of Winter" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXEMPLAR_ASPECT_OF_WINTER">
            <supports>Exemplar Heroic Aspect</supports>
            <description>
                <p>The aspect of winter embodies hardship and pain. Those who adopt this aspect are able to easily cripple their foes, leaving them helpless suffer the weight of winter.</p>
                <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_ASPECT_OF_WINTER_ASPECT_RITE" />
                <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_ASPECT_OF_WINTER_RIGHTEOUS_ACT" />
                <h5>ASPECT OF WINTER: BOONS</h5>
                <p>The following boons are available to an exemplar who adopts the aspect of winter.</p>
                <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_WINTER_BITING_COLD" />
                <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_WINTER_GLACIAL_GRASP" />
                <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_WINTER_SNAP_FREEZE" />
                <div element="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_WINTER_FROST_WALL" />
            </description>
            <sheet display="false" />
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_WINTER_BITING_COLD" level="20" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_WINTER_GLACIAL_GRASP" level="20" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_WINTER_SNAP_FREEZE" level="20" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_WINTER_FROST_WALL" level="20" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Aspect Rite" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_ASPECT_OF_WINTER_ASPECT_RITE">
                <description>
                    <p>You gain the following aspect rite, due to your connection to the aspect of winter.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b>Freezing Chill.</b> Once per turn when you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can reduce it’s speed by 10 feet until the start of your next turn.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet alt="Freezing Chill">
                    <description>Once per turn when you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can reduce it’s speed by 10 feet until the start of your next turn.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Righteous Act" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_ASPECT_OF_WINTER_RIGHTEOUS_ACT">
                <description>
                    <p>You gain access to the following righteous act, due to your connection to the aspect of the storm.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b>Bitter Winter.</b> You can embrace the chill of winter as an action, causing a winter storm to appear in a 10-foot radius sphere centered on a point you can see within 30 feet of you. The sphere is lightly obscured, and creatures of your choice inside of it have their movement speed reduced by half and can’t take reactions. At the start of each of your turns, the radius of the sphere increases by 5 feet, to a maximum of a 40-foot radius sphere.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="2 willpower" action="Action" alt="Bitter Winter">
                    <description>You cause a winter storm to appear in a 10-foot radius sphere centered on a point you can see within 30 feet of you. The sphere is lightly obscured, and creatures of your choice inside of it have their movement speed reduced by half and can’t take reactions. At the start of each of your turns, the radius of the sphere increases by 5 feet, to a maximum of a 40-foot radius sphere.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Biting Cold" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_WINTER_BITING_COLD">
                <supports>Exemplar Exalted Boon</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>Once per turn when you hit a creature who’s movement speed has been reduced or is 0, you can deal additional cold damage to it equal to 1d4 + your exemplar ability modifier.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b>Willpower.</b> You can spend 1 willpower when you deal this additional damage to have the target make a Strength saving throw, becoming restrained until the start of your next turn on a failed save.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>Once per turn when you hit a creature who’s movement speed has been reduced or is 0, you can deal additional 1d4 + {{exemplar-ability:modifier}} cold damage. You can spend 1 willpower when you deal this additional damage to have the target make a Strength saving throw (DC {{exemplar:save-dc}}), or be restrained until the start of your next turn.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Glacial Grasp" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_WINTER_GLACIAL_GRASP">
                <supports>Exemplar Exalted Boon</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>When a creature starts its turn within 5 feet of you, you can use your reaction to force it to make a Strength saving throw. On a failed save, it can’t move further than 15 feet away from you until the start of its next turn.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b>Willpower.</b> When a creature fails its saving throw, you can spend 1 willpower to enhance your grasp. The creature can’t move further than 5 feet away from you until the start of it’s next turn.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet action="Reaction">
                    <description>When a creature starts its turn within 5 feet of you, you can use your reaction to force it to make a Strength saving throw (DC {{exemplar:save-dc}}). On a failed save, it can’t move further than 15 feet away from you until the start of its next turn.  When a creature fails its saving throw, you can spend 1 willpower to enhance your grasp. The creature can’t move further than 5 feet away from you until the start of it’s next turn.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Snap Freeze" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_WINTER_SNAP_FREEZE">
                <supports>Exemplar Exalted Boon</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>When you take the Dodge action, you can cause the ground within 10 feet of you to freeze over with ice for 1 minute, or until you use this feature again. Creatures of your choice that enter the area or starts its turn on the ice must make a Dexterity saving throw or fall prone.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b>Willpower.</b> When you use this feature, you can spend 1 willpower to freeze the ground within 20 feet of you for 1 minute. Frozen ground created this way remains frozen, even if you use this feature again.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>When you take the Dodge action, you can cause the ground within 10 feet of you to freeze over with ice for 1 minute, or until you use this feature again. Creatures of your choice that enter the area or starts its turn on the ice must make a Dexterity saving throw  (DC {{exemplar:save-dc}}) or fall prone. When you use this feature, you can spend 1 willpower to freeze the ground within 20 feet of you for 1 minute. Frozen ground created this way remains frozen, even if you use this feature again.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Frost Wall" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXALTED_BOON_ASPECT_OF_WINTER_FROST_WALL">
                <supports>Exemplar Exalted Boon</supports>
                <description>
                    <p>As an action on your turn, you conjure a wall of ice on the ground between two points within 15 feet of each other and are within 30 feet of you. This wall is a 1 foot thick, 5 feet high, and provides half cover to creatures within 5 feet of it. If the wall cuts through a creature’s space when it appears, the creature is pushed to one side of the wall (your choice).</p>
                    <p class="indent">The wall is an object made of ice that can be damaged and destroyed. The wall has an AC of 15, hit points equal to 10 + your exemplar level. The wall lasts for 1 minute, until it’s reduced to 0 hit points, or until you use this feature again, at which point the wall shatters harmlessly.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><b>Willpower.</b> You can spend 1 willpower when you summon the wall to immediately summon a second wall of ice as part of the same action. If you summon a third wall, both walls shatter.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet action="Action">
                    <description>You conjure a wall of ice on the ground between two points within 15 feet of each other and are within 30 feet of you. This wall is a 1 foot thick, 5 feet high, and provides half cover to creatures within 5 feet of it. If the wall cuts through a creature’s space when it appears, the creature is pushed to one side of the wall (your choice). You can spend 1 willpower when you summon the wall to immediately summon a second wall of ice as part of the same action. If you summon a third wall, both walls shatter.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                </rules>
            </element>

    <!-- Exemplar Sublime Boons -->    
        <element name="Absolute Zero" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_ABSOLUTE_ZERO">
            <supports>Exemplar Sublime Boon</supports>
            <compendium display="false" />
            <requirements>ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXEMPLAR_ASPECT_OF_WINTER</requirements>
            <description>
                <p><p class="flavor">Requirements: Aspect of Winter</p></p>
                <p class="indent">Your very presence chills the air. Creatures of your choice treat any space within 10 feet of you as difficult terrain.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Creatures of your choice treat any space within 10 feet of you as difficult terrain.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Blinding Flare" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_BLINDING_FLARE">
            <supports>Exemplar Sublime Boon</supports>
            <compendium display="false" />
            <requirements>ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXEMPLAR_ASPECT_OF_FIRE</requirements>
            <description>
                <p><p class="flavor">Requirements: Aspect of Fire</p></p>
                <p class="indent">When you use your Wildfire rite on a creature, it must make a Constitution saving throw or become blinded until the start of their next turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you use your Wildfire rite on a creature, it must make a Constitution saving throw or become blinded until the start of their next turn.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Brightest Light" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_BRIGHTEST_LIGHT">
            <supports>Exemplar Sublime Boon</supports>
            <compendium display="false" />
            <requirements>ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXEMPLAR_ASPECT_OF_LIGHT</requirements>
            <description>
                <p><p class="flavor">Requirements: Aspect of Light</p></p>
                <p class="indent">You inner light always guides you. You gain the benefits of your Guiding Light rite for each attack you make on your turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You gain the benefits of your Guiding Light rite for each attack you make on your turn.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Enduring Body" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_ENDURING_BODY">
            <supports>Exemplar Sublime Boon</supports>
            <compendium display="false" />
            <requirements>ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXEMPLAR_ASPECT_OF_DEATH</requirements>
            <description>
                <p><p class="flavor">Requirements: Aspect of Death</p></p>
                <p class="indent">You're able to rise above death. You regain hit points equal to 1d6 + your exemplar ability modifier if you end your turn in combat with fewer than half of your hit points remaining and you aren't incapacitated.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You regain 1d6 + {{exemplar-ability:modifier}} hit points if you end your turn in combat with fewer than half of your hit points remaining and you aren't incapacitated.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Lightning Storm" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_LIGHTNING_STORM">
            <supports>Exemplar Sublime Boon</supports>
            <compendium display="false" />
            <requirements>ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXEMPLAR_ASPECT_OF_THE_STORM</requirements>
            <description>
                <p><p class="flavor">Requirements: Aspect of the Storm</p></p>
                <p class="indent">Your lightning arcs across the battlefield as you effortlessly control it. When you use your Arcing Storm rite, the initial target of the attack also takes the rite's damage. Additionally, you can have two lightning bolts arc from the initial target towards two different targets. The distance you can have the lightning arc increases by 15 feet.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you use your Arcing Storm rite, the initial target of the attack also takes the rite's damage. Additionally, you can have two lightning bolts arc from the initial target towards two different targets. The distance you can have the lightning arc increases by 15 feet.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Tempest's Wings" type="Class Feature" source="Rain-Junkie’s Exemplar" id="ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_TEMPESTS_WINGS">
            <supports>Exemplar Sublime Boon</supports>
            <compendium display="false" />
            <requirements>ID_RJ_TEC_CLASS_FEATURE_EXEMPLAR_ASPECT_OF_AIR</requirements>
            <description>
                <p><p class="flavor">Requirements: Aspect of Air</p></p>
                <p class="indent">You cause a large pair of magical wings sprout from your back, granting you a flying speed equal to half your current speed. You can create these wings as a bonus action on your turn. They last until you dismiss them (no action required).</p>
                <p class="indent">The wings you summon can take on an appearance of your choice, but appear somewhat translucent and obviously magical, and as such, don't impede you or affect any armor you're wearing.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>You cause a large pair of magical wings sprout from your back, granting you a flying speed equal to half your current speed.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>

    <!-- Exemplar Skills -->
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ACROBATICS">
            <supports>RJ Exemplar</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ATHLETICS">
            <supports>RJ Exemplar</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT">
            <supports>RJ Exemplar</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INVESTIGATION">
            <supports>RJ Exemplar</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION">
            <supports>RJ Exemplar</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERSUASION">
            <supports>RJ Exemplar</supports>
        </append>
</elements>