<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Bard College of Stars</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="bard-college-of-stars.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/aoths-grimore-to-aberrations/bard-college-of-stars.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>

    <element name="College of Stars" type="Archetype" source="Aoth’s Grimoire to Aberrations" id="ID_DAKOTA_AGTA_ARCHETYPE_BARD_COLLEGE_OF_STARS">
        <supports>Bard College</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The world we know is full of beauty. Beyond Faerun, the sight of the differing planes is magnificent. Bards that observe the night sky are often inspired by the stars and Selune. Often times, these bards take up other mediums of artwork, instead of song. This can be crafting jewelry or painting, in order to capture its glory.</p>
            <p class="indent">Their craft can manifest objects from outside of the material plane, granting minor boons or causing harm to others.</p>
            <div element="ID_DAKOTA_AGTA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_STARS_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" />
            <div element="ID_DAKOTA_AGTA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_STARS_MANIFEST_METEORITES" />
            <div element="ID_DAKOTA_AGTA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_STARS_COMET_TAILS" />
            <div element="ID_DAKOTA_AGTA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_STARS_PROTECTION_OF_THE_FALLEN_STAR" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DAKOTA_AGTA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_STARS_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DAKOTA_AGTA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_STARS_MANIFEST_METEORITES" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DAKOTA_AGTA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_STARS_COMET_TAILS" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DAKOTA_AGTA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_STARS_PROTECTION_OF_THE_FALLEN_STAR" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Bonus Proficiencies" type="Archetype Feature" source="Aoth’s Grimoire to Aberrations" id="ID_DAKOTA_AGTA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_STARS_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES">
            <description>
                <p>At 3rd level, you gain proficiency with two of the following choices - Glassblower’s Tools, Jeweler’s tools, or Painter’s Supplies. You can use either of these items as a spell focus to cast spells.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can use either of your College bonus proficiencies as a spell focus to cast spells.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Proficiency" name="Tool Proficiency, College of Stars" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_GLASSBLOWERS_TOOLS|ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_JEWELERS_TOOLS|ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_PAINTERS_SUPPLIES" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Manifest Meteorites" type="Archetype Feature" source="Aoth’s Grimoire to Aberrations" id="ID_DAKOTA_AGTA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_STARS_MANIFEST_METEORITES">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 3rd level, you create small rocks that orbit around your body, protecting you. As a bonus action, you can roll a bardic inspiration die. A number of meteors float around your head, equal to the result of the die. As part of the bonus action, and on other turns, you can fire one of these objects. It has a normal range of 30 feet, and a long range of 120 feet.</p>
                <p class="indent">Make a ranged spell attack, using your spell attack bonus. On a hit, the creature takes 1d6 damage of one of the following types - cold, fire, or radiant. Hit or miss, the object is destroyed.</p>
                <p class="indent">While you have at least one of these objects, you cannot create more.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>You can roll a bardic inspiration die. A number of meteors float around your head, equal to the result of the die. As part of the bonus action, and on other turns, you can fire one of these objects. It has a normal range of 30 feet, and a long range of 120 feet. Make a ranged spell attack, using your spell attack bonus. On a hit, the creature takes 1d6 damage of one of the following types - cold, fire, or radiant. Hit or miss, the object is destroyed. While you have at least one of these objects, you cannot create more.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Comet Tails" type="Archetype Feature" source="Aoth’s Grimoire to Aberrations" id="ID_DAKOTA_AGTA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_STARS_COMET_TAILS">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, you are protected by the meteors you have around you. Whenever a creature provokes an opportunity attack and you have at least one object remaining from your Manifest Meteorites feature, you can instead use your reaction to force them to make a Dexterity saving throw against your spell save DC.</p>
                <p class="indent">On a failure, the creature takes damage equal to your bard level, plus your Charisma modifier. This damage can be one of the following types - cold, fire, or radiant, and are also under the effect of one of the following traits below, depending on the damage type:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Cold: The creature has their speed drop to 0 until the end of their next turn.</li>
                    <li>Fire: The creature drops whatever they are holding in their hands, and cannot pick it up until the start of their next turn as an Action.</li>
                    <li>Radiant: The creature emits bright light for 10 feet, and dim light for another 10 feet beyond that. This light stays for 1 minute.</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">On a success, the creature only takes half damage. All of your meteorites from the Manifest Meteorites feature are expended.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Reaction">
                <description>Whenever a creature provokes an opportunity attack and you have at least one object remaining from your Manifest Meteorites feature, you can instead use your reaction to force them to make a Dexterity saving throw (save DC {{spellcasting:dc}}). On a failure, the creature takes {{level:bard}} of cold, fire or radiant damage (your choice). Cold: The targets speed rops to 0 unitl the end of their next turn. Fire: The target drops whatever they are holding and cannot pick it up until the start of their next turn as an Action. Radiant: The target emits bright light for 10 feet, and dim light for another 10 feet, for 1 minute.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Protection of the Fallen Star" type="Archetype Feature" source="Aoth’s Grimoire to Aberrations" id="ID_DAKOTA_AGTA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_STARS_PROTECTION_OF_THE_FALLEN_STAR">
            <description>
                <p>At 14th level, you can grant the protection of the stars to others. As a bonus action, or as part of the Manifest Meteorites feature, you can grab one of the objects and give it to another creature. A creature can destroy one of the objects as an Action, gaining one benefit of their choice below:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>The creature has darkvision out to 120 feet for 8 hours.</li>
                    <li>The creature is cured of one poison or disease currently affecting them.</li>
                    <li>The creature has resistance to one of the following damage types for 8 hours - cold, fire, or radiant.</li>
                    <li>The creature gains temporary hit points equal to their level.</li>
                    <li>The creature can choose to succeed on one failed saving throw in the next 8 hours.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>As a bonus action, or as part of the Manifest Meteorites feature, you can grab one of the objects and give it to another creature. A creature can destroy one of the objects as an Action, gaining one benefit of their choice: darkvision out 120 feet for 8 hours; cured of one poison or disease; resistance to cold, fire or radiant damage for 8 hours; temporary hit points equal to their level; or, chosse to succeed a failed saving throw in the next 8 hours.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
</elements>