<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Soul Binder</name>
        <auther url="https://www.reddit.com/user/FragSauce/">u/FragSauce</auther>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="class-soul-binder.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/classes/soul-binder/class-soul-binder.xml" />
        </update>
        <!-- https://www.gmbinder.com/share/-LlQlr97n5ERN5NmmGxi -->
    </info>
    
    <element name="Soul Binder" type="Class" source="GM Binder" id="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_CLASS_SOUL_BINDER">
        <description>
            <p>Loneliness. Weakness. The call to adventure. For most people these are passing moments, a part of the ups and downs of everyday life. There are those however, who are defined by these feelings. Whether feeling alone in a crowd, powerless to get what they deserve or eager to see all things the world has to offer, soul binders have taken a drastic step to solve their problems. Unable to meet the demands of the world alone they choose to give up a piece of their soul to bond with another creature and face life’s challenges together.</p>
            <h4>A COMPANION FOR LIFE</h4>
            <p>When soul binders bind themselves to another creature, they do so for life. They will stand together, always, two against the world. They will always look out for each other, because in the end, they need each other. Whether they like it or not. The companion will often be the stronger of the pair, but without the binder to guide it, the companion is nowhere near its full potential.</p>
            <h4>SPLIT SOUL</h4>
            <p>The process of binding your soul with another creature can be quite taxing, especially if the creature isn’t willing at first. Some people disappear into the wild to find a forest animal willing to bind, and return months later with a beast by their side willing to do anything for them, while others would rather summon a creature of untold horror, force it into submission, then bind the creature to follow their command.</p>
            <p class="indent">However, having your soul bound to another creature means that your soul will never be full again. There is always something missing. It gets even more apparent for the soul binder when their companion is far away from them, and can sometimes be physically painful for them to be a great distance from their companion.</p>
            <h4>CREATING A SOUL BINDER</h4>
            <p>When making your soul binder you must consider how you got your companion. Did you travel the world to seek a companion, was it easy for you, or was it a life goal, was it even your choice to bind your soul? Maybe you were captured by cultist, that forced you to bind with a creature against your and the creatures will.</p>
            <p class="indent">What kind of relationship do you have with your companion? Are you two inseparable friends? Or is it more of a master and servant relationship. Sometimes a Soul Binder might regret the act of soul binding and want to undo it, though it is a hard and lengthy process.</p>
            <p class="indent">Soul Binders are in contact with their companion like no other two beings will ever be, and when you play as a Soul Binder you can describe how you and your companion act.</p>
            <h5>QUICK BUILD</h5>
            <p>You can make a soul binder fast by following these suggestions. First, Charisma should be your highest ability modifier, followed by Constitution or Dexterity, depending if you need to take damage, or deal it. Second, you should take the Hermit background.</p>
            <h2>CLASS FEATURES</h2>
            <p>As an class, you gain the following class features.</p>
            <h5>HIT POINTS</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Hit Dice:</strong> 1d6 per class level</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at 1st Level:</strong> 6 + your Constitution modifier</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at Higher Levels:</strong> 1d6 (or 4) + your Constitution modifier per class level after 1st</li>
            </ul>
            <h5>PROFICIENCIES</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Armor:</strong> Light armor</li>
                <li><strong>Weapons:</strong> Simple weapons</li>
                <li><strong>Tools:</strong> Choose one type of artisan’s tools or one musical instrument.</li>
            </ul>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Saving Throws:</strong> Constitution, Charisma</li>
                <li><strong>Skills:</strong> Choose two from Animal Handling, History, Nature, Insight, Arcana, Persuasion, Intimidation.</li>
            </ul>
            <h5>EQUIPMENT</h5>
            <p>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>(a) two daggers (b) any simple weapon or (c) any martial weapon (if proficient)</li>
                <li>(a) a priest’s pack or (b) a scholar’s pack</li>
                <li>(a) a set of leather armor or (b) a set of scale mail (if proficient)</li>
                <li>(a) a set of tools of your choice</li>
            </ul>
            <div element="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SOUL_BINDER_SOUL_BOND" />
            <div element="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SOUL_BINDER_BONDED_COMPANION" />
            <div element="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SOUL_BINDER_SOULBOUND_TRAITS" />
            <div element="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SOUL_BINDER_MAGIC_ITEM_ABSORPTION" />
            <div element="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SOUL_BINDER_SPELLCASTING" />
            <div element="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SOUL_BINDER_EDICT" />
            <div element="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SOUL_BINDER_HIDDEN_FORM" />
            <div element="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SOUL_BINDER_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" />
            <div element="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SOUL_BINDER_ADVANCED_OFFENSE" />
            <div element="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SOUL_BINDER_SOUL_LINKED_CASTING" />
            <div element="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SOUL_BINDER_COMPANIONS_PROTECTION" />
            <div element="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SOUL_BINDER_RESTING_VOICE" />
            <div element="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SOUL_BINDER_COUNTERMEASURE" />
            <div element="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SOUL_BINDER_SOUL_PURIFICATION" />
            <div element="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SOUL_BINDER_INFUSED_ENERGY" />
            <div element="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SOUL_BINDER_QUICK_RENEWAL" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <setters>
            <set name="hd">d6</set>
            <set name="short">A being that has bound its soul to a companion for life.</set>
        </setters>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" />
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Tools Proficiency (Soul Binder)" number="2" supports="Tool||Musical Instrument" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CHARISMA" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CONSTITUTION" />
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency (Soul Binder)" number="2" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ANIMALHANDLING|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_HISTORY|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_NATURE|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ARCANA|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERSUASION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INTIMIDATION" />

            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SOUL_BINDER_SOUL_BOND" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SOUL_BINDER_BONDED_COMPANION" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SOUL_BINDER_SOULBOUND_TRAITS" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SOUL_BINDER_MAGIC_ITEM_ABSORPTION" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SOUL_BINDER_SPELLCASTING" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SOUL_BINDER_EDICT" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SOUL_BINDER_HIDDEN_FORM" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SOUL_BINDER_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" level="4" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SOUL_BINDER_ADVANCED_OFFENSE" level="5" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SOUL_BINDER_SOUL_LINKED_CASTING" level="5" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SOUL_BINDER_COMPANIONS_PROTECTION" level="6" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SOUL_BINDER_RESTING_VOICE" level="9" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SOUL_BINDER_COUNTERMEASURE" level="10" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SOUL_BINDER_SOUL_PURIFICATION" level="14" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SOUL_BINDER_INFUSED_ENERGY" level="18" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SOUL_BINDER_QUICK_RENEWAL" level="20" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Soul Bond" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SOUL_BINDER_SOUL_BOND">
        <description>
            <p>At 1st level, you have chosen to sacrifice a piece of your own soul to gain the aid of a creature stronger than you. You can choose one of several bonds detailed at the end of the class description. Your choice grants you additional features when you reach 3rd level and again at 7th, 11th and 15th levels.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Archetype" name="Soul Bond" supports="Soul Bond" level="1" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Bonded Companion" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SOUL_BINDER_BONDED_COMPANION">
        <description>
            <p>At 1st level, you gain a companion that will serve and aid you in every way it possibly can. The companion gains bonuses from being linked to your essence. In combat, the companion moves and acts on your turn in initiative. You can command it verbally (no action needed) and if you are incapacitated, it will do its best to protect you and itself from harm.</p>
            <p class="indent">You and your companion both become empowered from the bond you share, but only one of you can take full advantage of that power at first. If you take the Attack action or cast a spell with a casting time of one action, your companion can’t take the Attack action on the same turn, and if your companion takes the Attack action, you can’t take the Attack action or cast a spell with a casting time of one action on the same turn.</p>
            <p class="indent">More details about your companion can be found in the "Soulbound Traits" feature.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>If you take the Attack action or cast a spell with a casting time of one action, your companion can’t take the Attack action on the same turn, and if your companion takes the Attack action, you can’t take the Attack action or cast a spell with a casting time of one action on the same turn.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Soulbound Traits" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SOUL_BINDER_SOULBOUND_TRAITS">
        <description>
            <p>Your soulbound companion has its own hit dice, and can spend them during a short rest. At first level, its hit points are equal to the maximum value of its hit dice + its Constitution modifier. Whenever you gain a level in this class, your companion also levels up, and it can increase its hit point maximum using its hit dice as normal.</p>
            <p class="indent">Whenever you gain the Ability Score Improvement class feature in this class, your companion’s abilities also improve. You can increase one of its ability scores of your choice by 2, or you can increase two of its ability scores of your choice by 1. At the DM’s discretion you can forgo increasing the companion’s ability scores and instead take one feat of your choice for it. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature unless its description specifies otherwise.</p>
            <p class="indent">Your companion aids you in and out of battle, as it gains bonuses for being linked to your essence. It gains proficiency in two skills of your choice. In areas where it would use its proficiency bonus, it uses your proficiency bonus instead. It also uses your proficiency bonus when calculating its AC.</p>
            <p class="indent">Your companion will always use Strength for its attack and damage rolls (unless otherwise specified), and its damage dice is shown in the companion’s stat block. If a feature for your companion requires another creature to make a saving throw, the DC is equal to your Spell Save DC.</p>
            <p class="indent">If your soulbound is reduced to 0 hit points, it falls unconscious and makes death saving throws. When it is reduced to 0 hit points, the soul binder will take any excess damage from the attack. If it is killed, you can return it to life as part of a long rest. The process of reviving can be very hard on your soul, gaining one level of exhaustion at the end of the rest when you revive your companion.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="companion:proficiency" value="proficiency" />
            <stat name="companion:level" value="level:soul binder" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Magic Item Absorption" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SOUL_BINDER_MAGIC_ITEM_ABSORPTION">
        <description>
            <p>At 1st level, the soul binder can perform a special ritual to merge a magic item into its companion during a short rest. Merging with an item requires physical contact between the soul binder, the item and the companion.</p>
            <p class="indent">Certain items have prerequisites. The companion must meet any prerequisite for the item to successfully merge with it. Your companion cannot merge with items requiring a class prerequisite. If the short rest is interrupted, the merging fails. Otherwise, at the end of the short rest, the item merges into the companion.</p>
            <p class="indent">While merged, the companion gains an intuitive understanding of how to activate any magical properties of the item, including any necessary Command words. Your companion can use the magical properties of the item and apply the effects to its natural weapons and natural armor, but doesn’t get the benefit of the armor or weapon itself. It can only have one weapon merged at a time, and one piece of armor. The companions natural weapons can only benefit from one of the merged items, and you can change this on a short rest, the same goes for it’s natural armor.</p>
            <p class="indent">Example: if you bind a +1 Plate armor to your companion it gains +1 to its AC, but not the benefits of wearing Plate armor</p>
            <p class="indent">Each merged item within the creature counts as an attunement for the soul binder, regardless if whether the item required attunement. Attempting to merge with more than three items fails automatically. The soul binder can voluntarily end the merge by spending another short rest focused on the item, unless the item is cursed.</p>
            <p class="indent">If the companion dies, all the merges items are expelled from its corpse on the ground around it.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can perform a special ritual to merge a magic item into its companion during a short rest. Merging with an item requires physical contact between the soul binder, the item and the companion.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Spellcasting" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SOUL_BINDER_SPELLCASTING">
        <description>
            <p>By 2nd level, you are now more used to being bonded to a magical creature, and have started to be able to use some magic to help your allies or bolster your companion. See Chapter 10 in the <i>Player’s Handbook</i> for the general rules of spellcasting and Chapter 11 for the soul binder spell list.</p>
            <h5>CANTRIPS</h5>
            <p>At 2nd level, you know two cantrips of your choice from the soul binder spell list. You learn an additional soul binder cantrip of your choice at 4th level and another at 10th level.</p>
            <h5>PREPARING AND CASTING SPELLS</h5>
            <p>The Soul Binder table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your soul binder spells. To cast one of your soul binder spells of 1st level or higher, you must expend a slot of the spell’s level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.</p>
            <p class="indent">You prepare the list of soul binder spells that are available for you to cast, choosing from the soul binder spell list. When you do so, choose a number of soul binder spells equal to your Charisma modifier + half your soul binder level (minimum of one spell). The spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots.</p>
            <p class="indent">For example, if you are a 5th-level soul binder, you have four 1st-level and two 2nd-level spell slots. With a Charisma of 14, your list of prepared spells can include four spells of 1st or 2nd level, in any combination. If you prepare the 1st-level spell heroism, you can cast it using a 1st-level or a 2nd-level slot. Casting the spell doesn’t remove it from your list of prepared spells.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can change your list of prepared spells when you finish a long rest. Preparing a new list of soul binder spells requires time spent in meditation with your companion: at least 1 minute per spell level for each spell on your list.</p>
            <h5>SPELLCASTING ABILITY</h5>
            <p>Charisma is your spellcasting ability for your soul binder spells, since the power of your magic relies on you being able to communicate with your companion and the bond that you share. You use your Charisma whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Charisma modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a soul binder spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.</p>
            <p class="indent">Spell Save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier</p>
            <p class="indent">Spell attack modifier = your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier</p>
            <h5>SPELLCASTING FOCUS</h5>
            <p>You can use an arcane focus (see the Adventuring Gear section) as a spellcasting focus for your soul binder spells.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="spellcaster">true</set>
            <set name="spellcastingClass">Soul Binder</set>
            <set name="spellcastingAbility">Charisma</set>
        </setters>
        <spellcasting name="Soul Binder" ability="Charisma" prepare="true">
            <list known="true">Soul Binder</list>
        </spellcasting>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS_SPELLCASTING_SLOTS_HALF" requirements="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS"/>

            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_INTERNAL_PROFICIENCY_SPELLFOCUS_GROUP_ARCANE_FOCUS" />

            <stat name="soul binder:spellcasting:slots:1" value="2" level="2" />
            <stat name="soul binder:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="3" />
            <stat name="soul binder:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="5" />
            <stat name="soul binder:spellcasting:slots:2" value="2" level="5" />
            <stat name="soul binder:spellcasting:slots:2" value="1" level="7" />
            <stat name="soul binder:spellcasting:slots:3" value="2" level="9" />
            <stat name="soul binder:spellcasting:slots:3" value="1" level="11" />
            <stat name="soul binder:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="13" />
            <stat name="soul binder:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="15" />
            <stat name="soul binder:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="17" />
            <stat name="soul binder:spellcasting:slots:5" value="1" level="17" />
            <stat name="soul binder:spellcasting:slots:5" value="1" level="19" />

            <stat name="soul binder:spellcasting:prepare" value="charisma:modifier" />
            <stat name="soul binder:spellcasting:prepare" value="level:soul binder:half" />

            <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Soul Binder)" number="2" supports="$(spellcasting:list), 0" spellcasting="Soul Binder" level="2" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Soul Binder)" number="1" supports="$(spellcasting:list), 0" spellcasting="Soul Binder" level="4" />
            <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Soul Binder)" number="1" supports="$(spellcasting:list), 0" spellcasting="Soul Binder" level="10" />

        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Edict" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SOUL_BINDER_EDICT">
        <description>
            <p>You have gotten better control over your companion and can give it more complicated commands. You can use a bonus action to speak a command to your companion. It must be able to hear you for the command to take effect. </p>
            <p class="indent">At 2nd level, you learn the following commands:</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Strike.</i></b> You command your companion to attack with extra ferocity. The next time your companion hits another creature with an attack this turn, that attack deals extra damage of the attack’s type equal to 1d8 plus your soul binder level.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Toughen Up.</i></b> You command your companion to toughen up and be ready to withstand even more blows. Your companion gains temporary hit points equal to 1d8 plus your soul binder level.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Block.</i></b> You command your companion to evade or block incoming attacks rather than taking them. The companion’s AC is increased by an amount equal to your Charisma modifier, until the end of your next turn.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Move.</i></b> You tell your companion that it needs to move fast, or move safely. When given this command your companion can take the Disengage or Dash action as a bonus action on this turn.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum of 1), regaining all uses on a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="{{edict:uses}}/{{edict:reset}}">
            <description>You can speak one of the following commands to your companion: Strike, Toughen Up, Block or Move.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="edict:uses" value="1" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="edict:uses" value="charisma:modifier" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="edict:reset" value="Long Rest" inline="true" level="2" />
            <stat name="edict:reset" value="Short Rest" inline="true" level="9" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Hidden Form" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SOUL_BINDER_HIDDEN_FORM">
        <description>
            <p>You have learned how to reduce your companion’s size or hide them on another plane for an easy way to hide or carry it. When you reach 3rd level you learn one of the following features:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><b><i>Shrink.</i></b> You can use your bonus action to change your companion’s size to Tiny or back to its full size if it is within 30 feet of you. If there isn’t enough space for it to grow to its original size, it instead takes 1d10 force damage and stays Tiny. While in Tiny form, the companion can’t attack in any way.</li>
                <li><b><i>Pocket Dimension.</i></b> As an action, you can temporarily dismiss your companion as long as it is within 5 feet of you. It disappears into a pocket dimension where it awaits your summons. As an action, while it is dismissed, you can cause it to reappear in any unoccupied space within 5 feet of you. If you go unconscious while your companion is in its pocket dimension, it reappears within 5 feet on you.</li>
                <li><b><i>Disguise.</i></b> As an action you can create an illusion around your companion that makes it look like another beast or humanoid of similar build and size, such as making a drake look like a dog, or a demon look like a farmer. The disguise end if your companion takes any damage, deals damage to another creature or you end it as an action.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Hidden Form" supports="Soul Binder Hidden Form" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Hidden Form: Shrink" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SOUL_BINDER_HIDDEN_FORM_SHRINK">
            <description>
                <p>You can use your bonus action to change your companion’s size to Tiny or back to its full size if it is within 30 feet of you. If there isn’t enough space for it to grow to its original size, it instead takes 1d10 force damage and stays Tiny. While in Tiny form, the companion can’t attack in any way.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>You can change your companion’s size to Tiny or back to its full size if it is within 30 feet of you. If there isn’t enough space for it to grow to its original size, it instead takes 1d10 force damage and stays Tiny. While in Tiny form, the companion can’t attack in any way.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Hidden Form: Pocket Dimension" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SOUL_BINDER_HIDDEN_FORM_POCKET_DIMENSION">
            <description>
                <p>As an action, you can temporarily dismiss your companion as long as it is within 5 feet of you. It disappears into a pocket dimension where it awaits your summons. As an action, while it is dismissed, you can cause it to reappear in any unoccupied space within 5 feet of you. If you go unconscious while your companion is in its pocket dimension, it reappears within 5 feet on you.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>You can dismiss or recall your companion to/from a pocket dimension. Your companion must be within 5 feet of you; it reappears within 5 feet of you. If you go unconscious while your companion is in its pocket dimension, it reappears within 5 feet on you.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Hidden Form: Disguise" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SOUL_BINDER_HIDDEN_FORM_DISGUISE">
            <description>
                <p>As an action you can create an illusion around your companion that makes it look like another beast or humanoid of similar build and size, such as making a drake look like a dog, or a demon look like a farmer. The disguise end if your companion takes any damage, deals damage to another creature or you end it as an action.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>You can create an illusion around your companion that makes it look like another beast or humanoid of similar build and size. The disguise end if your companion takes any damage, deals damage to another creature or you end it as an action.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
    <element name="Ability Score Improvement" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SOUL_BINDER_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT">
        <description>
            <p>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score past 20 using this feature.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Soul Binder 4)" supports="Improvement Option,Soul Binder,4" level="4" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Soul Binder 8)" supports="Improvement Option,Soul Binder,8" level="8" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Soul Binder 12)" supports="Improvement Option,Soul Binder,12" level="12" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Soul Binder 16)" supports="Improvement Option,Soul Binder,16" level="16" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Soul Binder 19)" supports="Improvement Option,Soul Binder,19" level="19" />

            <select type="Class Feature" name="Companion Improvement Option (Companion 4)" supports="Companion Improvement Option" level="4" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Companion Improvement Option (Companion 8)" supports="Companion Improvement Option" level="8" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Companion Improvement Option (Companion 12)" supports="Companion Improvement Option" level="12" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Companion Improvement Option (Companion 16)" supports="Companion Improvement Option" level="16" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Companion Improvement Option (Companion 19)" supports="Companion Improvement Option" level="19" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Advanced Offense" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SOUL_BINDER_ADVANCED_OFFENSE">
        <description>
            <p>Beginning at 5th level, you and your companion have improved your skill in combat and work even better together. You gain one of the following features of your choice:</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Companion Extra Attack.</i></b> Your companion can attack twice instead of once, whenever it takes the Attack action on its turn.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Expert Commanding.</i></b> There is no longer any restrictions for whenever you or your companion can take the Attack action or cast a spell with a casting time of 1 action as long as it is a soul binder spell.</p>
            <p class="indent">At 11th level you get the other feature that you didn’t pick at 5th level.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Advanced Offense Option" supports="Advanced Offense" level="5" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Advanced Offense Option" supports="Advanced Offense" level="11" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Advanced Offense: Companion Extra Attack" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_ADVANCED_OFFENSE_COMPANION_EXTRA_ATTACK">
            <supports>Advanced Offense</supports>
            <description>
                <p>Your companion can attack twice instead of once, whenever it takes the Attack action on its turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet alt="Companion Extra Attack">
                <description>Your companion can attack twice instead of once, whenever it takes the Attack action on its turn.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Advanced Offense: Expert Commanding" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_ADVANCED_OFFENSE_EXPERT_COMMANDING">
            <supports>Advanced Offense</supports>
            <description>
                <p>There is no longer any restrictions for whenever you or your companion can take the Attack action or cast a spell with a casting time of 1 action as long as it is a soul binder spell.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet alt="Expert Commanding">
                <description>There is no longer any restrictions for whenever you or your companion can take the Attack action or cast a spell with a casting time of 1 action as long as it is a soul binder spell.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
    <element name="Soul Linked Casting" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SOUL_BINDER_SOUL_LINKED_CASTING">
        <description>
            <p>You and your companion are of the same soul, and you can channel magic through your link.</p>
            <p class="indent">At 5th level, when you cast a spell targeting yourself, you can choose to also have the spell affect your companion if the companion is within 60 feet of you. If you lose concentration on the spell, you both lose the effect.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you cast a spell targeting yourself, you can choose to also have the spell affect your companion if the companion is within 60 feet of you. If you lose concentration on the spell, you both lose the effect.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Companion’s Protection" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SOUL_BINDER_COMPANIONS_PROTECTION">
        <description>
            <p>When you reach 6th level your companion’s defense is better than ever, avoiding everything from traps to spells. It gains proficiency in all saving throws. Additionally, it has advantage on Intelligence and Charisma saving throws when you are within 100 feet of it and it can see you.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Your companion gains proficiency in all saving throws. Additionally, it has advantage on Intelligence and Charisma saving throws when you are within 100 feet of it and it can see you.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Resting Voice" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SOUL_BINDER_RESTING_VOICE">
        <description>
            <p>Beginning at 9th level you now regain all uses of your edicts on a short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Countermeasure" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SOUL_BINDER_COUNTERMEASURE">
        <description>
            <p>At 10th level, your companion is very protective of you and will harm anyone who seeks to hurt you. When you are targeted by an attack, your companion can take one of the following reactions:</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Revenge.</i></b> The companion can use its reaction to make one attack against the enemy if it is within range.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Roar.</i></b> It uses its reaction to let out a frightful roar to impose disadvantage on the attack roll as long as the attacker is within 30 feet of it and is not deafened.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Body Shield.</i></b> If your companion is within 5 feet of you when the attack is made, it can use its reaction to redirect the attack to hit it instead.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you are targeted by an attack, your companion can use its reaction to do one of the following: make one attack against the enemy if it is within range, roar to impose disadvantage on the attack if attacker within 30 feet or redirect the attack to itself instead if within 5 feet.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Soul Purification" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SOUL_BINDER_SOUL_PURIFICATION">
        <description>
            <p>When you reach 14th you can use your soul energy to flush out any bad effects currently impeding your companion.</p>
            <p class="indent">If your companion is affected by a magical effect that allows it to make a saving throw at the start or end of its turns, or as an action, you can use your action to allow your companion to immediately attempt to make the saving throw even if it has already done so on said turn.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>If your companion is affected by a magical effect that allows it to make a saving throw at the start or end of its turns, or as an action, you can use your action to allow your companion to immediately attempt to make the saving throw even if it has already done so on said turn.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Infused Energy" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SOUL_BINDER_INFUSED_ENERGY">
        <description>
            <p>At 18th level you can channel your energy though the link that binds you and your companion to empower your companion’s attacks.</p>
            <p class="indent">As an action you can infuse your companion with energy for 1 minute. While infused, they can add your Charisma modifier to their damage rolls.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you have used this feature you must finish a long rest before you can do so again.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>You can infuse your companion with energy for 1 minute. While infused, they can add your Charisma modifier (+{{charisma:modifier}}) to their damage rolls.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Quick Renewal" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SOUL_BINDER_QUICK_RENEWAL">
        <description>
            <p>When you reach 20th level, you are so closely connected with your companion that you can feel their very life force as easy as feeling the wind blow. You have also learned to empower their essence with a burst of energy. As an action, you can fill your companion with renewed life if they are within 120 feet of you. Your companion regains all of its hit points. If it is dead, it is returned to life with all of its hit points.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>You can fill your companion with renewed life if they are within 120 feet of you. Your companion regains all of its hit points. If it is dead, it is returned to life with all of its hit points.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    

    <element name="Companion Ability Score Improvement" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SOUL_BINDER_COMPANION_IMPROVEMENT_OPTION_ASI">
        <supports>Companion Improvement Option</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You can increase one of its ability scores of your choice by 2, or you can increase two of its ability scores of your choice by 1. </p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
		<setters>
			<set name="allow duplicate">true</set>
		</setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Companion Feat" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_SOUL_BINDER_COMPANION_IMPROVEMENT_OPTION_FEAT">
        <supports>Companion Improvement Option</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You can forgo increasing the companion's ability scores and instead take one feat of your choice for it.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
		<setters>
			<set name="allow duplicate">true</set>
		</setters>
        <rules>

        </rules>
    </element>
    <!-- Soul Binder Spells -->
      <!-- Cantrips -->
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLADE_WARD">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_CONTROL_FLAMES">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DANCING_LIGHTS">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FRIENDS">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_GUST">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LIGHT">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGE_HAND">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MESSAGE">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MENDING">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MINOR_ILLUSION">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_MOLD_EARTH">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PRESTIDIGITATION">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHAPE_WATER">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TRUE_STRIKE">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>

      <!-- 1st Level Spells-->
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BANE">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLESS">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BURNING_HANDS">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CHARM_PERSON">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CURE_WOUNDS">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_MAGIC">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISGUISE_SELF">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GREASE">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HEROISM">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_JUMP">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGIC_MISSILE">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LONGSTRIDER">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SANCTUARY">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SLEEP">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHIELD_OF_FAITH">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SILENT_IMAGE">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>

      <!-- 2nd Level Spells-->
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AID">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLUR">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLIND_DEAFNESS">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONTINUAL_FLAME">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CALM_EMOTIONS">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DARKVISION">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_THOUGHT">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DRAGONS_BREATH">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENLARGE_REDUCE">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INVISIBILITY">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_KNOCK">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MISTY_STEP">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAXIMILIANS_EARTHEN_GRASP">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PASS_WITHOUT_TRACE">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SCORCHING_RAY">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SEE_INVISIBILITY">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPIDER_CLIMB">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHATTER">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WARDING_BOND">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>

      <!-- 3rd Level Spells -->
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLINK">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CLAIRVOYANCE">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CATNAP">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISPEL_MAGIC">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FLY">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FEAR">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GASEOUS_FORM">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HYPNOTIC_PATTERN">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGIC_CIRCLE">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_STINKING_CLOUD">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SENDING">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_TIDAL_WAVE">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TONGUES">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WALL_OF_SAND">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WALL_OF_WATER">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WATER_WALK">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WATER_BREATHING">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>

      <!-- 4th Level Spells -->
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ARCANE_EYE">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BANISHMENT">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLIGHT">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONFUSION">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMPULSION">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DEATH_WARD">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_EVARDS_BLACK_TENTACLES">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIRE_SHIELD">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GREATER_INVISIBILITY">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HALLUCINATORY_TERRAIN">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LOCATE_CREATURE">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_STONESKIN">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WALL_OF_FIRE">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WATERY_SPHERE">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>

      <!-- 5th Level Spells -->
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AWAKEN">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONTROL_WINDS">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CREATION">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DREAM">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_IMMOLATION">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INSECT_PLAGUE">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAELSTROM">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FAR_STEP">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FLAME_STRIKE">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TELEPORTATION_CIRCLE">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TELEKINESIS">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SKILL_EMPOWERMENT">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SCRYING">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PLANAR_BINDING">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WALL_OF_STONE">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WALL_OF_LIGHT">
            <supports>Soul Binder</supports>    
        </append>
</elements>