<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Bond of the Wild Soul Bond</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="soul-binder-bond-of-the-wild.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/classes/soul-binder/soul-binder-bond-of-the-wild.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Bond of the Wild" type="Archetype" source="GM Binder" id="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_SOUL_BINDER_BOND_OF_THE_WILD">
        <supports>Soul Bond</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You are in touch with nature itself and have offered something of yourself to it. In return, you are given a trusty animal companion that protects you and carries out your orders. Your bond with the beast makes you inseparable.</p>
            <div element="ID____" />
            <div element="ID____" />
            <div element="ID____" />
            <div element="ID____" />
            <div element="ID____" />
            <div element="ID____" />
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID____" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID____" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID____" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID____" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID____" level="11" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID____" level="15" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Warrior of the Wild" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BOND_OF_THE_WILD_WARRIOR_OF_THE_WILD">
        <description>
            <p>When you choose this bond at 1st level, you gain proficiency with martial weapons and medium armor. Additionally your hit point maximum increases by 1 and increases by 1 again whenever you gain a level in this class.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_MARTIAL_WEAPONS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_MEDIUM_ARMOR" />
            <stat name="hp" value="level:soul binder" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Beast Companion" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BOND_OF_THE_WILD_BEAST_COMPANION">
        <description>
            <p>Also at 1st level, you gain the company of a loyal beast. It has the appearance of your choice, uses the Beast Companion stat block and gains one of the following features of your choice:</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Keen Hearing and Smell. </i></b>The beast has advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on hearing or smell.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Sneaky. </i></b>The beast has expertise in Dexterity (Stealth) checks.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Nocturnal. </i></b>The beast gains darkvision out to a range of 60 feet.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Amphibious. </i></b>The beast can breathe air and water. It also gains a swimming speed equal to its walking speed.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Leaper. </i></b>The beast's long jump is up to 20 feet and its high jump is up to 10 feet, with or without a running start.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Spider Climb. </i></b>The beast can climb difficult surfaces, including upside down on ceilings, without needing to make an ability check.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Big Boned. </i></b>The beast's size is Large.</p>
            <p class="indent">You may pick one additional trait at 11th level.</p>
            <p class="indent">You also get to allocate the following stats for your beast: 16, 14 and 12. You can replace the beast's Constitution, Dexterity and Strength scores with these stats.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can communicate basic ideas to your beast with a few hand signs and nods.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Companion" name="Beast Companion" supports="Soul Binder Beast Companion" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Run With the Pack" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BOND_OF_THE_WILD_RUN_WITH_THE_PACK">
        <description>
            <p>When you reach 3rd level, you and your beast know each other's every move and you perform best in combat when you are together. When you and your beast are within 10 feet of each other and neither of you are incapacitated, you gain the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>When your beast hits a creature with an attack, you can use your reaction to make one attack against the same creature.</li>
                <li>If one of you is prone, it only takes 5 feet of movement to stand up again.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you and your beast are within 10 feet of each other and neither of you are incapacitated: When your beast hits a creature with an attack, you can use your reaction to make one attack against the same creature; If one of you is prone, it only takes 5 feet of movement to stand up again.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Bestial Evolution" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BOND_OF_THE_WILD_BESTIAL_EVOLUTION">
        <description>
            <p>At 7th level, your beast is infused with magic via your bond and can evolve itself in different ways. You can pick one of the following features to grant to your beast:</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Fast Flier. </i></b>Your beast gains a flying speed equal to double its walking speed. It also gains Flyby, meaning it doesn't provoke opportunity attacks when it flies out of an enemy's reach.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Charger. </i></b>Your beast gains an extra 15 feet walking speed. Additionally, if the beast moves at least 20 feet straight toward a target and then hits it with an attack on the same turn, the attack deals an extra 2d10 damage to the target. If the target is a creature, it must succeed on a Strength saving throw or be knocked prone.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Relentless Rampager. </i></b>When the beast is reduced to 0 hit points but not killed outright, it can drop to 1 hit point instead. It can't use this feature again until you finish a long rest. Additionally when the beast reduces a creature to 0 hit points with a melee attack, the beast can use its reaction to move up to half of its speed and make one attack. If it hits with that attack, it gains half of the damage dealt as temporary hit points.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Nature's Commands" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BOND_OF_THE_WILD_">
        <description>
            <p>At 11th level, you can command your beast with the guidance of nature itself. The following commands are added to your Edict options but they do not count against your total number of commands known:</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Tooth and Nail. </i></b>Your beast can use its action to make a melee attack against each creature of its choice within 5 feet of it, with a separate attack roll for each target.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Dodge and Evade. </i></b>Until the end of your next turn, whenever your beast is hit by an attack that it can see, it can use its reaction to reduce the incoming attack's damage by half.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Ultimate Evolution" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_FRAGSAUCE_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BOND_OF_THE_WILD_">
        <description>
            <p>When you reach 15th level, your beast has surpassed any limits you could imagine. Your essence is infused within its body, pushing it to the peak of its evolution.</p>
            <p class="indent">It gains two additional traits from your Beast Companion feature and one additional option from your Bestial Evolution feature</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
</elements>