<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Nine-Sealed Nightmare Sorcerous Origin</name>
        <author url="https://drive.google.com/open?id=1nWiOmghhjC49TaeyyQjeee1587Xxf-qx">Green Fantasy Press</author>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="sorcerer-nine-sealed-nightmare.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aurorabuilder/elements/master/sorcerer-nine-sealed-nightmare.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Nine-Sealed Nightmare" type="Archetype" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_name">
        <supports>Sorcerous Origin</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You are a prisoner, trapped within a cage of flesh and bone. You devoured the mind of your captor, feasted upon their memories, but the seals and wards those wretched, cunning mortals etched into its skin are steadfast and self-repairing. You speak in the voice of the one you’ve consumed and play along with the indignity, concealing the fact that if the shell you are trapped within dies, then you will be banished to the afterlife in place of the soul you consumed. They are afraid of your nature, though they may not know what you truly are. You will be freed. Nine seals stand in your way, and the first is ever so delightfully fragile.</p>
            <p class="indent">Smile, nightmare, for your time has come.</p>
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NSN_ORIGIN_SPELLS" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NSN_THE_NINE_NIGHTMARE_SEALS" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NSN_VOICE_FROM_THE_DARKNESS" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NSN_EYES_OF_INK" />
            <div element="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NSN_IMMORTAL_CAGE" />
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NSN_ORIGIN_SPELLS" level="1" requirements="ID_GM_BINDER_OPTION_SORCERER_ORIGIN_SPELLS" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NSN_THE_NINE_NIGHTMARE_SEALS" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NSN_VOICE_FROM_THE_DARKNESS" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NSN_EYES_OF_INK" level="14" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NSN_IMMORTAL_CAGE" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Origin Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NSN_ORIGIN_SPELLS">
            <requirements>ID_GM_BINDER_OPTION_SORCERER_ORIGIN_SPELLS</requirements>
            <description>
                <p>When you choose this sorcerous origin, you gain access to the following spells, which do not count against your spells known but can only be cast once you reach the required sorcerer level.</p>
                <h5>NINE-SEALED NIGHTMARE ORIGIN SPELLS</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Level</td><td>Spell Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1st</td><td>1st</td><td><i>bane</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td>2nd</td><td><i>darkness</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5th</td><td>3rd</td><td><i>bestow curse</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>7th</td><td>4th</td><td><i>Evard’s black tentacles</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td>5th</td><td><i>dream</i></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>11th</td><td>6th</td><td><i>magic jar</i></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BANE" level="1" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DARKNESS" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BESTOW_CURSE" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_EVARDS_BLACK_TENTACLES" level="7" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DREAM" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGIC_JAR" level="11" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="The Nine Nightmare Seals" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NSN_THE_NINE_NIGHTMARE_SEALS">
            <description>
                <p>At 1st level, the sigils laid upon your prison begin to weaken. When you cast a sorcerer spell using a spell slot of 1st level or higher, the seals binding you crack an amount equal to the level of the spell slot used. Once the spell slot level total equals or exceeds a seal’s threshold, as listed in the Nine Seals table, the seal shatters and you gain access to a new feature. When you finish a long rest, the seals fully repair, locking your power away until you break them again.</p>
                <p class="indent">When you gain the Font of Magic feature at 2nd level, any sorcery points spent on your sorcerer features (except Flexible Casting) cause the seals binding you to crack an amount equal to the sorcery points spent.</p>
                <h5>NINE SEALS TABLE</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Seal</td><td>Threshold and Effect</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>2</td><td><b>The First Seal of Hunger:</b> You refuse to die so easily. When you are reduced to 0 hit points, you can immediately move up to 30 feet and make a melee spell attack targeting a hostile creature that deals 4d10 force damage on a hit. If you hit, you regain hit points equal to your sorcerer level. You can’t do so again until you finish a short or long rest.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5</td><td><b>The Second Seal of Spite:</b> Your cruel power flares through the cracks in your seals. When you target a hostile creature with a cantrip, it takes necrotic damage equal to your spellcasting modifier.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>10</td><td><b>The Third Seal of Trickery:</b> You move your prison like a puppet. Your jumping height and distance triple. You can use your Charisma modifier in place of your Strength modifier for attack and damage rolls with melee weapons, and you gain advantage on Dexterity saving throws.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>18</td><td><b>The Fourth Seal of Fury:</b> Your prison’s flesh warps and distorts, sprouting fangs, horns, and claws that are natural weapons you can use to make melee weapon attacks that deal 1d10 magical piercing damage. When you cast a cantrip, you can use your bonus action to make a single melee weapon attack.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>30</td><td><b>The Fifth Seal of Fervor:</b> Your otherworldly resilience protects your prison from death. Choose one damage type. You gain resistance to damage of that type. You can choose a different damage type each time you break this seal.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>44</td><td><b>The Sixth Seal of Suffering:</b> When you make a melee attack, you can expend 1 sorcery point to gain advantage on that attack roll.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>50</td><td><b>The Seventh Seal of Betrayal:</b> When you cast a spell of 1st level or higher that effects more than one hostile creature, choose one of those creatures. The creature must make a Wisdom saving throw against your sorcerer spell save DC. If it fails, it is frightened of one other target of the spell (your choice) for the spell’s duration.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>60</td><td><b>The Eigth Seal of Corruption:</b> When you fail a saving throw, you can expend 1 sorcery point to cause each hostile creature within 10 feet of you to take 2d10 necrotic damage.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>71</td><td>The Ninth Seal of Defiance: You can cast spells of 1st level with a casting time of 1 action without using a spell slot.</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>96</td><td><b>The Unspoken Seal of Death:</b> When you’ve broken the ninth seal and draw upon your power to this degree, your mortal shell breaks apart. You transform into a creature of your choosing with a CR of 20 or lower. You can’t use lair actions, legendary actions, or spellcasting granted by your new form, but you retain all class features while in this new form and can cast spells normally. When you finish a long rest, you return to your mortal form.</td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you cast a sorcerer spell using a spell slot of 1st level or higher, the seals binding you crack an amount equal to the level of the spell slot used. Any sorcery points spent on your sorcerer features (except Flexible Casting) cause the seals binding you to crack an amount equal to the sorcery points spent. Once the spell slot level total equals or exceeds a seal’s threshold, as listed in the Nine Seals table, the seal shatters and you gain access to a new feature. When you finish a long rest, the seals fully repair, locking your power away until you break them again.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Voice from the Darkness" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NSN_VOICE_FROM_THE_DARKNESS">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 6th level, you can choose to allow any creature that speaks a language to understand your speech.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can choose to allow any creature that speaks a language to understand your speech.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Eyes of Ink" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NSN_EYES_OF_INK">
            <description>
                <p>At 14th level, you can see clearly through magical darkness, and you can treat dim light and darkness as bright light.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can see clearly through magical darkness, and you can treat dim light and darkness as bright light.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Immortal Cage" type="Archetype Feature" source="The Compendium of Sacred Mysteries" id="ID_GFP_COSMR_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_NSN_IMMORTAL_CAGE">
            <description>
                <p>At 18th level, what was once your prison is now your body, tied to your essence for all eternity. If you die, and your corpse is not burned or otherwise totally destroyed, you return to life, fully restored, after a year and a day.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>If you die, and your corpse is not burned or otherwise totally destroyed, you return to life, fully restored, after a year and a day.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
</elements>