<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Variant Fighter Maneuvers for other Martial Archetypes</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="manuevers.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/classes/variant-fighter/manuevers.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <!-- Samurai and Cavalier maneuvers -->
    <!-- https://www.gmbinder.com/share/-LcbR2Glwh5xdwlH9UeU -->
        <element name="Dancing Blade" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_VDP_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_VF_MANEUVER_DANCING_BLADE">
            <supports>Variant Fighter Maneuver</supports>
            <requirements>ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FIGHTER_SAMURAI</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Samurai archetype</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Samurai archetype</p>
                <p>When you take the Attack action on your turn and have advantage on an attack roll against one of the targets, you can forgo the advantage for that roll to attempt a disorientingly elaborate strike. If that attack hits, the creature takes additional damage equal to your Wisdom modifier and cannot take any reactions until the end of your turn.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Superiority.</em></strong> In addition, you can move up to your base movement speed after making this attack. This movement does not provoke opportunity attacks.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you take the Attack action on your turn and have advantage on an attack roll against one of the targets, you can forgo the advantage for that roll to attempt a disorientingly elaborate strike. If that attack hits, the creature takes additional {{wisdom:modifier}} damage and cannot take any reactions until the end of your turn. Superiority: In addition, you can move up to your base movement speed after making this attack. This movement does not provoke opportunity attacks.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Debonair Death" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_VDP_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_VF_MANEUVER_DEBONAIR_DEATH">
            <supports>Variant Fighter Maneuver</supports>
            <requirements>ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FIGHTER_SAMURAI</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Samurai archetype</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Samurai archetype</p>
                <p>When you take damage that reduces you to 0 hit points and doesn't kill you outright, you can use your reaction to deal psychic damage equal to one quarter of your Fighter level (minimum 1) to the creature that reduced you to 0 hit points.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Superiority.</em></strong> This maneuver can be used without expending the use of your reaction, but still only once per round. In addition, you can make a single weapon attack against the creature that reduced you to 0 hit points.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Reaction">
                <description>When you take damage that reduces you to 0 hit points and doesn't kill you outright, you can deal psychic damage equal to one quarter of your Fighter level (minimum 1) to the creature that reduced you to 0 hit points. Superiority: This maneuver can be used without expending the use of your reaction, but still only once per round. In addition, you can make a single weapon attack against the creature that reduced you to 0 hit points.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Determined Strike" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_VDP_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_VF_MANEUVER_DETERMINED_STRIKE">
            <supports>Variant Fighter Maneuver</supports>
            <requirements>ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FIGHTER_SAMURAI</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Samurai archetype</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Samurai archetype</p>
                <p>When you take the Attack action on your turn and have advantage on an attack roll against one of the targets and miss, you can use your bonus action to make another attack roll against that same target with disadvantage.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Superiority.</em></strong> If this attack hits, you deal additional psychic damage equal to your Wisdom modifier.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description> When you take the Attack action on your turn and have advantage on an attack roll against one of the targets and miss, you can make another attack roll against that same target with disadvantage. Superiority: If this attack hits, you deal  {{wisdom:modifier}} additional psychic damage.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Able Recovery" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_VDP_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_VF_MANEUVER_ABLE_RECOVERY">
            <supports>Variant Fighter Maneuver</supports>
            <requirements>ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FIGHTER_CAVALIER</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Cavalier archetype</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Cavalier archetype</p>
                <p>If you fall off your steed and descend no more than 10 feet, you can land on your feet if you're not incapacitated.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Superiority.</em></strong> You can use your reaction to immediately draw a weapon and make a weapon attack against a creature you can see after falling from your steed.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>If you fall off your steed and descend no more than 10 feet, you can land on your feet if you're not incapacitated. Superiority: You can use your reaction to immediately draw a weapon and make a weapon attack against a creature you can see after falling from your steed.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Call to Arms" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_VDP_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_VF_MANEUVER_CALL_TO_ARMS">
            <supports>Variant Fighter Maneuver</supports>
            <requirements>ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FIGHTER_CAVALIER</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Cavalier archetype</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Cavalier archetype</p>
                <p>While not mounted on your steed, you can whistle or otherwise call to your steed as a bonus action. You make an audible noise that if your steed can hear, it can immediately use it's reaction to move towards you at double it's speed.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Superiority.</em></strong> If your steed reaches you, you can immediately mount it (no action required). If it has movement remaining from it's reaction, it can continue to move in a direction of your choice until it has no movement remaining.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>While not mounted on your steed, you can whistle or otherwise call to your steed, and it can immediately use it's reaction to move towards you at double it's speed. Superiority: If your steed reaches you, you can immediately mount it (no action required). If it has movement remaining from it's reaction, it can continue to move in a direction of your choice until it has no movement remaining.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Combat Vet" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_VDP_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_VF_MANEUVER_COMBAT_VET">
            <supports>Variant Fighter Maneuver</supports>
            <requirements>ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FIGHTER_CAVALIER</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Cavalier archetype</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Cavalier archetype</p>
                <p>If your steed is at zero hit points and was reduced to zero hit points within the last minute, you can administer first aid and attempt to stabilize it as an action. A successful DC 10 Wisdom (Medicine) check restores your steed to 1 hit point instead of 0 but the creature is prone.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Superiority.</em></strong> You automatically succeed your first aid attempt.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>If your steed is at zero hit points and was reduced to zero hit points within the last minute, you can administer first aid and attempt to stabilize it. A successful DC 10 Wisdom (Medicine) check restores your steed to 1 hit point instead of 0 but the creature is prone. Superiority: You automatically succeed your first aid attempt.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    <!-- Blood Knight archetype -->
    <!-- https://www.gmbinder.com/share/-LGkyNUbYlkBP9NmI2pK -->
        <element name="Bleeding Edge" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_LOBSTER_DOG_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_VF_MANEUVER_BLEEDING_EDGE">
            <supports>Variant Fighter Maneuver</supports>
            <requirements>ID_DAPC_ARCHETYPE_MARTIAL_ARCHETYPE_BLOOD_KNIGHT</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Blood Knight archetype</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Blood Knight archetype</p>
                <p>After you cast a hemomancy spell of 1st level or higher, the next creature you hit with a weapon attack takes additional necrotic damage at the beginning of its next turn equal to the number of hit points you spent to cast the spell.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Superiority.</em></strong> The damage dealt by this maneuver ignores resistance to necrotic damage. Additionally, you can expend a Blood Die when you trigger this superiority option to add the number rolled to the damage dealt by this maneuver.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>fter you cast a hemomancy spell of 1st level or higher, the next creature you hit with a weapon attack takes additional necrotic damage at the beginning of its next turn equal to the number of hit points you spent to cast the spell. Superiority: The damage dealt by this maneuver ignores resistance to necrotic damage. Additionally, you can expend a Blood Die when you trigger this superiority option to add the number rolled to the damage dealt by this maneuver.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Coagulate" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_LOBSTER_DOG_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_VF_MANEUVER_COAGULATE">
            <supports>Variant Fighter Maneuver</supports>
            <requirements>ID_DAPC_ARCHETYPE_MARTIAL_ARCHETYPE_BLOOD_KNIGHT</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Blood Knight archetype</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Blood Knight archetype</p>
                <p>When you take the attack action on your turn, you can forgo one of your attacks to thicken your foe’s blood. The target must make a Strength saving throw. On a failed save, the target has disadvantage on Strength checks until the end of your next turn.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Superiority.</em></strong> If the target fails its saving throw, its speed is also reduced to 0 until the end of your next turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you take the attack action on your turn, you can forgo one of your attacks to thicken your foe’s blood. The target must make a Strength saving throw. On a failed save, the target has disadvantage on Strength checks until the end of your next turn. Superiority: If the target fails its saving throw, its speed is also reduced to 0 until the end of your next turn.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Endure" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_LOBSTER_DOG_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_VF_MANEUVER_ENDURE">
            <supports>Variant Fighter Maneuver</supports>
            <requirements>ID_DAPC_ARCHETYPE_MARTIAL_ARCHETYPE_BLOOD_KNIGHT</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Blood Knight archetype</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Blood Knight archetype</p>
                <p>When you take damage, you can use your reaction and expend a Blood Die to reduce the damage by a number equal to the number rolled.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Superiority.</em></strong> You gain temporary hit points equal to twice the amount of hit points reduced.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Reaction">
                <description>When you take damage, you can expend a Blood Die to reduce the damage by a number equal to the number rolled. Superiority: You gain temporary hit points equal to twice the amount of hit points reduced.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Stalk the Wounded" type="Class Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_LOBSTER_DOG_GM_BINDER_CLASS_FEATURE_VF_MANEUVER_STALK_THE_WOUNDED">
            <supports>Variant Fighter Maneuver</supports>
            <requirements>ID_DAPC_ARCHETYPE_MARTIAL_ARCHETYPE_BLOOD_KNIGHT</requirements>
            <prerequisite>Blood Knight archetype</prerequisite>
            <description>
                <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Blood Knight archetype</p>
                <p>When you take the attack action on your turn, you can forgo one of your attacks to approach a suffering foe. Choose one creature that you can see that is below its hit point maximum. You can move 5 feet towards your target and you have advantage on your next attack roll against it.</p>
                <p class="indent"><strong><em>Superiority.</em></strong> The movement is increased to 15 feet.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you take the attack action on your turn, you can forgo one of your attacks to choose one creature that you can see that is below its hit point maximum. You can move 5 feet towards your target and you have advantage on your next attack roll against it. Superiority: The movement is increased to 15 feet.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
    

    <!-- Add existing Martial Archetypes as options -->
    <append id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FIGHTER_CAVALIER">
        <supports>Variant Martial Archetype</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FIGHTER_SAMURAI">
        <supports>Variant Martial Archetype</supports>
    </append>
    <append id="ID_DAPC_ARCHETYPE_MARTIAL_ARCHETYPE_BLOOD_KNIGHT">
        <supports>Variant Martial Archetype</supports>
    </append>
</elements>