<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>The Hunter’s Journal Adventuring Gear</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="items-gear.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aurorabuilder/elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/the-hunters-journal/items-gear.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Aquatic Bait" type="Item" source="The Hunter’s Journal" id="ID_AEYANA_THJ_ITEM_AQUATIC_BAIT">
        <description>
            <p>Animal bait grants advantage on checks made to lure, hunt, or tame beasts, and can be prepared as part of a short rest using specific materials: grubs and insects.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Adventuring Gear</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="cp">1</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">—</set>
            <set name="stackable">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Herbivore Bait" type="Item" source="The Hunter’s Journal" id="ID_AEYANA_THJ_ITEM_HERBIVORE_BAIT">
        <description>
            <p>Animal bait grants advantage on checks made to lure, hunt, or tame beasts, and can be prepared as part of a short rest using specific materials: aromatic fruits and herbs.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Adventuring Gear</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="sp">1</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0.5">½ lb.</set>
            <set name="stackable">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Carnivore Bait" type="Item" source="The Hunter’s Journal" id="ID_AEYANA_THJ_ITEM_CARNIVORE_BAIT">
        <description>
            <p>Animal bait grants advantage on checks made to lure, hunt, or tame beasts, and can be prepared as part of a short rest using specific materials: the remains of a freshly slain animal.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Adventuring Gear</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">1</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
            <set name="stackable">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Bola" type="Item" source="The Hunter’s Journal" id="ID_AEYANA_THJ_ITEM_BOLA">
        <description>
            <p>A bola consists of weighted balls attached by cord, and is used to ensnare and slow down prey. As an action, you can throw a bola up to 20 feet. Make a ranged attack against a creature or object, treating the bola as a simple weapon. On a hit, the bola deals no damage, and the target becomes entangled if it is a Large or smaller creature. The bola has no effect on creatures that are formless, creatures that don’t use legs for movement, or creatures that are Huge or larger. The entangled creature’s speed is halved, and it falls prone after using the Dash action. A creature can use its action to untangle itself or another creature within its reach. Dealing 5 slashing damage to the bola (AC 10) also frees the creature without harming it, ending the effect and destroying the bola.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Adventuring Gear</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="sp">5</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
            <set name="stackable">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Cage, 1-foot" type="Item" source="The Hunter’s Journal" id="ID_AEYANA_THJ_ITEM_CAGE_1_FOOT">
        <description>
            <p>A cage has a door or opening on one of its faces, and can contain a certain number of creatures depending on the size of the cage. Breaking the cage requires a successful DC 20 Strength check. Each cage comes with one key. Without the key, a creature proficient with thieves’ tools can pick the cage’s lock with a successful DC 15 Dexterity check. The cage imposes half cover on any attacks that pass through it.</p>
            <p class="indent">A 1 foot cube cage has 10 hit points, has a damage threshold of 3, and can contain 1 Tiny creature.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Adventuring Gear</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">3</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="10">10 lb.</set>
            <set name="stackable">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Cage, 5-foot" type="Item" source="The Hunter’s Journal" id="ID_AEYANA_THJ_ITEM_CAGE_5_FOOT">
        <description>
            <p>A cage has a door or opening on one of its faces, and can contain a certain number of creatures depending on the size of the cage. Breaking the cage requires a successful DC 20 Strength check. Each cage comes with one key. Without the key, a creature proficient with thieves’ tools can pick the cage’s lock with a successful DC 15 Dexterity check. The cage imposes half cover on any attacks that pass through it.</p>
            <p class="indent">A 5 foot cube cage has 25 hit points, has a damage threshold of 5, and can contain 1 Medium or Small creature or up to 4 Tiny creatures.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Adventuring Gear</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">30</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="100">100 lb.</set>
            <set name="stackable">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Cage, 10-foot" type="Item" source="The Hunter’s Journal" id="ID_AEYANA_THJ_ITEM_CAGE_10_FOOT">
        <description>
            <p>A cage has a door or opening on one of its faces, and can contain a certain number of creatures depending on the size of the cage. Breaking the cage requires a successful DC 20 Strength check. Each cage comes with one key. Without the key, a creature proficient with thieves’ tools can pick the cage’s lock with a successful DC 15 Dexterity check. The cage imposes half cover on any attacks that pass through it.</p>
            <p class="indent">A 10 foot cube cage has 100 hit points, has a damage threshold of 10, and can contain 1 Large creature or up to 4 Medium or Small creatures. Tiny creatures are able to slip through the cage’s bars or mesh.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Adventuring Gear</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">300</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="1000">1,000 lb.</set>
            <set name="stackable">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Camouflage" type="Item" source="The Hunter’s Journal" id="ID_AEYANA_THJ_ITEM_CAMOUFLAGE">
        <description>
            <p>A camouflage-pattern cloak or shroud can be used to conceal yourself in the wilderness. You can spend 1 minute donning the camouflage. You have advantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks as long as you remain under the cloak without moving or taking actions, and can hide from a creature even if it has line of sight on you. Once you move or take an action or a reaction, you must spend 1 minute donning the camouflage again to gain this benefit.</p>
            <p class="indent">Camouflage must be made appropriate to the immediate terrain in order to be effective, and can be crafted as part of a short rest. You must have access to fresh mud, dirt, plants, soot, and other naturally occurring materials with which to create camouflage.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Adventuring Gear</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">10</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="10">10 lb.</set>
            <set name="stackable">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Hammock" type="Item" source="The Hunter’s Journal" id="ID_AEYANA_THJ_ITEM_HAMMOCK">
        <description>
            <p></p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Adventuring Gear</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">1</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="3">3 lb.</set>
            <set name="stackable">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Rain Catcher" type="Item" source="The Hunter’s Journal" id="ID_AEYANA_THJ_ITEM_RAIN_CATCHER">
        <description>
            <p>A rain catcher is a simple contraption consisting of a 5-foot-square leather tarp and a wooden frame with legs. When the tarp is stretched across the wooden frame, it forms a basin that can catch 2 gallons of drinking water per inch of rainfall and hold up to 8 gallons. The tarp and wooden frame fold up for easy transport.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Adventuring Gear</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">1</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="5">5 lb.</set>
            <set name="stackable">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Smoke Bomb" type="Item" source="The Hunter’s Journal" id="ID_AEYANA_THJ_ITEM_SMOKE_BOMB">
        <description>
            <p>A tool for distraction and escape, smoke bombs come in many shapes and forms. As an action, you can throw this bomb up to 20 feet, producing a 10-foot radius cloud of white smoke on impact. This smoke heavily obscures the area and dissipates at the start of your next turn or until dispersed by a wind of moderate or greater speed (at least 10 miles per hour).</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Adventuring Gear</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">25</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0.5">½ lb.</set>
            <set name="stackable">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Thumper" type="Item" source="The Hunter’s Journal" id="ID_AEYANA_THJ_ITEM_THUMPER">
        <description>
            <p>This mechanical device can be wound up in 1 minute, after which it produces a regular thumping sound and vibration nearly indistinguishable from that of a humanoid creature’s footsteps for 1 hour. The sound is audible out to 60 feet. You can adjust the properties of the thumping using a set of dials on the device, making it produce a sound between that of a a Small creature in light clothes to a Medium creature in heavy armor. A creature can use its action to examine the sound, determining that it is fake with a successful DC 15 Intelligence (Investigation) check.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Adventuring Gear</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">400</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="3">3 lb.</set>
            <set name="stackable">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Tracking Scent (vial)" type="Item" source="The Hunter’s Journal" id="ID_AEYANA_THJ_ITEM_TRACKING_SCENT">
        <description>
            <p>This vial is filled with clear liquid bearing a powerful and distinct smell. As an action, you can splash the contents of this vial onto a creature within 5 feet of you or throw it up to 20 feet, shattering it on impact. In either case, make a ranged attack against a target creature, treating the liquid as an improvised weapon. On a hit, the target becomes doused with the liquid, and checks made to find or track it are at advantage for the next 8 hours. A creature can remove the scent by using a short rest to bathe in water, alcohol, or vinegar.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Adventuring Gear</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">5</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">—</set>
            <set name="stackable">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Trapper’s Kit" type="Item" source="The Hunter’s Journal" id="ID_AEYANA_THJ_ITEM_TRAPPERS_KIT">
        <description>
            <p>Whether braving the wilderness or guarding a location within a city, a trapper’s kit allow a you to efficiently set and disguise traps, to better ensnare your unwitting prey.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Components.</em></strong> A trapper’s kit contains a bell, a block and tackle, a 15 foot by 15 foot sheet of canvas, 10 pieces of chalk, and 10 feet of string.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Investigation and Perception.</em></strong> When you search an area for tracks or footprints, a trapper’s kit can help you highlight the tracks, pulling out more fine details. Additionally, your experience setting traps hones your senses when searching for traps yourself.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Nature and Survival.</em></strong> Your knowledge of traps grants you insight when determining which plants or animal parts may be usable as substitute for rope, string, or other aspects of making a trap. Additionally, your experience with trapping and tracking can provide insight on what kind of creatures are native to the area you are in.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Sleight of Hand.</em></strong> Your experience in the delicate work of setting traps improves your ability to carefully manipulate rope and string.</p>
            <div class="caption">TRAPPER’S KIT</div>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Activity</td><td>DC</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>Assess an area’s wildlife density</td><td>10</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Scavage for rope-like materials</td><td>15</td></tr>
            </table>
            <div class="sidebar">
                <h5 class="caption">TRAPPER’S KIT PROFICIENCY</h5>
                <p>Characters of the hunter class are proficient with the trapper’s kit. Characters of the druid and rogue classes, as well as those with the outlander background, can exchange a different tool proficiency for proficiency with the trapper’s kit.</p>
            </div>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Deadfall Trap.</em></strong> As part of a short rest, you can suspend a heavy object above a point, connecting it to a tripwire. Creating such a trap requires rope and a block and tackle to hoist the object, and string and pitons to set a tripwire. Make a check using a trapper’s kit. The total of your check becomes the DC for someone else’s attempt to avoid, discover, or disable the trap.</p>
            <p class="indent">When a creature pulls on the tripwire, it must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or take 2d10 bludgeoning damage and become restrained as it becomes pinned by the object. A creature that is restrained by this trap can use its action to make a Strength check against the same DC, freeing itself on a success.</p>
            <p class="indent">Alternatively, you can set the trap to swing in an arc, slamming into the creature. On a failed save, the creature takes 2d10 bludgeoning damage and is pushed 10 feet in a direction designated by you when you set the trap instead of being restrained.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Pitfall Trap.</em></strong> As part of a short rest, you can dig a pit in dirt, soil, or loose stone, covering it with a canvas. Creating such a trap requires a shovel to dig the pit, and a sheet of cloth or canvas to cover it. Make a check using a trapper’s kit. The total of your check becomes the DC for someone else’s attempt to avoid, discover or disable the trap.</p>
            <p class="indent">When a creature steps on the canvas, it must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or fall into the pit, knocking loose the canvas and landing prone at the bottom. A creature inside the pit can using all of its movement to make a Strength check against the same DC, climbing out of the pit on a success.</p>
            <p class="indent">If you have wooden stakes on hand, you can place them inside the pit. A creature that falls into the pit takes an additional 2d6 piercing damage.</p>
            <p class="indent">If you have a cage on hand, you can place it inside the pit, setting it to close and lock when a creature falls into it.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Reinforce Hunting Trap.</em></strong> When you set a hunting trap with a trapper’s kit on hand, you can add your proficiency bonus to the trap’s saving throw DC.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Snare Trap.</em></strong> As part of a short rest, you can set a loop of rope to pull taught if a tripwire is disturbed. Creating such a trap requires rope, string to serve as a tripwire, and an elevated anchor point (such as a tree branch) on which to attach the rope. Make a check using a trapper’s kit. The total of your check becomes the DC for someone else’s attempt to avoid, discover, or disable the trap.</p>
            <p class="indent">When a creature pulls on the tripwire, it must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or become snared by the rope. A creature that is snared this way is hoisted up to 20 feet into the air and hung upside down. While upside down, it can’t move, and has disadvantage on attack rolls. A creature that is snared can use its action to make a Dexterity check against the same DC, freeing itself on a success. If you use a net while setting this trap, the creature is also restrained while it is snared if it is Large or smaller, as it becomes enveloped in the net.</p>
            <p class="indent">Alternatively, you can set the trap to pull in a direction other than up. Setting such a trap does not require an elevated anchor point. On a failed save, the creature is pulled up to 20 feet towards the trap’s anchor point and is knocked prone. While snared in this way, the creature can’t move away from the anchor point.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Adventuring Gear</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">2</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="5">5 lb.</set>
            <set name="stackable">true</set>
			<set name="proficiency">ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_TRAPPERS_KIT</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
        <element name="Tool Proficiency (Hunter’s Kit)" type="Proficiency" source="The Hunter’s Journal" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_TRAPPERS_KIT">
            <supports>Tool</supports>
            <sheet alt="Hunter’s Kit" />
        </element>
    <element name="Tree Stand" type="Item" source="The Hunter’s Journal" id="ID_AEYANA_THJ_ITEM_TREE_STAND">
        <description>
            <p>This device consists of a 3 foot by 3 foot platform with a perpendicular bracing and leather strap. As an action, you can strap the tree stand to a tree or other cylindric feature, allowing it to support up to 300 lb. without collapsing. A creature can unstrap the tree stand as an action, causing it to drop.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Adventuring Gear</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">25</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="10">10 lb.</set>
            <set name="stackable">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Whistling arrow" type="Item" source="The Hunter’s Journal" id="ID_AEYANA_THJ_ITEM_WHISTLING_ARROW">
        <description>
            <p>When fired, this ammunition produces a high-pitched whistle audible out to 300 feet. This ammunition can be made to produce a wide range of pitches, and can even produce pitches too high for human perception, useful for signaling to hunting hounds.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Ammunition</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp" bulk="20">5</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0.05">5/100 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Ammunition</set>
            <set name="stackable">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Whistling blowgun needle" type="Item" source="The Hunter’s Journal" id="ID_AEYANA_THJ_ITEM_WHISTLING_BLOWGUN_NEEDLE">
        <description>
            <p>When fired, this ammunition produces a high-pitched whistle audible out to 300 feet. This ammunition can be made to produce a wide range of pitches, and can even produce pitches too high for human perception, useful for signaling to hunting hounds.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Ammunition</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp" bulk="50">5</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0.02">2/100 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Ammunition</set>
            <set name="stackable">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Whistling crossbow bolt" type="Item" source="The Hunter’s Journal" id="ID_AEYANA_THJ_ITEM_WHISTLING_CROSSBOW_BOLT">
        <description>
            <p>When fired, this ammunition produces a high-pitched whistle audible out to 300 feet. This ammunition can be made to produce a wide range of pitches, and can even produce pitches too high for human perception, useful for signaling to hunting hounds.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Ammunition</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp" bulk="20">5</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0.075">75/1000 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Ammunition</set>
            <set name="stackable">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Whistling sling bullet" type="Item" source="The Hunter’s Journal" id="ID_AEYANA_THJ_ITEM_WHISTLING_SLING_BULLET">
        <description>
            <p>When fired, this ammunition produces a high-pitched whistle audible out to 300 feet. This ammunition can be made to produce a wide range of pitches, and can even produce pitches too high for human perception, useful for signaling to hunting hounds.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Ammunition</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="sp" bulk="20">2</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0.075">75/1000 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Ammunition</set>
            <set name="stackable">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_POISONERS_KIT" />
</elements>