<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>The Hunter’s Journal PC Options</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="options.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/the-hunters-journal/options.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <append id="ID_AEYANA_HUNTER_CLASS_HUNTER">
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Most people enjoy their comfortable lives in there, in the city. Behind walls and under roofs, nice and warm, con- tent and utterly unconcerned with their own survival. But out here in the wilds, we don’t have those luxuries. Here, the monsters prowl, and it’s our job to stop them.</p>
            <div style="text-align: right;">
                <p class="flavor">–Aurora Kealin</p>
            </div>
            <p>Hunters are daring wanderers who guard the edges of civil- ization, braving the wild lands and keeping its denizens at bay. Some walk the path to defend their home, while others seek riches, fame, or merely the thrill of the kill. Tireless, hunters are vital to the preservation of a healthy ecosystem.</p>
            <p class="indent">A connection to the prey they hunt imbues every hunter’s personality and history. Some seek vengeance on a foe that has wronged them in the past. Others brave the wilds in search of fortune, either in lost treasure or in the rare guts of a magical beast. Still others maintain a balance across the wilderness, protecting travelers and beast alike and keeping the worlds of civilization and wilderness in harmony.</p>
            <p class="indent">If you’re creating or playing a hunter character, this section offers ideas for embellishing the character and enhancing your roleplaying experience. It focuses on three aspects: a hunter’s motivations, connections to the wild, and nemeses. For non-hunter characters, concepts from this section can be used to create a powerful and recurrent nemesis.</p>
            <h4>MOTIVATION</h4>
            <p>Various forces can push one away from the tranquility of civilization and down the bloody path of the hunter. What spurred your character to walk the wild lands? Was the choice made because of tradition or curiosity, or do you have a grudge to settle? Roll a d6 and find the number you rolled on the Motivations table.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">MOTIVATIONS</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d6</td><td>Motivation</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>I found purpose in the thrill of the hunt, adrenaline rushing through my veins as I cut my teeth and honed my craft against wild beasts at the edge of civilization.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>I seek bitter vengeance against a terrible mon- ster that brought great tragedy upon me and those I hold dear.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>I suffer from insatiable wanderlust, and the end- less hunt has given me reason not to remain in one place for too long.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>I have seen (and suffered) what happens when monsters roam unchallenged. I took it upon myself to become the first line of defense against the dangers that lie beyond the brink of of civilization.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>I owe a debt to a grizzled hunter, who taught me woodcraft and the secrets of the wild lands.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>Hunting is my means for providing for my family. Were I to lay down my arms now, we would surely starve.</td></tr>
            </table>
            <h4>CONNECTION TO THE WILD</h4>
            <p>All hunters draw some degree of power from their connection to the natural world and its various terrains. A hunter’s relationship to the wild can take many forms. Some were born or raised in the wilderness, while others formed a connection with the wilds later on. The specific form that this connection to the wild takes on may bear traits familiar to other classes, such as an innate understanding of the wild akin to a sorcerer, or a scholarly understanding of aspects of the wilderness more akin to a wizard.</p>
            <p class="indent">Consider your character’s backstory and decide what shape your connection with the wild will take. Does your character have a strong bond with a specific location in the wilderness, or with specific wild creatures? Does the connection influence which spells you use, and how you use them? Has this connection shaped the skills your character has developed?</p>
            <h5 class="caption">CONNECTIONS TO THE WILD</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d6</td><td>Connection</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>The primal energy of the wilds breathes life into you. You have a spiritual, almost druidic bond with nature.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>Toughened and raised by the ruthless trials of the untamed wilds, you were made strong through endless hardships.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>You have a feral intuition, a gut instinct that guides your hand amid the wilds. The energy of nature runs within your veins.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>When in the wilds, the winds seem to always be at your back, the sun never in your eyes. Nature itself seems to grant you its blessing.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>Through studies, memorization, and experimentation, you have developed a deep understanding of the wilds. Your relationship with nature is one of understanding.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>The wilds claimed that which you hold dear, and in turn you hold a lingering hatred or resentment for it. Your connection to nature is one of emnity.</td></tr>
            </table>
        </description>
        <rules>
            <select type="List" name="Motivation">
                <item id="1">I found purpose in the thrill of the hunt, adrenaline rushing through my veins as I cut my teeth and honed my craft against wild beasts at the edge of civilization.</item>
                <item id="2">I seek bitter vengeance against a terrible mon- ster that brought great tragedy upon me and those I hold dear.</item>
                <item id="3">I suffer from insatiable wanderlust, and the end- less hunt has given me reason not to remain in one place for too long.</item>
                <item id="4">I have seen (and suffered) what happens when monsters roam unchallenged. I took it upon myself to become the first line of defense against the dangers that lie beyond the brink of of civilization.</item>
                <item id="5">I owe a debt to a grizzled hunter, who taught me woodcraft and the secrets of the wild lands.</item>
                <item id="6">Hunting is my means for providing for my family. Were I to lay down my arms now, we would surely starve.</item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="Connection to the Wild">
                <item id="1">The primal energy of the wilds breathes life into you. You have a spiritual, almost druidic bond with nature.</item>
                <item id="2">Toughened and raised by the ruthless trials of the untamed wilds, you were made strong through endless hardships.</item>
                <item id="3">You have a feral intuition, a gut instinct that guides your hand amid the wilds. The energy of nature runs within your veins.</item>
                <item id="4">When in the wilds, the winds seem to always be at your back, the sun never in your eyes. Nature itself seems to grant you its blessing.</item>
                <item id="5">Through studies, memorization, and experimentation, you have developed a deep understanding of the wilds. Your relationship with nature is one of understanding.</item>
                <item id="6">The wilds claimed that which you hold dear, and in turn you hold a lingering hatred or resentment for it. Your connection to nature is one of emnity.</item>
            </select>
        </rules>
    </append>
    
</elements>