<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name></name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="items-gifts.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aurorabuilder/elements/master/items-gifts.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Boon of Vigil" type="Magic Item" source="Angels and Heralds" id="ID_L009_AAH_MAGIC_ITEM_BOON_OF_VIGIL">
        <description>
            <p>You have kept vigil countless times in prayer and meditation, and have devotedly forgone rest when your services were necessary.</p>
            <p class="indent">You do not gain a level of exhaustion as a result of not sleeping or completing a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
            <set name="type">Epic Boon</set>
            <set name="slot">gift</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Boon of Potency" type="Magic Item" source="Angels and Heralds" id="ID_L009_AAH_MAGIC_ITEM_BOON_OF_POTENCY">
        <description>
            <p>When a target succeeds on its saving throw against a spell you cast, you can use this boon to make it fail instead. Once you've used this boon, you can't do so again until you complete a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
            <set name="type">Epic Boon</set>
            <set name="slot">gift</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Boon of Celestial Strength" type="Magic Item" source="Angels and Heralds" id="ID_L009_AAH_MAGIC_ITEM_BOON_OF_CELESTIAL_STRENGTH">
        <description>
            <p>A great deed you have done in service of the good of the realm or Mount Celestial has granted you the favor of a powerful Planetar.</p>
            <p class="indent">As an action, you can call forth this gift in a moment of great need. For 1 minute, your Strength score becomes 27 and your eyes fill with radiant light. You gain 40 temporary hitpoints, gain truesight out to 60 ft., and have advantage on all saving throws.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you've used this boon, you can't use it again.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
            <set name="type">Epic Boon</set>
            <set name="slot">gift</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Boon of Arcane Knowledge" type="Magic Item" source="Angels and Heralds" id="ID_L009_AAH_MAGIC_ITEM_BOON_OF_ARCANE_KNOWLEDGE">
        <description>
            <p>You have gained the favor of Mystra, Mistress of Magic. You can unerringly recognize any spell you see being cast, and the level at which it is being cast. Additionally, you can sense the presence of magic within 30 feet of you, and you can use an action to identify its properties as per the identify spell.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
            <set name="type">Epic Boon</set>
            <set name="slot">gift</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Boon of Nullification" type="Magic Item" source="Angels and Heralds" id="ID_L009_AAH_MAGIC_ITEM_BOON_OF_NULLIFICATION">
        <description>
            <p>You can use your reaction to end the casting of a spell you see being cast within 60 feet of you. Once you've used this boon, you can't do so again until you complete a short rest.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
            <set name="type">Epic Boon</set>
            <set name="slot">gift</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Boon of Limited Magic Immunity" type="Magic Item" source="Angels and Heralds" id="ID_L009_AAH_MAGIC_ITEM_BOON_OF_LIMITED_MAGIC_IMMUNITY">
        <description>
            <p>You can't be affected by spells of 3rd level or lower unless you choose to be.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
            <set name="type">Epic Boon</set>
            <set name="slot">gift</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Boon of the Intimidator" type="Magic Item" source="Angels and Heralds" id="ID_L009_AAH_MAGIC_ITEM_BOON_OF_THE_INTIMIDATOR">
        <description>
            <p>You can use an action to frighten those that try to resist your will. Any creatures of your choice within 60 feet of you must succeed on a DC 20 Charisma saving throw, or become frightened of you for 1 minute. When a creature becomes frightened of you in this way, you can speak a single word as a command for the creature to follow. In its next turn, the creature obeys your word as per the command spell.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you've used this boon, you can't use it again until you complete a short rest.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
            <set name="type">Epic Boon</set>
            <set name="slot">gift</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Boon of Punishment" type="Magic Item" source="Angels and Heralds" id="ID_L009_AAH_MAGIC_ITEM_BOON_OF_PUNISHMENT">
        <description>
            <p>When you take damage, you can use your reaction to cause that blow to hit harder. You reduce your own maximum hitpoint score by the amount of damage you took, but you cause the enemy that damaged you to take twice as much damage. This reduction lasts until you finish a long rest. If your hitpoint maximum is reduced to 0 in this way, you die.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
            <set name="type">Epic Boon</set>
            <set name="slot">gift</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Boon of Devil's Sight" type="Magic Item" source="Angels and Heralds" id="ID_L009_AAH_MAGIC_ITEM_BOON_OF_DEVILS_SIGHT">
        <description>
            <p>You can see normally in darkness, both magical and nonmagical, out of a distance of 120 feet. Additionally, when a creature causes you to become blinded, you become blinded to everything else but you can still see the creature that blinded you.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
            <set name="type">Epic Boon</set>
            <set name="slot">gift</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Boon of Incomprehensible Arcana" type="Magic Item" source="Angels and Heralds" id="ID_L009_AAH_MAGIC_ITEM_BOON_OF_INCOMPREHENSIBLE_ARCANA">
        <description>
            <p>When a creature attempts to counterspell or dispel your magic, it takes psychic damage equal to your level.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
            <set name="type">Epic Boon</set>
            <set name="slot">gift</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Boon of Rage" type="Magic Item" source="Angels and Heralds" id="ID_L009_AAH_MAGIC_ITEM_BOON_OF_RAGE">
        <description>
            <p>When you see a close ally of yours die, you can fly into an uncontrollable rage. You make attack rolls with advantage, and have resistance to all damage for 1 minute or until you become incapacitated.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
            <set name="type">Epic Boon</set>
            <set name="slot">gift</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Boon of the Cycle" type="Magic Item" source="Angels and Heralds" id="ID_L009_AAH_MAGIC_ITEM_BOON_OF_THE_CYCLE">
        <description>
            <p>When you see a close ally of yours die, you can use their fleeting life's essence to bolster those that remain. Each creature of your choice within 120 feet regains hitpoints equal to twice your level.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
            <set name="type">Epic Boon</set>
            <set name="slot">gift</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Boon of the Fiend Horde" type="Magic Item" source="Angels and Heralds" id="ID_L009_AAH_MAGIC_ITEM_BOON_OF_THE_FIEND_HORDE">
        <description>
            <p>You can use an action to cast dominate monster (DC 20) on a fiend that you can see within range. Once you've used this boon, you can't do so again until you complete a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
            <set name="type">Epic Boon</set>
            <set name="slot">gift</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Boon of Adaptation" type="Magic Item" source="Angels and Heralds" id="ID_L009_AAH_MAGIC_ITEM_BOON_OF_ADAPTATION">
        <description>
            <p>After you've taken damage of a specific type, you can use your reaction to gain resistance to that damage type until the end of your next turn.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
            <set name="type">Epic Boon</set>
            <set name="slot">gift</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Boon of Malice" type="Magic Item" source="Angels and Heralds" id="ID_L009_AAH_MAGIC_ITEM_BOON_OF_MALICE">
        <description>
            <p>When you damage a creature, you can cause it take an extra 10 damage of the same damage type. If you kill a creature when you do so, you can use the Boon of Malice again. Otherwise you must complete a long rest before you are able to use it again.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
            <set name="type">Epic Boon</set>
            <set name="slot">gift</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Boon of Hate" type="Magic Item" source="Angels and Heralds" id="ID_L009_AAH_MAGIC_ITEM_BOON_OF_HATE">
        <description>
            <p>When you end your turn, any creature of your choice within 5 feet of you that has any hitpoints left takes 5 necrotic damage.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
            <set name="type">Epic Boon</set>
            <set name="slot">gift</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Boon of Envy" type="Magic Item" source="Angels and Heralds" id="ID_L009_AAH_MAGIC_ITEM_BOON_OF_ENVY">
        <description>
            <p>When you see a creature within 60 feet of you succeed on a saving throw, you can curse them with envy. They have disadvantage on the next saving throw they make.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you've used this boon, you can't do so again until you complete a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
            <set name="type">Epic Boon</set>
            <set name="slot">gift</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
</elements>