<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Fencer - Roguish Archetype</name>
        <author url="https://www.gmbinder.com/share/-LMBBIyBBtxDDWhVeOch">entrench - u/devikyn</author>
        <update version="0.0.3">
            <file name="rogue-fencer.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/user/gm-binder-devikyn/rogue-fencer.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Fencer" type="Archetype" source="GM Binder/entrench" id="ID_ENTRENCH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FENCER">
        <supports>Roguish Archetype</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Fencing rogues take on a philosophy of fighting normally adopted as a sport and a method of dueling. They imitate the balanced stance of classic fencers, allowing them to adapt techniques once used by these fighters to their own unique style.</p>
            <h5>FENCER FEATURES</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Rogue Level</td><td>Feature</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>3rd</td><td>Fencing Technique, Counter</td></tr>
                <tr><td>9th</td><td>Steady Hand</td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td>Continuation Strike</td></tr>
                <tr><td>17th</td><td>Centered Stance</td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_ENTRENCH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FENCING_TECHNIQUE" />
            <div element="ID_ENTRENCH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COUNTER" />
            <div element="ID_ENTRENCH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STEADY_HAND" />
            <div element="ID_ENTRENCH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CONTINUATION_STRIKE" />
            <div element="ID_ENTRENCH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CENTERED_STANCE" />
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ENTRENCH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FENCING_TECHNIQUE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ENTRENCH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COUNTER" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ENTRENCH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STEADY_HAND" level="9" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ENTRENCH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CONTINUATION_STRIKE" level="13" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_ENTRENCH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CENTERED_STANCE" level="17" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Fencing Technique" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder/entrench" id="ID_ENTRENCH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FENCING_TECHNIQUE">
        <description>
            <p>When you choose this archetype at 3rd level, you master the basic techniques of fencing. You learn two techniques, which are detailed under "Techniques" below. Techniques are used to enhance your attacks. When you take the Attack action on your turn and you attack with a melee weapon that has the finesse property, you can use one of your fencing techniques to add its effects to one of the attacks. Each technique is limited to one use per turn. Regardless of which technique you use, you also gain +2 to your AC until the start of your next turn.</p>
            <p class="indent">You learn one additional technique of your choice at 9th, 13th, and 17th level. When you learn a new technique, you can also replace one technique you know with a different one.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you take the Attack action on your turn and you attack with a melee weapon that has the finesse property, you can use one of your fencing techniques to add its effects to one of the attacks. Each technique is limited to one use per turn. You also gain +2 to your AC until the start of your next turn.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Fencing Technique (3rd level)" supports="Rogue Fencing Technique" number="2" level="3"/>
            <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Fencing Technique (9th level)" supports="Rogue Fencing Technique" number="1" level="9"/>
            <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Fencing Technique (13th level)" supports="Rogue Fencing Technique" number="1" level="13"/>
            <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Fencing Technique (17th level)" supports="Rogue Fencing Technique" number="1" level="17"/>
        </rules>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Counter" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder/entrench" id="ID_ENTRENCH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COUNTER">
        <description>
            <p>Also starting at 3rd level, you learn to direct a foe’s blow in a way that allows you to strike back. When an creature misses you with a melee attack, you can use your reaction to make one melee attack with a weapon you are holding against the creature. This special attack cannot benefit from your Sneak Attack feature.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Reaction">
            <description>When an creature misses you with a melee attack, you can make one melee attack with a weapon you are holding against the creature. This special attack cannot benefit from your Sneak Attack feature.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Steady Hand" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder/entrench" id="ID_ENTRENCH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STEADY_HAND">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 9th level, you gain finer control of your hands after practicing your combat technique so often. While you are conscious, you cannot have disadvantage on Dexterity checks that involve your hands, and you gain a bonus equal to your Constitution modifier to such checks.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You cannot have disadvantage on Dexterity checks that involve your hands, and you gain a +{{steady hand:bonus}} bonus to such checks.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="steady hand:bonus" value="1" />
            <stat name="steady hand:bonus" value="constitution:modifier" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Continuation Strike" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder/entrench" id="ID_ENTRENCH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CONTINUATION_STRIKE">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 13th level, you have attained such mastery of your techniques that you can convert a successful fencing technique into an opportunity for another strike. When you hit with one of the techniques granted by your Fencing Technique feature, you can make one additional attack as a bonus action against the creature affected by the technique.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Bonus Action">
            <description>When you hit with one of the techniques granted by your Fencing Technique feature, you can make one additional attack as a bonus action against the creature affected by the technique.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Centered Stance" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder/entrench" id="ID_ENTRENCH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CENTERED_STANCE">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 17th level, your fencing stance is so practiced that you can use the momentum of your strikes as leverage, piercing deeply where others would not, without losing your balance. When you hit with an attack that does not benefit from your Sneak Attack feature, you can deal an extra 2d6 damage. You can use this feature only once per turn.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Turn">
            <description>When you hit with an attack that does not benefit from your Sneak Attack feature, you can deal an extra 2d6 damage. You can use this feature only once per turn.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <!-- Fencing Techniques -->
    <element name="Disarm" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder/entrench" id="ID_ENTRENCH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FENCING_TECHNIQUE_DISARM">
        <supports>Rogue Fencing Technique</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You can attempt to knock a weapon from the target’s grasp. The target must make a Strength (Athletics) check or Dexterity (Acrobatics) check, opposing your attack roll. If you win the contest, the defender drops a weapon or object of your choice that it is holding, which lands at its feet.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>The target must make a Strength (Athletics) check or Dexterity (Acrobatics) check, opposing your attack roll. If you win the contest, the defender drops a weapon or object of your choice that it is holding, which lands at its feet.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="Fade" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder/entrench" id="ID_ENTRENCH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FENCING_TECHNIQUE_FADE">
        <supports>Rogue Fencing Technique</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You can attempt to threaten an enemy with your attack, allowing you to retreat. The target must make a Wisdom (Insight) check, opposing the attack roll. If you win the contest, you can move 5 feet immediately after your attack without provoking an attack of opportunity from the creature you hit.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>The target must make a Wisdom (Insight) check, opposing the attack roll. If you win the contest, you can move 5 feet immediately after your attack without provoking an attack of opportunity from the creature you hit.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Feint" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder/entrench" id="ID_ENTRENCH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FENCING_TECHNIQUE_FEINT">
        <supports>Rogue Fencing Technique</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You can glance an enemy with your weapon, goading them to reveal a weak point. The target must make a Wisdom (Insight) check, opposing the attack roll. If you win the contest, your attack deals no damage, and that enemy has disadvantage on the next attack roll it makes against you before the start of your next turn. If you use your Counter feature against the creature before the start of your next turn, you make the attack roll with advantage, and you can benefit from your Sneak Attack feature for the attack.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>The target must make a Wisdom (Insight) check, opposing the attack roll. If you win the contest, your attack deals no damage, and that enemy has disadvantage on the next attack roll it makes against you before the start of your next turn. If you use your Counter feature against the creature before the start of your next turn, you make the attack roll with advantage, and you can benefit from your Sneak Attack feature for the attack.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Flick" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder/entrench" id="ID_ENTRENCH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FENCING_TECHNIQUE_FLICK">
        <supports>Rogue Fencing Technique</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You can flick the blade of your weapon, allowing your blade to strike even guarded points that a straight thrust would miss. The target must make an Intelligence (Investigation) or Wisdom (Insight) check, opposing the attack roll. If you win the contest, the attack ignores resistance to piercing damage, and you have a +1 bonus to the damage roll.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>The target must make an Intelligence (Investigation) or Wisdom (Insight) check, opposing the attack roll. If you win the contest, the attack ignores resistance to piercing damage, and you have a +1 bonus to the damage roll.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Lunge" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder/entrench" id="ID_ENTRENCH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FENCING_TECHNIQUE_LUNGE">
        <supports>Rogue Fencing Technique</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You lunge with your attack, adding additional force to your strike. The range of your attack increases by 5 feet, and in order to use this technique, you must move 5 feet towards the target after your attack. The target must make a Dexterity (Acrobatics) check, opposing the attack roll. If you win the contest, you have advantage on the attack roll.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>The range of your attack increases by 5 feet, and in order to use this technique, you must move 5 feet towards the target after your attack. The target must make a Dexterity (Acrobatics) check, opposing the attack roll. If you win the contest, you have advantage on the attack roll.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Point-in-line" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder/entrench" id="ID_ENTRENCH_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FENCING_TECHNIQUE_POINT_IN_LINE">
        <supports>Rogue Fencing Technique</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You hold a pointed defensive stance after your attack, foiling counter-attack. The target must make a Strength (Athletics) or Dexterity (Acrobatics) check, opposing your attack roll. If you win the contest, the first time the creature attacks you during its next turn, it takes 3 piercing damage, and it provokes an attack of opportunity from you even if it uses the Disengage action before leaving your reach. These benefits last until the start of your next turn.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>The target must make a Strength (Athletics) or Dexterity (Acrobatics) check, opposing your attack roll. If you win the contest, the first time the creature attacks you during its next turn, it takes 3 piercing damage, and it provokes an attack of opportunity from you even if it uses the Disengage action before leaving your reach. These benefits last until the start of your next turn.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    
</elements>