<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Banneret Martial Archetype</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="fighter-banneret.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/rule-of-law/fighter-banneret.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Banneret" type="Archetype" source="Rule of Law" id="ID_IB_ROL_ARCHETYPE_FIGHTER_BANNERET">
        <supports>Martial Archetype</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Also known as warlords, sergeants, or knightcommanders, bannerets are leaders on the battlefield, commanding and inspiring their allies through their heroism. Bannerets are not generals who sit and command from afar, they command from the front, fighting alongside their soldiers and allies in the midst of battle.</p>
            <div element="ID_IB_ROL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BANNERET_MORALE" />
            <div element="ID_IB_ROL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BANNERET_LEADERSHIP" />
            <div element="ID_IB_ROL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BANNERET_HOLD_THE_LINE" />
            <div element="ID_IB_ROL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BANNERET_COMMANDERS_GAMBIT" />
            <div element="ID_IB_ROL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BANNERET_FEARLESS_LEADER" />
            <div element="ID_IB_ROL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BANNERET_WARLORD" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_IB_ROL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BANNERET_MORALE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_IB_ROL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BANNERET_LEADERSHIP" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_IB_ROL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BANNERET_HOLD_THE_LINE" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_IB_ROL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BANNERET_COMMANDERS_GAMBIT" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_IB_ROL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BANNERET_FEARLESS_LEADER" level="15" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_IB_ROL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BANNERET_WARLORD" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Morale" type="Archetype Feature" source="Rule of Law" id="ID_IB_ROL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BANNERET_MORALE">
            <description>
                <p>You are able to inspire and bolster your comrades in battle, using special dice called morale dice. To do so, you use a bonus action on your turn to choose one creature other than yourself within 30 feet of you who can see or hear you. That creature gains one Morale die, a d4, and temporary hitpoints equal to your fighter level + your Charisma modifier.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once within the next 10 minutes, the creature can roll the die and add the number rolled to one attack roll, weapon damage roll, or saving throw it makes. The creature can wait until after it rolls the d20 before deciding to use the Morale die, but must decide before the DM says whether the roll succeeds or fails.</p>
                <p class="indent">Alternatively, when an attack roll is made against the creature, it can use its reaction to roll the Morale die and add the number rolled to its AC against that attack, after seeing the roll but before knowing whether it hits or misses.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once the Morale die is rolled, or the creature loses its temporary hitpoints, it is lost. If the creature’s temporary hitpoints are overwritten by another source, the creature keeps the Morale die until rolled. A creature can have only one Morale die at a time.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier (a minimum of once). You regain any expended uses when you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="{{morale:uses}}/Short Rest">
                <description>You choose one creature other than yourself within 30 feet of you who can see or hear you. That creature gains one Morale die, a d{{morale:die-type}}, and {{morale:temp-hp}} temporary hit points. Once within the next 10 minutes, the creature can roll the die and add the number rolled to one attack roll, weapon damage roll, or saving throw it makes. The creature can wait until after it rolls the d20 before deciding to use the Morale die, but must decide before the DM says whether the roll succeeds or fails. Alternatively, when an attack roll is made against the creature, it can use its reaction to roll the Morale die and add the number rolled to its AC against that attack, after seeing the roll but before knowing whether it hits or misses.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="morale:die-type" value="4" bonus="base" level="3" />
                <stat name="morale:die-type" value="6" bonus="base" level="18" />
                <stat name="morale:temp-hp" value="level:fighter" />
                <stat name="morale:temp-hp" value="charisma:modifier" />
                <stat name="morale:uses" value="1" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="morale:uses" value="charisma:modifier" bonus="base" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Leadership" type="Archetype Feature" source="Rule of Law" id="ID_IB_ROL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BANNERET_LEADERSHIP">
            <description>
                <p>At 7th level, you lead your troops through fear or love. Choose Intimidation or Persuasion. You gain proficiency in the chosen skill. If you are already proficient in it, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks made with it.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Skill Proficiency, Leadership" supports="ID_IB_ROL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BANNERET_LEADERSHIP_INTIMIDATION|ID_IB_ROL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BANNERET_LEADERSHIP_PERSUASION" /> 
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Intimidation" type="Archetype Feature" source="Rule of Law" id="ID_IB_ROL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BANNERET_LEADERSHIP_INTIMIDATION">
                <description>
                    <p>You gain proficiency in Intimidation. If you are already proficient in it, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks made with it.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_OR_DOUBLE_INTIMIDATION" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Persuasion" type="Archetype Feature" source="Rule of Law" id="ID_IB_ROL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BANNERET_LEADERSHIP_PERSUASION">
                <description>
                    <p>You gain proficiency in Persuasion. If you are already proficient in it, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks made with it.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_OR_DOUBLE_PERSUASION" />
                </rules>
            </element>
        <element name="Hold the Line" type="Archetype Feature" source="Rule of Law" id="ID_IB_ROL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BANNERET_HOLD_THE_LINE">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 7th level, you can rally your allies even in the most dire of situations. When you use your Second Wind feature, you can expend one of your uses of Morale to rally your allies. When you do so, roll a morale die, and each friendly creature within 30 feet of you that can see or hear you regains hitpoints equal to the number rolled + your fighter level.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, when a friendly creature within 30 feet of you falls unconscious, you can use your reaction to expend one use of Morale and move up to your speed towards that creature. Roll a Morale die, the target regains hitpoints equal to the number rolled times the number of opportunity attacks you provoked by this movement (1, if no opportunity attacks were provoked).</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you use your Second Wind feature, you can expend one of your uses of Morale to rally your allies. When you do so, roll a morale die, and each friendly creature within 30 feet of you that can see or hear you regains hitpoints equal to the number rolled + {{level:fighter}}. Additionally, when a friendly creature within 30 feet of you falls unconscious, you can use your reaction to expend one use of Morale and move up to your speed towards that creature. Roll a Morale die, the target regains hitpoints equal to the number rolled times the number of opportunity attacks you provoked by this movement (1, if no opportunity attacks were provoked).</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Commander’s Gambit" type="Archetype Feature" source="Rule of Law" id="ID_IB_ROL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BANNERET_COMMANDERS_GAMBIT">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 10th level, you can lead your allies in daring assaults upon your enemies. As an action, you can expend one of your uses of Morale and make a weapon attack, rolling a Morale die and adding the number rolled to the attack roll. If the attack hits, you can immediately command your allies to attack. When you do so, choose a number of allies within 30 feet of you equal to your Charisma modifier (a minimum of 1). The chosen creatures can each use their reaction to make one weapon attack against the target.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>You can expend one of your uses of Morale and make a weapon attack, rolling a Morale die and adding the number rolled to the attack roll. If the attack hits, you can immediately command your allies to attack. When you do so, choose up {{morale:uses}} allies within 30 feet of you. The chosen creatures can each use their reaction to make one weapon attack against the target.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Fearless Leader" type="Archetype Feature" source="Rule of Law" id="ID_IB_ROL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BANNERET_FEARLESS_LEADER">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 15th level, your fearless presence emboldens your allies. You, friendly creatures within 10 feet of you, and creatures with a Morale die from you can’t be frightened while you are conscious.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You, friendly creatures within 10 feet of you, and creatures with a Morale die from you can’t be frightened while you are conscious.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Warlord" type="Archetype Feature" source="Rule of Law" id="ID_IB_ROL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BANNERET_WARLORD">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 18th level, you are a dominating presence in battle, striking fear into your enemies and courage into your allies. Your morale dice become d6s.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, when you score a critical hit, the target becomes frightened of you until the start of your next turn, and you regain 1 use of Morale.</p>
                </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Additionally, when you score a critical hit, the target becomes frightened of you until the start of your next turn, and you regain 1 use of Morale.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
    
</elements>