<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Yorviing's Arcane Grimoire Additional Player Options</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="additional-wizard-options.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/yorviings-arcane-grimoire/additional-wizard-options.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_WIZARD">
        <rules>
            <select type="List" name="I became a wizard because …" optional="true">
                <item id="1">I caught the attention of a mighty wizard, who asked me to perform magic for them. I failed to impress them, and thus decided I would do all that I could to make me worthy in their eyes.</item>
                <item id="2">One of my parents left me with a spellbook before they set off, never to be seen again. I have dedicated myself to learning all that I can and to find them.</item>
                <item id="3">I watched a group of wizards defend my city from an invading force. I now seek to learn magic to protect others.</item>
                <item id="4">While looting a room, I stumbled upon a spellbook. Keeping it for myself, I began reading it and became hooked on learning magic.</item>
                <item id="5">A dying wizard gave me their spellbook to keep out of the hands of those who would abuse it. I vow to keep that promise and to grow strong to protect it.</item>
                <item id="6">Powerful creatures from another realm opened a portal near me. I became fascinated with extraplanar travel and yearned to know all that I could about magic.</item>
                <item id="7">As my town was being attacked, I saw a few mages fend off the attack. From then on, I wanted to learn magic to defend myself and others.</item>
                <item id="8">I witnessed a mysterious magical event that caused a loved one to disappear, and this mystery remains unsolved to this day. I seek the answer to what happened, and to never have it happen again.</item>
                <item id="9">An infamous mage who ruled the land was removed from power unjustly. I was their child, and seek to right the wrongs done to them and set the record straight.</item>
                <item id="10">I watched as a wizard spewed forth dragon flame from their mouth. Since then, I have been awestruck by the power and might that wizards hold, and seek to become the greatest of them all.</item>
                <item id="11">A village elder cursed an outsider from stealing from my village. I became infatuated with the notion of controlling others through magic, and long to do so myself.</item>
                <item id="12">A terrible tragedy befell myself and my family long ago. I will learn as much as I can to harness magic capable of sending me back to prevent it from ever having happened.</item>
                <item id="13">I went into town to trade in something for gold, but was given a spellbook instead. Ever since I opened it, I haven’t turned back.</item>
                <item id="14">A relative of mine wrote in their will that I was to have their spellbook. I have since begun trying to read and learn it’s contents.</item>
                <item id="15">While out traveling, I bought a mysterious book from a wandering merchant. It turned out to be a spellbook, and I consider this the best purchase I ever made.</item>
                <item id="16">Everyone in my family has been a wizard. It was expected of me to do the same.</item>
                <item id="17">I was curious and went knocking on the door of the oldest person in town’s house. They welcomed the company, and I discovered that they were a wizard, and they began to teach me.</item>
                <item id="18">After having read story after story of great wizards and their triumphs, I decided to seek out everything that I could to become like them.</item>
                <item id="19">I was part of a raid on a caravan, and amongst the loot I found a spellbook. I didn’t think much of it at first, but then eventually began studying it and soon fell into wanting to learn more.</item>
                <item id="20">. I’ve always had a knack for magic, and I long to learn as much as I can about the magic that was known to people of the past.</item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="Beginning" optional="true">
                <item id="1">You conjured lightning in your hand, delivering a devastating blow to a would be assailant.</item>
                <item id="2">Yelling out loud the incantation necessary for a spell, you sneezed halfway through, causing the spell to misfire and almost hit one of your peers.</item>
                <item id="3">Waving your hand, you created an illusion of a flower blooming in mid air before exploding like a firework, to the awe and cheers of those watching.</item>
                <item id="4">Spewing forth fire from your mouth, you managed to catch a straw dummy instantly on fire, as well as the grass around it. Then a few trees. Then the side of a stable.</item>
                <item id="5">In a moment of desperation, lashed out by summoning spectral blades towards those who would have harmed you and your friend. Those attackers are no more.</item>
                <item id="6">Moved by a moment of passion or adrenaline, you quickly made it look as though your friend had soiled themselves to distract them. It was not your proudest moment.</item>
                <item id="7">Though every movement and word of your spell was executed flawlessly, no one was paying attention, and when they did, you couldn’t bring yourself to replicated what you had done.</item>
                <item id="8">You summoned ice to assault another in a practice duel. It hit with such accuracy and power that to this day your colleagues still talk about it, even the one who lost the duel.</item>
                <item id="9">Up until that point, not a single spell of yours had ever worked. Until that pivotal moment, when you finally managed to cast a successful spell.</item>
                <item id="10">You cheated at a game meant to test your magical skills by using a spell that was not allowed.</item>
                <item id="11">You waited for the right moment before casting the perfect spell to get the job done. From that day on, you were the go to person for planning and strategy.</item>
                <item id="12">The spell you cast managed to do what no other colleague of yours could do at the time. You are still viewed as clever and full of neat tricks up your sleeve.</item>
                <item id="13">Waving a wand and muttering some words, you managed to call forth fire to warm you and some traveling companions.</item>
                <item id="14">While trying to help someone with fixing something, your spell ended up making things worse by destroying the area that the person was trying to work in.</item>
                <item id="15">Someone challenged you to a fight after you talked up how strong you were. You cast a spell that missed completely, and were embarrassed because of it.</item>
                <item id="16">You tried for weeks to cast your first spell, and when you did, you rejoiced immensely as you saw this as the true beginning of your journey into magic.</item>
                <item id="17">By using magic, you managed to move some dirt to help a gardener. They seemed thankful, but not incredibly impressed.</item>
                <item id="18">You helped lift the spirits of children in a war torn land by casting little spell tricks.</item>
                <item id="19">You summoned forth a familiar, and you keep them close to you no matter wherever you go.</item>
                <item id="20">You frightened multiple people around you by summoning forth the power of ice.</item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="University" optional="true">
                <item id="1">Your university is as grand as the imperial palace, composed of great halls and towers that pierce the skies.</item>
                <item id="2">You studied in a small, wooden building far from the reaches of a great empire, where shamans of ancient tribes taught the wizards of the outlands.</item>
                <item id="3">The place of your study was an ancient tower of unknown origin, but has been instructing magic users for as long as history has been recorded.</item>
                <item id="4">Hidden in a vast desert, a domed structure sits amongst sands, where only those few who can survive the journey are allowed to enter, and it is here that you studied.</item>
                <item id="5">You went to study on a special ship that constantly sailed on expeditions, and the lower decks housed special equipment and spaces for practicing magic.</item>
                <item id="6">You studied in an underground cave system, where dark practitioners of magic accepted only those who could stomach their vile methods and experimentation.</item>
                <item id="7">You practiced and studied magic in a mysterious old mansion that randomly appeared in front of you one day, and would move to a new location each day.</item>
                <item id="8">The place you studied magic at was but one of multiple higher level institutions for arcane magical learning, and was housed inside of a castle built by ancient wizards.</item>
                <item id="9">You trained and studied in a mighty fortress, where wizards honed their abilities alongside soldiers and knights to fight on the frontlines of a great war.</item>
                <item id="10">You learned magic in a beautiful keep deep within a primordial forest on another plane, where you studied underneath otherworldly creatures and beings.</item>
                <item id="11">Your place of study was on the road, in a cart driven by an old mage who taught you and a few others whenever you would stop in a new area or region.</item>
                <item id="12">Far in the north amongst glaciers and snowy mountains, a colossal structure lies mostly buried under snow and ice, where a handful of students come to study.</item>
                <item id="13">On a cliff facing the sea, lies a small castle with a single tower. It is here that you studied underneath a mysterious figure, only accompanied by a handful of others.</item>
                <item id="14">You studied at the home of the village elder, who often made poultices and potions for the locals. The home was simple, yet cluttered with a variety of books and items. In exchange for helping them out, they taught you the fundamentals of magic.</item>
                <item id="15">You went to visit a pair of wizards who lived in a cave several miles outside of your town. These wizards lived here, and the caverns stretched deep into the earth, and they forbade you to go past a certain point.</item>
                <item id="16">At the edge of the world stands a small monastery, wherein a handful of wizards seek to train those they deem worthy. You managed to find this place, and trained within its vast, mysterious halls.</item>
                <item id="17">You trained outside when you could, as the one who taught you would travel from town to town, and would stop by yours roughly once a month for a few days. Thus, you learned magic outside under the canopy of trees or near a river.</item>
                <item id="18">Sailing into the air was a majestic sky skip, travelling across the lands. You managed to find a way to join its crew, and the captain’s wizard advisor saw your potential for magic, and you often trained on the deck or belly of the ship.</item>
                <item id="19">You trained in the woods behind your home, secluded enough that no one would hear what you were doing.</item>
                <item id="20">You studied magic in the home of a family member, and their home was a large but simple house that had enough room for them to teach you.</item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="Reception" optional="true">
                <item id="1">Wizards were the greatest people of society where you lived and trained at. To be a great wizards was the goal of many, and those that achieved it were seen as the greatest to walk the earth.</item>
                <item id="2">While magic was generally seen as being an alright thing to practice, and that wizards were overall good people, many commoners still had reservations about how it worked, though they respected wizards for their dedication to studying it.</item>
                <item id="3">The common folk rarely even saw magic, much less a wizard who could wield it. Thus, most people viewed magic as little more than a grand wive’s tale, and the idea that there would even be places to study it was generally laughed at as poppycock, and spellcasters as suspicious.</item>
                <item id="4">Wielders of any kind of magic outside of that granted by the gods or nature was seen as heresy, evil, and was deemed a forbidden and illegal practice. Many wizards from your homeland, despite their power, fell victim to the mob’s torch and pitchfork.</item>
                <item id="5">Those who had the ability to cast spells and learn magic were the rulers of your homeland, and they ruled justly and well. Through them, magic became more commonplace, and the public met this paradigm with mixed opinions and views.</item>
                <item id="6">Despite the kings and queens of the realm having great power, true might was held by a few great wizards, who practiced magic in remote areas. The common folk held the saying to ‘Never trust a wizard’, and many took that to heart.</item>
                <item id="7">Wizards were often found appropriately guilty of many a terrible crime in your homeland, and thus, to even say that you once thought about magic was met with brows raised and sneering looks.</item>
                <item id="8">The common folk feared magic, but had little say in its common place and practice, as a handful of spellcasters ruled the land with a dark hand. The public, fearing what may happen to them if they disobeyed, let these magic users do what they will.</item>
                <item id="9">So you could do magic. So what? So could any kid who could walk. Magic is incredibly common where you were from and has been for centuries. Most people were wizards of some degree anyways, and it was viewed as not that special.</item>
                <item id="10">Wizards were thought to be mysterious and powerful people, but they were held in great respect by those of your motherland and place of study. Many commoners would make great journeys just for a few minutes of council by learned wizards.</item>
                <item id="11">Wizards were seen as tricksters, pranksters, and a nuisance. Too often were younger wizards catching fields on fire or tricking the elderly, so the common folk often thought very little of wizards, wishing that they could be left in peace.</item>
                <item id="12">Powerful wielders of arcane magic once saved your homeland a century ago, but many of them were lost or died in doing so. Since then, the common folk long for the next wizards to arise, to protect them and lead society into a new era of peace.</item>
                <item id="13">The elder of the village was the only wielder of magic for at least 50 miles, and they were well respected in the community, if albeit considered strange. As such, while some people didn’t understand what magic really was, they didn’t think poorly of those who wanted to learn it.</item>
                <item id="14">While wielders of magic were not seen as worthless, they were seen as those who weren’t nearly as strong as those who trained on their own and could do things without the help of magic. At least, this is how it works in the land that you come from.</item>
                <item id="15">Where you came from, people of all types and skill sets came and went quite often, often setting sail or stopping only to stock up on supplies before setting out on their travels. Thus, while there may have not been many wizards in your land, they were used to seeing them.</item>
                <item id="16">It had been ages since your village had seen a wizard. However, that didn’t stop villagers from coming up with wild stories and fantasies of mighty wizards wielding magic against terrible forces in the world.</item>
                <item id="17">Wielders of magic were hunted down without mercy or trial, being seen as people who were too easily corrupted by power and temptation. Whether it was a governmental or religious reason for this, you saw many arcane users chased through the streets or hung in the city square.</item>
                <item id="18">Wizards were seen as the pinnacle of what one should do with magic. Through their years of disciplined and tedious magical learning, wizards displayed level headedness and respect when dealing with magic, and thus they were seen as the greatest examples of practitioners of magic.</item>
                <item id="19">To be a wizard meant that you had to be rich, at least where you hail from. Given the cost of attending an institution of magical learning, one had to be incredibly wealthy in order to even apply. Thus, wizards were seen as powerful by all, but with jealous or leering eyes by the poorer populations.</item>
                <item id="20">With their constant mumbling, magical experimenting, and their constant buying of all the good incense, wizards are seen as incredibly annoying by most people. Though sometimes useful, wizards were best seen as left alone.</item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="Colleagues" optional="true">
                <item id="1">Your colleagues were incredibly kind and courteous, encouraging both you and each other along with their studies and practice. They thought of you as a sibling, and would help you to the best of their ability.</item>
                <item id="2">Your colleagues were generally kind, but were a highly competitive bunch, always trying to challenge each other to magical duels or feats of wonder. They viewed you and each other based on how often you won and how skilled you were.</item>
                <item id="3">Your colleagues were a very bland and boring group of people, which contrasted against the nature of studying magic itself. They were kind but mainly kept to themselves, and you were never exactly sure how they felt about you.</item>
                <item id="4">Your colleagues were twisted, dangerous people, who sought nothing save for acquiring more power, whatever means necessary. You could tell that they thought little of anyone who did not make it their goal to become the strongest alive.</item>
                <item id="5">Your colleagues were not the brightest collection of people, and in fact, they were not the most talented or strongest either. They were kind, yet clumsy and often prone to mistakes. They viewed you in admiration, believing you to be the best of them.</item>
                <item id="6">Your colleagues were creatures and people from other planes, coming from far and wide to train and study at your university. They were hard to pin down collectively, as their personalities varied wildly, though they never looked down upon you.</item>
                <item id="7">Your colleagues were incredibly numerous, and keeping track of them was incredibly difficult. There was a multitude of eager students, and you made few friends amongst them. They did not think much of you, as you were lost in the masses.</item>
                <item id="8">Your colleagues were only a handful of people, each having faced terrible and dangerous events in their pasts. They were generally neutral towards you, mainly focusing on improving themselves and diving deep into their studies.</item>
                <item id="9">Your colleagues were snooty, prudish people who made it known how great and important their studies and magical skills were. They thought very little of you, often looking down their noses at you, viewing you as little more than a lucky novice.</item>
                <item id="10">Your colleagues were wacky, childish, and often misbehaved individuals and younger than most other practitioners of magic. However, despite what vibe and appearances they gave off, they were all powerful, and viewed you welcomingly.</item>
                <item id="11">Your colleagues were mean, harsh people, often performing their studies and experiments behind closed doors, accompanied by muffled screams and strange sounds. They cared not for you unless you hindered or helped their studies.</item>
                <item id="12">Your colleagues were incredibly powerful individuals, and were naturals with magical skill and control. They viewed you as the weakest amongst them, and though not harshly, they did critique your lack of power and magical knowledge.</item>
                <item id="13">Your colleagues were a group that varied greatly in terms of skill and personality. They viewed you as one of them, albeit with the occasional prank or jest. However, many times you would find that they focused more on gossip than on learning.</item>
                <item id="14">Your colleagues were a group of often immature and devious individuals. They would focus more on pranking each other and playing games than ever taking any form of magical learning seriously.</item>
                <item id="15">Your colleagues were people who had lived a long time, a group of individuals who were beginning to study the arcane as part of a new chapter in their lives. They were kind, though incredibly mysterious people.</item>
                <item id="16">Your colleagues were small in number, and picked up from the street at young ages by a group of secretive magical practitioners. You were among them, and you have never really lived a life outside of this group.</item>
                <item id="17">Your colleagues were people who never seemed to notice or care for anything outside of your place of study. Apathetic to most things, these people were difficult to read, and you never truly felt as though you were even considered by them.</item>
                <item id="18">Your colleagues were all soldiers, warriors trained to wield both might and magic to protect the realm. Regardless of whether or not they came from the common folk or nobility, all viewed each other as brothers and sisters in arms.</item>
                <item id="19">Your colleagues were a small group of people with unique and incredible talents, brought together to develop their magical powers at the last school of magic left in the world. They were all dedicated and fierce people.</item>
                <item id="20">Your colleagues were powerful, manipulative, and experimental people. They would often study dark secrets, focusing on harnessing raw and unfiltered power in order to become incredible beings of twisted arcane energy.</item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="Instructor" optional="true">
                <item id="1">Your instructor was considered the wisest person in the realm, and people came from far and wide to listen to their advice and knowledge. They hoped that one day, by listening and practicing under them, you would rise up and take their place.</item>
                <item id="2">Your instructor was one who ultimately cared for you, but was not one to show it. They were often away and rarely spoke with you unless giving you instructions or critiquing your progress, though they watched you grow stronger with great interest.</item>
                <item id="3">Your instructor was a chatty, sporadic, and clumsy wizard who often kept their home and office incredibly filthy and littered with pages and tomes. However, despite their initial appearance and demeanor, they were rumored to be the hero of an old war.</item>
                <item id="4">Your instructor was one of your parents, who trained you as an equal amongst your peers. They were cold, distant, and blunt, but made sure that you gave every action and spell that you cast everything that you could.</item>
                <item id="5">Your instructor was a battle hardened war mage, one who had seen many people fall to both spell and sword. They were calm, yet intimidating and powerful, and focused on training you and others in the ways of magical combat.</item>
                <item id="6">Your instructor was, despite being incredibly knowledgeable on a variety of subjects, unbearably boring. They often recited passage upon passage in lectures that seemed to drag on for days on end.</item>
                <item id="7">Your instructor was a being from another plane, and brought with them knowledge and magic that you could have only dreamed of knowing. Their methods were unorthodox to you, but familiar to them, and they focused on magic from their home.</item>
                <item id="8">Your instructor was a vile, cruel, and deadly individual, who had been expelled from their home long ago for deeds too evil to mention. They focused on making you harness your power, and hoped you would aid them in their revenge.</item>
                <item id="9">Your instructor was kind, but a perfectionist to their core. They would often make you repeat spells until you would almost collapse from exhaustion. They always made a point of speaking carefully and were precise in their choice of words.</item>
                <item id="10">Your instructor was a dirty, shifty, and unkempt individual who had seen the harsh truth of the world more times than they could count. They cared little for grace and appearance, and focused on making you clever and crafty in order to survive.</item>
                <item id="11">Your instructor was a creature whose origin you never were able to discover. They were a talking, magical animal, who spoke in a dialect long forgotten by the realm. They often would speak of a time long, long ago, and how times have since changed.</item>
                <item id="12">Your instructor was a kind, lovely, and cheerful individual who made it their waking goal to see you succeed in every aspect that you could. They were neat and clean, and expected you to be, and would rarely chide you, instead focusing on positivity.</item>
                <item id="13">Your instructor was the spirit of a long dead mage, bound to an existence of being trapped within an object. Though they can manifest their spirit outside of the object, they cannot cast magic, nor can they move beyond a few feet away from their prison.</item>
                <item id="14">Your instructor was a person from the future, sent back through time to train someone worthy of a specific task that has to be done in your future. They were mysterious, and their mannerisms and personality reflected a far away time.</item>
                <item id="15">Your instructor was a spy, someone who trained in a secret practice of combining the arcane with arts of subterfuge and espionage. They were hard on you, but only because they wished for you to succeed and take their place.</item>
                <item id="16">Your instructor was a strange yet incredibly brilliant philosopher, one who would tutor you not just in the art of magical manipulation, but also in its ethical and moral implications. They trained you by having you question most things in the world.</item>
                <item id="17">Your instructor was a crazed individual, one who lived just far enough away from civilization that they rarely saw other people. Though they were an odd bird, they were quite skilled at teaching you the ways of the arcane.</item>
                <item id="18">Your instructor was a collection of talking objects, from books to shelves to mounted animal heads. You trained with them in a forgotten library, and they would often teach you about more than just magic, such as history or linguistics.</item>
                <item id="19">Your instructor was a famous elementalist, one who focused primarily on the arts of manipulating flame, frost, stone, and wind. They were well known as having once defeating a powerful creature using their techniques.</item>
                <item id="20">Your instructor was a legendary witch or wizard who many had thought long dead. Hiding away in a remote area, they trained you in learning magic that was both common and forbidden, insisting you must learn as much as you can.</item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="Training" optional="true">
                <item id="1">Your training was incredibly difficult and involved incredibly long hours of one strenuous exercise after the other, pushing you to your body’s limit every day.</item>
                <item id="2">Your training involved being presented with one task at the beginning of each week, and you were not able to continue to the next one until you had completed it.</item>
                <item id="3">Your training was easy to you, while difficult to others. You blew past each test and objective with little to no effort.</item>
                <item id="4">Your training was difficult to you, though easy to others. You often struggle with each new task, watching as others passed by you with ease.</item>
                <item id="5">Your training involved dark and gruesome endeavors, things that even most shady folk would squirm and shiver at hearing.</item>
                <item id="6">Your training was often presented in the form of a riddle or puzzle, and you had to use your spells and knowledge in new, clever ways to progress</item>
                <item id="7">Your training involved learning the basics of not just magic, but combat strategy, the body, arts, and much more, with the intent being that you were to master everything.</item>
                <item id="8">Your training revolved around casting one spell at a time over and over again until it came to be like second nature to you, before you would move on to the next spell.</item>
                <item id="9">Your training had little to do with the actual practical application of magic, focusing moreso on the moral and ethical ramifications of spell use.</item>
                <item id="10">Your training had you journeying around to various places, seeking out great masters of magic to listen to their wisdom.</item>
                <item id="11">Your training often put you into positions to duel and work against your comrades in order to see which of you would emerge victorious.</item>
                <item id="12">Your training was a bland, dull affair, consisting of writing essays and studying areas of magic that held little to no interest for you.</item>
                <item id="13">Your training was combined with a sense of urgency, and at times you would feel overwhelmed at the amount of knowledge presented.</item>
                <item id="14">Your training involved many trips to far off places and lands, learning from a multitude of people who specialized in different magic.</item>
                <item id="15">Your training was a healthy mixture of theory, use, and practice of the arcane arts. You would never focus on one of these more than the other.</item>
                <item id="16">Your training felt like it would never end. It was grueling, difficult, and at many times you felt as though you could just give up and walk away.</item>
                <item id="17">Your training was lonely, as you and your peers each trained separately. You would often find yourself repeating the same spells over and over.</item>
                <item id="18">Your training always felt as though it was interrupted by something or someone, and thus you never felt as though you received a full training experience.</item>
                <item id="19">Your training was riddled with luxuries and the greatest things wealth could buy. You had exquisite lodging, ample room, and a welcome environment to study.</item>
                <item id="20">Your training was purely hands on use and practicality. You rarely considered or even studied theory, and rather would focus on the experience.</item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="Spellbook" optional="true">
                <item id="1">A pristine tome filled with images and information on magic, planets, and other celestial bodies.</item>
                <item id="2">A weathered tome, filled with both your spells as well as different theories on magic, from its use and application, to how individuals throughout history have viewed its use.</item>
                <item id="3">A heavy tome that contains thick pages, upon which are symbols, runes, and notes written in a code only who understand.</item>
                <item id="4">A dusty book with chalk dusted pages that describe magical effects on the body and soul, as well as spells and rituals for contacting the deceased.</item>
                <item id="5">A series of artistic designs for pictures or tattoos, presented in a sketchbook.</item>
                <item id="6">A collection of smooth pieces of wood, etched with arcane designs and symbols that are kept in a leather pouch.</item>
                <item id="7">A rope with a series of intricate, special knots for each spell.</item>
                <item id="8">A collection of arm, chest, or leg wraps that are bound tight across the body, inscribed with your spells.</item>
                <item id="9">A deck of tarot cards, upon which are symbols that represent your spells.</item>
                <item id="10">A bundle of metal or wooden rings or charms, connected to one circular loop, bracelet, or necklace, upon which spells are written on the inner and outer parts of each ring.</item>
                <item id="11">A series of beads inscribed with spells that are looped onto bracelets, or put in hairstyles such as braids or dreadlocks.</item>
                <item id="12">A mask, made of wood, metal, or leather, that is adorned in symbols and runes for spells, and is either worn during battle or kept on a strap around the waist.</item>
                <item id="13">A long scroll, wrapped neatly around a metal or wooden rod, that lists in elaborate font</item>
                <item id="14">A special device composed of metal and electronics, generally worn around the wrist or is handheld.</item>
                <item id="15">A collection of scarves, upon which are stitched special designs that signify spells.</item>
                <item id="16">A bracelet or necklace that contains small dangling items, such as charms, animal teeth, or wooden reeds, which are inscribed with arcane symbology.</item>
                <item id="17">A collection of small, thin wooden boards inscribed with arcane runes, strung together on a thick rope that dangles from the waist.</item>
                <item id="18">A large gourd, carried on the back that contains within a collection of thin strips of parchment upon which spells are written.</item>
                <item id="19">A collection of crystals, each embedded with spells in the form of mystical etchings, that you keep in a special box or bag.</item>
                <item id="20">A tome forged out of sheets of metal, with the text written in a special ink that carves the writing into the metal itself.</item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="Study" optional="true">
                <item id="1">You focus your studies on trying to find some way to become immortal, without becoming or working alongside of a lich.</item>
                <item id="2">You focus your studies on trying to archive as many pieces of arcane knowledge that you can, in the hopes of keeping it secret and safe.</item>
                <item id="3">You focus your studies on trying to learn how to become a deity, in the hopes of one day being amongst the gods with their knowledge and powers.</item>
                <item id="4">Your focus your studies on trying to obtain as much power as you can, gathering an arsenal of spells that can be used to help you maintain power.</item>
                <item id="5">You focus your studies on trying to bend reality in more permanent ways, so as to shape the world to act in accordance to your will and dreams.</item>
                <item id="6">You focus your studies on trying to find the best ways to protect those that you love and care for, wanting to defend them against all that would harm them.</item>
                <item id="7">You focus your studies on trying to create a new school of magic, so that the world can remember you as an important and powerful spellcaster.</item>
                <item id="8">You focus your studies on learning ways to transform your body, in a way to make you stronger and to preserve your life against all that the world would throw at it.</item>
                <item id="9">You focus your studies on trying to master the elements, wanting to control fire, earth, wind, water, and lighting.</item>
                <item id="10">You focus your studies on wanting to learn every spell in existence, seeking out any method that you can in order to become a repository for magical abilities.</item>
                <item id="11">You focus your studies on wanting to uncover the truth, in whatever way you can, and whatever the truth ends up revealing itself to be.</item>
                <item id="12">You focus your studies on trying to help people, even if the methods you take are not seen by them to be the best one for them.</item>
                <item id="13">You focus your studies on trying to understand the structure and nature of what makes a spell a spell.</item>
                <item id="14">You focus your studies on ways of improving travel, both near and far.</item>
                <item id="15">You focus your studies on methods of creating new and exciting magical items.</item>
                <item id="16">You focus your studies on ways of perfecting the body and mind.</item>
                <item id="17">You focus your studies on trying to answer an age old magical quandary.</item>
                <item id="18">You focus your studies on developing new and experimental forms of magic.</item>
                <item id="19">You focus your studies on what constitutes a wielder of magic, and why some can wield more than others.</item>
                <item id="20">You focus your studies on trying to ascertain the nature of one of the Planes of Existence, and what constitutes a Plane to begin with.</item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="Hobby" optional="true">
                <item id="1">You like to play chess, loving the strategy of the game.</item>
                <item id="2">You often paint outside, preferring to paint what you see in the wild.</item>
                <item id="3">You play an instrument, playing alone so as to have an escape.</item>
                <item id="4">You have the expensive hobby of buying new clothes, always keeping up with the latest fashion trends.</item>
                <item id="5">You like to make tea for your friends and host small get togethers.</item>
                <item id="6">You whittle, making little figurines in the shape of animals or people you see.</item>
                <item id="7">You enjoy getting tattooed, the pain of the needle drowning out the headache you may have gotten from your studies.</item>
                <item id="8">You often play with a pet or your familiar, enjoying the outdoors with games.</item>
                <item id="9">You like to read, whether it be books about fiction or historical figures.</item>
                <item id="10">You enjoy cooking, preparing excellent meals for yourself or for others.</item>
                <item id="11">You like to box and fight, believing that the body should be trained as much as your control over spells.</item>
                <item id="12">You enjoy going to see sideshow performers, maybe even dabbling in some of those performances and skills yourself.</item>
                <item id="13">You collect books about anything and everything.</item>
                <item id="14">You enjoy working with machines and getting yourself covered in grime and grease.</item>
                <item id="15">You like to knit and have made many of your friends scarves.</item>
                <item id="16">You sometimes graffiti the outside of buildings.</item>
                <item id="17">You have developed quite a habit of gambling and betting on any and everything.</item>
                <item id="18">You like to tell jokes, and enjoy making others laugh.</item>
                <item id="19">You like to read smut and very filthy literature, but make a habit of never letting others read the book.</item>
                <item id="20">You play pranks on your travelling companions.</item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="Mishap" optional="true">
                <item id="1">By casting a spell improperly, you managed to catch fire to the buttocks of one of your fellow students.</item>
                <item id="2">You accidentally summoned a foul demon from the Abyss.</item>
                <item id="3">The backlash from a spell gone wrong injured only you, but made you lose one of your arms. You have since had it replaced with a magical prosthetic made of wood and metal.</item>
                <item id="4">You misfired and set some curtains on fire.</item>
                <item id="5">Pronouncing a spell’s phrase incorrectly resulted in the spell not working. You have not had that issue since.</item>
                <item id="6">Everyone in the vicinity watched you get propelled backwards into a window after casting a spell.</item>
                <item id="7">Your mishandling of a spell caused you to become covered in scars, a constant reminder of what happens when magic is misused.</item>
                <item id="8">Your actions caused another person to permanently lose an eye. You have had a hard time trying to forgive yourself.</item>
                <item id="9">You electrified an innocent sheep.</item>
                <item id="10">People still talk about the day you ruined a celebration by pulling a prank on a spokesperson by making it seem like they passed gas very loudly.</item>
                <item id="11">While reading a spell tome that you should not have had access to, you caused your instructor to turn into a toad for a few minutes.</item>
                <item id="12">Both you and another novice of the arcane arts dueled one another, resulting in both of you becoming severely injured.</item>
                <item id="13">You tried using your instructor's wand, and somehow managed to lose it.</item>
                <item id="14">You once summoned a pig when you meant to summon a sword. It was a really cool pig, in your defense.</item>
                <item id="15">You accidentally caused someone to have a severe reaction to a poisonous spray you conjured.</item>
                <item id="16">So what if you had once accidentally let a skeleton run amok in the hallways.</item>
                <item id="17">You performed a ritual horribly wrong.</item>
                <item id="18">You tried to make a cake taste better, but ended up mispronouncing the spell’s words, and it tasted much worse.</item>
                <item id="19">You accidentally ended the life of someone watching you cast a spell.</item>
                <item id="20">You froze over the door to your room, and had to wait for it to thaw out.</item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="Eccentricity" optional="true">
                <item id="1">You often hum simple melodies or songs when reading or writing.</item>
                <item id="2">You don’t talk often, but when someone brings up a subject you study or are greatly interested in, it is hard to pull you away from the conversation.</item>
                <item id="3">You obsess over having the areas in which you work and study neat, organized, and spotless.</item>
                <item id="4">When struggling to comprehend or solve something, you often will argue with yourself, sometimes even giving one side of this self-argument another name.</item>
                <item id="5">You often stay up for hours on end when you are thinking or studying. However, once you finally are asleep, you are a prominently sound sleeper and snorer.</item>
                <item id="6">You keep in your possession some item from the day you first cast a spell or started to study magic, such as a special inkwell or a glove you had burned.</item>
                <item id="7">You often pace back and forth when trying to learn a new spell, often ignoring where you’re stepping.</item>
                <item id="8">You practice the somatic components of spells as a daily ritual, usually right after dawn or before dusk.</item>
                <item id="9">You insist that the verbal components of spells are to be spoken in a language that is most appropriate to that spell, such as speaking in Ignan for fire spells.</item>
                <item id="10">Changing your familiar’s form at the beginning of each season helps you to better keep track of time.</item>
                <item id="11">You often make the mistake of mumbling out loud as you think, often in long streams of run on sentences.</item>
                <item id="12">When learning or studying, you write your notes in a complicated cypher that makes sense to you.</item>
                <item id="13">You have a habit of eating while going over and studying your spells.</item>
                <item id="14">You have to have everything as quiet and remote as possible for you to study.</item>
                <item id="15">When learning or studying arcane theory, you become almost oblivious to the world around you.</item>
                <item id="16">You insist that every mage or wizard knows as much about theory as they can.</item>
                <item id="17">You find the resuscitation and studying of spells to be so incredibly boring, so you make little rhymes and tunes to keep you interested.</item>
                <item id="18">You make many drawings and notes in the margins of your spellbook.</item>
                <item id="19">You have a habit of switching topics in mid sentence.</item>
                <item id="20">You always have this feeling that someone is trying to spy on or steal your work.</item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="Ambition" optional="true">
                <item id="1">You will bend the universe to your will and desire.</item>
                <item id="2">Your endeavors will bring about a new paradigm in magical theory, application, and discovery.</item>
                <item id="3">You aim to be a pivotal figure in your specific school of magic.</item>
                <item id="4">The soul of someone close to you has moved on, with no means of return. You hope to change that.</item>
                <item id="5">Your aim with magic is artistic in nature, and thus your pursuits are focused on combining magic with art to create a new wave of creativity.</item>
                <item id="6">The use of magic is directly tied to the balance of both nature and the world, and you will see that balance is maintained.</item>
                <item id="7">Ancient cultures had an understanding of magic that must be found, preserved, and remembered.</item>
                <item id="8">True magical understanding rests in gaining deep knowledge from each of the planes of existence.</item>
                <item id="9">You aim to change the manner in which magic is viewed in society, by both the common folk and mages alike.</item>
                <item id="10">You will use the knowledge of previous wizards and magical scholars to create new forms of magic, or even new schools.</item>
                <item id="11">You will establish the greatest center of magical learning the world has ever seen, where all are welcome to learn.</item>
                <item id="12">By wielding your magic, you will show all of those who mocked and mistreated you how wrong they were.</item>
                <item id="13">You aim to be famous for magic, using whatever tricks and routes to get there.</item>
                <item id="14">You will become the strongest wielder of magic that ever lived, or die trying.</item>
                <item id="15">You wish to create a new school of magic, and new spells that can be learned by all.</item>
                <item id="16">Magic should be used to rule society. Those who can’t wield it should step aside.</item>
                <item id="17">You will bring about the death of one or more of the gods.</item>
                <item id="18">The magic of a long forgotten age will be restored.</item>
                <item id="19">I wish to combine magic and technology to bring about a new era in history.</item>
                <item id="20">There is so much misuse of magic. Those who mistreat it must pay for their crimes.</item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="Ideology" optional="true">
                <item id="1">The purpose of magic is to assist the poor, destitute, and helpless, so as to bring into the world goodness and peace. The common folk have little to lose, but much to gain by your aid in assisting them. Whether it be a sense of justice or some divine inspiration, you are where the people are most needed. You are often found in the dirty streets and slums of the cities, alongside the medical tents on the fields of battle, or helping the poor in trying to better their own living conditions. You are thoughtful, kind, and orderly in your approach to magic.</item>
                <item id="2">To you, the use of magic is tied towards your own will and ambition. You see magic as tool (albeit a powerful one) with which you can enact your desires into reality, whether they be towards good or evil. You are often found training alone a ways away from the morning camp, constantly searching for those who you can test your skills against, or working your way up through the social ladder towards your end goals. You are dedicated, determined, and strong willed in regards to your magical empowering.</item>
                <item id="3">Magic is as vital to life as breathing, drinking, and resting. For you, magic should be taught to all, so as to harness the incredible strength of the Weave in a manner that would bring people closer together, and make magical skills become as natural as walking or eating. You are often found teaching in a school or university, wandering from town to town giving lectures on magical theory and practice, or being amongst the people as you show them what good magic can do. You are enthusiastic, respectful, and encouraging by nature.</item>
                <item id="4">The more power that you can acquire, the stronger you will become. Your worldview consists of utilizing every aspect of magic to make you rise above the common folk, and eventually kings and lords, as you believe the right to rule is truly meant for your hands, and your hands alone. For too long have you dealt with the horrors and struggles of the world, and you long to sit at the top, where you are within control. You are often found mingling amidst the courts of royal families, establishing contacts with the dark underbelly of society, or find ways to communicate with powerful creatures from other realms to obtain even more strength. You are selfish, greedy, and strong.</item>
                <item id="5">To have a talent for practicing magic is an incredible thing to have, yet it is also a mighty responsibility. To study magic is to not only memorize incantations and movements, but to understand it’s purpose, time, and place. Those who would abuse the power of magic for themselves have no right to wield it, and thus they must be stripped of all magical talent. You are often found amongst the ranks of witch hunters and seekers of criminal mages, finding ways to implement laws regarding magic, or finding those worthy of magical talent so as to better their skills. You are steadfast, cautious, and old fashioned.</item>
                <item id="6">Magic equals the right to rule, in your view. Those who have incredible control and versatility to their magical prowess, regardless of who they are or where they come from, should be the ones to help guide and lead society towards a better future, ruling over those who lack the skill and capacity to use magic, though never done so with the use of cruel or demeaning methods. Society needs magic to progress, but not everyone is capable of wielding it. You are often found amidst the political circles of the land, helping to better the conditions of magical universities, or searching the land in order to find the rule that the realm desperately needs. You are contemplative, political, and fair.</item>
                <item id="7">You long simply to be left to your studies, whether they be alone or with a close group of colleagues. While you care for the general well being of others and the good of society, political and social aspects of the world hold little interest in your eyes. You want to learn, and to keep learning, for as long as you can. This isn’t out of selfishness or greed, however, but rather a simple desire to just learn. You are often found huddled within the confines of an old library, studying within the safety of your own tower or home, or mingling with your fellow academics as you work on experiments and magic. You are hermetic, quiet, and thoughtful.</item>
                <item id="8">Those who toil away at studying magic within universities and colleges claim to be the intelligent ones, but lo, are they misguided. To you, the true way to learn magic and to hone your skills is with the more direct approach of experiencing the world for what it truly is, and there exists no better teacher than that of experience. You are often found wandering the countryside as you observe magic in the wild, studying how ancient creatures wield magic themselves, or testing your skills in arenas and gauntlets throughout the realm. You are grounded, practical, and open-minded.</item>
            </select>
        </rules>
    </append>
    
</elements>