<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Way of the Stone Will Monastic Tradition</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="monk-way-of-the-stone-will.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/subclasses/monk/monk-way-of-the-stone-will.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Way of the Stone Will" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_CTN_HOMEBREWERY_SOURCE_Way of the Stone Will">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation">WOTSW</set>
            <set name="url">https://drive.google.com/file/d/1IaZ115tkvhr0Y94jDauvkr25wdzDNNsi/view</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" abbreviation="CTN" url="https://www.reddit.com/user/coletnelson/">u/coletnelson</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">true</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20200526</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Way of the Stone Will" type="Archetype" source="Way of the Stone Will" id="ID_CTN_WOTSW_ARCHETYPE_MONK_WAY_OF_THE_STONE_WILL">
        <supports>Monastic Tradition</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The Way of the Stone Will trains its students in a soundness of mind and form that view will every achieve, and to use this strength to create a body of stone hard form. Focused on anchoring themselves to the ground beneath their feet, Monks of the Way of the Stone Will are unmovable and unbreakable, and a fearsome foe to battle in combat.</p>
            <p class="indent">A stone will monk often adorns themselves with marks of mud and sand across their chest and traveling in ornate designs down their legs to their feet in beautiful twisting motifs that identify them.</p>
            <div element="ID_CTN_WOTST_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WOTSW_MOLDED_INTO_FORM" />
            <div element="ID_CTN_WOTST_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WOTSW_MONOLITHIC_STRIKES" />
            <div element="ID_CTN_WOTST_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WOTSW_SHIFTING_SANDS" />
            <div element="ID_CTN_WOTST_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WOTSW_FORCE_OF_THE_RUBBLE" />
            <div element="ID_CTN_WOTST_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WOTSW_MOUNTAIN_WALKER" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CTN_WOTST_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WOTSW_MOLDED_INTO_FORM" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CTN_WOTST_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WOTSW_MONOLITHIC_STRIKES" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CTN_WOTST_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WOTSW_SHIFTING_SANDS" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CTN_WOTST_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WOTSW_FORCE_OF_THE_RUBBLE" level="11" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CTN_WOTST_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WOTSW_MOUNTAIN_WALKER" level="17" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Molded into Form" type="Archetype Feature" source="Way of the Stone Will" id="ID_CTN_WOTST_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WOTSW_MOLDED_INTO_FORM">
            <description>
                <p>Starting when you choose this tradition at 3rd level, your monastic training has connected your physical form to the physicality of the earth and stone beneath you. Your hit point maximum increases by 3, and it increases by 1 whenever you gain a level in this class. Additionally, while on the ground, you have advantage on ability checks and saving throws against effects that would move you or knock you prone.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>While on the ground, you have advantage on ability checks and saving throws against effects that would move you or knock you prone.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="hp" value="2" />
                <stat name="hp" value="level:monk" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Monolithic Strikes" type="Archetype Feature" source="Way of the Stone Will" id="ID_CTN_WOTST_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WOTSW_MONOLITHIC_STRIKES">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 3rd level, you have mastered the ability to ground yourself to the earth beneath and deliver devistating blows. At the start of your turn if you choose not to expend any movement, you may spend 1 Ki point before any attack with an unarmed strike or monk weapon to deal maximum damage, instead of rolling. You may make this choice after the attack roll is made, but before it is determined whether the attack hits or misses.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Ki">
                <description>At the start of your turn if you choose not to expend any movement, you may spend 1 Ki point before any attack with an unarmed strike or monk weapon to deal maximum damage, instead of rolling. You may make this choice after the attack roll is made, but before it is determined whether the attack hits or misses.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Shifting Sands" type="Archetype Feature" source="Way of the Stone Will" id="ID_CTN_WOTST_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WOTSW_SHIFTING_SANDS">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, you begin to learn how to physically meld yourself into the earth around you. While on natural terrain you gain a burrow speed equal to the additional speed granted by your Unarmored Movement, burrowing in this way, so long as you do not use any additional movement, does not prevent you from using Monolithic Strikes. Additionally, the first attack against you after burrowing in this way has disadvantage.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>While on natural terrain you gain a burrow speed equal to the additional speed granted by your Unarmored Movement, burrowing in this way, so long as you do not use any additional movement, does not prevent you from using Monolithic Strikes. Additionally, the first attack against you after burrowing in this way has disadvantage.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Force of the Rubble" type="Archetype Feature" source="Way of the Stone Will" id="ID_CTN_WOTST_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WOTSW_FORCE_OF_THE_RUBBLE">
            <description>
                <p>By 11th level, you have learned to channel the core strength of stone into your body, and deliver a punishing blow in return. As a reaction when you are hit with a melee attack, you may spend any number of Ki points to reduce the damage taken by a number of Martial Arts die equal to the amount of Ki points spent.</p>
                <p class="indent">If this reduction reduces the damage taken to 0, you may make one unarmed strike against the attacker as a part of this reaction; if this attack hits, the target is knocked prone.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Reaction">
                <description>When you are hit with a melee attack, you may spend any number of Ki points to reduce the damage taken by a number of Martial Arts die equal to the amount of Ki points spent. If this reduction reduces the damage taken to 0, you may make one unarmed strike against the attacker as a part of this reaction; if this attack hits, the target is knocked prone.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Mountain Walker" type="Archetype Feature" source="Way of the Stone Will" id="ID_CTN_WOTST_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WOTSW_MOUNTAIN_WALKER">
            <description>
                <p>At 17th level, you no longer merely invoke the strength of the stone, but can will mountains themselves to move at your command. Once per long rest, you may cast <em>bones of the earth</em> as an action on your turn. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for this spell. When cast in this way, you may use your burrow movement granted by Shifting Sands to move from one pillar to another as if there were no space between them, costing only 5 feet of movement to enter one pillar and exit another, appearing in an unoccupied space within 5 feet of the destination pillar.</p>
                <div class="reference">
                    <div element="ID_XGTE_SPELL_BONES_OF_THE_EARTH" />
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest" action="Action">
                <description>You may cast bones of the earth (Wisdom). When cast in this way, you may use your burrow movement granted by Shifting Sands to move from one pillar to another as if there were no space between them, costing only 5 feet of movement to enter one pillar and exit another, appearing in an unoccupied space within 5 feet of the destination pillar.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_BONES_OF_THE_EARTH" />
            </rules>
        </element>
</elements>