<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Alpha Druid Class by u/SWecky</name>
        <update version="0.0.2">
            <file name="class-alpha-druid.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/classes/alpha-druid/class-alpha-druid.xml" />
        </update>
        <!-- https://drive.google.com/file/d/1HH-t_gPo88a_V26P3VG3KDHz4hjpWLj0/view -->
    </info>
    
    <element name="Alpha Druid" type="Class" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_CLASS_ALPHA_DRUID">
        <description>
			<!-- <p class="flavor">A priest of the Old Faith, wielding the powers of nature— moonlight and plant growth, fire and lightning—and adopting animal forms.</p> -->
			<p>Holding high a gnarled staff wreathed with holly, an elf summons the fury of the storm and calls down explosive bolts of lightning to smite the torch-carrying orcs who threaten her forest.</p>
			<p class="indent">Crouching out of sight on a high tree branch in the form of a leopard, a human peers out of the jungle at the strange construction of a temple of Evil Elemental Air, keeping a close eye on the cultists’ activities.</p>
			<p class="indent">Swinging a blade formed of pure fire, a half-elf charges into a mass of skeletal soldiers, sundering the unnatural magic that gives the foul creatures the mocking semblance of life.</p>
			<p class="indent">Whether calling on the elemental forces of nature or emulating the creatures of the animal world, druids are an embodiment of nature’s resilience, cunning, and fury. They claim no mastery over nature. Instead, they see themselves as extensions of nature’s indomitable will.</p>
			<h4>POWER OF NATURE</h4>
			<p>Druids revere nature above all, gaining their spells and other magical powers either from the force of nature itself or from a nature deity. Many druids pursue a mystic spirituality of transcendent union with nature rather than devotion to a divine entity, while others serve gods of wild nature, animals, or elemental forces. The ancient druidic traditions are sometimes called the Old Faith, in contrast to the worship of gods in temples and shrines.</p>
			<p class="indent">Druid spells are oriented toward nature and animals— the power of tooth and claw, of sun and moon, of fire and storm. Druids also gain the ability to take on animal forms, and some druids make a particular study of this practice, even to the point where they prefer animal form to their natural form.</p>
			<h4>PRESERVE THE BALANCE</h4>
			<p>For druids, nature exists in a precarious balance. The four elements that make up a world—air, earth, fire, and water—must remain in equilibrium. If one element were to gain power over the others, the world could be destroyed, drawn into one of the elemental planes and broken apart into its component elements. Thus, druids oppose cults of Elemental Evil and others who promote one element to the exclusion of others.</p>
			<p class="indent">Druids are also concerned with the delicate ecological balance that sustains plant and animal life, and the need for civilized folk to live in harmony with nature, not in opposition to it. Druids accept that which is cruel in nature, and they hate that which is unnatural, including aberrations (such as beholders and mind flayers) and undead (such as zombies and vampires). Druids sometimes lead raids against such creatures, especially when the monsters encroach on the druids’ territory.</p>
			<p class="indent">Druids are often found guarding sacred sites or watching over regions of unspoiled nature. But when a significant danger arises, threatening nature’s balance or the lands they protect, druids take on a more active role in combating the threat, as adventurers.</p>
			<h4>CREATING A DRUID</h4>
			<p>When making a druid, consider why your character has such a close bond with nature. Perhaps your character lives in a society where the Old Faith still thrives, or was raised by a druid after being abandoned in the depths of a forest. Perhaps your character had a dramatic encounter with the spirits of nature, coming face to face with a giant eagle or dire wolf and surviving the experience. Maybe your character was born during an epic storm or a volcanic eruption, which was interpreted as a sign that becoming a druid was part of your character’s destiny.</p>
			<p class="indent">Have you always been an adventurer as part of your druidic calling, or did you first spend time as a caretaker of a sacred grove or spring? Perhaps your homeland was befouled by evil, and you took up an adventuring life in hopes of finding a new home or purpose.</p>
			<h5>QUICK BUILD</h5>
			<p>You can make a druid quickly by following these suggestions. First, Wisdom should be your highest ability score, followed by Constitution. Second, choose the hermit background.</p>
			<h3>CLASS FEATURES</h3>
			<p>As a druid, you gain the following class features.</p>
			<h5>HIT POINTS</h5>
			<ul>
				<li><strong>Hit Dice:</strong> 1d8 per druid level</li>
				<li><strong>Hit Points at 1st Level:</strong> 8 + your Constitution modifier</li>
				<li><strong>Hit Points at Higher Levels:</strong> 1d8 (or 5) + your Constitution modifier per druid level after 1st</li>
			</ul>
			<h5>PROFICIENCIES</h5>
			<ul class="unstyled mb">
				<li><strong>Armor:</strong> Light armor, medium armor, shields</li>
				<li><strong>Weapons:</strong> Clubs, daggers, darts, javelins, maces, quarterstaffs, scimitars, sickles, slings, spears</li>
				<li><strong>Tools:</strong> Herbalism kit</li>
			</ul>
			<ul>
				<li><strong>Saving Throws:</strong> Intelligence, Wisdom</li>
				<li><strong>Skills:</strong> Choose two from Animal Handling, Arcana, Insight, Medicine, Nature, Perception, Religion, and Survival</li>
			</ul>
			<h5>EQUIPMENT</h5>
			<p>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>(a) a wooden shield or (b) any simple weapon</li>
				<li>(a) a scimitar or (b) any simple melee weapon</li>
				<li>Leather armor, an explorer’s pack, and a druidic focus</li>
			</ul>
			<h5 class="caption">THE DRUID</h5>
			<table class="class-features">
				<thead>
					<tr><td class="col-5">Level</td><td class="left">Features</td><td class="col-10">Cantrips Known</td><td>1st</td><td>2nd</td><td>3rd</td><td>4th</td><td>5th</td><td>6th</td><td>7th</td><td>8th</td><td>9th</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td> 1st</td><td class="left">Druidic, Spellcasting</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 2nd</td><td class="left">Druid Circle</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 3rd</td><td class="left">Nature’s Boon</td><td>3</td><td>4</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 4th</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 5th</td><td class="left">—</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 6th</td><td class="left">Druid Circle Feature</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 7th</td><td class="left">—</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>1</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 8th</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td> 9th</td><td class="left">Nature’s Ward</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>1</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td>10th</td><td class="left">Druid Circle Feature</td><td>5</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td>11th</td><td class="left">—</td><td>5</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td>12th</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>5</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td>13th</td><td class="left">—</td><td>5</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td>14th</td><td class="left">Druid Circle Feature</td><td>5</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td>15th</td><td class="left">—</td><td>5</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td>16th</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>5</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td>17th</td><td class="left">—</td><td>5</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>1</td></tr>
				<tr><td>18th</td><td class="left">Druid Circle Feature, Timeless Body</td><td>5</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>1</td></tr>
				<tr><td>19th</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>5</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>1</td></tr>
				<tr><td>20th</td><td class="left">Archdruid</td><td>5</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>1</td></tr>
			</table>
            <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_ALPHA_DRUID_DRUIDIC" />
            <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_ALPHA_DRUID_SPELLCASTING" />
            <div class="sidebar">
                <h5 class="caption">Sacred Plants and Wood</h5>
                <p>A druid holds certain plants to be sacred, particularly alder, ash, birch, elder, hazel, holly, juniper, mistletoe, oak, rowan, willow, and yew. Druids often use such plants as part of a spellcasting focus, incorporating lengths of oak or yew or sprigs of mistletoe.</p>
                <p class="indent">Similarly, a druid uses such woods to make other objects, such as weapons and shields. Yew is associated with death and rebirth, so weapon handles for scimitars or sickles might be fashioned from it. Ash is associated with life and oak with strength. These woods make excellent hafts or whole weapons, such as clubs or quarterstaffs, as well as shields. Alder is associated with air, and it might be used for thrown weapons, such as darts or javelins.</p>
                <p class="indent">Druids from regions that lack the plants described here have chosen other plants to take on similar uses. For instance, a druid of a desert region might value the yucca tree and cactus plants.</p>
            </div>
            <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_ALPHA_DRUID_DRUID_CIRCLE" />
            <div class="sidebar">
                <h5 class="caption">Druids and the Gods</h5>
                <p>Some druids venerate the forces of nature themselves, but most druids are devoted to one or several of nature deities. The worship of these deities is often considered a more ancient tradition than the faiths of clerics and urbanized peoples. This belief sometimes make druids clash with priests from other religions, especially those formed around the newer, less inclusive deities.</p>
                <p class="indent">Some druids hold animistic beliefs completely unconnected to deities. They believe that every living thing and every natural phenomenon—sun, moon, wind, fire, and the world itself—has a spirit. Their spells, then, are a means to communicate with and command these spirits. Different druidic sects, though, hold different philosophies about the proper relationship of these spirits to each other and to the forces of civilization.</p>
            </div>
            <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_ALPHA_DRUID_NATURES_BOON" />
            <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_ALPHA_DRUID_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" />
            <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_ALPHA_DRUID_NATURES_WARD" />
            <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_ALPHA_DRUID_TIMELESS_BODY" />
            <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_ALPHA_DRUID_ARCHDRUID" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
		<setters>
			<set name="short">A priest of the Old Faith, wielding the powers of nature—moonlight and plant growth, fire and lightning—and adopting animal forms.</set>
			<set name="hd">d8</set>
		</setters>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_ALPHA_DRUID_DRUIDIC" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_ALPHA_DRUID_SPELLCASTING" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_ALPHA_DRUID_DRUID_CIRCLE" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_ALPHA_DRUID_NATURES_BOON" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_ALPHA_DRUID_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" level="4" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_ALPHA_DRUID_NATURES_WARD" level="9" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_ALPHA_DRUID_TIMELESS_BODY" level="18" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_ALPHA_DRUID_ARCHDRUID" level="20" />
        </rules>
		<multiclass id="ID_WOTC_PHB_MULTICLASS_DRUID">
			<prerequisite>Wisdom 13</prerequisite>
			<requirements>[wis:13]</requirements>
			<setters>
				<set name="multiclass proficiencies">Light armor, medium armor, shields (druids will not wear armor or use shields made of metal)</set>
			</setters>
			<rules>
				<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS" />
				<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" />
				<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_MEDIUM_ARMOR" />
				<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_SHIELDS" />
			</rules>
		</multiclass>
    </element>
        <element name="Druidic" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_ALPHA_DRUID_DRUIDIC">
            <description>
                <p>You know Druidic, the secret language of druids. You can speak the language and use it to leave hidden messages. You and others who know this language automatically spot such a message. Others spot the message’s presence with a successful DC 15 Wisdom (Perception) check but can’t decipher it without magic.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can use it to leave hidden messages. You and others who know this language automatically spot such a message. Others spot the message’s presence with a successful DC 15 Perception check but can’t decipher it without magic.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
    			<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_DRUIDIC" />                
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Spellcasting" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_ALPHA_DRUID_SPELLCASTING">
            <description>
                <p>Drawing on the divine essence of nature itself, you can cast spells to shape that essence to your will. See Spells Rules for the general rules of spellcasting and the Spells Listing for the druid spell list.</p>
                <h5>Cantrips</h5>
                <p>At 1st level, you know three cantrips of your choice from the druid spell list. You learn additional druid cantrips of your choice at higher levels, as shown in the Cantrips Known column of the Druid table.</p>
                <h5>Preparing and Casting Spells</h5>
                <p>The Druid table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your spells of 1st level and higher. To cast one of these druid spells, you must expend a slot of the spell’s level or higher.</p>
                <p class="indent">You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.</p>
                <p class="indent">You prepare the list of druid spells that are available for you to cast, choosing from the druid spell list. When you do so, choose a number of druid spells equal to your Wisdom modifier + your druid level (minimum of one spell). The spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots.</p>
                <p class="indent">For example, if you are a 3rd-level druid, you have four 1st-level and two 2nd-level spell slots. With a Wisdom of 16, your list of prepared spells can include six spells of 1st or 2nd level, in any combination. If you prepare the 1st-level spell cure wounds, you can cast it using a 1st-level or 2nd-level slot. Casting the spell doesn’t remove it from your list of prepared spells.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can also change your list of prepared spells when you finish a long rest. Preparing a new list of druid spells requires time spent in prayer and meditation: at least 1 minute per spell level for each spell on your list.</p>
                <h5>Spellcasting Ability</h5>
                <p>Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for your druid spells, since your magic draws upon your devotion and attunement to nature. You use your Wisdom whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Wisdom modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a druid spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.</p>
                <center>
                    <p><strong>Spell save DC</strong> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier</p>
                    <p><strong>Spell attack modifier</strong> = your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier</p>
                </center>
                <h5>Ritual Casting</h5>
                <p>You can cast a druid spell as a ritual if that spell has the ritual tag and you have the spell prepared.</p>
                <h5>Spellcasting Focus</h5>
                <p>You can use a druidic focus as a spellcasting focus for your druid spells.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <spellcasting name="Alpha Druid" ability="Wisdom" prepare="true">
                <list known="true">Druid</list>
            </spellcasting>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS_SPELLCASTING_SLOTS_FULL" requirements="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS"/>
                <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_RITUAL_CASTING" />
                <stat name="alpha druid:spellcasting:slots:1" value="2" level="1" />
                <stat name="alpha druid:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="2" />
                <stat name="alpha druid:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="3" />
                <stat name="alpha druid:spellcasting:slots:2" value="2" level="3" />
                <stat name="alpha druid:spellcasting:slots:2" value="1" level="4" />
                <stat name="alpha druid:spellcasting:slots:3" value="2" level="5" />
                <stat name="alpha druid:spellcasting:slots:3" value="1" level="6" />
                <stat name="alpha druid:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="7" />
                <stat name="alpha druid:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="8" />
                <stat name="alpha druid:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="9" />
                <stat name="alpha druid:spellcasting:slots:5" value="1" level="9" />
                <stat name="alpha druid:spellcasting:slots:5" value="1" level="10" />
                <stat name="alpha druid:spellcasting:slots:5" value="1" level="18" />
                <stat name="alpha druid:spellcasting:slots:6" value="1" level="11" />
                <stat name="alpha druid:spellcasting:slots:6" value="1" level="19" />
                <stat name="alpha druid:spellcasting:slots:7" value="1" level="13" />
                <stat name="alpha druid:spellcasting:slots:7" value="1" level="20" />
                <stat name="alpha druid:spellcasting:slots:8" value="1" level="15" />
                <stat name="alpha druid:spellcasting:slots:9" value="1" level="17" />
                <stat name="alpha druid:spellcasting:prepare" value="wisdom:modifier" />
                <stat name="alpha druid:spellcasting:prepare" value="level:alpha druid" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Alpha Druid)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), 0" level="1" number="3" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Alpha Druid)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), 0" level="4" number="1" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Alpha Druid)" supports="$(spellcasting:list), 0" level="10" number="1" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Druid Circle" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_ALPHA_DRUID_DRUID_CIRCLE">
            <description>
                <p>At 2nd level, you choose to identify with a circle of druids, all detailed at the end of the class description. Your choice grants you features at 2nd level and again at 6th, 10th, 14th and 18th level.</p>
                <h5>Circle Spells</h5>
                <p>Your mystical connection to the land infuses you with the ability to cast certain spells. At 2nd, 3rd, 5th, 7th, and 9th level you gain access to circle spells connected to your chosen Circle.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you gain access to a circle spell, you always have it prepared, and it doesn’t count against the number of spells you can prepare each day. If you gain access to a spell that doesn’t appear on the druid spell list, the spell is nonetheless a druid spell for you.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Archetype" name="Druid Circle" supports="Alpha Druid Circle" level="2" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Nature’s Boon" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_ALPHA_DRUID_NATURES_BOON">
            <description>
                <p>As you protect nature, nature protects you, leaving you untouched by natural hazards. Beginning at 3rd level, you’re naturally acclimated to high altitude and adapted to warm and cold climates, as described in chapter 5 of the <em>Dungeon Master’s Guide</em> (Pg. 110).</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You’re naturally acclimated to high altitude and adapted to warm and cold climates.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Ability Score Improvement" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_ALPHA_DRUID_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can forgo taking this feature to take a feat of your choice instead.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Druid 4)" supports="Improvement Option,Druid,4" level="4" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Druid 8)" supports="Improvement Option,Druid,8" level="8" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Druid 12)" supports="Improvement Option,Druid,12" level="12" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Druid 16)" supports="Improvement Option,Druid,16" level="16" />
                <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Druid 19)" supports="Improvement Option,Druid,19" level="19" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Nature’s Ward" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_ALPHA_DRUID_NATURES_WARD">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 9th level, you can’t be charmed or frightened by elementals or fey, and you are immune to poison and disease.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can’t be charmed or frightened by elementals or fey, and you are immune to poison and disease.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Timeless Body" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_ALPHA_DRUID_TIMELESS_BODY">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 18th level, the primal magic that you wield causes you to age more slowly. For every 10 years that pass, your body ages only 1 year.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>For every 10 years that pass, your body ages only 1 year.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Archdruid" type="Class Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_ALPHA_DRUID_ARCHDRUID">
            <description>
                <p>At 20th level, you and nature have become one, and you can draw upon its full power with a mere thought. As a bonus action you can enter a state of deep connection to the world which lasts for 1 minute. While in this state you may cast any spell from the druid spell list as if you had it prepared. You can enter this state again after you finish a long rest.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, you can ignore the verbal and somatic components of your druid spells, as well as any material components that lack a cost and aren’t consumed by a spell.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You can enter a state of deep connection to the world which lasts for 1 minute. While in this state you may cast any spell from the druid spell list as if you had it prepared. Additionally, you can ignore the verbal and somatic components of your druid spells, as well as any material components that lack a cost and aren’t consumed by a spell.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>

    <!-- Druid Circles -->
        <element name="Circle of Growth" type="Archetype" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_ALPHA_DRUID_">
            <supports>Alpha Druid Circle</supports>
            <description>
                <p>Circle of Growth Druids of the Circle of Growth delve more completely into the ancient rituals and hidden knowledge of nature. These druids draw upon the power of the forests they protect to heal, defend, or help others understand them. As a member of this circle, your magic allows you to be one with your surroundings, gaining control over the plants around you.</p>
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_GROWTH_CIRCLE_SPELLS" />
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_GROWTH_PLANT_SHAPE" />
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_GROWTH_THE_WAY_OF_NATURE" />
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_GROWTH_BLUDGEONING_LIMBS" />
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_GROWTH_TAKE_ROOT" />
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_GROWTH_GREAT_TREE" />
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_GROWTH_ROOTS_OF_THE_WORLD" />
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_GROWTH_CIRCLE_SPELLS" level="2" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_GROWTH_PLANT_SHAPE" level="2" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_GROWTH_THE_WAY_OF_NATURE" level="2" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_GROWTH_BLUDGEONING_LIMBS" level="6" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_GROWTH_TAKE_ROOT" level="10" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_GROWTH_GREAT_TREE" level="14" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_GROWTH_ROOTS_OF_THE_WORLD" level="18" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Circle Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_GROWTH_CIRCLE_SPELLS">
                <description>
                    <p>You gain circle spells at the druid levels listed.</p>
                    <h5 class="caption">Growth Spells</h5>
                    <table>
                        <thead>
                            <tr><td>Druid Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                        </thead>
                        <tr><td>2nd</td><td><i>entangle, safety net</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>3rd</td><td><i>arm of the wild, spike growth</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>5th</td><td><i>skewering branch, spray of thorns</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>7th</td><td><i>grasping vine, tree strike</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>9th</td><td><i>tree stride, wrath of nature</i></td></tr>
                    </table>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENTANGLE" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="2" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_SPELL_SAFETY_NET" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="2" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_SPELL_ARM_OF_THE_WILD" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="3" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPIKE_GROWTH" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="3" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_SPELL_SKEWERING_BRANCH" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="5" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_SPELL_SPRAY_OF_THORNS" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="5" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GRASPING_VINE" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="7" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_SPELL_TREE_STRIKE" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="7" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TREE_STRIDE" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="9" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_WRATH_OF_NATURE" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="9" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Plant Shape" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_GROWTH_PLANT_SHAPE">
                <description>
                    <p>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your bonus action to magically assume the shape of an arboreal protector. You can use this feature twice and regain expended uses when you finish a short or long rest.</p>
                    <p class="indent">You can stay in this shape for up to 1 hour. You then revert to your normal form unless you expend another use of this feature. You can revert to your normal form earlier by using a bonus action on your turn. You automatically revert if you fall unconscious, drop to 0 hit points, or die.</p>
                    <p class="indent">While you are transformed, the following rules apply:</p>
                    <ul>
                        <li>Your game statistics are replaced by the statistics of the arboreal protector, but you retain your alignment, personality, proficiency modifier (already added in the statblock for attacks, increase it with levels), skill proficiencies, saving throws, and Intelligence, Wisdom, and Charisma scores.</li>
                        <li>When you transform, you assume the form’s hit points and Hit Dice. When you revert to your normal form, you return to the number of hit points you had before you transformed. However, if you revert as a result of dropping to 0 hit points, any excess damage carries over to your normal form and you must make a Constitution saving throw against the excess damage, gaining a level of exhaustion on a failure. For example, if you take 10 damage in plant form and have only 1 hit point left, you revert and take 9 damage and must make a DC 9 Constitution saving throw. As long as the excess damage doesn’t reduce your normal form to 0 hit points, you aren’t knocked unconscious.</li>
                        <li>You cannot cast any spells except spells on your Circle spell list. Transforming doesn’t break your concentration on a spell you’ve already cast or prevent you from taking actions that are part of a spell, such as call lightning, that you’ve already cast. You retain the benefit of any features from your class, race, or other source and can use them if the tree would be physically capable of doing so. However, you can’t use any of your special senses, such as darkvision.</li>
                        <li>Your equipment merges into your new form and has no effect (unless stated otherwises) until you leave the form.</li>
                    </ul>
                </description>
                <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="2/Short Rest">
                    <description>You can magically assume the shape of an arboreal protector. You can stay in this shape for up to 1 hour. You then revert to your normal form unless you expend another use of this feature. You can revert to your normal form earlier by using a bonus action on your turn. You automatically revert if you fall unconscious, drop to 0 hit points, or die.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_GROWTH_PLANT_SHAPE_ARBOREAL_PROTECTOR" level="2" />
                </rules>
            </element>
                <element name="Arboreal Protector" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_GROWTH_PLANT_SHAPE_ARBOREAL_PROTECTOR">
                    <description>
                        <p class="flavor">Large Plant</p>
                        <p><strong>Armor Class</strong> 16 (thick bark)</p>
                        <p><strong>Hit Points</strong> 15 (2d6 + 8)</p>
                        <p><strong>Speed</strong> 15 ft.</p>
                        <table>
                            <thead>
                                <tr><td>STR</td><td>DEX</td><td>CON</td></tr>
                            </thead>
                            <tr><td>18 (+4)</td><td>7 (-2)</td><td>18 (+4)</td></tr>
                        </table>
                        <p><strong>Thick Bark.</strong> Your AC is 16 and your Hit Points in this form increase by 8 (1d6 + 4) for each druid level above 2nd.</p>
                        <p><strong>Wooden Arms.</strong> When you try to a grapple a creature you have a reach of 10 feet. At the start of your turn you can pull a grappled creature 5 feet closer.</p>
                        <h5>Actions</h5>
                        <p><em><strong>Slam.</strong> Melee Attack:</em> +6 (proficiency bonus + Strength modifier), reach 10 ft., one target. <em>Hit:</em> 1d12 + 4 bludgeoning damage.</p>
                    </description>
                    <sheet usage="Plant Shape">
                        <description></description>
                    </sheet>
                </element>
            <element name="The Way of Nature" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_GROWTH_THE_WAY_OF_NATURE">
                <description>
                    <p>Starting at 2nd level, moving through nonmagical difficult terrain costs you no extra movement. You can also pass through plants without being slowed by them and without taking damage from them if they have thorns, spines, or a similar hazard.</p>
                    <p class="indent">In addition, you have advantage on saving throws against plants that are magically created or manipulated to impede movement, such those created by the <em>entangle</em> spell.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>Moving through nonmagical difficult terrain costs you no extra movement. You can also pass through plants without being slowed by them and without taking damage from them if they have thorns, spines, or a similar hazard. In addition, you have advantage on saving throws against plants that are magically created or manipulated to impede movement.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Bludgeoning Limbs" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_GROWTH_BLUDGEONING_LIMBS">
                <description>
                    <p>At 6th level, the strength of your tree limbs and plant magic increases. If you successfully grapple, attack, or deal damage to a creature with a Circle spell while in Plant Shape it takes an additional 1d8 bludgeoning damage. A creature also takes this damage if it is grappled or restrained by you or one of your Circle spells at the start of their turn. This damage increases by 1d8 at level 10 (2d8) and at level 14 (3d8).</p>
                    <p class="indent">Additionally, your attacks in tree form count as magical for the purpose of overcoming resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>If you successfully grapple, attack, or deal damage to a creature with a Circle spell while in Plant Shape it takes an additional {{bludgeoning-limbs:damage-dice}}d8 bludgeoning damage. A creature also takes this damage if it is grappled or restrained by you or one of your Circle spells at the start of their turn. Additionally, your attacks in tree form count as magical for the purpose of overcoming resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="bludgeoning-limbs:damage-dice" value="1" level="6" />
                    <stat name="bludgeoning-limbs:damage-dice" value="1" level="10" />
                    <stat name="bludgeoning-limbs:damage-dice" value="1" level="14" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Take Root" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_GROWTH_TAKE_ROOT">
                <description>
                    <p>Starting at 10th level, your connection to the natural world deepens. As an action you can root yourself to the ground while in your Plant Shape. You can end this effect by using a bonus action. While rooted you gain the following:</p>
                    <ul>
                        <li>Your movement speed is 0 and you have advantage on Strength (Athletics) checks.</li>
                        <li>You can use a bonus action to try and Grapple a creature within 15 feet.</li>
                        <li>Your AC increases to 20, unless already higher.</li>
                        <li>You have resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage.</li>
                        <li>You have advantage on Strength and Constitution saving throws, but disadvantage on Dexterity saving throw.</li>
                    </ul>
                </description>
                <sheet action="Action">
                    <description>You can root yourself to the ground while in your Plant Shape. Your movement speed is 0 and you have advantage on Strength (Athletics) checks. You can use a bonus action to try and Grapple a creature within 15 feet. Your AC increases to 20, unless already higher. You have resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage. You have advantage on Strength and Constitution saving throws, but disadvantage on Dexterity saving throw.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Great Tree" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_GROWTH_GREAT_TREE">
                <description>
                    <p>Starting at 14th level, while in Plant Shape your movement speed is now 30 feet and you gain an additional arm making you able to grapple an additional creature, as well as attack while grappling two creatures.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Also, while rooted you can make two Grapple attempts using a bonus action.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>While in Plant Shape your movement speed is now 30 feet and you gain an additional arm making you able to grapple an additional creature, as well as attack while grappling two creatures. Also, while rooted you can make two Grapple attempts using a bonus action.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Roots of the World" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_GROWTH_ROOTS_OF_THE_WORLD">
                <description>
                    <p>At 18th level, you can stay in Plant Shape for an unlimited amount of time and you can choose to become Huge when transforming. Also, while rooted, you can cast any spells you have prepared. Finally, you are always under the effect of the <em>speak with plants</em> spell.</p>
                    <div class="reference">
                        <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_PLANTS" />
                    </div>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>You can stay in Plant Shape for an unlimited amount of time and you can choose to become Huge when transforming. Also, while rooted, you can cast any spells you have prepared. Finally, you are always under the effect of the speak with plants spell.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_PLANTS" />
                </rules>
            </element>


        <element name="Circle of Keepers" type="Archetype" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_ALPHA_DRUID_CIRCLE_OF_KEEPERS">
            <supports>Alpha Druid Circle</supports>
            <description>
                <p>Druids are allies of nature and the creatures that make it their home. A few druids take it upon themselves to wander across the lands to protect the wilds from harm. During these travels they often gain a staunt ally which helps them preserve and protect. Together they form a powerful bond which empowers the them both.</p>
                <p class="indent"></p>
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_KEEPERS_CIRCLE_SPELLS" />
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_KEEPERS_OLD_TONGUE" />
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_KEEPERS_ANIMAL_COMPANION" />
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_KEEPERS_SUPERNATURAL_BOND" />
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_KEEPERS_SHARE_SPELLS" />
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_KEEPERS_TWIN_SPIRITS" />
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_KEEPERS_KEEPERS_OF_THE_LAND" />
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_KEEPERS_CIRCLE_SPELLS" level="2" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_KEEPERS_OLD_TONGUE" level="2" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_KEEPERS_ANIMAL_COMPANION" level="2" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_KEEPERS_SUPERNATURAL_BOND" level="6" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_KEEPERS_SHARE_SPELLS" level="10" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_KEEPERS_TWIN_SPIRITS" level="14" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_KEEPERS_KEEPERS_OF_THE_LAND" level="18" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Circle Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_KEEPERS_CIRCLE_SPELLS">
                <description>
                    <p>You gain circle spells at the druid levels listed.</p>
                    <h5 class="caption">Keeper Spells</h5>
                    <table>
                        <thead>
                            <tr><td>Druid Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                        </thead>
                        <tr><td>2nd</td><td><i>find familiar, sanctuary</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>3rd</td><td><i>enhance ability, enlarge/reduce</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>5th</td><td><i>haste, nondetection</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>7th</td><td><i>death ward, freedom of movement</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>9th</td><td><i>Rary’s telepathic bond, skill empowerment</i></td></tr>
                    </table>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIND_FAMILIAR" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="2" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SANCTUARY" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="2" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENHANCE_ABILITY" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="3" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENLARGE_REDUCE" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="3" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HASTE" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="5" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_NONDETECTION" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="5" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DEATH_WARD" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="7" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FREEDOM_OF_MOVEMENT" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="7" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RARYS_TELEPATHIC_BOND" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="9" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_SKILL_EMPOWERMENT" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="9" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Old Tongue" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_KEEPERS_OLD_TONGUE">
                <description>
                    <p>You have a deep connection to nature and the creatures therein. At 2nd level you have advantage on Wisdom (Animal Handling) checks.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>You have advantage on Wisdom (Animal Handling) checks.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Animal Companion" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_KEEPERS_ANIMAL_COMPANION">
                <description>
                    <p>At 2nd level, you bond yourself to a willing beast which is of importance to you. The rules for creating an Animal Companion are at the end of the document. The Companion obeys your commands as best it can.</p>
                    <p class="indent">If your Animal Companion is ever slain, the magical bond you share allows you to return it to life. By performing a 1 hour ritual and the expenditure of 15 gp per druid level worth of rare herbs and fine food, you call forth your Companion’s spirit and use your magic to create a new body for it. You can return a Companion to life in this manner even if you do not possess any part of its body.</p>
                    <h5 class="caption">Companion’s Bond</h5>
                    <p>Your Animal Companion gains a variety of benefits while it is accompanying you:</p>
                    <ul>
                        <li>It acts on your initiative, and you determine its actions, decisions, attitudes, and so on (no action required by you). If you are incapacitated or absent, your Companion acts on its own.</li>
                        <li>Your Animal Companion has abilities and game statistics determined in part by your level. Your Companion uses your proficiency bonus rather than its own.</li>
                        <li>Whenever you gain the Ability Score Improvement druid class feature, so does your Companion. Your Companion can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or it can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. Your Companion can’t increase an ability score above 22 using this feature.</li>
                    </ul>
                    <div class="sidebar">
                        <h5 class="caption">Co-owned</h5>
                        <p>If you have an Animal Companion from the Ranger class, you don’t get a new Companion, though it does gain Ability Score Increases as it would if you were a druid.</p>
                    </div>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>You bond yourself to a willing beast which is of importance to you. The Companion obeys your commands as best it can. It acts on your initiative, and you determine its actions, decisions, attitudes, and so on (no action required by you). If you are incapacitated or absent, your Companion acts on its own.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <select type="Companion" name="Animal Companion (Circle of Keepers)" supports="Beast" level="2" />
                    <stat name="companion:proficiency" value="proficiency" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Supernatural Bond" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_KEEPERS_SUPERNATURAL_BOND">
                <description>
                    <p>Your magic reverberates with your companion empowering its attacks. At 6th level, your Companion’s attacks counts as magical for the purpose of overcoming damage reduction.</p>
                    <p class="indent">In addition, whenever you target your Companion with a spell of 1st level or higher or it is under the effect of one of your spells, your Companion deals additional damage equal to your Wisdom modifier + the spell’s level on all attacks until the start of its next turn.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>Your Companion’s attacks counts as magical for the purpose of overcoming damage reduction. In addition, whenever you target your Companion with a spell of 1st level or higher or it is under the effect of one of your spells, your Companion deals {{wisdom:modifier}} + the spell’s level additional damage on all attacks until the start of its next turn.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Share Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_KEEPERS_SHARE_SPELLS">
                <description>
                    <p>At 10th level, whenever you cast a spell targeting a creature, you can also target your Companion if it is within range of the spell.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>Whenever you cast a spell targeting a creature, you can also target your Companion if it is within range of the spell.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Twin Spirits" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_KEEPERS_TWIN_SPIRITS">
                <description>
                    <p>At 14th level, you can use an action to turn your familiar into the same animal as your companion, gaining the same statistics as it. The transformation lasts for 10 minutes and if it dies, you have to resummon it using find familiar. While transformed your familiar can attack as your Companion can.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Once you’ve done this, you cannot do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
                    <description>You can turn your familiar into the same animal as your companion, gaining the same statistics as it. The transformation lasts for 10 minutes and if it dies, you have to resummon it using find familiar. While transformed your familiar can attack as your Companion can.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Keepers of the Land" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_KEEPERS_KEEPERS_OF_THE_LAND">
                <description>
                    <p>At 18th level, your Animal Companion doesn’t have to be in range to be targeted by a spell you cast on a creature and if your familiar is affected by Twin Spirits you can target it as well.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Additionally, if your familiar is affected by Twin Spirits and within 5 feet of your Companion, both gain advantage on melee attacks.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>Your Animal Companion doesn’t have to be in range to be targeted by a spell you cast on a creature and if your familiar is affected by Twin Spirits you can target it as well. Additionally, if your familiar is affected by Twin Spirits and within 5 feet of your Companion, both gain advantage on melee attacks.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>


        <element name="Circle of Remembrance" type="Archetype" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_ALPHA_DRUID_CIRCLE_OF_REMEMBERANCE">
            <supports>Alpha Druid Circle</supports>
            <description>
                <p>The druids of the Circle of Remembrance believes that no living being deserves to be forgotten. They spend most of their lives living the past, walking the memories and tasting the emotions of creatures they never met. Some of the memories are from the long dead, but the intensity of their emotions are so powerful that they linger even after any other remnant of their being is long gone.</p>
                <p class="indent">These memories can affect the druid deeply, often making them sullen and later alienated, as their mood changes harshly from day to day. Sometimes they are seen as judges, able to see past facades and see what is real and true.</p>
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_REMEMBERANCE_CIRCLE_SPELLS" />
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_REMEMBERANCE_EMPATHIC_CHRONICLER" />
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_REMEMBERANCE_RESERVOIR_OF_MEMORIES" />
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_REMEMBERANCE_EMOTIONAL_RESONANCE" />
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_REMEMBERANCE_EMBOLDENED_MIND" />
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_REMEMBERANCE_CONSCIOUS_DUALITY" />
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_REMEMBERANCE_WORLDLY_ECHOES" />
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_REMEMBERANCE_CIRCLE_SPELLS" level="2" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_REMEMBERANCE_EMPATHIC_CHRONICLER" level="2" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_REMEMBERANCE_RESERVOIR_OF_MEMORIES" level="2" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_REMEMBERANCE_EMOTIONAL_RESONANCE" level="6" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_REMEMBERANCE_EMBOLDENED_MIND" level="10" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_REMEMBERANCE_CONSCIOUS_DUALITY" level="14" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_REMEMBERANCE_WORLDLY_ECHOES" level="18" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Circle Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_REMEMBERANCE_CIRCLE_SPELLS">
                <description>
                    <p>You gain circle spells at the druid levels listed.</p>
                    <h5 class="caption">Remembrance Spells</h5>
                    <table>
                        <thead>
                            <tr><td>Druid Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                        </thead>
                        <tr><td>2nd</td><td><i>identify</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>3rd</td><td><i>detect thoughts</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>5th</td><td><i>speak with dead</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>7th</td><td><i>locate creature</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>9th</td><td><i>legend lore</i></td></tr>
                    </table>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_IDENTIFY" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="2" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_THOUGHTS" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="3" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_DEAD" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="5" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LOCATE_CREATURE" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="7" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LEGEND_LORE" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="9" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Empathic Chronicler" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_REMEMBERANCE_EMPATHIC_CHRONICLER">
                <description>
                    <p>Starting at 2nd level, you are starting to be able to see and feel the memories of the world as if they were your own. You gain the <em>flash enchantment</em> cantrip and proficiency in History. When you use <em>flash enchantment</em> it deals psychic damage instead of the original.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>When you use flash enchantment it deals psychic damage instead of the original.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_SPELL_FLASH_ENCHANTMENT" spellcasting="Druid" known="true" level="2" />
                    <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_HISTORY" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Reservoir of Memories" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_REMEMBERANCE_RESERVOIR_OF_MEMORIES">
                <description>
                    <p>At 2nd level, you can manifest a memory, focusing the raw emotion into a semi-transparent totem. As an action you can choose; anguish, despair, or hope, and an unoccupied 5-foot square within 15 feet of you. A totem of the chosen memory appears within the area and you gain access to its memory spells. As past of manifesting the memory, you can cast one of the spells related to that particular memory.</p>
                    <p class="indent">When casting a memory spell, you can only cast it through the totem, as if you stood in its area. You can do so as long as you are within 15 feet of the it. If a spell has range of Touch, you can target any creature within 15 feet of the totem.</p>
                    <p class="indent">A totem is an object that fills a 5-foot square, it has an AC equal to 14 + your proficiency bonus, and hit points equal to 10 + twice your druid level, but it can’t be affected by spells and abilities which targets an area of effect. If the totem is destroyed, any spell being cast through it immediately ends. It blocks the area but it cannot be climbed upon, since any creature which tries to enter its area are overwhelmed by emotions. After 1 minute, or if it is destroyed, it disappears into nothingness.</p>
                    <p class="indent">You can use this feature twice and regain expended uses when you finish a short or long rest but you can only have one memory manifested at any one time.</p>
                    <h5 class="caption">Memory of Anguish Spells</h5>
                    <table>
                        <thead>
                            <tr><td>Druid Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                        </thead>
                        <tr><td>2nd</td><td><i>inflict wounds</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>3rd</td><td><i>suffer</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>5th</td><td><i>slow</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>7th</td><td><i>phantasmal killer</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>9th</td><td><i>agonizing whip</i></td></tr>
                    </table>
                    <h5 class="caption">Memory of Despair Spells</h5>
                    <table>
                        <thead>
                            <tr><td>Druid Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                        </thead>
                        <tr><td>2nd</td><td><i>bane</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>3rd</td><td><i>hold person</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>5th</td><td><i>fear</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>7th</td><td><i>banishment</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>9th</td><td><i>hold monster</i></td></tr>
                    </table>
                    <h5 class="caption">Memory of Hope Spells</h5>
                    <table>
                        <thead>
                            <tr><td>Druid Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                        </thead>
                        <tr><td>2nd</td><td><i>heroism</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>3rd</td><td><i>lesser restoration</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>5th</td><td><i>beacon of hope</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>7th</td><td><i>freedom of movement</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>9th</td><td><i>circle of power</i></td></tr>
                    </table>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_REMEMBERANCE_RESERVOIR_OF_MEMORIES_2" level="2" />
                    <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_REMEMBERANCE_RESERVOIR_OF_MEMORIES_ANGUISH" level="2" />
                    <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_REMEMBERANCE_RESERVOIR_OF_MEMORIES_DESPAIR" level="2" />
                    <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_REMEMBERANCE_RESERVOIR_OF_MEMORIES_HOPE" level="2" />
                </rules>
            </element>
                <element name="Reservoir of Memories" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_REMEMBERANCE_RESERVOIR_OF_MEMORIES_2">
                    <description>
                        <p>At 2nd level, you can manifest a memory, focusing the raw emotion into a semi-transparent totem. As an action you can choose; anguish, despair, or hope, and an unoccupied 5-foot square within 15 feet of you. A totem of the chosen memory appears within the area and you gain access to its memory spells. As past of manifesting the memory, you can cast one of the spells related to that particular memory.</p>
                        <p class="indent">When casting a memory spell, you can only cast it through the totem, as if you stood in its area. You can do so as long as you are within 15 feet of the it. If a spell has range of Touch, you can target any creature within 15 feet of the totem.</p>
                        <p class="indent">A totem is an object that fills a 5-foot square, it has an AC equal to 14 + your proficiency bonus, and hit points equal to 10 + twice your druid level, but it can’t be affected by spells and abilities which targets an area of effect. If the totem is destroyed, any spell being cast through it immediately ends. It blocks the area but it cannot be climbed upon, since any creature which tries to enter its area are overwhelmed by emotions. After 1 minute, or if it is destroyed, it disappears into nothingness.</p>
                        <p class="indent">You can use this feature twice and regain expended uses when you finish a short or long rest but you can only have one memory manifested at any one time.</p>
                    </description>
                    <sheet action="Action" usage="2/Short Rest">
                        <description>You can manifest a memory as a totem, choosing anguish, despair, or hope, in an unoccupied space within 15 feet of you. You gain access to the totems memory spells.</description>
                    </sheet>
                </element>
                <element name="Memory of Anguish" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_REMEMBERANCE_RESERVOIR_OF_MEMORIES_ANGUISH">
                    <description>
                        <table>
                            <thead>
                                <tr><td>Druid Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                            </thead>
                            <tr><td>2nd</td><td><i>inflict wounds</i></td></tr>
                            <tr><td>3rd</td><td><i>suffer</i></td></tr>
                            <tr><td>5th</td><td><i>slow</i></td></tr>
                            <tr><td>7th</td><td><i>phantasmal killer</i></td></tr>
                            <tr><td>9th</td><td><i>agonizing whip</i></td></tr>
                        </table>
                    </description>
                    <sheet usage="Reservoir of Memories">
                        <description>inflict wounds, suffer, slow, phantasmal killer, agonizing whip</description>
                    </sheet>
                    <rules>
                        <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INFLICT_WOUNDS" prepared="false" level="2" />
                        <grant type="Spell" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_SPELL_SUFFER" prepared="false" level="3" />
                        <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SLOW" prepared="false" level="5" />
                        <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PHANTASMAL_KILLER" prepared="false" level="7" />
                        <grant type="Spell" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_SPELL_AGONIZING_WHIP" prepared="false" level="9" />
                    </rules>
                </element>
                <element name="Memory of Despair" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_REMEMBERANCE_RESERVOIR_OF_MEMORIES_DESPAIR">
                    <description>
                        <table>
                            <thead>
                                <tr><td>Druid Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                            </thead>
                            <tr><td>2nd</td><td><i>bane</i></td></tr>
                            <tr><td>3rd</td><td><i>hold person</i></td></tr>
                            <tr><td>5th</td><td><i>fear</i></td></tr>
                            <tr><td>7th</td><td><i>banishment</i></td></tr>
                            <tr><td>9th</td><td><i>hold monster</i></td></tr>
                        </table>
                    </description>
                    <sheet usage="Reservoir of Memories">
                        <description>bane, hold person, fear, banishment,hold monster</description>
                    </sheet>
                    <rules>
                        <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BANE" prepared="false" level="2" />
                        <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HOLD_PERSON" prepared="false" level="3" />
                        <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FEAR" prepared="false" level="5" />
                        <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BANISHMENT" prepared="false" level="7" />
                        <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HOLD_MONSTER" prepared="false" level="9" />
                    </rules>
                </element>
                <element name="Memory of Hope" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_REMEMBERANCE_RESERVOIR_OF_MEMORIES_HOPE">
                    <description>
                        <table>
                            <thead>
                                <tr><td>Druid Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                            </thead>
                            <tr><td>2nd</td><td><i>heroism</i></td></tr>
                            <tr><td>3rd</td><td><i>lesser restoration</i></td></tr>
                            <tr><td>5th</td><td><i>beacon of hope</i></td></tr>
                            <tr><td>7th</td><td><i>freedom of movement</i></td></tr>
                            <tr><td>9th</td><td><i>circle of power</i></td></tr>
                        </table>
                    </description>
                    <sheet usage="Reservoir of Memories">
                        <description>heroism, lesser restoration, beacon of hope, freedom of movement, circle of power</description>
                    </sheet>
                    <rules>
                        <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HEROISM" prepared="false" level="2" />
                        <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LESSER_RESTORATION" prepared="false" level="3" />
                        <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BEACON_OF_HOPE" prepared="false" level="5" />
                        <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FREEDOM_OF_MOVEMENT" prepared="false" level="7" />
                        <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CIRCLE_OF_POWER" prepared="false" level="9" />
                    </rules>
                </element>
            <element name="Emotional Resonance" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_REMEMBERANCE_EMOTIONAL_RESONANCE">
                <description>
                    <p>Beginning at 6th level, the minds of your enemies becomes unstable in the presence of your manifested memories. While you are concentrating on a spell through your totem, you can use your reaction when a creature within 15 feet of it takes damage to inflict an additional 1d6 psychic damage.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet action="Reaction">
                    <description>While you are concentrating on a spell through your totem, you can inflict an additional 1d6 psychic damage on a creature within 15 feet of your totem.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Emboldened Mind" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_REMEMBERANCE_EMBOLDENED_MIND">
                <description>
                    <p>At 10th level, you have begun to long for more powerful experiences. While within 15 feet of a totem, your Emotional Resonance ability is strengthened depending on the memory:</p>
                    <ul>
                        <li><strong>Anguish.</strong> The target takes an additional 1d6 damage (2d6).</li>
                        <li><strong>Despair.</strong> You can target a creature within 30 feet.</li>
                        <li><strong>Hope.</strong> You are healed for the same amount.</li>
                    </ul>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>While within 15 feet of a totem, your Emotional Resonance ability is strengthened depending on the memory. Anguish: The target takes an additional 1d6 damage (2d6). Despair: You can target a creature within 30 feet. Hope: You are healed for the same amount.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Conscious Duality" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_REMEMBERANCE_CONSCIOUS_DUALITY">
                <description>
                    <p>At 14th level, you have become powerful enough to maintain two different memories at the same time. You can have two different manifested memories at a time. You may only cast spells of the particular memory through its associated totem. For example, you can only channel memory of hope spells through the hope totem.</p>
                    <p class="indent">You can summon two additional totems before you must finish a short or long rest.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="2/Short Rest">
                    <description>You can have two different manifested memories at a time. You may only cast spells of the particular memory through its associated totem.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Worldly Echoes" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_REMEMBERANCE_WORLDLY_ECHOES">
                <description>
                    <p>At 18th level, you’ve embraced the memories of the world, channeling their power without much thought. While you are concentrating on a memory spell, you can cast an additional memory spell of a different memory that requires concentration and choose to maintain concentration on both spells simultaneously. For example, you can cast hold person from your despair totem and beacon of hope from your hope totem, but you can’t concentrate on two hold person spells.</p>
                    <p class="indent">If you fail a Constitution saving throw to maintain concentration, you lose concentration on both spells.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>While you are concentrating on a memory spell, you can cast an additional memory spell of a different memory that requires concentration and choose to maintain concentration on both spells simultaneously. If you fail a Constitution saving throw to maintain concentration, you lose concentration on both spells.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>


        <element name="Circle of Spores" type="Archetype" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_ALPHA_DRUID_CIRCLE_OF_SPORES">
            <supports>Alpha Druid Circle</supports>
            <description>
                <p>Druids of the Circle of Spores find beauty in decay. They see within mold and other fungi the ability to transform lifeless material into abundant, albeit somewhat strange, life.</p>
                <p class="indent">These druids believe that life and death are parts of a grand cycle, with one leading to the other and then back again. Death isn’t the end of life, but instead a change of state that sees life shift into a new form.</p>
                <p class="indent">Druids of this circle have a complex relationship with the undead. Unlike most other druids, they see nothing inherently wrong with undeath, which they consider to be a companion to life and death. But these druids believe that the natural cycle is healthiest when each segment of it is vibrant and changing. Undead that seek to replace all life with undeath, or that try to avoid passing to a final rest, violate the cycle and must be thwarted.</p>
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_SPORES_CIRCLE_SPELLS" />
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_SPORES_HALO_OF_SPORES" />
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_SPORES_SYMBIOTIC_ENTITY" />
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_SPORES_FUNGAL_INFESTATION" />
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_SPORES_SPREADING_SPORES" />
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_SPORES_FUNGAL_BODY" />
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_SPORES_INVADING_SPORES" />
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_SPORES_CIRCLE_SPELLS" level="2" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_SPORES_HALO_OF_SPORES" level="2" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_SPORES_SYMBIOTIC_ENTITY" level="2" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_SPORES_FUNGAL_INFESTATION" level="6" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_SPORES_SPREADING_SPORES" level="10" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_SPORES_FUNGAL_BODY" level="14" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_SPORES_INVADING_SPORES" level="18" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Circle Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_SPORES_CIRCLE_SPELLS">
                <description>
                    <p>You gain circle spells at the druid levels listed.</p>
                    <h5 class="caption">Spore Spells</h5>
                    <table>
                        <thead>
                            <tr><td>Druid Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                        </thead>
                        <tr><td>2nd</td><td><i>rapport spores, ray of sickness</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>3rd</td><td><i>blindness/deafness, gentle repose</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>5th</td><td><i>animate dead, gaseous form</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>7th</td><td><i>blight, confusion</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>9th</td><td><i>cloudkill, contagion</i></td></tr>
                    </table>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_SPELL_RAPPORT_SPORES" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="2" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RAY_OF_SICKNESS" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="2" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLINDNESS_DEAFNESS" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="3" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GENTLE_REPOSE" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="3" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANIMATE_DEAD" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="5" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GASEOUS_FORM" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="5" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLIGHT" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="7" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONFUSION" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="7" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONTAGION" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="9" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CLOUDKILL" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="9" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Halo of Spores" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_SPORES_HALO_OF_SPORES">
                <description>
                    <p>Starting at 2nd level, you are surrounded by invisible necrotic spores that are harmless until you unleash them on a creature nearby. When a creature you can see moves into a space within 10 feet of you or starts its turn there, you can use your reaction to deal 1d4 poison damage to that creature unless it succeeds on a Constitution saving throw against your spell save DC. The poison damage increases to 1d6 at 6th level, 1d8 at 10th level, and 1d10 at 14th level.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Additionally, you learn the blightclaw cantrip.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet action="Reaction">
                    <description>When a creature you can see moves into a space within 10 feet of you or starts its turn there, you can deal 1d{{halo-of-spores:die-type}} poison damage to that creature unless it succeeds on a Constitution saving throw against your spell save DC.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="halo-of-spores:die-type" value="4" bonus="base" level="2" />
                    <stat name="halo-of-spores:die-type" value="6" bonus="base" level="10" />
                    <stat name="halo-of-spores:die-type" value="8" bonus="base" level="14" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_SPELL_BLIGHTCLAW" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" known="true" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Symbiotic Entity" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_SPORES_SYMBIOTIC_ENTITY">
                <description>
                    <p>At 2nd level, you gain the ability to channel magic into your spores. At the start of your turn, you can awaken those spores and you gain 4 temporary hit points for each level you have in this class. While this feature is active, you gain the following benefits:</p>
                    <ul>
                        <li>When you deal your Halo of Spores damage, roll the damage die a second time and add it to the total.</li>
                        <li>Your melee attacks deal an extra 1d6 poison damage to any target they hit.</li>
                    </ul>
                    <p>These benefits last for 10 minutes, until you lose all these temporary hit points, or until you use this feature again.</p>
                    <p class="indent">You can do this twice before you have to finish a short or long rest.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="2/Short Rest">
                    <description>At the start of your turn, you channel magic into your spores, granting you {{symbiotic-entity:temp-hp}} temporary hit points. While this is in effect, when you deal your Halo of Spores damage, roll the damage die a second time and add it to the total, and your melee attacks deal an extra 1d6 poison damage. These benefits last for 10 minutes, until you lose all these temporary hit points, or until you use this feature again.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="symbiotic-entity:temp-hp" value="level:alpha druid" />
                    <stat name="symbiotic-entity:temp-hp" value="level:alpha druid" />
                    <stat name="symbiotic-entity:temp-hp" value="level:alpha druid" />
                    <stat name="symbiotic-entity:temp-hp" value="level:alpha druid" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Fungal Infestation" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_SPORES_FUNGAL_INFESTATION">
                <description>
                    <p>At 6th level, when you cast <em>blightclaw</em> you can cast it again as a bonus action and your poison damage and poisoned condition ignore resistance and immunity.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Also your spores gain the ability to infest a corpse and animate it. If a beast or a humanoid that is Small or Medium dies within 10 feet of you, you can use your reaction to animate it, causing it to stand up immediately as an infested. It remains animate for 1 hour, after which time it collapses and dies.</p>
                    <p class="indent">In combat, the infested’s turn comes immediately after yours. It obeys your mental commands, and the only action it can take is the Attack action, making one melee attack.</p>
                    <p class="indent">You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier (minimum of once), and you regain all expended uses of it when you finish a long rest.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet usage="{{fungal-infestation:uses}}/Long Rest">
                    <description>If a beast or a humanoid that is Small or Medium dies within 10 feet of you, you can use your reaction to animate it, causing it to stand up immediately as an infested. It remains animate for 1 hour, after which time it collapses and dies. Additionally, whenever you cast blightclaw you can cast it again as a bonus action and your poison damage and poisoned condition ignore resistance and immunity.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="fungal-infestation:uses" value="1" bonus="base" />
                    <stat name="fungal-infestation:uses" value="wisdom:modifier" bonus="base" />
                    <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_SPORES_FUNGAL_INFESTATION_INFESTED" level="6" />
                </rules>
            </element>
                <element name="Infested" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_SPORES_FUNGAL_INFESTATION_INFESTED">
                    <description>
                        <p class="flavor">Medium undead, neutral evil</p>
                        <p><strong>Armor Class</strong> 8</p>
                        <p><strong>Hit Points</strong> 4</p>
                        <p><strong>Speed</strong> 20 ft.</p>
                        <table>
                            <thead>
                                <tr><td>STR</td><td>DEX</td><td>CON</td><td>INT</td><td>WIS</td><td>CON</td></tr>
                            </thead>
                            <tr><td>13 (+1)</td><td>6 (-2)</td><td>16 (+3)</td><td>3 (-4)</td><td>6 (-2)</td><td>5 (-3)</td></tr>
                        </table>
                        <p><strong>Damage Immunities</strong> poison</p>
                        <p><strong>Condition Immunities</strong> poisoned</p>
                        <p><strong>Senses</strong> darkvision 60 ft., passive Perception 8</p>
                        <p><strong>Languages</strong> understands the druid but can’t speak</p>
                        <p><strong>Challenge</strong> 1/4 (50 XP)</p>
                        <p><strong>Undead Fortitude.</strong> If damage reduces the infested to 0 hit points, it must make a Constitution saving throw with a DC of 5 + the damage taken, unless the damage is radiant or from a critical hit. On a success, the infested drops to 1 hit point instead.</p>
                        <h5>Actions</h5>
                        <p><em><strong>Slam.</strong> Melee Attack:</em> +3 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. <em>Hit:</em> 4 (1d6+1) bludgeoning damage.</p>
                    </description>
                    <sheet usage="Fungal Infestation">
                        <description></description>
                    </sheet>
                </element>
            <element name="Spreading Spores" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_SPORES_SPREADING_SPORES">
                <description>
                    <p>At 10th level, you gain the ability to seed an area with deadly spores. As a bonus action while your Symbiotic Entity feature is active, you can hurl spores up to 30 feet away, where they swirl in a 10-foot cube for 1 minute. The spores disappear early if you use this feature again, if you dismiss them as a bonus action, or if your Symbiotic Entity feature is no longer active.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Whenever a creature moves into the cube or starts its turn there, that creature takes your Halo of Spores damage, unless the creature succeeds on a Constitution saving throw against your spell save DC. A creature can take this damage no more than once per turn.</p>
                    <p class="indent">While the cube of spores persists, you can’t use your Halo of Spores reaction.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                    <description>While your Symbiotic Entity feature is active, you can hurl spores up to 30 feet away, where they swirl in a 10-foot cube for 1 minute. Whenever a creature moves into the cube or starts its turn there, that creature takes your Halo of Spores damage, unless the creature succeeds on a Constitution saving throw against your spell save DC. A creature can take this damage no more than once per turn. While the cube of spores persists, you can’t use your Halo of Spores reaction.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Fungal Body" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_SPORES_FUNGAL_BODY">
                <description>
                    <p>At 14th level, the fungal spores in your body alter you: you can’t be blinded, deafened, or frightened, and any critical hit against you counts as a normal hit instead, unless you’re incapacitated.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>You can’t be blinded, deafened, or frightened, and any critical hit against you counts as a normal hit instead, unless you’re incapacitated.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Invading Spores" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_SPORES_INVADING_SPORES">
                <description>
                    <p>Beginning at 18th level, when an undead creature under your control dies, it explodes in a cloud of spores. Each creature of your choice within 10 feet must roll a Constitution saving throw against your spell save DC or take 5d6 poison damage and become poisoned for 1 minute. On a successful save, a creature takes half damage and is not poisoned.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>When an undead creature under your control dies, it explodes in a cloud of spores. Each creature of your choice within 10 feet must roll a Constitution saving throw against your spell save DC or take 5d6 poison damage and become poisoned for 1 minute. On a successful save, a creature takes half damage and is not poisoned.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>


        <element name="Circle of the Courts" type="Archetype" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_ALPHA_DRUID_CIRCLE_OF_THE_COURTS">
            <supports>Alpha Druid Circle</supports>
            <description>
                <p>Druids who are members of the Circle of the Courts hail from regions that have strong ties to the Feywild and its dreamlike realms. These druids seek to fill the world with wonders which are beyond the Material Plane.</p>
                <p class="indent">To succeed in this they must successfully manage the fey, creatures who are both fickle and dangerous. Fey are often divided into Seelie and Unseelie, light and dark, summer and winter, but that doesn’t mean one is more evil than the other. Both are just as prone to cause terror as they are to bring joy since they are both unpredictable and hard to please.</p>
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_COURTS_CIRCLE_SPELLS" />
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_COURTS_COURT_ATTENDEE" />
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_COURTS_WARRIOR_OF_THE_FEYWILD" />
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_COURTS_UNCONVENTIONAL_WARFARE" />
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_COURTS_GRACE_OF_THE_SEELIE" />
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_COURTS_BEAUTY_OF_THE_UNSEELIE" />
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_COURTS_DREAM_WARRIOR" />
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_COURTS_CIRCLE_SPELLS" level="2" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_COURTS_COURT_ATTENDEE" level="2" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_COURTS_WARRIOR_OF_THE_FEYWILD" level="2" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_COURTS_UNCONVENTIONAL_WARFARE" level="6" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_COURTS_GRACE_OF_THE_SEELIE" level="10" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_COURTS_BEAUTY_OF_THE_UNSEELIE" level="14" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_COURTS_DREAM_WARRIOR" level="18" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Circle Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_COURTS_CIRCLE_SPELLS">
                <description>
                    <p>You gain circle spells at the druid levels listed.</p>
                    <h5 class="caption">Court Spells</h5>
                    <table>
                        <thead>
                            <tr><td>Druid Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                        </thead>
                        <tr><td>2nd</td><td><i>charm person, klazomania</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>3rd</td><td><i>darkness, invisibility</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>5th</td><td><i>perplex, pincushion</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>7th</td><td><i>confusion, greater invisibility</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>9th</td><td><i>dominate person, far step</i></td></tr>
                    </table>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CHARM_PERSON" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="2" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_SPELL_KLAZOMANIA" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="2" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DARKNESS" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="3" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INVISIBILITY" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="3" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_SPELL_PERPLEX" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="5" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_SPELL_PINCUSHION" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="5" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONFUSION" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="7" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GREATER_INVISIBILITY" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="7" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DOMINATE_PERSON" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="9" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_FAR_STEP" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="9" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Court Attendee" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_COURTS_COURT_ATTENDEE">
                <description>
                    <p>Starting at 2nd level, you have gained enough prowess to survive the dangerous fey courts. You learn to speak, read, and write Sylvan and gain proficiency in the Deception and Persuasion skill.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_DECEPTION" />
                    <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERSUASION" />
                    <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_SYLVAN" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Warrior of the Feywild" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_COURTS_WARRIOR_OF_THE_FEYWILD">
                <description>
                    <p>At 2nd level, the warriors of the fey have taught you much of how to fight. You gain proficiency with simple weapons, longbows, longswords, rapiers, shortswords and tridents.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Additionally, you gain the <em>minor illusion</em> and <em>vicious mockery</em> cantrips.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" />
                    <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_LONGBOW" />
                    <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_LONGSWORD" />
                    <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_RAPIER" />
                    <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SHORTSWORD" />
                    <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_TRIDENT" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MINOR_ILLUSION" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" level="2" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_VICIOUS_MOCKERY" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" level="2" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Unconventional Warfare" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_COURTS_UNCONVENTIONAL_WARFARE">
                <description>
                    <p>At 6th level, you have taken on another aspect of fey combat. After you take the Attack action on your turn, you can cast <em>vicious mockery</em> or one of your Circle Spells at its lowest level as a bonus action.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                    <description>After you take the Attack action on your turn, you can cast vicious mockery or one of your Circle Spells at its lowest level.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Grace of the Seelie" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_COURTS_GRACE_OF_THE_SEELIE">
                <description>
                    <p>At 10th level, the court of summer has granted your their blessing. Whenever you hit a creature with a weapon attack, the target is charmed by you until the end of your turn. If you had advantage on the attack roll, the creature is charmed until the end of its turn.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>Whenever you hit a creature with a weapon attack, the target is charmed by you until the end of your turn. If you had advantage on the attack roll, the creature is charmed until the end of its turn.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Beauty of the Unseelie" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_COURTS_BEAUTY_OF_THE_UNSEELIE">
                <description>
                    <p>At 14th level, the court of winter has bestowed their powers upon you. When casting <em>charm person</em> or <em>dominate person</em>, the target doesn’t gain advantage on the saving throw if it is fighting you.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Additionally, creatures have disadvantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks against you.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>When casting charm person or dominate person, the target doesn’t gain advantage on the saving throw if it is fighting you. Additionally, creatures have disadvantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks against you.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Dream Warrior" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_COURTS_DREAM_WARRIOR">
                <description>
                    <p>Beginning at 18th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Also, you can cast your Circle Spells of 2nd level or lower without expending a spell slot.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>You can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn. Also, you can cast your Circle Spells of 2nd level or lower without expending a spell slot.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
        			<stat name="extra attack:count" value="2" level="18" bonus="extra attack" />
                </rules>
            </element>


        <element name="Circle of the Forgotten" type="Archetype" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_ALPHA_DRUID_CIRCLE_OF_THE_FORGOTTEN">
            <supports>Alpha Druid Circle</supports>
            <description>
                <p>Not much is known about the Circle of the Forgotten since they tend to keep to the darkest corners of nature, usually seen wandering alone. Druids of this circle are disconnected from the regular life most live, often finding themselves bonding with the millions of unseen lives they protect. Those who have come upon such a druid often feel uncomfortable speaking about it, sometimes even downright fearful of mentioning the druid’s name.</p>
                <p class="indent">What little is known is that they use insects to control their enemies and aid their allies. The swarms they control move with a singular mind and with a dangerous intellect.</p>
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_FORGOTTEN_CIRCLE_SPELLS" />
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_FORGOTTEN_FOCUSED_HARASSMENT" />
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_FORGOTTEN_MILLING_SHIELD" />
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_FORGOTTEN_STRENGTH_OF_THE_SWARM" />
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_FORGOTTEN_HIVE_MIND" />
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_FORGOTTEN_RELENTLESS_HORDE" />
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_FORGOTTEN_MILLING_SWARM" />
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_FORGOTTEN_CIRCLE_SPELLS" level="2" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_FORGOTTEN_FOCUSED_HARASSMENT" level="2" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_FORGOTTEN_MILLING_SHIELD" level="2" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_FORGOTTEN_STRENGTH_OF_THE_SWARM" level="6" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_FORGOTTEN_HIVE_MIND" level="10" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_FORGOTTEN_RELENTLESS_HORDE" level="14" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_FORGOTTEN_MILLING_SWARM" level="18" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Circle Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_FORGOTTEN_CIRCLE_SPELLS">
                <description>
                    <p>You gain circle spells at the druid levels listed.</p>
                    <h5 class="caption">Forgotten Spells</h5>
                    <table>
                        <thead>
                            <tr><td>Druid Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                        </thead>
                        <tr><td>2nd</td><td><i>false life, inflict wounds</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>3rd</td><td><i>locate object, mind spike</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>5th</td><td><i>enemies abound, fear</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>7th</td><td><i>giant insect, locate creature</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>9th</td><td><i>insect plague, modify memory</i></td></tr>
                    </table>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FALSE_LIFE" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="2" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INFLICT_WOUNDS" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="2" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LOCATE_OBJECT" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="3" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_MIND_SPIKE" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="3" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ENEMIES_ABOUND" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="5" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FEAR" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="5" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GIANT_INSECT" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="7" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LOCATE_CREATURE" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="7" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INSECT_PLAGUE" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="9" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MODIFY_MEMORY" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="9" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Focused Harassment" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_FORGOTTEN_FOCUSED_HARASSMENT">
                <description>
                    <p>At 2nd level, you’ve learned how to attack your enemies in such a way to force them to move where you want them. You gain the <em>infestation</em> cantrip. When you cast the <em>infestation</em> cantrip, you can choose which direction the creature moves.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Additionally, you can choose for <em>infestation</em> to deal piercing damage instead of poison.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>When you cast the infestation cantrip, you can choose which direction the creature moves. Additionally, you can choose for infestation to deal piercing damage instead of poison.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_INFESTATION" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" level="2" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Milling Shield" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_FORGOTTEN_MILLING_SHIELD">
                <description>
                    <p>Starting at 2nd level, the thousands of insects around you will put themselves as a barrier between you and danger. Each time you cast a druid spell of 1st level or higher you gain temporary hit points equal to your Wisdom modifier. If the spell gives temporary hit points, this is in addition.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>Each time you cast a druid spell of 1st level or higher you gain {{wisdom:modifier}} temporary hit points. If the spell gives temporary hit points, this is in addition.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Strength of the Swarm" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_FORGOTTEN_STRENGTH_OF_THE_SWARM">
                <description>
                    <p>Beginning at 6th level, your swarm will aid your allies as well. When you cast <em>infestation</em>, you can take the Help action as a bonus action and you can do so from 30 feet away.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                    <description>When you cast infestation, you can take the Help action and you can do so from 30 feet away.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Hive Mind" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_FORGOTTEN_HIVE_MIND">
                <description>
                    <p>At 10th level, your minute control over insects is frightening to behold. While you have Milling Shield active, you can use your reaction to consume the temporary hit points, activating one of the following effects:</p>
                    <p class="indent"><strong>Biting Swarm.</strong> When a creature moves within 30 feet while under the effect of one of your spells, you can deal 3d4 piercing damage.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><strong>Covering Mass.</strong> Before a creature rolls a ranged attack you can grant half cover to the targeted creature, if it is within 30 feet of you, for that attack only.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><strong>Intense Harassment.</strong> When a creature within 30 feet would make an opportunity attack, you can make it unable to do so until the end of the current turn.</p>
                    <p class="indent"><strong>Intervening Shield.</strong> When a creature within 30 feet of you makes a melee attack, you can reduce the damage the targeted creature takes by the amount of temporary hit points you consume.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet action="Reaction">
                    <description>While you have Milling Shield active, you can consume the temporary hit points, activating one of the following effects: Biting Swarm, Covering Mass, Intense Harrassment, or Intervening Shield.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Relentless Horde" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_FORGOTTEN_RELENTLESS_HORDE">
                <description>
                    <p>At 14th level, some insects stay behind to continue harassing their victims. When you cast a Circle spell, you may cast <em>infestation</em> on one of the affected creature as part of the same action.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>When you cast a Circle spell, you may cast infestation on one of the affected creature as part of the same action.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Milling Swarm" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_FORGOTTEN_MILLING_SWARM">
                <description>
                    <p>Starting at 18th level, the swarm you control are consistently returning to protect you. At the start of your turn, you gain a Milling Shield and the temporary hit points granted by Milling Shield is now equal to twice your Wisdom modifier.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Additionally, while under the effect of Milling Shield you gain resistance to all damage except psychic.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>At the start of your turn, you gain a Milling Shield and {{milling-swarm:temp-hp}} temporary hit points. Additionally, while under the effect of Milling Shield you gain resistance to all damage except psychic.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="milling-swarm:temp-hp" value="wisdom:modifier" />
                    <stat name="milling-swarm:temp-hp" value="wisdom:modifier" />
                </rules>
            </element>


        <element name="Circle of the Sun" type="Archetype" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_ALPHA_DRUID_CIRCLE_OF_THE_SUN">
            <supports>Alpha Druid Circle</supports>
            <description>
                <p>Druids of this circle revere the sun, one of the most important astral bodies, as it is a wellspring of life. They draw upon its power to restore and repair those in need, as well as burn away those who spurn the living. There are many stories where these druids turn up and heal someone in need without asking for anything in return, other tales tell about how a king’s request and gold was turned down.</p>
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_SUN_CIRCLE_SPELLS" />
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_SUN_NURTURED_BY_THE_SUN" />
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_SUN_RADIANT_POWER" />
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_SUN_LIGHTS_EMBRACE" />
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_SUN_THE_SUNS_GRACE" />
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_SUN_BLINDING_RADIANCE" />
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_SUN_LIGHTBRINGER" />
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_SUN_CIRCLE_SPELLS" level="2" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_SUN_NURTURED_BY_THE_SUN" level="2" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_SUN_RADIANT_POWER" level="2" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_SUN_LIGHTS_EMBRACE" level="6" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_SUN_THE_SUNS_GRACE" level="10" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_SUN_BLINDING_RADIANCE" level="14" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_SUN_LIGHTBRINGER" level="18" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Circle Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_SUN_CIRCLE_SPELLS">
                <description>
                    <p>You gain circle spells at the druid levels listed.</p>
                    <h5 class="caption">Sun Spells</h5>
                    <table>
                        <thead>
                            <tr><td>Druid Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                        </thead>
                        <tr><td>2nd</td><td><i>bless, healing word</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>3rd</td><td><i>guiding light, prayer of healing</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>5th</td><td><i>daylight, mass healing word</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>7th</td><td><i>aura of life, hammer of the gods</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>9th</td><td><i>dawn, mass cure wounds</i></td></tr>
                    </table>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLESS" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="2" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HEALING_WORD" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="2" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_SPELL_GUIDING_LIGHT" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="3" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PRAYER_OF_HEALING" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="3" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DAYLIGHT" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="5" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MASS_HEALING_WORD" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="5" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AURA_OF_LIFE" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="7" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_SPELL_HAMMER_OF_THE_GODS" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="7" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_DAWN" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="9" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MASS_CURE_WOUNDS" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="9" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Nurtured by the Sun" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_SUN_NURTURED_BY_THE_SUN">
                <description>
                    <p>At 2nd level, the sun blesses you with its power, you gain the <em>light</em> and <em>sacred flame</em> cantrips.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Additionally, as long as you have spent 2 hours or more in the sun during the day, you don’t need to eat, drink, or sleep for the next 24 hours.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>As long as you have spent 2 hours or more in the sun during the day, you don’t need to eat, drink, or sleep for the next 24 hours.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LIGHT" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" known="true" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SACRED_FLAME" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" known="true" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Radiant Power" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_SUN_RADIANT_POWER">
                <description>
                    <p>Also at 2nd level, your powers scorches those who are careless. When you cast a spell to heal a creature you can use your reaction to damage another creature within 5 feet of it. The damage is radiant and equals half the amount for which you healed the creature.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Also, the dice you roll for healing spells increase by one dice size, for example cure wounds use d10’s instead of d8’s.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet action="Reaction">
                    <description>When you cast a spell to heal a creature you can damage another creature within 5 feet of it. The damage is radiant and equals half the amount for which you healed the creature. Also, the dice you roll for healing spells increase by one dice size.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Light’s Embrace" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_SUN_LIGHTS_EMBRACE">
                <description>
                    <p>At 6th level, you further the reach of the sun’s powers. As long as a you and a target share the same bright light of a spell you have created, you can target it with a healing spell, disregarding its normal range.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Additionally, as long as an allied creature is in magical or non-magical bright light, you don’t need line of sight to target it with a spell.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>As long as a you and a target share the same bright light of a spell you have created, you can target it with a healing spell, disregarding its normal range. Additionally, as long as an allied creature is in magical or non-magical bright light, you don’t need line of sight to target it with a spell.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="The Sun’s Grace" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_SUN_THE_SUNS_GRACE">
                <description>
                    <p>At 10th level, your power which burns down evil can also restore those true of heart. When you cast a spell that deals radiant damage in an area, you can choose one creature within the area which is unaffected. This creature is healed for half the damage rolled.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>When you cast a spell that deals radiant damage in an area, you can choose one creature within the area which is unaffected. This creature is healed for half the damage rolled.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Blinding Radiance" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_SUN_BLINDING_RADIANCE">
                <description>
                    <p>Beginning at 14th level, the light you bring can singe the eyes of those unpure. When you cast a spell that sheds bright light, each creature of your choice within the bright light must make a Constitution saving throw against your spell save DC. On a failure, the creature is blinded until the end of their next turn.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>When you cast a spell that sheds bright light, each creature of your choice within the bright light must make a Constitution saving throw against your spell save DC. On a failure, the creature is blinded until the end of their next turn.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>
            <element name="Lightbringer" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_THE_SUN_LIGHTBRINGER">
                <description>
                    <p>At 18th level, you can control all of the sun’s powers. When an allied creature within 50 feet of you is in within an magical light you created or sunlight, it is affected by the bless spell.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Also, the bright light of your spells count as sunlight.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Additionally, when you use The Sun’s Grace, you can choose up to five creatures which are unaffected and healed.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Finally, you can cast <em>light</em> as a bonus action.</p>
                    <div class="reference">
                        <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLESS" />
                    </div>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>When an allied creature within 50 feet of you is in within an magical light you created or sunlight, it is affected by the bless spell. Also, the bright light of your spells count as sunlight. Additionally, when you use The Sun’s Grace, you can choose up to five creatures which are unaffected and healed. Finally, you can cast light as a bonus action.</description>
                </sheet>
            </element>


        <element name="Circle of Wrath" type="Archetype" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_ALPHA_DRUID_CIRCLE_OF_WRATH">
            <supports>Alpha Druid Circle</supports>
            <description>
                <p>Most druids strives toward protecting nature and its balance by indirect means, but there are a few which have taken a to arms to solve the problems in a more immediate way. These druids have seen the hardships and death brought by oppressors and tyrants, and have taken upon themselves to crush any who threaten the innocent. Some creatures will never see the fault in taking what they can and must be removed from the scales to reattain balance.</p>
                <p class="indent">Some see this violence as a last resort, while others believe that everyone that stands idly by have chosen a side. A few spill the blood of their enemies to sate the spirits of the old world.</p>
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_WRATH_CIRCLE_SPELLS" />
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_WRATH_IRE_OF_THE_OPPRESSED" />
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_WRATH_PROTECTIVE_MARKINGS" />
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_WRATH_EXTRA_ATTACK" />
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_WRATH_ELEMENTALLY_IMBUED_WEAPONS" />
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_WRATH_WRATHFUL_STEPS" />
                <div element="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_WRATH_FURY_OF_THE_WORLD" />
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_WRATH_CIRCLE_SPELLS" level="2" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_WRATH_IRE_OF_THE_OPPRESSED" level="2" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_WRATH_PROTECTIVE_MARKINGS" level="2" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_WRATH_EXTRA_ATTACK" level="6" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_WRATH_ELEMENTALLY_IMBUED_WEAPONS" level="10" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_WRATH_WRATHFUL_STEPS" level="14" />
                <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_WRATH_FURY_OF_THE_WORLD" level="18" />
            </rules>
        </element>
            <element name="Circle Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_WRATH_CIRCLE_SPELLS">
                <description>
                    <p>You gain circle spells at the druid levels listed.</p>
                    <h5 class="caption">Wrath Spells</h5>
                    <table>
                        <thead>
                            <tr><td>Druid Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                        </thead>
                        <tr><td>2nd</td><td><i>absorb elements, zephyr strike</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>3rd</td><td><i>corrode metal, skyward rise</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>5th</td><td><i>blink, grasp of the wind</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>7th</td><td><i>avenger’s wrath, steel wind strike</i></td></tr>
                        <tr><td>9th</td><td><i>nemesis, shard storm</i></td></tr>
                    </table>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ABSORB_ELEMENTS" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="2" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ZEPHYR_STRIKE" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="2" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_SPELL_CORRODE_METAL" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="3" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_SPELL_SKYWARD_RISE" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="3" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLINK" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="5" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_SPELL_GRASP_OF_THE_WIND" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="5" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_SPELL_AVENGERS_WRATH" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="7" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_STEEL_WIND_STRIKE" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="7" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_SPELL_NEMESIS" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="9" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_SPELL_SHARD_STORM" spellcasting="Alpha Druid" prepared="true" level="9" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Ire of the Oppressed" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_WRATH_IRE_OF_THE_OPPRESSED">
                <description>
                    <p>At 2nd level, you have begun taking your first steps towards protecting nature against those who mean it harm. You gain proficiency in martial melee weapons and Intimidation.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet display="false">
                    <description></description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_MARTIAL_MELEE_WEAPONS" />
                    <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INTIMIDATION" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Protective Markings" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_WRATH_PROTECTIVE_MARKINGS">
                <description>
                    <p>Also at 2nd level, whenever you reduce a creature to 0 hit points, you gain temporary hit points equal to your druid level + your Wisdom modifier.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>Whenever you reduce a creature to 0 hit points, you gain {{protective-markings:temp-hp}} temporary hit points</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="protective-markings:temp-hp" value="level:alpha druid" />
                    <stat name="protective-markings:temp-hp" value="wisdom:modifier" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Extra Attack" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_WRATH_EXTRA_ATTACK">
                <description>
                    <p>Beginning at 6th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>You can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
        			<stat name="extra attack:count" value="2" level="6" bonus="extra attack" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Elementally Imbued Weapons" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_WRATH_ELEMENTALLY_IMBUED_WEAPONS">
                <description>
                    <p>Starting at 10th level, the elements themselves have granted you their blessing. You can cast <em>elemental weapon</em> at its lowest level targeting your own weapons without expending a spell slot. When cast in this way, you don’t need to concentrate on the spell and you can target weapons which are magical. The spell ends if you let go of the weapon.</p>
                    <div class="reference">
                        <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_ELEMENTAL_WEAPON" />
                    </div>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>You can cast elemental weapon at its lowest level targeting your own weapons without expending a spell slot. When cast in this way, you don’t need to concentrate on the spell and you can target weapons which are magical. The spell ends if you let go of the weapon.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ELEMENTAL_WEAPON" />
                    <stat name="elementally-imbued-weapons:spell-level" inline="true" value="its lowest" level="10" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Wrathful Steps" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_WRATH_WRATHFUL_STEPS">
                <description>
                    <p>At 14th level, your unleashed fury carry you through combat. When you walk more than 10 feet during your turn, you can move vertically without falling down. If you are still in the air at the end of your turn, you fall down. If you travel through the air you gain resistance to nonmagical piercing, slashing and bludgeoning damage until the start of your next turn.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Finally, your movement speed increases by 10 feet.</p>
                </description>
                <sheet>
                    <description>When you walk more than 10 feet during your turn, you can move vertically without falling down. If you are still in the air at the end of your turn, you fall down. If you travel through the air you gain resistance to nonmagical piercing, slashing and bludgeoning damage until the start of your next turn.</description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="speed:misc" value="10" level="14" />
                </rules>
            </element>
            <element name="Fury of the World" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SWECKY_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CIRCLE_OF_WRATH_FURY_OF_THE_WORLD">
                <description>
                    <p>Beginning at 18th level, you can use an action to unleash centuries of collected fury. You gain the effects of the haste spell, except you don’t have to concentrate on it and you don’t get stunned when the effect ends. Once you’ve done this, you can’t do so again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
                    <p class="indent">Additionally, when you enchant a weapon using Elementally Imbued Weapons, it is cast as a 5th-level spell.</p>
                    <div class="reference">
                        <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_HASTE" />
                    </div>
                </description>
                <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Short Rest">
                    <description>You gain the effects of the haste spell, except you don’t have to concentrate on it and you don’t get stunned when the effect ends. </description>
                </sheet>
                <rules>
                    <stat name="elementally-imbued-weapons:spell-level" inline="true" value="5th" level="10" />
                    <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HASTE" />
                </rules>
            </element>


</elements>