<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Artificer’s Almanac, Volume 1</name>
        <author url="https://homebrewery.naturalcrit.com/print/ByPMPrTtrB?dialog=true">u/Anathemys</author>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="artificers-almanac-vol1.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aurorabuilder/elements/master/artificers-almanac-vol1.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Assassin’s Eye" type="Magic Item" source="Artificer’s Almanac" id="ID_ANATHEMYS_AAV1_MAGIC_ITEM_Assassin’s Eye">
        <description>
            <p>The <i>assassin’s eye</i> is dread artifact with a storied past. To create one, the eye of a murderer or assassin is removed shortly before the creature is executed. After death many necromantic and divination spells are cast over the eye, transforming it into a permanent <i>arcane eye</i>.</p>
            <p class="indent">This eye can be used as in the <i>arcane eye spell</i> with an unlimited duration. The eye is invisible, but can be damaged by magical effects or attacks; damage is transferred to the user directly. Furthermore, once per day the user can cause the eye to materialize fully, becoming visible. The user can then cast a single spell through the eye, as though they were fully in the eye’s space. If the spell would damage the caster normally, the damage is transferred to the user. This property functions once per sunset.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a spellcaster">true</set>
            <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Egg of Vapors" type="Magic Item" source="Artificer’s Almanac" id="ID_ANATHEMYS_AAV1_MAGIC_ITEM_EGG_OF_VAPORS">
        <description>
            <p>An <i>egg of vapor</i> is a fine jeweled or metallic egg worked with intricate designs. Most have patterns suggestive of the egg’s contents. When thrown, the egg shatters on contact with a solid surface, or the surface of a liquid. Different eggs have different effects depending on their type; when applicable the DC of any saves is 15.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b>Mists (Uncommon).</b> Casts the <i>fog cloud</i> spell centered on where the egg broke.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b>Winds (Rare).</b> Casts the <i>gust of wind</i> spell beginning at the point where the egg broke. The gust blows in the direction the egg was thrown in, unless the egg impacts a wall, in which case the wind blows opposite to the direction thrown.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b>Stench (Rare).</b> Casts the <i>stinking cloud</i> spell centered on where the egg broke. When found, roll 1d6. On a 1, the egg appears to be an egg of service, and on a 2 it appears to be an egg of mists.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b>Death (Rare).</b> Casts the <i>cloudkill</i> spell centered on where the egg broke.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b>Flames (Very Rare).</b> Casts the <i>incendiary cloud</i> spell centered on where the egg broke.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b>Service (Very Rare).</b> Casts the <i>conjure elemental</i> spell and summons an air elemental. The elemental remains for the full duration and does not require concentration.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">rarity varies by egg</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Tuning Fork of Travel" type="Magic Item" source="Artifier’s Almanac" id="ID_ANATHEMYS_AAV1_MAGIC_ITEM_TUNING_FORK_OF_TRAVEL">
        <description>
            <p>Similar to the tuning forks used in the <i>plane shift</i> spell, this item helps enable the user to find the right way to a destination. When used at a fork in a path or another split in travel (such as a crossroads, a side path, or similar), the fork can be commanded to find the best way to a destination the user is familiar with.</p>
            <p class="indent">The fork can be commanded to find the best route using one of three parameters; safety, shortness, or luck. The path best matching the choice will cause the fork to hum pleasantly, while the path which least matches the criteria will shrill loudly. This functions once per dawn.</p>
            <p class="indent">A normal <i>tuning fork of travel</i> only functions on the Material Plane. However, other forks exist which work on a certain Inner or Outer Plane; these forks can also be used as the material component for a plane shift to the plane in question.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

  <!-- Spells -->
    <element name="Bands of Glass" type="Spell" source="Artificer’s Alamanac" id="ID_AMATHESYS_AAV1_SPELL_BANDS_OF_GLASS">
        <supports>Artificer, Cleric, Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You summon burning bands of molten glass around a creature of Large size or smaller that you can see within range. The target must make a Strength saving throw, breaking free on a success. On a failure the creature is restrained by the glass and takes 3d6 fire damage at the beginning of each of its turns.</p>
            <p class="indent">A trapped creature can use an action to repeat the Strength saving throw on each of its turns, breaking free on a success. Whenever this spell ends due to a creature breaking free, large shards of glass scatter on the ground in a 10ft radius, making the area difficult terrain for the remaining duration.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When cast at 6th level, you can target up to two creatures within range, as long as they are within 5ft of each other. If both targets fail the saving throw, the two creatures are pulled together and bound by the same band of glass. If one successfully breaks free, both creatures are freed.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">4</set>
            <set name="school">Conjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">1 minute</set>
            <set name="range">60 ft.</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a glass bracelet</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
</elements>