<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Homebrew Tools</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="items-tools.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/user/items-tools.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Arcanist’s Tools" type="Item" source="reddit/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_RDDT_ITEM_TOOL_ARCANISTS_TOOLS">
        <description>
            <p>Skill in the Arcane arts allows one to more easily identify magic items and their properties, as well as active effects of magic around them given the wealth of arcane knowledge they've come to possess. Proficieny in Arcanist’s Tools could be considered necessary to scribe a spell scroll.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b>Components. </b>Arcanist’s tools include a scribing rune, a pair of lenses, an arcanic conduit in the form of a gem or enchanted mineral, and a magnifying glass especially made to pick out details in arcane runes.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b>Arcana. </b>Your knowledge in arcane matters allows you to glean more insights when examining magical effects, or otherwise calling upon your knowledge on the subjet.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b>History. </b>You are familiar with famous arcansists and enchanters of the past, as well as trailblazing wizards, either because of their ideas or their deeds. You are also knowledgeable about any historic events that featured a prominent magical involvement, such as the Wizarding Wars or the Vicar Convention (which outlawed certain types of magic that involved automation as they proved to be too dangerous).</p>
            <p class="indent"><b>Nature. </b>You are able to more skillfully deduce that an instance of nature is innately magical.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b>Greater Identification. </b>Once per day, you can use your arcanist’s tools to spend 10 minutes examining and object or creature. At the end of your examination you know the object’s magical properties magical properties as per the <i>identify</i> spell. In addition, you know the skill of its crafter, an estimation on how long ago it was enchanted, and what kinds of materials had to be used for this enchantment. If some of those materials are rare, or only found in specific territories, your DM may ask you to roll a Nature or History check to ascertain what precisely you know of those materials, if their nature is relevant to your circumstances.</p>
            <p class="indent"><i>Variant. </i>At your DM’s discretion, they could allow you to roll an Arcana check to see if you detect any cursed properties in an item you examine with your arcanist’s tools.</p>
            <h5>ARCANIST’S TOOLS</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Activity</td><td>DC</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>Scribe a Spell Scroll</td><td>10 + Spell Level</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Recognize magical effects</td><td>15</td></tr>
                <tr><td>Identify a Curse in a magical item</td><td>20</td></tr>
            </table>
        </description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Tools</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">100</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="6">3 lbs.</set>
      		<set name="type">Tool</set>
		</setters>
    </element>
    
</elements>