<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Material Theory Philosopher Personal Theory</name>
        <author url="https://www.gmbinder.com/share/-L5AHePdc4TeS9w1MyKG">/u/BunnygeonMaster</author>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="philosopher-material-theory.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/user/philosopher-material-theory.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    
    
    <element name="Material Theory" type="Archetype" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_PHILOSOPHER_MATERIAL_THEORY">
        <supports>Personal Theory</supports>
        <description>
            <p>As a philosopher of the Material Theory, you hold that the physical world is the only world that exists, and all else is a symptom thereof. Tools drive thought, might makes right, and lucre begets lifestyles. By leveraging experience with the history and future of material to survive the world’s dangers, you’re able to adapt to the times and live with, not against, danger and harm. You’re reminiscent of the Rogue, acting as a knife to bend your foes to the demands of material reality.</p>
            <div element="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MATERIAL_THEORY_MATERIAL_BOOK" />
            <div element="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MATERIAL_THEORY_SYNTHESIS" />
            <div element="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MATERIAL_THEORY_EVASION" />
            <div element="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MATERIAL_THEORY_PRODUCT_RELATIONS" />
            <div element="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MATERIAL_THEORY_MATERIAL_MAGIC" />
            <div element="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MATERIAL_THEORY_MATERIAL_WORLD" />
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MATERIAL_THEORY_MATERIAL_BOOK" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MATERIAL_THEORY_SYNTHESIS" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MATERIAL_THEORY_EVASION" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MATERIAL_THEORY_PRODUCT_RELATIONS" level="11" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MATERIAL_THEORY_MATERIAL_MAGIC" level="15" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MATERIAL_THEORY_MATERIAL_WORLD" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    
        <element name="Material Book" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MATERIAL_THEORY_MATERIAL_BOOK">
            <description>
                <p>When you choose this personal theory at 1st level, you gain proficiency with one set of tools of your choice, and your proficiency bonus is doubled for any ability check you make that uses the chosen proficiency.</p>
                <p class="indent">Also, you can use any book you hold as an improvised melee weapon with which you are proficient with the thrown (30/120) property that inflicts 1d8 bludgeoning, piercing, or slashing damage on a hit (your choice). When you make a ranged weapon attack using a book, it flies back to your hand after the attack is resolved, whether you hit or miss.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Your proficiency bonus is doubled for any ability check using your selected Material Book tool proficiency. You can use any book you hold as an improvised melee weapon with which you are proficient with the thrown (30/120) property that inflicts 1d8 bludgeoning, piercing, or slashing damage on a hit (your choice). When you make a ranged weapon attack using a book, it flies back to your hand after the attack is resolved, whether you hit or miss.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Proficiency" name="Tool Proficiency (Material Book)" supports="Tool" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Synthesis" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MATERIAL_THEORY_SYNTHESIS">
            <description>
                <p>At 7th level, your witchcraft and warfare are one and the same, for each exists only as material. When a creature you can see makes a saving throw against a spell cast by you, you can make a weapon attack with a book against it as a reaction. On a hit, the target takes half the value rolled on one of the damage dice as a penalty to its saving throw.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Reaction">
                <description>When a creature you can see makes a saving throw against a spell cast by you, you can make a weapon attack with a book against it as a reaction. On a hit, the target takes half the value rolled on one of the damage dice as a penalty to its saving throw.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Evasion" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MATERIAL_THEORY_EVASION">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 7th level, your enemies can’t make you answer if you change the question. You can nimbly dodge out of the way of certain area effects, such as a red dragon’s fiery breath or an ice storm spell. When you are subjected to an effect that allows you to make a Dexterity saving throw to take only half damage, you instead take no damage if you succeed on the saving throw, and only half damage if you fail.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you are subjected to an effect that allows you to make a Dexterity saving throw to take only half damage, you instead take no damage if you succeed on the saving throw, and only half damage if you fail.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Product Relations" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MATERIAL_THEORY_PRODUCT_RELATIONS">
            <description>
                <p>By 11th level, your world is defined by material exchange. You gain a climbing speed equal to your walking speed, and at the end of a short or long rest you can grant yourself proficiency with one set of artisan’s tools of your choice until the end of your next short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>At the end of a short or long rest you can grant yourself proficiency with one set of artisan’s tools of your choice until the end of your next short or long rest.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="speed:climb" value="speed" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Material Magic" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MATERIAL_THEORY_MATERIAL_MAGIC">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 15th level, your flexible attitude easily adapts to the times. Once per turn when you would deal damage to a creature, you can change the type of the damage to any other of your choice.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Once per turn when you would deal damage to a creature, you can change the type of the damage to any other of your choice.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Material World" type="Archetype Feature" source="GM Binder" id="ID_GM_BINDER_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MATERIAL_THEORY_MATERIAL_WORLD">
            <description>
                <p>At 18th level, your materialist lens reshapes the world. As an action, you can magically teleport yourself and any creatures you see within 120 feet of you to any point you can see within 120 feet of you. An unwilling creature can make a Charisma saving throw against your Theorycraft save DC, resisting the effect on a success. Additionally, you can change any surface within 120 feet feet of you from normal terrain to difficult terrain, or vice versa.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can use this feature once and regain its use after finishing a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You can magically teleport yourself and any creatures you see within 120 feet of you to any point you can see within 120 feet of you. An unwilling creature can make a Charisma saving throw (save DC {{spellcasting:dc}}), resisting the effect on a success. Additionally, you can change any surface within 120 feet feet of you from normal terrain to difficult terrain, or vice versa.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
</elements>