<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Ember Elf</name>
        <author url="https://homebrewery.naturalcrit.com/share/BJZIcmE1H">Corefusion82 and haimurashoichi</author>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="subrace-ember-elf.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aurorabuilder/elements/master/subrace-ember-elf.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Ember Elf" type="Sub Race" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_RDDT_UA_SUBRACE_EMBER_ELF">
        <supports>Elf</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Hidden from everyone’s eyes, the ember elves, or Arsorians, live in caverns underneath Mount Hotenow. It is located in the north-east of the city of Neverwinter. Their people are made up of crafters that equal dwarves in skill. The ember elves have no relations with other elves due to their reclusive nature.</p>
            <p class="indent">Ember elves look similar to the drow, but do not share their affinity to evil, and don fiery red hair instead of the pale white shades of their underdark cousins. Ember elves tend toward the neutral alignment, not sharing interest in the world and focusing on their work instead. They do not feel emotions, and give off a very distant impression for those who never heard of these rare elven master crafters.</p>
            <p class="indent">They are the descendants of Darahl Tilvenar and worship him as well as Correlon. They wield a resistance to the furnace's fires and are master crafters of weapons, armor, potions and jewellery.</p>
            <h4>EMBER ELF TRAITS</h4>
            <p>
                <span class="feature">Ability Score Increase.</span> Your Constitution score increases by 1.<br />
                <span class="feature">Ignatious Resistance.</span> You have resistance to fire damage.<br />
                <span class="feature">Tool Proficiency.</span> You have proficiency with the artisan’s tools of your choice: smith’s tools, glassblower’ tools or jeweler’s tools.<br />
                <span class="feature">Languages.</span> You can speak, read and write Ignan.<br />
            </p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="constitution" value="1" />
            <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_FIRE" />
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Ember Elf Tool Proficiency" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_SMITHS_TOOLS|ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_GLASSBLOWERS_TOOLS|ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_JEWELERS_TOOLS" />
            <grant type="Language" id="ID_MM_LANGUAGE_IGNAN" />
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Arsorian Crafter" type="Background" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_RDDT_UA_BACKGROUND_EMBER_ELF_ARSORIAN_CRAFTER">
        <requirements>ID_RDDT_UA_SUBRACE_EMBER_ELF</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>The ember elves are not well known in any regard, largely keeping to themselves. To them, measure in skill is what makes you stand out. For years, you laboured under your master of the craft, enduring long hours and unaffectionate treatment in order to gain the fine skills you possess today. What made you leave your home is concerning, however, seeing as ember elves almost never leave the tunnels they are born, live and die in. You might seem unappeasable and unlikeable, but given time, you may just learn to understand the emotions of those around you, and learn to find interest in things outside of crafting a perfect sword.</p>
            <p class="indent"></p>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Skill Proficiencies:</strong> History, Performance</li>
                <li><strong>Tool Proficiencies:</strong> One type of artisan’s tools.</li>
                <li><strong>Languages:</strong> Ignan</li>
                <li><strong>Equipment:</strong> A set of artisan’s tools with which you are proficient, a maker’s mark chisel used to mark your handiwork with the symbol of the clan of Arsorians you learned your skill from, a set of elven blacksmith’s clothing and an apron, scrap metal (20lbs), a pouch containting 5gp and a gem worth 10gp.</li>
            </ul>
            <div element="ID_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_EMBER_ELF_ARSORIAN_MASTERY" />
            <h5>SUGGESTED CHARACTERISTICS</h5>
            <p>Use the tables for the guild artisan background in the Player’s Handbook as the basis for your traits and motivations, modifiying the entries when appropriate to suit your identity as an Arsorian Crafter. Your bond is almost certainly related to the master or the clan that taught you, or else to the work that you produce. Your ideal might have something to do with maintaining the high qualitiy of your work or preserving the Arsorian traditions of craftsmanship.</p>
        </description>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_HISTORY" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERFORMANCE" />
            <grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_EMBER_ELF_ARSORIAN_MASTERY" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_OPTIONAL_BACKGROUND_FEATURE"/>
			<select name="Personality Trait" type="List" number="2">
				<item id="1">I believe that anything worth doing is worth doing right. I can’t help it— I’m a perfectionist.</item>
				<item id="2">I’m a snob who looks down on those who can’t appreciate fine art.</item>
				<item id="3">I always want to know how things work and what makes people tick.</item>
				<item id="4">I’m full of witty aphorisms and have a proverb for every occasion.</item>
				<item id="5">I’m rude to people who lack my commitment to hard work and fair play.</item>
				<item id="6">I like to talk at length about my profession.</item>
				<item id="7">I don’t part with my money easily and will haggle tirelessly to get the best deal possible.</item>
				<item id="8">I’m well known for my work, and I want to make sure everyone appreciates it. I’m always taken aback when people haven’t heard of me.</item>
			</select>
			<select name="Ideal" type="List">
				<item id="1">Community. It is the duty of all civilized people to strengthen the bonds of community and the security of civilization. (Lawful)</item>
				<item id="2">Generosity. My talents were given to me so that I could use them to benefit the world. (Good)</item>
				<item id="3">Freedom. Everyone should be free to pursue his or her own livelihood. (Chaotic)</item>
				<item id="4">Greed. I’m only in it for the money. (Evil)</item>
				<item id="5">People. I’m committed to the people I care about, not to ideals. (Neutral)</item>
				<item id="6">Aspiration. I work hard to be the best there is at my craft.</item>
			</select>
			<select name="Bond" type="List">
				<item id="1">The workshop where I learned my trade is the most important place in the world to me.</item>
				<item id="2">I created a great work for someone, and then found them unworthy to receive it. I’m still looking for someone worthy.</item>
				<item id="3">I owe my guild a great debt for forging me into the person I am today.</item>
				<item id="4">I pursue wealth to secure someone’s love.</item>
				<item id="5">One day I will return to my guild and prove that I am the greatest artisan of them all.</item>
				<item id="6">I will get revenge on the evil forces that destroyed my place of business and ruined my livelihood.</item>
			</select>
			<select name="Flaw" type="List">
				<item id="1">I’ll do anything to get my hands on something rare or priceless.</item>
				<item id="2">I’m quick to assume that someone is trying to cheat me.</item>
				<item id="3">No one must ever learn that I once stole money from guild coffers.</item>
				<item id="4">I’m never satisfied with what I have— I always want more.</item>
				<item id="5">I would kill to acquire a noble title.</item>
				<item id="6">I’m horribly jealous of anyone who can outshine my handiwork. Everywhere I go, I’m surrounded by rivals.</item>
			</select>
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Feature: Arsorian Mastery" type="Background Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_EMBER_ELF_ARSORIAN_MASTERY">
        <description>
            <p>You have mastered your craft, and not without effort. You know your way around the furnace’s tools, and have practised many years to learn how to make artifacts of great skill. You may repair and craft elven weapons and armor at half the time it would normally take.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet alt="Arsorian Mastery">
            <description>You may repair and craft elven weapons and armor at half the time it would normally take.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
</elements>