<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Weaver Class v3.1</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="class-weaver.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/frostbladestorm/complete-guide-to-sanctum/class-weaver.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Weaver" type="Class" source="Complete Guide to Sanctum" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_CLASS_WEAVER">
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">WIZARDS LEARN FROM KNOWLEDGE. SORCERERS have their birthright. Warlocks trade dignity for a pact, and Clerics devote themselves to another being. But us? We of the coven do not adhere to such traditions and instead we develop our connection with our ancestors, a bond with the natural cycle of life and death that only we truly can master.</p>
            <p style="text-align: right;">-Mother of Witches</p>
            <p>Clutching her staff in her silver hands, she steps back to feel the earth at her feet crumble by the cliffside. Her face serene, she knows her fate as the ogres make their last lunge towards her. She calls upon the afterlife, asking for their aid in her final stand.</p>
            <p class="indent">The goliath looks at his tribekin, placing a hand on each of their shoulders, divining their destiny. His clan is strong, but the spirits never lie, and he knows the upcoming ritual will help to alleviate the burdens his tribe will face in the winter. He gazes in the distance, a figure nods, and he stares back down at the closest of his kin. This was the one.</p>
            <p class="indent">Drawing his sword, the human dashes between his foes, slashing their clothes, striking their chests, blood pouring onto the pavement. With a flick of his wrist, his armour glows spectral blue, and his onslaught can continue into the night.</p>
            <p class="indent">Whether calling on the spirits to guide them or sending them back to oblivion, weavers are the embodiment of the cycle of life and death. Their strength lies in their ability to walk this divide, communing with spirits and harvesting souls for their own benefit. Weavers see themselves as an extension of the natural life and death cycle. Some may see this as a privilege, where as others gain this power only to show their mastery over the world’s most absolute power. No matter the situation, a weaver’s control over the spiritual world and their ability to command aspects of the eternal cycle makes them revered.</p>
            <div class="sidebar">
                <p class="flavor">Spirits? Apparitions? Sacraments? I cannot say I am well versed in such magic, but I have met those who are. The Shaman of the West has been my friend since the early days of my training, and I once even met the Mother of Witches: the first Weaver!</p>
                <p style="text-align: right;">-Ari</p>
            </div>
            <h4>THE SPIRITUAL WORLD</h4>
            <p>The spiritual world is a part of the Weave that all beings that have since passed on must go through. It’s a culmination of the realms of the multiverse, having no tangible presence in any world and instead persists as energy that fuels, guides and watches over the world. Spirits exist within this world as entities of departed creatures. Restless spirits often enter the material plane or never depart if their role in the world is not complete, and these are the spirits most adventurers would encounter. Revenants, spectres and ghosts are just some of many examples of a being like this. A weaver is able to attune themselves to detect the spirits inside their own world, and with enough practice, drain their energy as a source of power. Weavers that draw from this power do so temporarily, always releasing the spirit to the eternal void when its done.</p>
            <h4>LIFE, DEATH, REBIRTH</h4>
            <p>The afterlife is a solid, representable force for a weaver. It is intrinsic to their nature, and affects their way of life dramatically. Having a spiritual connection with the occult and the absolute cycle changes the very essence of a weaver, and influences their actions, decisions, and choices in life. A constant between all weavers is their respect and admiration for the cycle of life. Living is a gift, and their spirit guide often helps to direct their abilities and growth to better respect their own role within the life and death cycle.</p>
            <p class="indent">Some souls need guidance to continue on to the afterlife and eventually rebirth if they desire. Weavers guide this process, acting as an intermediary and a way to balance out this cycle. To help guide the souls, they harvest them from those who they defeat, performing the ancient art of the sacrament to allow them to pass onto the afterlife and gain a boon in the process. Weaponising this process is sometimes frowned upon by those who do not understand their role, and often by religious types who believe the spirits should be left to depart in any way they wish to. Regardless of the weaver, their attitudes to life, death, and eventual rebirth at their hands is rarely consistent with another of their kind.</p>
            <h4>CREATING A WEAVER</h4>
            <p>When creating your weaver, you must first consider your relationship with the spiritual world. How and why did you connect with the spirits? Answering this question will help to cement the powers your weaver has and their world view. Consider the details of the connection they have.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you’ve decided the nature of their spirital connection and beliefs, you can start to consider the deeper aspects of this relationship. Are they using the connection to get closer to their ancestors? Are they on a quest to save the soul of a loved one? Are they purely using their powers to conquer heights the world has never seen? Why do the spirits help you? How has your upbringing influenced this connection? How would you be perceived by priests, mages, or other spellcasters? What are your ultimate goals? Do these goals have any relation to your spiritual connection? What drives you to continue as a weaver?</p>
            <p class="indent">The sections below offer ways to add more depth and a few personal touches to your weaver.</p>
            <div class="sidebar">
                <p class="flavor">The cycle of life and death. I myself have been through it a few times. Word of warning: resurrection scrolls are not cheap.</p>
                <p style="text-align: right;">-Ari</p>
            </div>
            <h4>SPIRIT GUIDE’S ATTITUDE</h4>
            <p>A weaver’s relationship with their spirit guide is fundamental to their understanding of the spiritual world and how they will seek to extract knowledge from it. A spirit guide is chosen by the Weave itself, intertwining the fates of two beings to one another. While a weaver gains the greatest benefit from the relationship, a spirit guide inevitably gains something in the process too. Sometimes this is the ability to live again through their weaver’s actions. For others the idea of training a pupil may be enough. The opinion a weaver holds for their spirit guide may not necessarily be the reciprocated and they can view each other with disdain.</p>
            <p class="indent">When you determine the relationship you have with your spirit guide, consider the attitude your spirit guide has to you. Also consider how they behave towards you. Will this change throughout your adventure? Is your spirit guide your friend, or are they so disgusted with you and your actions and only working with you as that will bring the destiny you share two quicker?</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d6</td><td>Attitude</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>Your spirit guide has been with you since birth, teaching you everything it knows since before you even knew you had this gift.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>Your spirit guide resents you for ending its eternal slumber, and it only works with you to return to its rest quicker.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>Your spirit guide seeks to teach you to be its successor, training you to be perfect, and refuses to let you be anything but that.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>Your spirit guide wants to be worshiped by you, only working alongside you when you give them the respect they demand.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>Your spirit guide wishes for you to complete something it did not complete in life, and is only satisfied while you are working on that goal.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>Your spirit guide is bored with the afterlife, only spending time with you to break up the monotony of eternity.</td></tr>
            </table>
            <h4>VIEW ON THE SACRAMENT</h4>
            <p>The sacrament is a sacred rite that only a weaver can truly embrace. It is the process of connecting a soul with your own, embracing their every memory, every belief, every part of their personality, and ultimately everything that makes them unique. Using a sacrament will bring you closer to the spirits you use, allowing you to know them for who they truly were. This action can alter the beliefs and ideology of those who use it, for better or for worse.</p>
            <p class="indent">How does your weaver view the sacrament? Do they revel in the knowledge that they know the spirit better than anyone? Do they lament the idea of connecting with the spirits so intimately? Consider the beliefs they have on the sacrament.</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d6</td><td>Views</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>You use the sacrament to better understand yourself, connecting with the spirits to find parallels.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>You do not care for the emotional aspect of the sacrament, instead using it purely for your own gain.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>You seek for something everytime you perform the ritual, though you are not quite sure what.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>Drawing upon the afterlife makes you feel powerful and you seek to gain even more power.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>The pursuit of a specific spirit drives you, maybe searching every spirit will help you in your quest.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>You lost your soul, the sacrament allows you to fill that void, even if it is temporary.</td></tr>
            </table>
            <h4>SPIRITUAL EMOTIONS</h4>
            <p>Each weaver sees the conjuration of their spirits in a different way. Being on the border of life and death is not an easy feat, and sometimes this takes a negative toll on the weaver. A weaver might choose to only harvest souls they have had the ability to gain consent from. Some see spirits as nothing more than energy they can use to gain more power.</p>
            <p class="indent">Does your weaver see harvesting souls as a necessary evil? Or do they refuse to entertain the idea of a moral problem? Consider the emotional attachment your weaver has to their power and whether they have a problem interrupting the cycle of life and death.</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d6</td><td>Style</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>You see the afterlife as your birthright.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>You try to seek consent from all those you use the souls from, atoning on the rare occasion when you don’t.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>You are merely helping the spirits to pass on, so they should be thanking you.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>Using spirits is something you have learned to do, and while the ethics of it are questionable you seek to help make the act kinder.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>You do not see an issue, after all you are just part of the natural cycle.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>Using spirits is heartwrenching, but I don’t have a choice if I am to achieve my goals.Weaver</td></tr>
            </table>
            <h5>QUICK BUILD</h5>
            <p>You can make a weaver quickly by following these suggestions. First, Intelligence should be your highest ability score, followed by Constitution or Wisdom. Second, choose the haunted one background.</p>
            <h2>CLASS FEATURES</h2>
            <p>As a weaver, you gain the following class features.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">HIT POINTS</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Hit Dice:</strong> 1d8 per weaver level</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at 1st Level:</strong> 8 + your Constitution modifier</li>
                <li><strong>Hit Points at Higher Levels:</strong> 1d8 (or 5) + your Constitution modifier per weaver level after 1st</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">PROFICIENCIES</h5>
            <ul class="unstyled mb">
                <li><strong>Armor:</strong> Light armour</li>
                <li><strong>Weapons:</strong> Simple weapons</li>
                <li><strong>Tools:</strong> None</li>
            </ul>
            <ul class="unstyled">
                <li><strong>Saving Throws:</strong> Constitution, Intelligence</li>
                <li><strong>Skills:</strong> Choose two from Animal Handling, Arcana, Deception, History, Insight, Medicine, Nature, and Religion.</li>
            </ul>
            <h5 class="caption">EQUIPMENT</h5>
            <p>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>(a) a quarterstaff or (b) any simple ranged weapon</li>
                <li>(a) two daggers or (b) any simple melee weapon</li>
                <li>Leather armour, a priest’s pack, and a spiritual focus</li>
            </ul>
            <h5>Optional Rule: Multiclassing</h5>
            <p>If your group uses the optional rule on multiclassing in the <i>Player’s Handbook</i>, you must have an Intelligence score of at least 13 to take a level in this class. You gain no additional proficiencies when you multiclass into a weaver.</p>
        <!-- class table here -->
            <h5 class="caption">THE WEAVER</h5>
            <table class="class-features">
                <thead>
                    <tr><td class="col-5">Level</td><td class="col-10">Proficiency Bonus</td><td class="left">Features</td><td class="col-10">Spells Known</td><td>1st</td><td>2nd</td><td>3rd</td><td>4th</td><td>5th</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td> 1st</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Sacrament, Shield of Souls, Death Sight</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 2nd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Spellcasting, Arcane Essence</td><td>2</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 3rd</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Spirit Guide, Spiritual Awakening</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 4th</td><td>+2</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>2</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 5th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Soul Strike</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 6th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Spirit Guide Feature</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 7th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Respite</td><td>5</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 8th</td><td>+3</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>5</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td> 9th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Font of Death</td><td>6</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>10th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>6</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>11th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Spirit Guide Feature</td><td>7</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>12th</td><td>+4</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>7</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>—</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>13th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">—</td><td>8</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>1</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>14th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Vessel of Life</td><td>8</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>1</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>15th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Gravecaller</td><td>9</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>16th</td><td>+5</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>9</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>—</td></tr>
                <tr><td>17th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">—</td><td>10</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>1</td></tr>
                <tr><td>18th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Spirit Guide Feature</td><td>10</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>1</td></tr>
                <tr><td>19th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td><td>11</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td></tr>
                <tr><td>20th</td><td>+6</td><td class="left">Samsara</td><td>11</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>2</td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_FBS_CGTS_CLASS_FEATURE_WEAVER_DEATH_SIGHT" />
            <div element="ID_FBS_CGTS_CLASS_FEATURE_WEAVER_SACRAMENT" />
            <div element="ID_FBS_CGTS_CLASS_FEATURE_WEAVER_SHIELD_OF_SOULS" />
            <div element="ID_FBS_CGTS_CLASS_FEATURE_WEAVER_SPELLCASTING" />
            <div element="ID_FBS_CGTS_CLASS_FEATURE_WEAVER_ARCANE_ESSENCE" />
            <div element="ID_FBS_CGTS_CLASS_FEATURE_WEAVER_SPIRIT_GUIDE" />
            <div element="ID_FBS_CGTS_CLASS_FEATURE_WEAVER_SPIRITUAL_AWAKENING" />
            <div element="ID_FBS_CGTS_CLASS_FEATURE_WEAVER_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" />
            <div element="ID_FBS_CGTS_CLASS_FEATURE_WEAVER_SOUL_STRIKE" />
            <div element="ID_FBS_CGTS_CLASS_FEATURE_WEAVER_RESPITE" />
            <div element="ID_FBS_CGTS_CLASS_FEATURE_WEAVER_FONT_OF_DEATH" />
            <div element="ID_FBS_CGTS_CLASS_FEATURE_WEAVER_VESSEL_OF_LIFE" />
            <div element="ID_FBS_CGTS_CLASS_FEATURE_WEAVER_GRAVECALLER" />
            <div element="ID_FBS_CGTS_CLASS_FEATURE_WEAVER_SAMSARA" />
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="hd">d8</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" requirements="!ID_FBS_CGTS_MULTICLASS_WEAVER" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" requirements="!ID_FBS_CGTS_MULTICLASS_WEAVER" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CONSTITUTION" requirements="!ID_FBS_CGTS_MULTICLASS_WEAVER" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_INTELLIGENCE" requirements="!ID_FBS_CGTS_MULTICLASS_WEAVER" />
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill, Weaver" supports="Skill, Weaver" number="2" requirements="!ID_FBS_CGTS_MULTICLASS_WEAVER" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_CLASS_FEATURE_WEAVER_DEATH_SIGHT" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_CLASS_FEATURE_WEAVER_SACRAMENT" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_CLASS_FEATURE_WEAVER_SHIELD_OF_SOULS" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_CLASS_FEATURE_WEAVER_SPELLCASTING" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_CLASS_FEATURE_WEAVER_ARCANE_ESSENCE" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_CLASS_FEATURE_WEAVER_SPIRIT_GUIDE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_CLASS_FEATURE_WEAVER_SPIRITUAL_AWAKENING" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_CLASS_FEATURE_WEAVER_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT" level="4" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_CLASS_FEATURE_WEAVER_SOUL_STRIKE" level="5" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_CLASS_FEATURE_WEAVER_RESPITE" level="7" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_CLASS_FEATURE_WEAVER_FONT_OF_DEATH" level="9" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_CLASS_FEATURE_WEAVER_VESSEL_OF_LIFE" level="14" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_CLASS_FEATURE_WEAVER_GRAVECALLER" level="15" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_CLASS_FEATURE_WEAVER_SAMSARA" level="20" />
            <stat name="int-mod:min-one" value="1" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="int-mod:min-one" value="intelligence:modifier" bonus="base" />
        </rules>
        <multiclass id="ID_FBS_CGTS_MULTICLASS_WEAVER">
            <prerequisite>Intelligence 13</prerequisite>
            <requirements>[int:13]</requirements>
            <setters>
                <set name="multiclass proficiencies">You gain no additional proficiencies when you multiclass into a weaver.</set>
            </setters>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS" />
            </rules>
        </multiclass>
    </element>
        <element name="Death Sight" type="Class Feature" source="Complete Guide to Sanctum" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_CLASS_FEATURE_WEAVER_DEATH_SIGHT">
            <description>
                <p>You feel an overpowering connection to the spiritual world that allows you to track the newly deceased. As an action, you can open your awareness to detect nearby corpses and spirits. For the next minute, you know the location of any corpses within 60 feet of you, provided that the creature has been dead no longer than 10 days, and you can see into the Ethereal Plane. Ethereal creatures and objects appear ghostly and translucent.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can use this feature a number of times equal to 1 + your Intelligence modifier. When you finish a long rest, you regain all expended uses.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="{{death-sight:uses}}/Long Rest">
                <description>For the next minute, you know the location of any corpses within 60 feet of you, provided that the creature has been dead no longer than 10 days, and you can see into the Ethereal Plane.</description>
                <description level="9" usage="{{death-sight:uses}}/Short Rest">For the next minute, you know the location of any corpses within 60 feet of you, provided that the creature has been dead no longer than 10 days, and you can see into the Ethereal Plane.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="death-sight:uses" value="1" />
                <stat name="death-sight:uses" value="intelligence:modifier" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Sacrament" type="Class Feature" source="Complete Guide to Sanctum" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_CLASS_FEATURE_WEAVER_SACRAMENT">
            <description>
                <p>You have the ability to draw life essence from the world around you. You have a pool of Essence up to a maximum of twice your weaver level, which is used to fuel your weaver features. You can gain essence through the following ways:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>As an action, you can touch a corpse of a creature and gain some essence, provided that it has been dead no longer than 10 days. The amount you gain is equal to the creature’s number of hit die. The corpse glows with ethereal energy while you use this feature.</li>
                    <li>As a reaction, when a creature you can see is killed within 60 feet of you, you gain life essence equal the creature’s number of hit die. This feature creates a visible, ethereal tether to the target as you drain the energy.</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">To use this feature, you must have free use of one of at least one of your hands. You cannot use this feature on a creature of CR 0, or a creature that does not have hit die. Once a corpse has been targeted by this feature, they cannot be targeted again unless they return to life.</p>
                <p class="indent">Essence lasts until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You have a pool of up to {{essence:pool}}. You can gain essence by touching a corpse (action) or when a creature you can see is killed within 60 feet of you (reaction), based on the creature’s hit dice. You must have a free hand. Essence lasts until you finish a short or long rest.</description>
                <description level="14">You have a pool of up to {{essence:pool}}. You can gain essence by touching a corpse (action) or when a creature you can see is killed within 60 feet of you (reaction), based on the creature’s hit dice. You must have a free hand. Essence lasts until you finish a long rest.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="essence:pool" value="level:weaver" />
                <stat name="essence:pool" value="level:weaver" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Shield of Souls" type="Class Feature" source="Complete Guide to Sanctum" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_CLASS_FEATURE_WEAVER_SHIELD_OF_SOULS">
            <description>
                <p>As a bonus action, you can touch a creature and expend a number of essence up to your Intelligence modifier (minimum 1), to grant 1d6 temporary hit points to that creature for every essence expended. Temporary hit points gained this way last for 1 minute.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>you can touch a creature and expend up to {{intelligence:modifier}} essence (minimum 1) to grant 1d6 temporary hit points per essence expended.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Spellcasting" type="Class Feature" source="Complete Guide to Sanctum" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_CLASS_FEATURE_WEAVER_SPELLCASTING">
            <description>
                <p>By 2nd level, you have learned to channel magical energy through your experience and study with the weave. See chapter 10 of the Player’s Handbook for the general rules of spellcasting and chapter 8 of the Complete Guide to Sanctum for the weaver spell list.</p>
                <h5>SPELL SLOTS</h5>
                <p>The Weaver table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your weaver spells of 1st level and higher. To cast one of these spells, you must expend a slot of the spell’s level or higher. You regain all expended slots when you finish a long rest. For example, if you know the 1st-level spell Bless and have a 1st-level and a 2nd-level spell slot available, you can cast Bless using either slot.</p>
                <h5>SPELLS KNOWN OF 1ST LEVEL AND HIGHER</h5>
                <p>You know two 1st-level spells of your choice from the weaver spell list. The Spells Known column of the Weaver table shows when you learn more weaver spells of your choice. Each of these spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots. For instance, when you reach 5th level in this class, you can learn one new spell of 1st or 2nd level.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, when you gain a level in this class, you can choose one of the weaver spells you know and replace it with another spell from the weaver spell list, which also must be of a level for which you have spell slots.</p>
                <h5>SPELLCASTING ABILITY</h5>
                <p>Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for your weaver spells. The power of your spells comes from your experimentation and conceptual understanding of the spiritual world. You use your Intelligence whenever a weaver spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Intelligence modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a weaver spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.</p>
                <p style="text-align: center;"><b>Spell save DC</b> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier</p>
                <p style="text-align: center;"><b>Spell attack modifier</b> = your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier</p>
                <h5>RITUAL CASTING</h5>
                <p>You can cast any weaver spell you know as a ritual if that spell has the ritual tag.</p>
                <h5>SPELLCASTING FOCUS</h5>
                <p>You must use a spiritual focus as a spellcasting focus for your weaver spells. You can take an hour to turn an arcane focus into a spiritual focus.</p>
                <div class="sidebar">
                    <h5 class="caption">SPIRITUAL FOCUS</h5>
                    <p>As a weaver, you have a new casting device: the spiritual focus. A spiritual focus is a worthless totem, token, or item of similar design that can coalesce spirits and energy within it. When a weaver attunes to the device, a small portion of their soul is locked within the focus, meaning only the attuned weaver can use the focus.</p>
                </div>
                <div class="sidebar">
                    <h5 class="caption">Variant: Wisdom</h5>
                    <p>Some applications of this class fit better with Wisdom as the spellcasting ability. Change all elements of this class that reference Intelligence to Wisdom, and change the saving throws you become proficient in to Wisdom and Intelligence.</p>
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <spellcasting name="Weaver" ability="Intelligence" prepare="false" allowReplace="true">
                <list>Weaver</list>
            </spellcasting>
            <rules>
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS_SPELLCASTING_SLOTS_HALF" requirements="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS"/>
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_RITUAL_CASTING" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_FBS_WEAVER_PROFICIENCY_SPELLFOCUS_GROUP_SPIRITUAL_FOCUS" />
			<stat name="weaver:spellcasting:slots:1" value="2" level="2" />
			<stat name="weaver:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="3" />
			<stat name="weaver:spellcasting:slots:1" value="1" level="5" />
			<stat name="weaver:spellcasting:slots:2" value="2" level="5" />
			<stat name="weaver:spellcasting:slots:2" value="1" level="7" />
			<stat name="weaver:spellcasting:slots:3" value="2" level="9" />
			<stat name="weaver:spellcasting:slots:3" value="1" level="11" />
			<stat name="weaver:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="13" />
			<stat name="weaver:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="15" />
			<stat name="weaver:spellcasting:slots:4" value="1" level="17" />
			<stat name="weaver:spellcasting:slots:5" value="1" level="17" />
			<stat name="weaver:spellcasting:slots:5" value="1" level="19" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Weaver)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="2" number="2" spellcasting="Weaver"/>
			<select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Weaver)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="3" spellcasting="Weaver" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Weaver)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="5" spellcasting="Weaver" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Weaver)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="7" spellcasting="Weaver" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Weaver)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="9" spellcasting="Weaver" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Weaver)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="11" spellcasting="Weaver" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Weaver)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="13" spellcasting="Weaver" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Weaver)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="15" spellcasting="Weaver" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Weaver)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="17" spellcasting="Weaver" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (Weaver)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="19" spellcasting="Weaver" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Arcane Essence" type="Class Feature" source="Complete Guide to Sanctum" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_CLASS_FEATURE_WEAVER_ARCANE_ESSENCE">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 2nd level, as an action, you can expend a spell slot to gain essence equal to four times the level of the spell slot that was expended.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>You can expend a spell slot to gain essence equal to four times the level of the spell slot that was expended.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Spirit Guide" type="Class Feature" source="Complete Guide to Sanctum" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_CLASS_FEATURE_WEAVER_SPIRIT_GUIDE">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 3rd level, your supernatural abilities allow you to connect to a spiritual guide. Up to this time, your spirit guide had yet to reveal themselves to you, instead choosing to direct you from a distance. Now you choose the one of the following guides: Archmage, King, and Scoundrel, all detailed at the end of the class description.</p>
                <p class="indent">Your choice grants you features at 3rd level and again at 6th, 10th, and 18th level. Those features include spirit spells and a unique use for your essence.</p>
                <p class="indent">A spirit guide is a spiritual being that a weaver learns from. Their unending knowledge and wisdom helps to guide them in their actions and their situations. Unlike clerics, warlocks, and other adventurers who often have little contact with the source of their power, a weaver’s spirit guide exists solely for them, and is often communicating with them during their downtime. Weavers take great pride in their spirit guides, and they strive to represent their teacher the best way they can.</p>
                <div class="sidebar">
                    <h5>SPIRIT GUIDE’S ROLE WITH THE WEAVER</h5>
                    <p>Spirit Guide’s fill a similar role to that of a Patron to their Warlocks. While they don’t grant their powers to their weavers directly, they instead help to educate them on using their supernatural powers. A spirit guide can be as active or as passive as the DM wants, but it can prove to be a useful tool to inspire roleplaying and help to solidify their character within the world.</p>
                </div>
                <p class="indent">As a weaver, you should carefully consider the relationship you have with your spirit guide. Does your spirit guide hope to bolster your skills for their personal gain, or another reason? Do you know who your spirit guide was in life?</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Archetype" name="Weaver Spirit Guide" supports="Weaver Spirit Guide" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Spiritual Awakening" type="Class Feature" source="Complete Guide to Sanctum" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_CLASS_FEATURE_WEAVER_SPIRITUAL_AWAKENING">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 3rd level, you have studied enough about how spirits work to channel their energy through your being. You can only be possessed if you are willing.</p>
                <div class="sidebar">
                    <h5>RULES ON POSSESSION</h5>
                    <p>Possession is not one of the listed conditions in the <i>Dungeon Master’s Guide</i>, however a few creatures in the published material use it. Ghost is a prime example with their Possession feature. The Dungeon Master has the final say on what constitutes as a possession, but as a guideline it is an effect when a creature or similar being inhabits the body of another and takes control over that form.</p>
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can only be possessed if you are willing.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Ability Score Improvement" type="Class Feature" source="Complete Guide to Sanctum" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_CLASS_FEATURE_WEAVER_ABILITY_SCORE_IMPROVEMENT">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 10th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
				<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Weaver 4)" supports="Improvement Option,Weaver,4" level="4" />
				<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Weaver 8)" supports="Improvement Option,Weaver,8" level="8" />
				<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Weaver 12)" supports="Improvement Option,Weaver,12" level="12" />
				<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Weaver 16)" supports="Improvement Option,Weaver,16" level="16" />
				<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Weaver 19)" supports="Improvement Option,Weaver,19" level="19" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Soul Strike" type="Class Feature" source="Complete Guide to Sanctum" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_CLASS_FEATURE_WEAVER_SOUL_STRIKE">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 5th level, when you make a weapon attack, or a spell attack that targets a single creature, you can expend two essence to gain advantage on the attack roll.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="2 essence">
                <description>When you make a weapon attack, or a spell attack that targets a single creature, you can expend two essence to gain advantage on the attack roll.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Respite" type="Class Feature" source="Complete Guide to Sanctum" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_CLASS_FEATURE_WEAVER_RESPITE">
            <description>
                <p>At 7th level, death doesn’t take you and your allies easily. Creatures of your choice within 60 feet of you make death saving throws with advantage. Likewise, creatures have advantage on Wisdom (Medicine) checks to stabilise a dying creature. You must be conscious to grant this bonus.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Creatures of your choice within 60 feet of you make death saving throws with advantage. Likewise, creatures have advantage on Wisdom (Medicine) checks to stabilise a dying creature. You must be conscious to grant this bonus.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Font of Death" type="Class Feature" source="Complete Guide to Sanctum" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_CLASS_FEATURE_WEAVER_FONT_OF_DEATH">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 9th level, you regain all of your expended uses of your Death Sight feature when you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Vessel of Life" type="Class Feature" source="Complete Guide to Sanctum" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_CLASS_FEATURE_WEAVER_VESSEL_OF_LIFE">
            <description>
                <p>By 14th level, you have a greater control over essence you collect. Essence you obtain lasts until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Gravecaller" type="Class Feature" source="Complete Guide to Sanctum" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_CLASS_FEATURE_WEAVER_GRAVECALLER">
            <description>
                <p>At 15th level, when a creature that you can see (other than yourself) becomes stable within 60 feet of you, you can use your reaction and expend an essence to cause the target to regain hit points equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum 1).</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Reaction" usage="1 essence">
                <description>When a creature that you can see (other than yourself) becomes stable within 60 feet of you, you can cause the target to regain {{int-mod:min-one}} hit points.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Samsara" type="Class Feature" source="Complete Guide to Sanctum" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_CLASS_FEATURE_WEAVER_SAMSARA">
            <description>
                <p>You have mastered the cycle when you reach 20th level. When you are reduced to 0 hit points but not killed outright while you have essence, you can expend all your essence and gain hit points equal to the number of essence expended.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
                <description>When you are reduced to 0 hit points but not killed outright while you have essence, you can expend all your essence and gain hit points equal to the number of essence expended.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>

    <element name="Archmage" type="Archetype" source="Complete Guide to Sanctum" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_WEAVER_ARCHMAGE">
        <supports>Weaver Spirit Guide</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Archmagi are the pinnacle of mortal magical power, commanding extreme and often unparalleled mastery over the craft. The spirit of one of the great Archmagi lives on through you, and you seek to learn from their experience and unmatched study. The nature of your Archmage guide may be a specific wizard, one who lived and breathed in a time before you. Maybe your guide is nothing more than an embodiment of your will to better understand the arcane force within the universe.</p>
            <p class="indent">Regardless of who they are, the Archmage spirit guide will teach and guide you down the coveted arcane path, and train you into a masterful spellcaster that few will match.</p>
            <div element="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCHMAGE_EXPANDED_SPELLS" />
            <div element="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCHMAGE_BONUS_CANTRIPS" />
            <div element="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCHMAGE_INCANTATION" />
            <div element="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCHMAGE_ARCANE_SOLUTION" />
            <div element="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCHMAGE_MAGICAL_RECOVERY" />
            <div element="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCHMAGE_SPIRITUAL_RESERVOIR" />
            <div element="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCHMAGE_MAGICAL_GIFT" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCHMAGE_EXPANDED_SPELLS" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCHMAGE_BONUS_CANTRIPS" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCHMAGE_INCANTATION" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCHMAGE_ARCANE_SOLUTION" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCHMAGE_MAGICAL_RECOVERY" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCHMAGE_SPIRITUAL_RESERVOIR" level="11" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCHMAGE_MAGICAL_GIFT" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Expanded Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="Complete Guide to Sanctum" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCHMAGE_EXPANDED_SPELLS">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 3rd level, you learn an additional spell when you reach certain levels in this class, as shown in the Archmage Spells table. The spell counts as a weaver spell for you, but it doesn’t count against the number of weaver spells you know.</p>
                <h5 class="caption">ARCHMAGE SPELLS</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Weaver Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>magic missile</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5rd</td><td><em>arcane lock</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><em>tiny servant</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>13th</td><td><em>arcane eye</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>17th</td><td><em>teleportation circle</em></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGIC_MISSILE" spellcasting="Weaver" known="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ARCANE_LOCK" spellcasting="Weaver" known="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_TINY_SERVANT" spellcasting="Weaver" known="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ARCANE_EYE" spellcasting="Weaver" known="true" level="13" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TELEPORTATION_CIRCLE" spellcasting="Weaver" known="true" level="17" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Bonus Cantrips" type="Archetype Feature" source="Complete Guide to Sanctum" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCHMAGE_BONUS_CANTRIPS">
            <description>
                <p>At 3rd level, you learn the three cantrips of your choice from the Wizard spell list. Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for these cantrips.</p>
                <div class="sidebar">
                    <h5 class="caption">THE ARCHMAGE CANTRIPS</h5>
                    <p>The three subclasses presented in this book cover the three major archetypes: mage, thief, and warrior. Each class has a way to make up for lack of damage being built in, with the other two subclasses gaining that benefit at 6th level. The Archmage instead gains access to cantrips, which have a damage step increase at certain levels as its damage bonus. Consider choosing a damage cantrip with your choices.</p>
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip, Archmage Spirit Guide" supports="Wizard,0" spellcasting="Weaver" number="3" level="3" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Incantation" type="Archetype Feature" source="Complete Guide to Sanctum" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCHMAGE_INCANTATION">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 3rd level, as a bonus action, you can spend six essence to gain resistance to one damage type of your choice: acid, cold, fire, lightning, poison, or thunder. This resistance lasts for 1 minute.</p>
                <p class="indent">The maximum number of incantations you can have active at a time is equal to your proficiency bonus.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="6 essence">
                <description>You can spend six essence to gain resistance to one damage type of your choice: acid, cold, fire, lightning, poison, or thunder. This resistance lasts for 1 minute. You can have a maximum of {{proficiency}} incantations active at one time.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Arcane Solution" type="Archetype Feature" source="Complete Guide to Sanctum" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCHMAGE_ARCANE_SOLUTION">
            <description>
                <p>At 3rd level, when you expend a spell slot to gain essence, you gain additional essence equal to the your Intelligence modifier (minimum 1).</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you expend a spell slot to gain essence, you gain {{int-mod:min-one}} additional essence.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Magical Recovery" type="Archetype Feature" source="Complete Guide to Sanctum" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCHMAGE_MAGICAL_RECOVERY">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 6th level, you can regain a small amount of magical energy by meditating with the spirits. Once per day when you finish a short rest, you can choose expended spell slots to recover. The spell slots can have a combined level that is equal to or less than half your Weaver level (rounded up).</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Once per day when you finish a short rest, you can choose expended spell slots to recover. The spell slots can have a combined level that is equal to or less than {{level:weaver:half:up}}.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Spiritual Reservoir" type="Archetype Feature" source="Complete Guide to Sanctum" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCHMAGE_SPIRITUAL_RESERVOIR">
            <description>
                <p>By 11th level, the maximum number of essence you can have at any given time is increased by your Intelligence modifier (minimum 1).</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="essence:pool" value="int-mod:min-one" level="11" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Magical Gift" type="Archetype Feature" source="Complete Guide to Sanctum" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCHMAGE_MAGICAL_GIFT">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 18th level, your spirit guide has blessed you with the strongest of magical knowledge. As an action, you can expend a spell slot and target one spellcaster within 60 feet. The target regains any number of used spell slots up to a combined level equal to the level of the spell slot you expended.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>

    <element name="King" type="Archetype" source="Complete Guide to Sanctum" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_WEAVER_KING">
        <supports>Weaver Spirit Guide</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The King is a powerful spirit guide. Ruled by their desire to become stronger, a weaver who takes the time to master the teachings of the King will command a dominating presence and voice on the battlefield. Weavers of this discipline are extremely devout warriors, combining their supernatural abilities with their martial prowess for a deadly combination. Your king may be a forgotten one, lost to time after a millenia of fallen kingdoms. Maybe your guide is a renowned leader, known to legend as a powerful entity.</p>
            <p class="indent">In any case, the King spirit guide will train you in martial skills and tactics, taking you down the path of domination.</p>
            <div element="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_KING_EXPANDED_SPELLS" />
            <div element="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_KING_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" />
            <div element="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_KING_KINGS_CHALLENGE" />
            <div element="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_KING_SPECTRAL_WARFARE" />
            <div element="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_KING_EXTRA_ATTACK" />
            <div element="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_KING_IMPROVED_CRITICAL" />
            <div element="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_KING_SPIRITS_OF_WAR" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_KING_EXPANDED_SPELLS" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_KING_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_KING_KINGS_CHALLENGE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_KING_SPECTRAL_WARFARE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_KING_EXTRA_ATTACK" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_KING_IMPROVED_CRITICAL" level="11" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_KING_SPIRITS_OF_WAR" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Expanded Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="Complete Guide to Sanctum" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_KING_EXPANDED_SPELLS">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 3rd level, you learn an additional spell when you reach certain levels in this class, as shown in the King Spells table. The spell counts as a weaver spell for you, but it doesn’t count against the number of weaver spells you know.</p>
                <h5 class="caption">KING SPELLS</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Weaver Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>shield</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5rd</td><td><em>magic weapon</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><em>elemental weapon</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>13th</td><td><em>banishment</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>17th</td><td><em>steel wind strike</em></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHIELD" spellcasting="Weaver" known="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGIC_WEAPON" spellcasting="Weaver" known="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ELEMENTAL_WEAPON" spellcasting="Weaver" known="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BANISHMENT" spellcasting="Weaver" known="true" level="13" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_STEEL_WIND_STRIKE" spellcasting="Weaver" known="true" level="17" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Bonus Proficiencies" type="Archetype Feature" source="Complete Guide to Sanctum" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_KING_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES">
            <description>
                <p>When you choose this spirit guide at 3rd level, you gain proficiency in martial weapons, medium armour, and shields.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_MARTIAL_WEAPONS" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_MEDIUM_ARMOR" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_SHIELDS" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="King’s Challenge" type="Archetype Feature" source="Complete Guide to Sanctum" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_KING_KINGS_CHALLENGE">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 3rd level, your spirit guide has given you knowledge on how to better defend yourself. As a bonus action, you can expend an essence and target a creature within 30 feet. The target must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw against your weaver spell save DC or have disadvantage on attack rolls against creatures other than you. At the end of each of the target’s turns, it can repeat the saving throw, ending the effect on itself on a success.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="1 essence">
                <description>A target within 30 feet must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw (DC {{spellcasting:dc:int}}) or have disadvantage on attack rolls against creatures other than you. At the end of each of the target’s turns, it can repeat the saving throw.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Spectral Warfare" type="Archetype Feature" source="Complete Guide to Sanctum" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_KING_SPECTRAL_WARFARE">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 3rd level, you learn to weave essence as you fight. When you land a critical hit on a creature, you gain an essence.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you land a critical hit on a creature, you gain an essence.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Extra Attack" type="Archetype Feature" source="Complete Guide to Sanctum" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_KING_EXTRA_ATTACK">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, you can Attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can Attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="extra attack:count" value="2" level="5" bonus="extra attack" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Improved Critical" type="Archetype Feature" source="Complete Guide to Sanctum" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_KING_IMPROVED_CRITICAL">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 11th level, your weapon attacks score a critical hit on a roll of 19 or 20.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Your weapon attacks score a critical hit on a roll of 19 or 20.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Spirits of War" type="Archetype Feature" source="Complete Guide to Sanctum" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_KING_SPIRITS_OF_WAR">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 18th level, you can temporarily rip the boundaries between the ethereal and material plane, drawing power from the spirits of those around you. As an action, you can expend all your essence and begin to sap the life from those around you. Any creature that moves within 15 feet of you for the first time on their turn or ends their turn there takes 5d8 necrotic damage. In addition, when a creature takes damage from this feature you gain an essence.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You can expend all your essence and any creature that moves within 15 feet of you for the first time on their turn or ends their turn there takes 5d8 necrotic damage. In addition, when a creature takes damage from this feature you gain an essence.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>

    <element name="Scoundrel" type="Archetype" source="Complete Guide to Sanctum" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_WEAVER_SCOUNDREL">
        <supports>Weaver Spirit Guide</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The one that listens to those who skulks in the shadows follows the path of the Scoundrel. A trickster of sorts, the Scoundrel teaches their weavers how to use the shadows to their advantage and manipulate the battle from a hidden position. Weavers of this discipline embrace the darkness and their unnatural abilities, combining their abilities to strike fear where they go. The Scoundrel you follow may be an infamous assassin, or a highly regarded thief. Maybe your guide is a charlatan who seeks revenge through you.</p>
            <p class="indent">Regardless, the Scoundrel spirit guide will hone your sneaking skills and your connection with the shadows.</p>
            <div element="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SCOUNDREL_EXPANDED_SPELLS" />
            <div element="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SCOUNDREL_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" />
            <div element="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SCOUNDREL_COVERT" />
            <div element="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SCOUNDREL_FADE" />
            <div element="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SCOUNDREL_SPECTRE_OF_THE_DYING" />
            <div element="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SCOUNDREL_GHOSTLY_ESCAPE" />
            <div element="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SCOUNDREL_SPIRIT_STRIDE" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SCOUNDREL_EXPANDED_SPELLS" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SCOUNDREL_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SCOUNDREL_COVERT" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SCOUNDREL_FADE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SCOUNDREL_SPECTRE_OF_THE_DYING" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SCOUNDREL_GHOSTLY_ESCAPE" level="11" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SCOUNDREL_SPIRIT_STRIDE" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Expanded Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="Complete Guide to Sanctum" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SCOUNDREL_EXPANDED_SPELLS">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 3rd level, you learn an additional spell when you reach certain levels in this class, as shown in the Scoundrel Spells table. The spell counts as a weaver spell for you, but it doesn’t count against the number of weaver spells you know.</p>
                <h5 class="caption">SCOUNDREL SPELLS</h5>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Weaver Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>disguise self</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5rd</td><td><em>invisibility</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>9th</td><td><em>nondetection</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>13th</td><td><em>greater invisibility</em></td></tr>
                    <tr><td>17th</td><td><em>mislead</em></td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISGUISE_SELF" spellcasting="Weaver" known="true" level="3" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INVISIBILITY" spellcasting="Weaver" known="true" level="5" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_NONDETECTION" spellcasting="Weaver" known="true" level="9" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GREATER_INVISIBILITY" spellcasting="Weaver" known="true" level="13" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MISLEAD" spellcasting="Weaver" known="true" level="17" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Bonus Proficiencies" type="Archetype Feature" source="Complete Guide to Sanctum" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SCOUNDREL_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES">
            <description>
                <p>When you choose this spirit guide at 3rd level, you gain proficiency in thieves tools, and your Proficiency Bonus is doubled for any ability check you make with it.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>Your proficiency bonus is doubled for any Thieves’ Tools check you make.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_THIEVES_TOOLS" />
                <stat name="thieves tools:proficiency" value="proficiency" bonus="double" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Covert" type="Archetype Feature" source="Complete Guide to Sanctum" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SCOUNDREL_COVERT">
            <description>
                <p>At 3rd level, you no longer create a visual effect when you use your Sacrament feature. In addition, when you roll initiative you gain a number of essence equal to half your Intelligence modifier (minimum 1).</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You no longer create a visual effect when you use your Sacrament feature. In addition, when you roll initiative you gain {{covert:essence}} essence.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="covert:essence" value="1" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="covert:essence" value="1" requirements="[intelligence:modifier:4]" />
                <stat name="covert:essence" value="1" requirements="[intelligence:modifier:6]" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Fade" type="Archetype Feature" source="Complete Guide to Sanctum" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SCOUNDREL_FADE">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 3rd level, you can use essence to temporarily step to a new location. As a bonus action, you can expend an essence and teleport up to 20 feet to an unoccupied space that you can see. You can choose to expend additional essence to increase this distance by an additional 10 feet for each essence you use.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="1 essence">
                <description>You can teleport up to 20 feet to an unoccupied space that you can see. You can choose to expend additional essence to increase this distance by an additional 10 feet for each essence you use.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Spectre of the Dying" type="Archetype Feature" source="Complete Guide to Sanctum" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SCOUNDREL_SPECTRE_OF_THE_DYING">
            <description>
                <p>Beginning at 6th level, when you use your reaction to gain essence through your Sacrament feature, you can choose to target one creature within 30 feet of you. That creature must succeed an Intelligence saving throw or take psychic damage equal to four times the number of essence you gained.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you use your reaction to gain essence through your Sacrament feature, you can choose to target one creature within 30 feet of you. That creature must succeed an Intelligence saving throw (DC {{spellcasting:dc:int}}) or take psychic damage equal to four times the number of essence you gained.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Ghostly Escape" type="Archetype Feature" source="Complete Guide to Sanctum" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SCOUNDREL_GHOSTLY_ESCAPE">
            <description>
                <p>At 11th level, when you use your Fade feature, your movement does not provoke opportunity attacks until the beginning of your next turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you use your Fade feature, your movement does not provoke opportunity attacks until the beginning of your next turn.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Spirit Stride" type="Archetype Feature" source="Complete Guide to Sanctum" id="ID_FBS_CGTS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SCOUNDREL_SPIRIT_STRIDE">
            <description>
                <p>Upon reaching 18th level, you can channel the spirits to temporarily step into the ethereal plane. As an action, you become under the effects of the etherealness spell. At the start of your next turn, if you are on the Ethereal Plane, you return to an unoccupied space of your choice that you can see within 10 feet of the space you vanished from. If no unoccupied space is available within that range, you appear in the nearest unoccupied space (chosen at random if more than one space is equally near). While in the Ethereal Plane, you can use your Sacrament feature as if you were in your current plane of existence. This feature lasts for 1 minute or until you end it as a bonus action.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You become under the effects of the etherealness spell. While in the Ethereal Plane, you can use your Sacrament feature as if you were in your current plane of existence. This feature lasts for 1 minute or until you end it as a bonus action.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
            </rules>
        </element>


    <!-- Weaver Skills -->
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ANIMALHANDLING">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ARCANA">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_DECEPTION">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_HISTORY">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_MEDICINE">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_NATURE">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_RELIGION">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>

    <!-- Weaver Spells -->
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ABSORB_ELEMENTS">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ALARM">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BANE">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CAUSE_FEAR">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CHARM_PERSON">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMPREHEND_LANGUAGES">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMMAND">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CREATE_OR_DESTROY_WATER">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CURE_WOUNDS">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_MAGIC">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_EVIL_AND_GOOD">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_POISON_AND_DISEASE">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_EXPEDITIOUS_RETREAT">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FALSE_LIFE">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FEATHER_FALL">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIND_FAMILIAR">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HEX">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_IDENTIFY">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGE_ARMOR">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PURIFY_FOOD_AND_DRINK">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SLEEP">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AID">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AUGURY">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLUR">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CALM_EMOTIONS">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DARKVISION">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_THOUGHTS">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENTHRALL">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GENTLE_REPOSE">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_HEALING_SPIRIT">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HOLD_PERSON">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LESSER_RESTORATION">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LEVITATE">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MISTY_STEP">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PHANTASMAL_FORCE">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SEE_INVISIBILITY">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SILENCE">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SUGGESTION">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BESTOW_CURSE">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLINK">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CLAIRVOYANCE">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FEAR">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LIFE_TRANSFERENCE">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PHANTOM_STEED">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PROTECTION_FROM_ENERGY">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_REMOVE_CURSE">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_DEAD">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPIRIT_GUARDIANS">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_VAMPIRIC_TOUCH">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_CHARM_MONSTER">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMPULSION">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DEATH_WARD">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DIMENSION_DOOR">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DIVINATION">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ELEMENTAL_BANE">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FREEDOM_OF_MOVEMENT">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LOCATE_CREATURE">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONTACT_OTHER_PLANE">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_FAR_STEP">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GEAS">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MASS_CURE_WOUNDS">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RAISE_DEAD">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>
        <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WALL_OF_FORCE">
            <supports>Weaver</supports>
        </append>

    <!-- Weaver Spiritual Focus -->
        <element name="Spiritual Focus" type="Spellcasting Focus Group" source="The Weaver" id="ID_FBS_WEAVER_SPELLFOCUS_GROUP_SPIRITUAL_FOCUS">
            <description>
                <p>As a weaver, you have a new casting device: the spiritual focus. A spiritual focus is in ways similar to an arcane focus, acting as a magical source for spellcasting. In order to use spell slots in the Weaver class, you must have one of these on your person. You can create a spiritual focus by spending 1 hour retuning an arcane focus.</p>
            </description>
        </element>
        <element name="Spellcasting Focus Group (Spiritual Focus)" type="Proficiency" source="The Weaver" id="ID_FBS_WEAVER_PROFICIENCY_SPELLFOCUS_GROUP_SPIRITUAL_FOCUS">
            <rules>
                <grant type="Proficiency" name="ID_FBS_WEAVER_ITEM_SPIRITUAL_FOCUS" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" name="ID_FBS_WEAVER_ITEM_SPIRITUAL_FOCUS_CRYSTAL" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" name="ID_FBS_WEAVER_ITEM_SPIRITUAL_FOCUS_ORB" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" name="ID_FBS_WEAVER_ITEM_SPIRITUAL_FOCUS_ROD" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" name="ID_FBS_WEAVER_ITEM_SPIRITUAL_FOCUS_STAFF" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" name="ID_FBS_WEAVER_ITEM_SPIRITUAL_FOCUS_WAND" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Spiritual Focus" type="Item" source="The Weaver" id="ID_FBS_WEAVER_ITEM_SPIRITUAL_FOCUS">
            <description>
                <p>A spiritual focus is in ways similar to an arcane focus, acting as a magical source for spellcasting. In order to use spell slots in the Weaver class, you must have one of these on your person. You can create a spiritual focus by spending 1 hour retuning an arcane focus.</p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="category">Spellcasting Focus</set>
                <set name="cost" currency="gp">5</set>
                <set name="weight" lb="2">2 lb.</set>
                <set name="container">Spiritual Focus</set>
                <set name="slot">onehand</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
        <element name="Crystal" type="Item" source="The Weaver" id="ID_FBS_WEAVER_ITEM_SPIRITUAL_FOCUS_CRYSTAL">
            <description>
                <p>A spiritual focus is in ways similar to an arcane focus, acting as a magical source for spellcasting. In order to use spell slots in the Weaver class, you must have one of these on your person. You can create a spiritual focus by spending 1 hour retuning an arcane focus.</p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="category">Spellcasting Focus</set>
                <set name="cost" currency="gp">10</set>
                <set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
                <set name="container">Spiritual Focus</set>
                <set name="slot">onehand</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
        <element name="Orb" type="Item" source="The Weaver" id="ID_FBS_WEAVER_ITEM_SPIRITUAL_FOCUS_ORB">
            <description>
                <p>A spiritual focus is in ways similar to an arcane focus, acting as a magical source for spellcasting. In order to use spell slots in the Weaver class, you must have one of these on your person. You can create a spiritual focus by spending 1 hour retuning an arcane focus.</p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="category">Spellcasting Focus</set>
                <set name="cost" currency="gp">20</set>
                <set name="weight" lb="3">3 lb.</set>
                <set name="container">Spiritual Focus</set>
                <set name="slot">onehand</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
        <element name="Rod" type="Item" source="The Weaver" id="ID_FBS_WEAVER_ITEM_SPIRITUAL_FOCUS_ROD">
            <description>
                <p>A spiritual focus is in ways similar to an arcane focus, acting as a magical source for spellcasting. In order to use spell slots in the Weaver class, you must have one of these on your person. You can create a spiritual focus by spending 1 hour retuning an arcane focus.</p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="category">Spellcasting Focus</set>
                <set name="cost" currency="gp">1</set>
                <set name="weight" lb="2">2 lb.</set>
                <set name="container">Spiritual Focus</set>
                <set name="slot">onehand</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
        <element name="Staff" type="Item" source="The Weaver" id="ID_FBS_WEAVER_ITEM_SPIRITUAL_FOCUS_STAFF">
            <description>
                <p>A spiritual focus is in ways similar to an arcane focus, acting as a magical source for spellcasting. In order to use spell slots in the Weaver class, you must have one of these on your person. You can create a spiritual focus by spending 1 hour retuning an arcane focus.</p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="category">Spellcasting Focus</set>
                <set name="cost" currency="gp">5</set>
                <set name="weight" lb="4">4 lb.</set>
                <set name="container">Spiritual Focus</set>
                <set name="slot">onehand</set>
            </setters>
        </element>
        <element name="Wand" type="Item" source="The Weaver" id="ID_FBS_WEAVER_ITEM_SPIRITUAL_FOCUS_WAND">
            <description>
                <p>A spiritual focus is in ways similar to an arcane focus, acting as a magical source for spellcasting. In order to use spell slots in the Weaver class, you must have one of these on your person. You can create a spiritual focus by spending 1 hour retuning an arcane focus.</p>
            </description>
            <setters>
                <set name="category">Spellcasting Focus</set>
                <set name="cost" currency="gp">10</set>
                <set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
                <set name="container">Spiritual Focus</set>
                <set name="slot">onehand</set>
            </setters>
        </element>

</elements>