<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Compendium of Familiar Resurgence Magic Items</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="items-wondrous.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/compendium-of-familiar-resurgence/items-wondrous.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Maleciful's Comb for Loved Familiars" type="Magic Item" source="Compendium of Familiar Resurgence" id="ID_L009_COFR_MAGIC_ITEM_MALECIFULS_COMB_FOR_LOVED_FAMILIARS">
        <description>
            <p>This comb comes in different varieties and shapes, each made for specific species of familiars. After completing a long rest, you can spend 1 minute to groom your familiar using this comb. Until you complete a long rest, it gains a +2 bonus to its AC and gains inspiration after the care and attention you show to it. At any point, it can choose to gain advantage on a d20 roll once.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">familiar</set>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="slot"></set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">uncommon</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Petting Comb" type="Magic Item" source="Compendium of Familiar Resurgence" id="ID_L009_COFR_MAGIC_ITEM_PETTING_COMB">
        <description>
            <p>This small sparkling comb is especially pleasureable to the touch when used to pet or groom small animals. You can use it to pet a small animal, and gain advantage on Wisdom (Animal Handling) checks made to tame or befriend small and tiny beasts.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">familiar</set>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="slot"></set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">common</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Companion's Bond" type="Magic Item" source="Compendium of Familiar Resurgence" id="ID_L009_COFR_MAGIC_ITEM_COMPANIONS_BOND">
        <description>
            <p>This beautiful blue collar can be used to form a bond between you and a deared animal which is friendly to you. Once worn, the name of your pet appears on the comfortable collar, and it can never be erased. Your pet now becomes your familiar, as per the find familiar spell. However, when your familiar drops to 0 hitpoints, it does not disappear. Instead it falls unconscious, and rolls death saving throws as a character would.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once it has bonded with a familiar, this collar cannot be used to bond with another beast in this manner. If you remove the collar from your familiar, you can choose to end the bond with your familiar as an action, letting your pet roam free. If you use multiple collars, or the find familiar spell, you can form multiple familiar bonds. However, you cannot have more than one familiar summoned at a time. If you fail to give a name to your familiar, the bond fails to form.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">familiar</set>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="slot"></set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">uncommon</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Emergency Familiar Orb" type="Magic Item" source="Compendium of Familiar Resurgence" id="ID_L009_COFR_MAGIC_ITEM_EMERGENCY_FAMILIAR_ORB">
        <description>
            <p>This small glass orb radiates bright warm light in a 5-foot radius, and is made to ease the pain of a spellcaster who has just seen their familiar violently return to their home plane, and need them back.</p>
            <p class="indent">If you know the find familiar spell, have it prepared, or inscibed in a spellbook, you can use an action to shatter this orb, immediately casting find familiar and summoning your familiar in the last form it had.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">familiar</set>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="slot"></set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">uncommon</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Misty Bell" type="Magic Item" source="Compendium of Familiar Resurgence" id="ID_L009_COFR_MAGIC_ITEM_MISTY_BELL">
        <description>
            <p>This elegant bell shines with a dull blue light under moonlight, and constantly produces small wisps of mist underneath its mouth. While worn by your familiar, it can use a bonus action to cast the misty step spell or an action to cast the fog cloud spell. It must complete a long rest before it can do so again.</p>
            <p class="indent">Additionally, if the familiar is wearing this bell, it can use an action to magically ring it, producing a clear bell sound audible up to 60 feet away for up to 1 minute. It can use its action again to end this effect.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">familiar</set>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="slot"></set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">uncommon</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Bonding Ring" type="Magic Item" source="Compendium of Familiar Resurgence" id="ID_L009_COFR_MAGIC_ITEM_BONDING_RING">
        <description>
            <p>A familiar equiped with this ring can use its reaction to give you advantage on an Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma saving throw while it is within 30 feet of you. It takes 1d6 psychic damage when doing so as it shares part of the burden of your mental anguish.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">familiar</set>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="slot"></set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">uncommon</set>
            <set name="attunement" addition=" by a familiar">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Talent's Bow" type="Magic Item" source="Compendium of Familiar Resurgence" id="ID_L009_COFR_MAGIC_ITEM_TALENTS_BOW">
        <description>
            <p>This beautiful red bow changes colors when its abilities are invoked. While your familiar is wearing this bow, it can use its action to cast the enhance ability spell on itself. It must complete a long rest before being able to do so again.</p>
            <p class="indent">The color of the bow changes to brown when Bear's Endurance is chosen, red for Bull's Strength, green for Cat's Grace, white for Eagle's Splendor, purple for Fox's Cunning and blue for Owl's Wisdom.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">familiar</set>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="slot"></set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">uncommon</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Free Wings" type="Magic Item" source="Compendium of Familiar Resurgence" id="ID_L009_COFR_MAGIC_ITEM_FREE_WINGS">
        <description>
            <p>Your familiar does not provoke attacks of opportunity when it leaves a creature's reach while flying.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">familiar</set>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="slot"></set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">rare</set>
            <set name="attunement" addition=" by a familiar with a fly speed">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Potion of Cherising" type="Magic Item" source="Compendium of Familiar Resurgence" id="ID_L009_COFR_MAGIC_ITEM_POTION_OF_CHERISING">
        <description>
            <p>You can administer this potion to your familiar using an action. Your familiar gains the effects of death ward. Your familiar cannot administer this potion to itself or another familiar.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">familiar</set>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="slot"></set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">rare</set>
            <set name="stackable">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Belt of the Airborne Medic" type="Magic Item" source="Compendium of Familiar Resurgence" id="ID_L009_COFR_MAGIC_ITEM_BELT_OF_THE_AIRBORNE_MEDIC">
        <description>
            <p>This belt is fitted to be worn by owl or eagle familiars. You can strap into the belt as many as 5 regular healing potions. The familiar wearing this belt can use its action to administer one of the healing potions in this belt by flying directly over a creature, and releasing the healing potion. The belt is only designed to function with regular healing potions, as other larger sizes are to unwieldly to fit into this belt, and other kinds of potions are too volatile to have been tested with this belt.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">familiar</set>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="slot"></set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">rare</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Amulet of the Bondkeeper" type="Magic Item" source="Compendium of Familiar Resurgence" id="ID_L009_COFR_MAGIC_ITEM_AMULET_OF_THE_BONDKEEPER">
        <description>
            <p>This gold chained amulet houses a dull ruby in its center that begins to take a vivid red color once you perform an 1-hour ritual to bond it with your familiars. You can use this amulet to cast Aid as a third level spell once per long rest. You can only target yourself and any familiars bonded to you with this casting of the spell.</p>
            <p class="indent">Additionally, whenever you see your familiar take damage, you can use your reaction to invoke the protective powers of this amulet. Your familiar takes half as much damage as it would normally take, and this amulet takes the same amount of damage as your familiar. This amulet has 50 hitpoints. Once it reaches 0 hitpoints, the ruby in its center shatters, and the amulet is destroyed. If the amulet has any hitpoints remaining, it regains all of its hitpoints at each dawn.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">familiar</set>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="slot"></set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">rare</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Ring of Familiar Escape" type="Magic Item" source="Compendium of Familiar Resurgence" id="ID_L009_COFR_MAGIC_ITEM_RING_OF_FAMILIAR_ESCAPE">
        <description>
            <p>This smooth brass ring gleams in the sunlight, and produces small vibrations whenever your familiar is damaged. When you can see that your familiar is about to take damage, you can use your reaction to immediately dismiss your familiar back to its pocket plane, before any damage is dealt to it.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">familiar</set>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="slot">ring</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">very rare</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Satchel of Missives" type="Magic Item" source="Compendium of Familiar Resurgence" id="ID_L009_COFR_MAGIC_ITEM_SATCHEL_OF_MISSIVES">
        <description>
            <p>This small satchel is designed to be worn by familiars. The sathcel has an interior space considerably larger than its outside dimensions, and can hold up to 2 cubic feet or 20 pounds of material. The satchel always weighs 1 pound regardless of its contents.</p>
            <p class="indent">When you place an object inside the satchel, you can designate its intended recipient. Any creature that opens the satchel can use an action to retrieve from it any items that it is the recipient of. The satchel otherwise appears empty to it. You can designate which creatures can view the contents of the satchel in full.</p>
            <p class="indent">While wearing this satchel your familiar has advantage on Wisdom (Survival) ability checks made to navigate and find its way towards a prescribed destination.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">familiar</set>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="slot"></set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">uncommon</set>
            <set name="attunement" addition=" by a familiar">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Ring of the Familiar Planeswalker" type="Magic Item" source="Compendium of Familiar Resurgence" id="ID_L009_COFR_MAGIC_ITEM_RING_OF_THE_FAMILIAR_PLANESWALKER">
        <description>
            <p>This noble ring can be crafted only by the most powerful of archmages, and is used by them to make their familiar as awesome as they are.</p>
            <p class="indent">This ring has 10 charges. Your familiar can expend a number of the ring's charges to cast the following spells from it: teleport (2 charges, only self), plane shift (3 charges, only self), dimension door (1 charge). If the last charge on the ring is expended roll 1d20. On a result of 1, the ring loses its magical capabilities. The ring regains 1d6+4 of its charges each dawn.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">familiar</set>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="slot">ring</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">legendary</set>
            <set name="attunement" addition=" by a familiar">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Plumage of Evasive Maneuvers" type="Magic Item" source="Compendium of Familiar Resurgence" id="ID_L009_COFR_MAGIC_ITEM_PLUMAGE_OF_EVASIVE_MANEUVERS">
        <description>
            <p>This colorful dust changes the color of your familiar's plumage once sprinkled on it. This dust can only be applied to familiars that have a fly speed. Ranged weapon and spell attacks have disadvantage on your familiar, as it uses its wings to fly in unique and dazzling evasive maneuvers.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">familiar</set>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="slot"></set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">rare</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Ring of Disappearance" type="Magic Item" source="Compendium of Familiar Resurgence" id="ID_L009_COFR_MAGIC_ITEM_RING_OF_DISAPPEARANCE">
        <description>
            <p>This ring is designed to be worn by a familiar. Your familiar can use its action to cast the invisibility spell on itself while wearing this ring. It has to complete a long rest before it can do so again.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">familiar</set>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="slot"></set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">uncommon</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Ring of Alteration" type="Magic Item" source="Compendium of Familiar Resurgence" id="ID_L009_COFR_MAGIC_ITEM_RING_OF_ALTERATION">
        <description>
            <p>While your familiar is wearing this ring, it can use its action to cast the alter self spell. It must complete a long rest before being able to do so again.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">familiar</set>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="slot"></set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">uncommon</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Ring of the Far Spy" type="Magic Item" source="Compendium of Familiar Resurgence" id="ID_L009_COFR_MAGIC_ITEM_RING_OF_THE_FAR_SPY">
        <description>
            <p>This ring is designed to be worn by a familiar. Your familiar can use an action to cause the ring to become Invisible until it uses another action to make it visible, until it removes the ring, or until it drops to 0 hitpoints.</p>
            <p class="indent">This ring has 3 charges. While your are inhabiting your familiar's senses, you can have your familiar expend one of the ring's charges to cast <i>detect thoughts</i>.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">familiar</set>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="slot"></set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">rare</set>
            <set name="attunement" addition=" by a familiar">true</set>
            <set name="charges">3</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Goggles of Arcanasight" type="Magic Item" source="Compendium of Familiar Resurgence" id="ID_L009_COFR_MAGIC_ITEM_GOGGLES_OF_ARCANASIGHT">
        <description>
            <p>While your familiar is wearing these goggles, it can use an action to cast the detect magic spell from them. The familiar then can't do so again until it has completed a short rest. While you are inhabiting your familiar's senses and the spell is active, you benefit from the effect as well.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">familiar</set>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="slot"></set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">uncommon</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Badges of the Liaison" type="Magic Item" source="Compendium of Familiar Resurgence" id="ID_L009_COFR_MAGIC_ITEM_BADGES_OF_THE_LIAISON">
        <description>
            <p>This set of two badges is designed to be worn by a familiar and its bonded companion, and are meant to connect the two worlds of their bearers, that of the humanoid and animal kingdoms. This badge grants the familiar the ability to verbally communicate with any beast, and advantage on any Charisma based checks with beasts, while its companion gains the ability to be recognized as a friend. Any beast that sees these badges innately perceives the two creatures wearing them to be connected — as two halves of the same circle — and any impressions or feelings formed towards one of these creatures are likely to apply to both of them. For example, if the familiar manages to ingratiate itself into an animal habitat, then its bonded companion is also made welcome, as the familiar acts as a liason between the humanoid and animal kingdoms.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">familiar</set>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="slot"></set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">uncommon</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Tether of Harmonious Casting" type="Magic Item" source="Compendium of Familiar Resurgence" id="ID_L009_COFR_MAGIC_ITEM_TETHER_OF_HARMONIOUS_CASTING">
        <description>
            <p>This thin silver string can barely be seen in the moonlight. While your familiar is attuned to it, you can use a bonus action to tether yourself to your familiar. You become connected by the tether, which phases out into the ethereal plane. While tethered, you and your familiar can't willingly move in a way that you become further apart than 60 feet from each other. Additionally while you are tethered, you can cast spells through your familiar. The tether has 15 charges. You can expend a number of charges equal to the level of the spell being cast (1 charge for cantrips) to cast the spell through your familiar. You cannot cast spells of 7th level or higher in this way. The tether regains 1d10+5 charges each dawn.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">familiar</set>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="slot"></set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">rare</set>
            <set name="attunement" addition=" by a familiar">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Bead of Familiar Awakening" type="Magic Item" source="Compendium of Familiar Resurgence" id="ID_L009_COFR_MAGIC_ITEM_BEAD_OF_FAMILIAR_AWAKENING">
        <description>
            <p>This round bead pulses with green vibrant energy. Birdsong and the rustling of leaves can be heard emanating from it. It is known to exist naturally only in bountiful druid groves, where the natural care and attention of the druids towards the animals innately imbues the earth with the magic of life.</p>
            <p class="indent">When you feed this bead to your familiar, it gains the benefits of the awaken spell. However, the familiar is not charmed by you when it is awakened. It needs to eat, sleep and has the same bodily needs as it otherwise would, but retains its original creature type. If it wishes so at any point, the familiar can now end its service to you as your familiar.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">familiar</set>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="slot"></set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">very rare</set>
            <set name="stackable">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Gloves of the Familiar Spellsurge" type="Magic Item" source="Compendium of Familiar Resurgence" id="ID_L009_COFR_MAGIC_ITEM_GLOVES_OF_THE_FAMILIAR_SPELLSURGE">
        <description>
            <p>While wearing these gloves you can use an action to expend a spell slot of 5th level or lower. If your familiar is within 30 feet of you, you can channel the expended magical energy towards it in order to reinforce it. Your familiar gains 10 hitpoints for each level of the spell you expended.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">familiar</set>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="slot">hands</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">rare</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Belts of Dimensional Swapping" type="Magic Item" source="Compendium of Familiar Resurgence" id="ID_L009_COFR_MAGIC_ITEM_BELTS_OF_DIMENSIONAL_SWAPPING">
        <description>
            <p>This belt comes with an identical copy of itself in miniature size. While both you and your familiar are wearing these belts, you can use your action to swap positions with your familiar if you are within 60 feet of each other. You appear in its place, while it appears in yours.</p>
            <p class="indent">Additionally, when one of you is hit by an attack or takes damage, you can use your reaction to swap positions with your familiar. You appear in its position, while it appears in yours. The target of the attack or the recipient of the damage is also swapped. If your familiar was to take damage, you take the same amount of damage instead, and vice versa. This damage cannot be reduced in any way.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">familiar</set>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="slot">waist</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">legendary</set>
            <set name="attunement" addition=" by a familiar and a spellcaster">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Rings of Dual Focus" type="Magic Item" source="Compendium of Familiar Resurgence" id="ID_L009_COFR_MAGIC_ITEM_RINGS_OF_DUAL_FOCUS">
        <description>
            <p>These two rings are made by the same brass-alchrium aloy, and are adorned by a miniscule piece of blue quartz. When you cast a concentration spell and you can see your familiar, you can choose to have your familiar concentrate on the spell for you. You can concentrate on another spell only if the total spell levels of the spells you and your familiar are concentrating on are 8 or lower. Otherwise, the casting of the spell fails, and your action is wasted, but not your spell slot. For example, you and your familiar can concentrate on invisibility and hypnotic pattern, but not wall of force and sickening radiance.</p>
            <p class="indent">If your familiar ever willingly moves to a place out of your line of sight or is not on the same plane of existence as you, its concentration is broken as the link created by the rings breaks.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">familiar</set>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="slot">ring</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">very rare</set>
            <set name="attunement" addition=" by a familiar">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Brazier of Flocks" type="Magic Item" source="Compendium of Familiar Resurgence" id="ID_L009_COFR_MAGIC_ITEM_BRAZIER_OF_FLOCKS">
        <description>
            <p>This brass brazier can be used to burn the incense necessary for the casting of the find familiar spell. You can use this brazier to cast find familiar as usual, with the exception that when the ritual is complete you gain the service of an additional familiar for each addition 10 gold worth of incense you offered. The maximum number of additional familiars you can gain is equal to half your proficiency modifier (rounded down).</p>
            <p class="indent">To change the forms of any of these familiars, you can cast find familiar using this brazier again.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">familiar</set>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="slot"></set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">very rare</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Echo Charge" type="Magic Item" source="Compendium of Familiar Resurgence" id="ID_L009_COFR_MAGIC_ITEM_ECHO_CHARGE">
        <description>
            <p>You can equip your familiar with this blue belt, which shimmers with arcane energy. When your familiar drops to 0 hitpoints, the belt harnesses the errant energy let out by the dissipating familiar and focuses it outwards. Each creature within 10 feet of the familiar must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw, taking 21 (6d6) force damage on a failure, or half as much damage on a success.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">familiar</set>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="slot"></set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">rare</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    
</elements>