<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Covenant of the Anomaly Chimeric Covenant</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <author url="https://www.reddit.com/u/Spirit-of-the-Maker">u/Spirit-of-the-Maker</author>
            <file name="slayer-covenant-of-the-anomaly.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/subclasses/slayer/slayer-covenant-of-the-anomaly.xml" />
        </update>
        <!-- https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B8nQR8rIryqeLTNaWXdTVHY3T3c/view -->
    </info>
    
    <element name="Covenant of the Vestige" type="Archetype" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SPIRITOFTHEMAKER_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_SLAYER_COVENANT_OF_THE_ANOMALY">
        <supports>Chimeric Covenant</supports>
        <description>
            <p>To most, Time and Space are simply immutable elements of day-to-day life. The sun will rise, the sun will set, and you can only run so far in that time. To a select few, however, this is not the case. The Slayers that populate the Covenant of the Anomaly often come from realms unknown or were touched by entities outside mortal comprehension, and thus can manipulate these otherwise fixed forces.</p>
            <p class="indent">It is a lonely path for Anomalous Slayers - it is very rare for two to meet even in their extended lives, and their purposes are as incomprehensible as the eldritch monsters they battle. Anomaly Covenant Quirks</p>
            <h5 class="caption">Anomaly Covenant Quirks</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d6</td><td>Quirk</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>You sometimes slip into tongues displaced in time.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>You see people and objects shift to various stages of their lives while remaining in the present.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>Your body flickers, having trouble staying in the present.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>Your mood shifts rapidly for no apparent reason.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>Stars and strands of fate sometimes dance across your skin, emitting an eerie light.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>You accidentally use inproper social conventions for the situation, even though they may be correct in the past or future.</td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_SPIRITOFTHEMAKER_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLAYER_ANOMALY_MONSTROUS_AFFINITY" />
            <div element="ID_SPIRITOFTHEMAKER_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLAYER_ANOMALY_BLINK_STEP" />
            <div element="ID_SPIRITOFTHEMAKER_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLAYER_ANOMALY_IRREGULAR_ARMS" />
            <div element="ID_SPIRITOFTHEMAKER_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLAYER_ANOMALY_RECALL" />
            <div element="ID_SPIRITOFTHEMAKER_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLAYER_ANOMALY_THE_BEST_MEDICINE" />
            <div element="ID_SPIRITOFTHEMAKER_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLAYER_ANOMALY_MASTER_OF_TIME_AND_SPACE" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SPIRITOFTHEMAKER_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLAYER_ANOMALY_MONSTROUS_AFFINITY" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SPIRITOFTHEMAKER_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLAYER_ANOMALY_BLINK_STEP" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SPIRITOFTHEMAKER_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLAYER_ANOMALY_IRREGULAR_ARMS" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SPIRITOFTHEMAKER_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLAYER_ANOMALY_RECALL" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SPIRITOFTHEMAKER_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLAYER_ANOMALY_THE_BEST_MEDICINE" level="14" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_SPIRITOFTHEMAKER_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLAYER_ANOMALY_MASTER_OF_TIME_AND_SPACE" level="20" />
            <select type="List" name="Anomaly Covenant Quirk">
                <item id="1">You sometimes slip into tongues displaced in time.</item>
                <item id="2">You see people and objects shift to various stages of their lives while remaining in the present.</item>
                <item id="3">Your body flickers, having trouble staying in the present.</item>
                <item id="4">Your mood shifts rapidly for no apparent reason.</item>
                <item id="5">Stars and strands of fate sometimes dance across your skin, emitting an eerie light.</item>
                <item id="6">You accidentally use inproper social conventions for the situation, even though they may be correct in the past or future.</item>
            </select>
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Monstrous Affinity" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SPIRITOFTHEMAKER_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLAYER_ANOMALY_MONSTROUS_AFFINITY">
            <description>
                <p>Your cross-dimensional nature gives you an affinity for Aberrations.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you make a skill or ability check directly involving aberrations, you can use your Occult Studies without expending a use.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Blink Step" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SPIRITOFTHEMAKER_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLAYER_ANOMALY_BLINK_STEP">
            <description>
                <p>Starting when you join this covenant at 3rd level, you can inherently shift your location in time and space.</p>
                <p class="indent">Once on your turn, as a bonus action, you may teleport back to the space you ended your Quick Step on your previous turn. Your Blink Step does not provoke opportunity attacks. If you end your Blink Step in a space that is now occupied by a solid object, you suffer 1d10 force damage and are shunted into the nearest free space.</p>
                <p class="indent">At 6th level, you can Blink Step as a reaction to which you take in response to being damaged.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>Once on your turn, you may teleport back to the space you ended your Quick Step on your previous turn. Your Blink Step does not provoke opportunity attacks. If you end your Blink Step in a space that is now occupied by a solid object, you suffer 1d10 force damage and are shunted into the nearest free space.</description>
                <description level="6">Once on your turn, you may teleport back to the space you ended your Quick Step on your previous turn. Your Blink Step does not provoke opportunity attacks. If you end your Blink Step in a space that is now occupied by a solid object, you suffer 1d10 force damage and are shunted into the nearest free space. You can Blink Step as a reaction to which you take in response to being damaged.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Irregular Arms" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SPIRITOFTHEMAKER_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLAYER_ANOMALY_IRREGULAR_ARMS">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 3rd level, you can manipulate time in incomprehensible ways. You add psychic damage to the list of damage types you can inflict with your imbued weapons, or with any slayer spell that can inflict your choice of cold, fire, or lightning damage.</p>
                <p class="indent">As an action, you can return every piece of ammunition fired with Cursed Brand active within the last 10 minutes to you. Additionally, you can reroll the damage of one attack of your choice on your turn, as long as the next attack you make uses the original damage roll.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action">
                <description>You can return every piece of ammunition fired with Cursed Brand active within the last 10 minutes to you. Additionally, you can reroll the damage of one attack of your choice on your turn, as long as the next attack you make uses the original damage roll. You add psychic damage to the list of damage types you can inflict with your imbued weapons, or with any slayer spell that can inflict your choice of cold, fire, or lightning damage.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Recall" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SPIRITOFTHEMAKER_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLAYER_ANOMALY_RECALL">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, you recall memories that seem to be both yours and not. You gain proficiency in an additional skill of your choice. In addition, you may double your proficiency bonus in one skill of your choice.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency (Slayer)" supports="Skill" level="6" />
    			<select type="Class Feature" name="Expertise (Slayer)" level="6" number="1" supports="ID_INTERNAL_SUPPORT_EXPERTISE"/>
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="The Best Medicine" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SPIRITOFTHEMAKER_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLAYER_ANOMALY_THE_BEST_MEDICINE">
            <description>
                <p>At 14th level, you find your body shifting into how it was in your prime, down to the most minute detail. You are immune to any ability that would magically alter your form unwillingly, and can no longer be aged by magical or natural means.</p>
                <p class="indent">In addition, you may actively reset your body. Once on your turn, as a bonus action, you may end all effects, conditions, and diseases against you, at the cost of reducing your current and maximum hit points by an amount equal to twice your player level. Alternatively, you may gain current and maximum hit points equal to twice your player level, at the cost of gaining a random effect, condition, or disease, chosen by the DM. You regain your normal hit point maximum after a short rest. Any excess hit points are lost.</p>
                <p class="indent">You may use this ability a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum one). You regain all expended uses after a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="{{the-best-medicien:uses}}/Long Rest" action="Bonus Action">
                <description>Once on your turn, you may end all effects, conditions, and diseases against you, at the cost of reducing your current and maximum hit points by {{the-best-medicine:lost-hp}}. Alternatively, you may gain {{the-best-medicine:lost-hp}} current and maximum hit points, at the cost of gaining a random effect, condition, or disease, chosen by the DM. You regain your normal hit point maximum after a short rest. Additionally, you are immune to any ability that would magically alter your form unwillingly, and can no longer be aged by magical or natural means.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="the-best-medicine:lost-hp" value="level:slayer" />
                <stat name="the-best-medicine:lost-hp" value="level:slayer" />
                <stat name="the-best-medicien:uses" value="1" bonus="base" />
                <stat name="the-best-medicien:uses" value="intelligence:modifier" bonus="base" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Master of Time and Space" type="Archetype Feature" source="r/Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_SPIRITOFTHEMAKER_RDDT_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLAYER_ANOMALY_MASTER_OF_TIME_AND_SPACE">
            <description>
                <p>At 20th level, you may use your action to take on the aspect of Time and Space itself. The details are up to you; you might become a silhouette of space and stars, or a mesh of glowing threads of fate.</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Time slows for you alone. At the start of your turn, roll 1d4. This is the number of additional actions you may take on this turn. You may not take the same action more than once on this turn.</li>
                    <li>As a bonus action, you can speed up time for one creature within 60 feet that you can see. This creature can only take a bonus action, attack, or make a skill check this turn.</li>
                    <li>Psychic and force damage you deal in this form is doubled.</li>
                    <li>You cannot be restrained, petrified, stunned, petrified, or grappled. In addition, you have resistance to force, psychic, and nonmagical bludgeoning, slashing, and piercing damage.</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">This transformation lasts 1d4 + 1 rounds, after which time returns to normal. Once you use this feature, you cannot use it again until you complete a long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You take on the aspects of Time and Space itself for 1 minute. At the start of your turn, roll 1d4. This is the number of additional actions you may take on this turn. You may not take the same action more than once on this turn. As a bonus action, you can speed up time for one creature within 60 feet that you can see. This creature can only take a bonus action, attack, or make a skill check this turn. Psychic and force damage you deal in this form is doubled.You cannot be restrained, petrified, stunned, petrified, or grappled. In addition, you have resistance to force, psychic, and nonmagical bludgeoning, slashing, and piercing damage.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
    
</elements>