<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Covenant of the Vestige Chimeric Covenant</name>
        <update version="0.0.2">
            <file name="slayer-covenant-of-the-vestige.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/subclasses/slayer/slayer-covenant-of-the-vestige.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>

    <element name="Covenant of the Vestige" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_REVLID_HOMEBREWERY_SOURCE_COVENANT_OF_THE_VESTIGE">
        <description>
            <![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="abbreviation">COTV</set>
            <set name="url">https://homebrewery.naturalcrit.com/share/H1bhgctwVN</set>
            <set name="image"></set>
            <set name="author" abbreviation="REVLID" url="https://www.reddit.com/u/revlid">Wizards of the Coast</set>
            <set name="official">false</set>
            <set name="supplement">false</set>
            <set name="playtest">false</set>
            <set name="third-party">false</set>
            <set name="homebrew">false</set>
            <set name="league">false</set>
            <set name="release">20200118</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Covenant of the Vestige" type="Archetype" source="Covenant of the Vestige" id="ID_REVLID_COTV_ARCHETYPE_SLAYER_COVENANT_OF_THE_VESTIGE">
        <supports>Chimeric Covenant</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The shamans of forgotten gods, the smuggler-priests of banished spirits, the occultists so desperate as to seek devils that do not exist... The Covenant of the Vestige bind such strange entities to their very soul.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">Vestige Covenant Quirks</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>d6</td><td>Quirk</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1</td><td>You bear a secret brand that makes priests flinch.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>You dream of an age when temples rose in your name.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>3</td><td>When you speak, your voice is twinned with another.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>4</td><td>Inexplicable and ancient rituals populate your day.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>5</td><td>While bound, you gain monstrous attributes.</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>You crave food you’ve never even tasted.</td></tr>
            </table>
            <div element="ID_REVLID_COTV_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLAYER_VESTIGE_MONSTROUS_AFFINITY" />
            <div element="ID_REVLID_COTV_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLAYER_VESTIGE_RITUAL_OF_BINDING" />
            <div element="ID_REVLID_COTV_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLAYER_VESTIGE_FORBIDDEN_PACT" />
            <div element="ID_REVLID_COTV_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLAYER_VESTIGE_LINGERING_WISDOM" />
            <div element="ID_REVLID_COTV_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLAYER_VESTIGE_SOUL_GUARDIAN" />
            <div element="ID_REVLID_COTV_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLAYER_VESTIGE_TOTEM_OF_ELDER_POWERS" />
            <div element="ID_REVLID_COTV_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLAYER_VESTIGE_SAMPLE_VESTIGES" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_REVLID_COTV_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLAYER_VESTIGE_MONSTROUS_AFFINITY" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_REVLID_COTV_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLAYER_VESTIGE_RITUAL_OF_BINDING" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_REVLID_COTV_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLAYER_VESTIGE_FORBIDDEN_PACT" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_REVLID_COTV_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLAYER_VESTIGE_LINGERING_WISDOM" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_REVLID_COTV_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLAYER_VESTIGE_SOUL_GUARDIAN" level="14" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_REVLID_COTV_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLAYER_VESTIGE_TOTEM_OF_ELDER_POWERS" level="20" />
            <select type="List" name="Vestige Covenant Quirk">
                <item id="1">You bear a secret brand that makes priests flinch.</item>
                <item id="2">You dream of an age when temples rose in your name.</item>
                <item id="3">When you speak, your voice is twinned with another.</item>
                <item id="4">Inexplicable and ancient rituals populate your day.</item>
                <item id="5">While bound, you gain monstrous attributes.</item>
                <item id="6">You crave food you’ve never even tasted.</item>
            </select>
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Monstrous Affinity" type="Archetype Feature" source="Covenant of the Vestige" id="ID_REVLID_COTV_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLAYER_VESTIGE_MONSTROUS_AFFINITY">
            <description>
                <p>You lack a natural affinity for a particular type of creature, but can gain one through your Forbidden Pact feature.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you make a skill or ability check directly involving the creature type associated with your bound vestige, you can use your Occult Studies without expending a use.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Ritual of Binding" type="Archetype Feature" source="Covenant of the Vestige" id="ID_REVLID_COTV_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLAYER_VESTIGE_RITUAL_OF_BINDING">
            <description>
                <p>Once you join this covenant at 3rd level, you can cast slayer spells you know as rituals, if that spell has the ritual tag.</p>
                <p class="indent">You also learn to bind forgotten spirits called vestiges, with the use of a special trinket (<em>Player’s Handbook</em>, p. 159) called a seal. For example, Acererak, the unmade demilich, might have as his seal a half-demon’s tooth, a time-ravaged spellbook, or an eyeball-shaped ruby. You acquire two seals by joining this covenant, and can discover more by exploring and adventuring, just as a wizard finds spellbooks or scrolls. Seals are often considered heretical, and locked away where an adventuring party might stumble upon them.</p>
                <p class="indent">Each vestige is associated with a single creature type, damage type, invocation, and proficiency. Several examples are given at the end of this covenant entry.</p>
                <p class="indent">You can bind a vestige during a long rest by performing a special, hour-long ritual involving its seal. At the end of the ritual, the seal merges with your body and the vestige is bound. This replaces any vestige you currently have bound.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can cast ritual spells as rituals. You can also bind 1 vestige during a long rest, merging it with your body. </description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Forbidden Pact" type="Archetype Feature" source="Covenant of the Vestige" id="ID_REVLID_COTV_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLAYER_VESTIGE_FORBIDDEN_PACT">
            <description>
                <p>While bound to a vestige, you gain its associated invocation, as well as an affinity for its associated creature type. You also gain the ability to inflict its damage type with your Cursed Brand feature, if you could not already.</p>
                <p class="indent">Invocations provided by vestiges follow additional rules:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>You must meet the normal prerequisites, but ignore the Pact of the Blade prerequisite.</li>
                    <li>You can use any weapon that benefits from your Cursed Brand feature in place of a pact weapon.</li>
                    <li>You use Intelligence in place of Charisma.</li>
                    <li>Any invocation which allows you to spend a Pact Magic spell slot to cast a spell requires a Pact Magic spell slot of the appropriate level or higher.</li>
                    <li>Replace any mention of "warlock spell slot" with "Pact Magic spell slot".</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">Invocations are detailed in the Warlock class entry in the <em>Player’s Handbook</em> and <em>Xanathar’s Guide to Everything</em>.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You gain the invocation associated with your bound vestige. You use Intelligence in place of Charisma for your invocations.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Lingering Wisdom" type="Archetype Feature" source="Covenant of the Vestige" id="ID_REVLID_COTV_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLAYER_VESTIGE_LINGERING_WISDOM">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 6th level, you can perform a ritual lasting 1 minute to contact a vestige through its seal, asking it a single question as described in the <i>commune</i> spell.</p>
                <p class="indent">In addition, while bound to a vestige you gain its associated proficiency, and can spend Occult Studies dice to enhance rolls involving it. If your bound vestige’s proficiency is an Intelligence skill that you have proficiency with, you can receive the benefits of Occult Studies without expending a use of that feature.</p>
                <div class="reference">
                    <div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMMUNE" />
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can perform a ritual lasting 1 minute to contact a vestige through its seal, asking it a single question as described in the commune spell. While bound to a vestige you gain its associated proficiency, and can spend Occult Studies dice to enhance rolls involving it. If your bound vestige’s proficiency is an Intelligence skill that you have proficiency with, you can receive the benefits of Occult Studies without expending a use of that feature.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Soul Guardian" type="Archetype Feature" source="Covenant of the Vestige" id="ID_REVLID_COTV_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLAYER_VESTIGE_SOUL_GUARDIAN">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 14th level, while bound to a vestige, you gain resistance to its associated damage type.</p>
                <p class="indent">In addition, if you would be charmed while you have a bound vestige, you can use your reaction to become immune to that condition until the end of the turn. You must complete a short rest before you do so again.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Short Rest" action="Reaction">
                <description>If you would be charmed while you have a bound vestige, you can use your reaction to become immune to that condition until the end of the turn. While bound to a vestige, you gain resistance to its associated damage type.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Totem of Elder Powers" type="Archetype Feature" source="Covenant of the Vestige" id="ID_REVLID_COTV_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLAYER_VESTIGE_TOTEM_OF_ELDER_POWERS">
            <description>
                <p>When you reach 20th level, you can use an action on your turn to fully manifest your bound vestige, which appears to emanate from you like a terrifying guardian spirit.</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>When you take the Attack action, you can make an extra melee spell attack against a creature within 10 feet. The attack does damage equal to 1d12 + your Intelligence modifier, of the type associated with your vestige.</li>
                    <li>You gain an additional reaction, which you can only use on your turn to make an opportunity attack. This opportunity attack uses the spell attack described above.</li>
                    <li>You gain immunity to your vestige’s associated damage type. You also gain temporary hit points equal to your Intelligence modifier at the start of each of your turns, as your vestige soaks up what damage it can.</li>
                </ul>
                <p class="indent">This feature ends after 1 minute. You must complete a short or long rest to use it again.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Short Rest">
                <description>You can manifest your bound vestige for 1 minute. When you take the Attack action, you can make an extra melee spell attack against a creature within 10 feet. The attack does damage equal to 1d12 + {{intelligence:modifier}}, of the type associated with your vestige. You gain an additional reaction, which you can only use on your turn to make an opportunity attack. This opportunity attack uses the spell attack described above. You gain immunity to your vestige’s associated damage type. You also gain {{intelligence:modifier}} temporary hit points at the start of each of your turns.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
    
        <element name="Sample Vestiages" type="Archetype Feature" source="Covenant of the Vestige" id="ID_REVLID_COTV_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLAYER_VESTIGE_SAMPLE_VESTIGES">
            <description>
                <table>
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Name</td><td>Creature</td><td>Damage</td><td>Invocation</td><td>Proficiency</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>Acererak</td><td>Undead</td><td>Necrotic</td><td>Whispers of the Grave</td><td>Arcana</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>Agares</td><td>Elementals</td><td>Bludgeoning</td><td>Minions of Chaos</td><td>Gaming set</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>Aym</td><td>Humanoids (Dwarfs)</td><td>Fire</td><td>Armor of Shadows</td><td>Blacksmith’s tools</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>Geryon</td><td>Fiends</td><td>Acid</td><td>Devil’s Sight</td><td>Religion</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>Haagenti</td><td>Giants</td><td>Cold</td><td>Bewitching Whispers</td><td>Disguise kit</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>Malphas</td><td>Humanoids (Elves)</td><td>Poison</td><td>One With Shadows</td><td>Poisoner’s kit</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>Naberius</td><td>Monstrosities</td><td>Psychic</td><td>Mask of Many Faces</td><td>Deception</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>Savnok</td><td>Celestials</td><td>Lightning</td><td>Improved Pact Weapon</td><td>Sleight of Hand</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>Vanus</td><td>Fiends</td><td>Thunder</td><td>Trickster’s Escape</td><td>Perception</td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
</elements>