<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Bard College of the Eternal Veil</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="bard-college-of-the-eternal-veil.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/musica-aeternam/bard-college-of-the-eternal-veil.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="College of the Eternal Veil" type="Archetype" source="Musica Aeternam" id="ID_DJM_MABH_ARCHETYPE_BARD_COLLEGE_OF_THE_ETERNAL_VEIL">
        <supports>Bard College</supports>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">All the world’s a stage, and all the men and women merely players</p>
            <p class="flavor" style="text-align: right;">—Shakespeare, As you like it</p>
            <p>They call themselves Weavers. Some would say they’ve completely lost touch with reality, that they truly don’t know what’s real and what isn’t anymore. But a Weaver would simply ask, “What is reality? Is this chair real? Can you see it? Smell the wood and dust? Hear it creak when I move it? Can you feel it splintering along the top?” Then with a wink the chair is gone. “If you can’t trust that it was real, when you had it right in front of you, how do you know anything is?”</p>
            <p class="indent">Weavers are Bards who combine acting with the magic of illusion to create immersive stories of their own design. They aren’t content to act only on the stage a few nights a week. No, the thrill of acting is far too great to restrict only to the theater. They choose instead to make the world around them at any given moment their stage, whenever, wherever, and with whomever passing by drawn into their drama. They can be anyone and anywhere they wish and in a blink of an eye it’s all shifted and they’re gone.</p>
            <div element="ID_DJM_MABH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COTETV_THE_WEAVERS_CRAFT" />
            <div element="ID_DJM_MABH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COTETV_SETTING_THE_STAGE" />
            <div element="ID_DJM_MABH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COTETV_SPINNING_THE_TALE" />
            <div element="ID_DJM_MABH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COTETV_LOWERING_THE_VEIL" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DJM_MABH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COTETV_THE_WEAVERS_CRAFT" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DJM_MABH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COTETV_SETTING_THE_STAGE" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DJM_MABH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COTETV_SPINNING_THE_TALE" level="14" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DJM_MABH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COTETV_LOWERING_THE_VEIL" level="20" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="The Weaver’s Craft" type="Archetype Feature" source="Musica Aeternam" id="ID_DJM_MABH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COTETV_THE_WEAVERS_CRAFT">
            <description>
                <p>At 3rd level you specialize in the school of illusion and begin to incorporate these skills into your performances. You learn the <em>minor illusion</em> cantrip. If you already know this cantrip, you learn a different bard cantrip of your choice. The cantrip doesn’t count against your cantrips known. When you cast <em>minor illusion</em>, you can create both a sound and an image with a single casting of the spell.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you cast minor illusion, you can create both a sound and an image with a single casting of the spell.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MINOR_ILLUSION" spellcasting="Bard" known="true" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Setting the Stage" type="Archetype Feature" source="Musica Aeternam" id="ID_DJM_MABH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COTETV_SETTING_THE_STAGE">
            <description>
                <p>By 6th level, you can seamlessly blend your acting with your illusions to great effect. When you attempt a Deception check in the presence of one of your illusions, you can manipulate it to reinforce your charade and gain advantage on the roll.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you attempt a Deception check in the presence of one of your illusions, you can manipulate it to reinforce your charade and gain advantage on the roll.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Spinning the Tale" type="Archetype Feature" source="Musica Aeternam" id="ID_DJM_MABH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COTETV_SPINNING_THE_TALE">
            <description>
                <p>At 14th level, you are allowed to make a Performance check when a creature is presented with proof that your illusion is not real. If your roll is higher than their Insight roll, you soothe their doubts and they still believe in your illusion.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You are allowed to make a Performance check when a creature is presented with proof that your illusion is not real. If your roll is higher than their Insight roll, you soothe their doubts and they still believe in your illusion.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Lowering the Veil (optional)" type="Archetype Feature" source="Musica Aeternam" id="ID_DJM_MABH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COTETV_LOWERING_THE_VEIL">
            <description>
                <p>Once you reach 20th level, your illusions are so real that they trick a creature’s mind into believing that they can actually be felt. As a bonus action, you can imbue an existing illusion of yours with this potent ability, which lasts for ten minutes. Each time a creature comes into contact with part of the illusion they make an Intelligence save. If they fail, their body involuntarily stops itself, as if they had actually touched the object, and the illusion is not broken. For example, you could effectively lock them in a room with no way out or lose them in a crowd of people. The illusions can do them no harm, other than the sense of touching something solid. You can use this ability once per long rest.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>You can imbue your illusion with the ability to be felt for 10 minutes. Each time a creature comes into contact with part of the illusion they make an Intelligence save. If they fail, their body involuntarily stops itself, as if they had actually touched the object, and the illusion is not broken.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
    
</elements>