<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Bard College of the Sacred Yew</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="bard-college-of-the-sacred-yew.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/musica-aeternam/bard-college-of-the-sacred-yew.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="College of the Sacred Yew" type="Archetype" source="Musica Aeternam" id="ID_DJM_MABH_ARCHETYPE_BARD_COLLEGE_OF_THE_SACRED_YEW">
        <supports>Bard College</supports>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Hear the voice of the bard,</p>
            <p class="flavor">Who present, past, and future sees;</p>
            <p class="flavor">Whose ears have heard</p>
            <p class="flavor">The Holy Word</p>
            <p class="flavor">That walk’d among the ancient trees.</p>
            <p class="flavor" style="text-align:right">—William Blake, Hear the Voice</p>
            <p>While most Druids keep to themselves and hold their private rituals in sacred groves, others are also often priests of secluded tribal societies, preaching the balance of nature and leading the villagers into a life of harmony with the plants and animals around them. In these places, Bards hold a place of honor akin to their Druidic brethren. They are magicians and wonder-workers to those around them and use their arcane skills to tend to and protect the close-knit communities that they are born into. They learn the histories of their people by memory, keep track of their systems of laws, and often become advisors to the local chieftan or king, aided by their talents in divination and prophecy.</p>
            <div element="ID_DJM_MABH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COTSY_DRUIDIC_TRAINING" />
            <div element="ID_DJM_MABH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COTSY_WILD_SHAPE" />
            <div element="ID_DJM_MABH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COTSY_EAR_OF_THE_KING" />
            <div element="ID_DJM_MABH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COTSY_GIFT_OF_PROPHESY" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DJM_MABH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COTSY_DRUIDIC_TRAINING" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DJM_MABH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COTSY_WILD_SHAPE" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DJM_MABH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COTSY_EAR_OF_THE_KING" level="14" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DJM_MABH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COTSY_GIFT_OF_PROPHESY" level="20" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Druidic Training" type="Archetype Feature" source="Musica Aeternam" id="ID_DJM_MABH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COTSY_DRUIDIC_TRAINING">
            <description>
                <p>At 3rd level, the Bard of the Sacred Yew undergoes initiation into the Druidic orders to further his or her training. You add Druidic to your known languages and learn two cantrips of your choice from the Druid spell list. These are considered Bard spells for you.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_DRUIDIC" />
                <select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Druidic Training)" number="2" supports="Druid,0" spellcasting="Bard" known="true" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Wild Shape" type="Archetype Feature" source="Musica Aeternam" id="ID_DJM_MABH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COTSY_WILD_SHAPE">
            <description>
                <p>Once reaching 6th level, you are taught the secrets of Druidic shapeshifting. You can use this ability as a Druid of 2nd level. At 12th level you can change form as a Druid of 4th level, but with flying speed allowed, and at 19th level you can change form as a Druid of 8th level. For the complete rules, see the Druid Wild Shape ability on pages 66-67 of the <em>Player’s Handbook</em>.</p>
                <p class="indent">In addition, at 12th level you may choose from three specific bird forms, unique to the College of the Sacred Yew: bardic sparrow, bardic owl, and bardic eagle. When in each of these forms, the Bard can sing a bird song that imparts benefits to party members within 60 feet. This benefit lasts for as long as the Bard continues to sing. The sparrow song grants 10 speed, the owl song grants darkvision 30 feet, and the eagle song grants advantage on perception checks that rely on sight.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="2/Short Rest">
                <description>You can magically assume the shape of a beast (CR of 1/4 or lower that doesn’t have a flying or swimming speed) that you have seen before. You can stay in a beast shape for 1 hour. You then revert to your normal form unless you expend another use of this feature. You can revert to your normal form earlier by using a bonus action on your turn. You automatically revert if you fall unconscious, drop to 0 hit points, or die.</description>
                <description level="12">You can magically assume the shape of a beast (CR of 1/2 or lower that doesn’t have a swimming speed) that you have seen before, a bardic sparrow, a bardic owl, or a bardic eagle. When in each of these special bird forms, the Bard can sing a bird song that imparts benefits to party members within 60 feet. This benefit lasts for as long as the Bard continues to sing. The sparrow song grants 10 speed, the owl song grants darkvision 30 feet, and the eagle song grants advantage on perception checks that rely on sight. You can stay in a beast shape for 2 hours. You then revert to your normal form unless you expend another use of this feature. You can revert to your normal form earlier by using a bonus action on your turn. You automatically revert if you fall unconscious, drop to 0 hit points, or die.</description>
                <description level="19">You can magically assume the shape of a beast (CR of 1 or lower) that you have seen before, a bardic sparrow, a bardic owl, or a bardic eagle. When in each of these special bird forms, the Bard can sing a bird song that imparts benefits to party members within 60 feet. This benefit lasts for as long as the Bard continues to sing. The sparrow song grants 10 speed, the owl song grants darkvision 30 feet, and the eagle song grants advantage on perception checks that rely on sight. You can stay in a beast shape for 2 hours. You then revert to your normal form unless you expend another use of this feature. You can revert to your normal form earlier by using a bonus action on your turn. You automatically revert if you fall unconscious, drop to 0 hit points, or die.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Ear of the King" type="Archetype Feature" source="Musica Aeternam" id="ID_DJM_MABH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COTSY_EAR_OF_THE_KING">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 14th level, the reputation of your College precedes you and your advice is highly valued and sought after. You can always find food and lodging with nobility or other local authority figures. You also have advantage on Persuasion checks made to influence their actions.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can always find food and lodging with nobility or other local authority figures. You also have advantage on Persuasion checks made to influence their actions.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Gift of Prophesy (optional)" type="Archetype Feature" source="Musica Aeternam" id="ID_DJM_MABH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COTSY_GIFT_OF_PROPHESY">
            <description>
                <p>At 20th level, once per long rest you can glimpse the future clearly enough to warn others of the dangers that lie before them. If you spend 1 minute concentrating on a person, you can look into their future and tell them fragments of what you see. They roll two d20s and record the numbers rolled. They can then replace any attack roll, saving throw, or ability check made by them with one of these rolls. They must choose to do so before the roll, and can only replace a roll in this way once per turn. Each roll can only be used once. When they finish a long rest, they lose any unused rolls.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
                <description>If you spend 1 minute concentrating on a person, you can look into their future and tell them fragments of what you see. They roll two d20s and record the numbers rolled. They can then replace any attack roll, saving throw, or ability check made by them with one of these rolls. They must choose to do so before the roll, and can only replace a roll in this way once per turn. Each roll can only be used once. When they finish a long rest, they lose any unused rolls.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
    
</elements>