<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Bard College Troupe of the Shadowdancers</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="bard-troupe-of-the-shadowdancers.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/musica-aeternam/bard-troupe-of-the-shadowdancers.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Troupe of the Shadowdancers" type="Archetype" source="Musica Aeternam" id="ID_DJM_MABH_ARCHETYPE_BARD_TROUPE_OF_THE_SHADOWDANCERS">
        <supports>Bard College</supports>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">All the beauty of life is made up of light and shadow.</p>
            <p class="flavor" style="text-align: right;">—Leo Tolstoy</p>
            <p>Stories of shadowdancers have long filled the imagination of common and learned folk alike. Most people have never encountered one, but they will insist they know exactly what they are: Thieves and cutthroats all, ones who sell their souls for power over the darkness. Some have even heard that they travel to the shadow realm itself to uncover long forgotten and forbidden secrets.</p>
            <p class="indent">All of this is utter nonsense, of course, but the real shadowdancers enjoy the stories as much as the next traveler. No, learning to dance with shadows isn’t a matter of dark pacts but an art, born of hard practice and sweat like any other and combined with bardic magic. Dance and the search for beauty in perfect movements lies at the heart of their craft, not darkness. In fact, what use is darkness if no one can then see you move? No, the light and shadows are just their partners, illuminating their bodies with fleeting shadowy images and shades of gray. In time they learn to control the shadows around them and perfect their beautiful duet.</p>
            <div element="ID_DJM_MABH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TOTSD_FLEET_OF_FOOT" />
            <div element="ID_DJM_MABH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TOTSD_GRACE_UNDER_PRESSURE" />
            <div element="ID_DJM_MABH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TOTSD_FADING_LIGHT" />
            <div element="ID_DJM_MABH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TOTSD_TWISTING_SHADOWS" />
            <div element="ID_DJM_MABH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TOTSD_SHADOW_DANCE" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DJM_MABH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TOTSD_FLEET_OF_FOOT" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DJM_MABH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TOTSD_GRACE_UNDER_PRESSURE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DJM_MABH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TOTSD_FADING_LIGHT" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DJM_MABH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TOTSD_TWISTING_SHADOWS" level="14" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DJM_MABH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TOTSD_SHADOW_DANCE" level="20" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Fleet of Foot" type="Archetype Feature" source="Musica Aeternam" id="ID_DJM_MABH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TOTSD_FLEET_OF_FOOT">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 3rd level, your training in dance grants you improved athleticism that you can use in combat. You can take a bonus action on each of your turns in combat, which can be used only to take the Dash, Disengage, or Hide actions.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Bonus Action">
                <description>You can take the Dash, Disengage, or Hide actions.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Grace under Pressure" type="Archetype Feature" source="Musica Aeternam" id="ID_DJM_MABH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TOTSD_GRACE_UNDER_PRESSURE">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 3rd level, your natural agility can inspire those around you. A creature that has a Bardic Inspiration die from you can use that die to increase their movement speed by 15 feet for one turn.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Bardic Inspiration">
                <description>A creature that has a Bardic Inspiration die from you can use that die to increase their movement speed by 15 feet for one turn.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Fading Light" type="Archetype Feature" source="Musica Aeternam" id="ID_DJM_MABH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TOTSD_FADING_LIGHT">
            <description>
                <p>Shadowdancers learn to shape light at 6th level, to create the ideal conditions for shadows to exist. Once per short rest you can dim the light in a 30 foot radius centered on you. This effect lasts for 1 minute, moves with you, and gives you and your party (those within the radius) advantage on stealth checks based on sight.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
                <description>You can dim the light in a 30 foot radius centered on you. This effect lasts for 1 minute, moves with you, and gives you and your party (those within the radius) advantage on stealth checks based on sight.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Twisting Shadows" type="Archetype Feature" source="Musica Aeternam" id="ID_DJM_MABH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TOTSD_TWISTING_SHADOWS">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 14th level, you can control your shadow and the shadows that fall across you to mislead an attacker, by moving them sporadically in unnatural directions. When targeted with a melee or ranged attack, you can use your reaction to force your attacker to roll at disadvantage. This ability uses a Bardic Inspiration die.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="Bardic Inspiration" action="Reaction">
                <description>When targeted with a melee or ranged attack, you can use your reaction to force your attacker to roll at disadvantage.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Shadow Dance (optional)" type="Archetype Feature" source="Musica Aeternam" id="ID_DJM_MABH_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TOTSD_SHADOW_DANCE">
            <description>
                <p>At 20th level, you have reached the pinnacle of the Shadowdancer’s craft and can animate your own shadow to aid you in combat. Once per long rest, you can use your action to have your shadow rise off the ground in two-dimensions and attack your nearest opponent for up to 1 minute.</p>
                <p class="indent">The shadow is opaque and partially obstructs vision (other than yours and those that can see through magical darkness). It is also immaterial and exists in your space, passing harmlessly through you and your attacks as it fights. The constant barrage of movement from your shadow distracts your opponent and gives all of your attacks advantage. It also causes your opponent to suffer disadvantage on their attacks against you. This only affects a single target that both you and your shadow attack together, though as a free action you can direct your shadow to attack a new target once per round. At the end of the minute, your shadow melds back down to its normal position on the floor.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet usage="1/Long Rest" action="Action">
                <description>You can have your shadow rise off the ground in two-dimensions and attack your nearest opponent for up to 1 minute. The constant barrage of movement from your shadow distracts your opponent and gives all of your attacks advantage. It also causes your opponent to suffer disadvantage on their attacks against you. This only affects a single target that both you and your shadow attack together, though as a free action you can direct your shadow to attack a new target once per round.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
    
</elements>