<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Bard College of Nobility</name>
        <author url="https://www.gmbinder.com/profile/kibblestasty">KibblesTasty</author>
        <update version="0.0.4">
            <file name="bard-college-of-nobility.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/aurora-elements/master/x-the-elder/compendia/kibblestasty/compendium-1-civilization/bard-college-of-nobility.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="College of Nobility" type="Archetype" source="Compendium 1:Civilization" id="ID_KIBBLESTASTY_C1C_ARCHETYPE_BARD_COLLEGE_OF_NOBILITY">
        <supports>Bard College</supports>
        <description>
            <p>A Bard from the College of Nobility does not reflect the notion of many would have of a Bard, for these are no traveling minstrels who prance for the entertainment of others. No, these Bards are more likely to be served than serve others, as they hail from the bluest of bloodlines and the more vaunted of halls.</p>
            <p class="indent">From the lord astride his horse issuing authoritative commands to his men to the graceful princess calling her servitors to action, the very words of these nobles can inspire heroics. To these blessed bloodlines, the enchanting magic of a Bard is as natural as breathing.</p>
            <p class="indent">An adventurer on this path is not inherently of noble background, though they most often are. A noble reared on the laws of the land is usually lawful, but extraordinary circumstances may have brought about a rebellious streak in one that now seeks to overthrow unfit rulers (or rulers that aren’t them, anyway).</p>
            <div element="ID_KIBBLESTASTY_C1C_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_NOBILITY_LIVING_INSPIRATION" />
            <div element="ID_KIBBLESTASTY_C1C_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_NOBILITY_INSPIRE_TO_ACTION" />
            <div element="ID_KIBBLESTASTY_C1C_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_NOBILITY_NOBLESSE" />
            <div element="ID_KIBBLESTASTY_C1C_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_NOBILITY_DIVINE_RIGHT" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KIBBLESTASTY_C1C_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_NOBILITY_LIVING_INSPIRATION" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KIBBLESTASTY_C1C_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_NOBILITY_INSPIRE_TO_ACTION" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KIBBLESTASTY_C1C_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_NOBILITY_NOBLESSE" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KIBBLESTASTY_C1C_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_NOBILITY_DIVINE_RIGHT" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
        <element name="Living Inspiration" type="Archetype Feature" source="Compendium 1:Civilization" id="ID_KIBBLESTASTY_C1C_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_NOBILITY_LIVING_INSPIRATION">
            <description>
                <p>When you join the College of Nobility at 3rd level, your grace and presence are such that you gain additional two additional uses of Bardic Inspiration. This increases to three additionally uses at 11th level, and 4 additional uses at 17th level.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet display="false">
                <description></description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="bardic-inspiration:count" value="2" level="3" />
                <stat name="bardic-inspiration:count" value="1" level="11" />
                <stat name="bardic-inspiration:count" value="1" level="17" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Inspire to Action" type="Archetype Feature" source="Compendium 1:Civilization" id="ID_KIBBLESTASTY_C1C_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_NOBILITY_INSPIRE_TO_ACTION">
            <description>
                <p>Also at 3rd level, you learn how to use your charisma to propel others to greater action, spurring them to act. As an action, you can expend a use of your Bardic Inspiration to allow an ally that can see or hear you within 60 feet to use their reaction to immediately making a single weapon attack. If the attack hits, they can add your Inspiration Dice + Charisma Modifier to the damage dealt.</p>
                <p class="indent">Directing another creature to attack in this manner does not count as as making an attack or casting a spell.</p>
                <div class="sidebar">
                    <h5>INSPIRING ROGUES TO ACTION</h5>
                    <p>Some veteran players and Dungeon Masters may instantly see a powerful synergy between Inspire to Action and the Rogue class feature Sneak Attack. While this is indeed a powerful combination, consider that, ultimately, while this ability can be used to get a second sneak attack for on a rogue player, it still has the cost of a player action to accomplish.</p>
                    <p class="indent">While it is a powerful combination, there are combinations that can leverage the same power with less action cost in the hands of clever players already.</p>
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet action="Action" usage="Bardic Inspiration">
                <description>You can expend a use of your Bardic Inspiration to allow an ally that can see or hear you within 60 feet to use their reaction to immediately making a single weapon attack. If the attack hits, they can add your Inspiration Dice + Charisma Modifier to the damage dealt. Directing another creature to attack in this manner does not count as as making an attack or casting a spell.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
        <element name="Noblesse" type="Archetype Feature" source="Compendium 1:Civilization" id="ID_KIBBLESTASTY_C1C_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_NOBILITY_NOBLESSE">
            <description>
                <p>At 6th level, when you roll for initiative you can add your Charisma modifier to your roll and you can choose to swap your result with another willing creature within 30 feet, immediately exchanging total Initiative roll results.</p>
                <p class="indent">Additionally, you learn the spell <i>command</i>, and it counts as a Bard spell for you.</p>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>You can choose to swap your Initiative result with another willing creature within 30 feet, immediately exchanging total Initiative roll results.</description>
            </sheet>
            <rules>
                <stat name="initiative" value="charisma:modifier" />
                <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMMAND" spellcasting="Bard" known="true" />
            </rules>
        </element>
        <element name="Divine Right" type="Archetype Feature" source="Compendium 1:Civilization" id="ID_KIBBLESTASTY_C1C_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_NOBILITY_DIVINE_RIGHT">
            <description>
                <p>Starting at 14th level, you are never truly out of inspiration, as your mere presence is an inspiration. When you’ve exhausted your last use of Bardic Inspiration, you can continue to use features that require Bardic Inspiration, but your Inspiration dice are reduced to d4 dice until complete a short or long rest.</p>
                <div class="sidebar">
                    <h5>RELYING ON YOUR COMPANIONS</h5>
                    <p>A Bard of the College of Nobility works best when surrounded by loyal retainers or companions to whom inspire to action with their noble presence. While originally derived as an NPC archetype (and ideal for such a role), it can be a rewarding player archetype, but consider carefully if you have reliably companions before decided to rely on them by choosing this College!</p>
                </div>
            </description>
            <sheet>
                <description>When you’ve exhausted your last use of Bardic Inspiration, you can continue to use features that require Bardic Inspiration, but your Inspiration dice are reduced to d4 dice until complete a short or long rest.</description>
            </sheet>
        </element>
</elements>